<?xml version='1.0' ?>
<!DOCTYPE announcements SYSTEM "http://elleconnect.com/andrewdo/bleaf/dtds/bLeaf.dtd">
<evidences>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Alaska</title>
  <description>
    The animal rights group Friends of Animals has announced a boycott of travelling to Alaska because of the Alaskan Government s decision to allow wolf hunting.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Alaska</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Animal testing and animal rights</title>
  <description>
    A number of companies are on the list for their poor record on animal testing. These companies include Boots, British Heart Foundation, Estee Lauder, Herbal Essences, Iams, Johnson and Johnson and Nestle. There are also several companies on list for animal rights related issues. These include: Adidas, Burberry, Escada, Japan, Harrods, Joseph Ltd, Kentucky Fried Chicken, Kurt Geiger and Tesco. Find out more on the animal rights boycotts page .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Animal testing and animal rights</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Air travel</title>
  <description>
    Aviation is the fastest-growing source of climate change causing greenhouse gas emissions. Visit low fly zone for more informaion on the boycott . For information on airlines see Ethical Consumer's &quot;Travel in the UK and to Europe&quot; report .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Air travel</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Adidas</title>
  <description>
    Is on the list due to a boycott call from Viva for using kangaroo skin to make some types of football boots.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Adidas</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Ahava Dead Sea Laboratories</title>
  <description>
    CODEPINK , the US women s anti-war movement, has launched the Stolen Beauty campaign targeting Ahava Dead Sea Laboratories for its invlovement in the occupied territories.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Ahava Dead Sea Laboratories</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Bacardi</title>
  <description>
    Is on the list for continuing to use its Cuban origins in its marketing despite being active in anti-Cuba lobby groups in the US. For more information see Rock around the Blockade . To see how they rated and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's buyers' guide to rum.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Bacardi</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Barclays</title>
  <description>
    This bank is subject to a boycott call by Ethical Consumer for its involvement in the Canadian oil sands. To see how they rated and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to current accounts.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Barclays</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Bluefin Tuna</title>
  <description>
    According to Greenpeace Bluefin tuna is an endangered species which could be extinct by 2012. Despite this it is still being served in sushi restaurants in the UK. For more information see the Greenpeace website . For more information see Ethical Consumers free Buyers' Guide to tinned tuna .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Bluefin Tuna</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Boots</title>
  <description>
    The company is listed in the 11th edition of Naturewatch's Compassionate Shopping Guide as a company to avoid. To see how they rated and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to shampoo.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Boots</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Botswana</title>
  <description>
    Survival International have called a travel boycott of Botswana due to the treatment of indigenous communities. A group of Bushmen were illegally evicted from their land in 2002 to make way for diamond mining.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Botswana</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott BP</title>
  <description>
    The company has come in for a boycott call thanks to one of the worst environmental disasters ever to befall the United states, the Deepwater Horizon oil spill in the Gulf of Mexico. You can find out more at two boycott sites here and here . To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guides to petrol and diesel .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>BP</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott British Heart Foundation</title>
  <description>
    Is on the list for conducting animal testing in order to find out about a human condition. The boycott is called by PETA whose British Heartless Foundation website contains a list of health charities which do not test on animals.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>British Heart Foundation</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Burberry</title>
  <description>
    Peta are calling for a boycott of Burberry over its use of fur. See www.bloodyburberry.com/home.asp and www.bloodyburberry.com/features/chavs/index.asp for more information.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Burberry</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Canada</title>
  <description>
    Respect for Animals has called a boycott of Canada due to the government-subsidised slaughter of nearly one million seals over the last three years. Respect for Animals ,
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Canada</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Caterpillar</title>
  <description>
    War on Want have called for a boycott of Caterpillar for selling bulldozers to Israel in full knowledge that they will be armoured and used to destroy Palestinian homes, infrastructure and agriculture in the Occupied Palestinian Territories. It is also subjuct to a boycott call from Ethical Consumer for involvement in the Canadian oil sands . Chevron Texaco Is subject to 2 boycott calls. The first from Chevron Toxico for dumping billions of gallons of toxic waste in the Ecuadorian Amazon and failing to clean it up. The second from Avaaz.org are also calling for a global boycott of Chevron and all its subsidiaries over its involvement with Burma. To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guides to petrol and diesel . China Boycottmadeinchina have called a boycott of the country for its continued human rights abuses and for its occupation of Tibet.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Caterpillar</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Coca-Cola</title>
  <description>
    Is under boycott calls from the Colombia Solidarity Campaign , and the India Resource Centre.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Coca-Cola</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott EDF Energy</title>
  <description>
    Kick Nuclear have called a boycott of EDF for its invlovement in the planned building of a new generation of nuclear power stations across the UK in 2011. To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guides to gas and electricity suppliers .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>EDF Energy</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Escada</title>
  <description>
    T he Campaign Against the Fur Trade are calling for a boycott of fashion group Escada for using fur products.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Escada</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Estee Lauder</title>
  <description>
    Uncaged are calling for a boycott of Estee Lauder. It was named as a company that either openly used animal-tested chemicals, or failed to demonstrated that the finished products and ingredients they used had not been tested on animals since a fixed cut-off date. To see how they rate and for alternatives see several of Ethical Consumer's Buyers' Guides in the health and beauty section.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Estee Lauder</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Gecko's Adventures</title>
  <description>
    Burma Campaign UK call for a boycott of Gecko's Adventures as they offer package tours to Burma.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Gecko's Adventures</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott H &amp;M</title>
  <description>
    The Palestinian Boycott, Divestment and Sanctions National Committee (BNC) has called for a boycott of Swedish fashion giant H&amp;M in response to the opening of its second store in Israel.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>H &amp;M</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Harrods</title>
  <description>
    When contacted by Ethical Consumer in May 2008 the Campaign Against the Fur Trade stated that were calling for a boycott of Harrods, the last department store in the UK to stock fur products.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Harrods</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Herbal Essences</title>
  <description>
    The Boycott Hurtful Essences campaign was started by Uncaged because of the company's animal testing policy. To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to shampoo .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Herbal Essences</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Hitachi</title>
  <description>
    This company subjuct to a boycott call from Ethical Consumer for involvement in Canadian oil sands . To see how they rate and for alternatives see several of Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guides in the audio visual section.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Hitachi</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott HSBC</title>
  <description>
    This company is subjuct to a boycott call from Ethical Consumer for involvement in Canadian oil sands . To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to current accounts
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>HSBC</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Iams (owned by Procter &amp; Gamble)</title>
  <description>
    This brand is under a boycott call from Uncaged for unnecessary animal testing. It is estimated Procter &amp; Gambles is responsible for the deaths of 50,000 animals each year. For more information see the Proctor and Gamble boycotts profile page For ratings and alternative brands see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers Guides to cat and dog food .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Iams (owned by Procter &amp; Gamble)</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Israel</title>
  <description>
    This country is under several boycott calls for following 'decades of refusal to abide by UN resolutions, International Humanitarian law and the Fourth Geneva Convention.' See our Israel boycotts page for more information.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Israel</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Jamaica</title>
  <description>
    Activists say that &quot;this nation should be avoided at all costs until the Jamaican government takes action to end the country s virulently homophobic climate and draconian laws that persecute homosexuals.&quot; For more information see www.boycottjamaica.org .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Jamaica</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Japan</title>
  <description>
    Japan is under a boycott call from International Fund for Animal Welfare (IFAW) due to whale hunting for &quot;scientific&quot; reasons in a protected whale sactuary around Antartica.See the Boycott Japan facebook group for more information or sign the petition.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Japan</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Johnson &amp; Johnson</title>
  <description>
    Uncaged is calling a boycott of Johnson &amp; Johnson. Uncaged have named the company as one that either openly uses animal-tested chemicals, or failed to demonstrated that the finished products and ingredients it used had not been tested on animals since a fixed cut-off date. To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guides in the health and beauty section
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Johnson &amp; Johnson</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Joseph Ltd</title>
  <description>
    Thi scompany is under a boycott call from Campaign Against the Fur Trade for selling coats and other products made from animal fur.for selling boots made from rabbit fur.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Joseph Ltd</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Junckers</title>
  <description>
    Junckers is on the boycott list due to selling Indonesian merbau flooring despite confirming that it is of unknown source. Without guarantees of the wood's origin, it's likely that merbau wood flooring could have come from Indonesia's last remaining rainforests. Contact Environmental Investigation Agency for more information. To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to carpet and flooring
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Junckers</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Kahrs</title>
  <description>
    Kahrs is on the boycott list due to selling Indonesian merbau flooring despite confirming that it is of unknown source. Without guarantees of the wood's origin, it's likely that merbau wood flooring could have come from Indonesia's last remaining rainforests.Contact Environmental Investigation Agency for more information. To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to carpet and flooring
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Kahrs</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Kentucky Fried Chicken</title>
  <description>
    PETA has called a boycott of KFC for animal welfare reasones. They say suppliers cram birds into huge waste-filled factories, breed and drug them to grow so large that they can t even walk, and often break their wings and legs. At slaughter, the birds throats are slit and they are dropped into tanks of scalding-hot water often while they are still conscious.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Kentucky Fried Chicken</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Kellogg's</title>
  <description>
    For using sugar from genetically engineered sugar beets in its products. For more information see the Organic Consumers Association website. To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to cereal . Kurt Geiger Kurt Geiger under a boycott call from Campaign Against the Fur Trade for selling boots made from rabbit fur.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Kellogg's</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott LG</title>
  <description>
    This company group is under a boycott call for their involvement in a mining project in Rapu-Rapu. See the SAVE RAPU-RAPU. SAVE OUR FUTURE. website for more info.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>LG</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Liberty Apparel</title>
  <description>
    to hold the clothing company accountable for sweatshop conditions in its suppliers' factories. The Ain't I A Woman campaign is sponsored by National Mobilisation Against Sweatshops and the Chinese Staff and Workers Association .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Liberty Apparel</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Liebherr Fridges</title>
  <description>
    is subject to a boycott call from Ethical Consumer for its involvement in Canadian oil sands . To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to fridges
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Liebherr Fridges</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott L'Oreal</title>
  <description>
    Naturewatch has a long-standing boycott of L'Oreal due to its continued use of animal testing for cosmetics. The French multinational uses ingredients that have been tested on animals, despite public statements to the contrary. It has also been criticised for lobbying against an EU ban on animal testing for cosmetics. See Ethical Consumer's buyers guides to skin care , eyeshadow and mascara for the L'Oreal company rating and alternative brands.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>L'Oreal</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott LV=</title>
  <description>
    Nottingham campaign Shut Down H&amp;K is calling for a boycott of financial services mutual LV= (formerly know as London Victoria). Activists discovered that LV= owns a small business park on an industrial estate in Nottingham which is home to H&amp;K s UK head office.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>LV=</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott M auritius</title>
  <description>
    The Gateway to Hell campaign is calling a boycott of Mauritius over its complicity in the live export of primates. See the campaign website for more details.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>M auritius</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Motorola</title>
  <description>
    The New York Campaign for the Boycott of Israel has called for a boycott of Motorola over the firm's business dealings with the Israel Defense Forces.For more information see the NYCBI website. To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to mobile phones .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Motorola</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Nestl</title>
  <description>
    Baby Milk Action , ha s called a boycott of Nestle for its irresponsible marketing of baby milk formula which infringes the International Code of Marketing of Breastmilk Substitutes. Nestl Purina is listed on the Uncaged website's petfood and animal testing page as a brand to boycott. View the Nestle Boycott profile page .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Nestl</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Nokia Siemens</title>
  <description>
    This company recently provided the Iranian regime with a &quot;monitoring center&quot; that enables security forces to tap cell phones, scramble text-messages, and interrupt calls. Nokia's new surveillance system has enhanced the regime's ability to crack down on dissent during recent protests. See the pledge page or facebook group for information. To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to mobile phones .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Nokia Siemens</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Procter and Gamble</title>
  <description>
    This company is on the list for its continued use of animal testing for cosmetics, household products and pet food. For more information see the Proctor and Gamble boycott profile page .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Procter and Gamble</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Rachel's Organic (owned by Dean Foods)</title>
  <description>
    
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Rachel's Organic (owned by Dean Foods)</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Royal Bank of Scotland</title>
  <description>
    RBS
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Royal Bank of Scotland</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott S hell</title>
  <description>
    MOSOP-UK and
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>S hell</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Starbucks</title>
  <description>
    Starbusks is under a boycott call from the Industrial Workers of the World and US Organic Consumer's Association over its treatment of Ethiopian coffee farmers.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Starbucks</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Superdrug</title>
  <description>
    Cheung Kong Holdings also have shares in oil giant Hutchinson Whampoa. Superdurg therefore also appear on the Tar Sands boycott list . For more information see the Boycott Superdrug campaign pages . To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's free Buyers' Guide to shampoo .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Superdrug</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Target</title>
  <description>
    US retailer Target has become the subject of a boycott by gay rights campaigners, Moveon.org , after it was revealed the company donated funds to a lobby group that supports Republican Senator Tom Emmer, a fervent supporter of anti-gay legislation. See the facebook page here
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Target</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Tarkett</title>
  <description>
    This company is on the list for refusing to provide evidence to prove the legal source of their merbau flooring. Without guarantees of the wood's origin, it's likely that merbau wood flooring could have come from Indonesia's last remaining rainforests. Contact Environmental Investigation Agency for more information.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Tarkett</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Tesco</title>
  <description>
    Tesco is under a boycott call from
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Tesco</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Three Mobile</title>
  <description>
    Three mobile is also on Ethical Consumers boycott list for its involvement in the Canadian oil sands . To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's Buyers' Guide to mobile phone networks.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Three Mobile</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Total</title>
  <description>
    Avaaz.org's are calling for a global boycott of Total and all its subsidiaries over its involvement with Burma. To see how they rate and for alternatives see Ethical Consumer's Buyers' Guide to petrol and diesel.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Total</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Unilever</title>
  <description>
    The Naturewatch Compassionate Shopping Guide 12th Edition 2010 listed Unilever as a company that was not endorsed by Naturewatch. It did not endorse Unilever as the company was unable to demonstrate a fixed cut off date for its animal testing policy. For more information see the Unilever boycott profile page .
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Unilever</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott W al-mart / Asda</title>
  <description>
    The Organic Consumers Association (OCA) are calling a boycott against Wal-Mart was found. The OCA called on people to boycott Wal-Mart and support commerce that was organic, local, fair trade and fair made Find out more on the ASDA / Wal Mart boycott profile page
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>W al-mart / Asda</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
 <evidence>
  <title>Boycott Welsh Dairy Products</title>
  <description>
    Viva! are calling for people to boycott Welsh dairy products. This is in response to the Welsh Assembly s decision to press ahead with a five year cull of badgers in parts of Wales in an effort to curtail the spread of bovine TB. Badgers will be trapped, caged and then shot, despite contradictory evidence on the effectiveness of such action. For more information visit www.viva.org.uk/campaigns/badgers/boycott.htm We report on all the progressive boycotts which have a registered headquarters. Inclusion in the list does not constitute an endorsement.
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>
      <name>Other</name>
      <rating>NULL</rating>
    </category>
  </categories>
  <source>
    Ethical Consumer
  </source>
  <link>
    http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/Boycotts/currentboycottslist.aspx
  </link>
  <companies>
    <company>Welsh Dairy Products</company>
  </companies>
 </evidence>
</evidences>
