<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society is a national voluntary health agency dedicated to curing leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin's disease and myeloma, and to improving the quality of life of patients and their families.   The Society was established in 1949 as The de Villiers Foundation. In 2000, the Society changed its name from The Leukemia Society of America to The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society to emphasize its commitment to fighting all blood cancers. 


Today, the Society supports the following major programs: research, patient services, public and professional education, advocacy and community services. With headquarters in White Plains, NY, the Society has chapter offices across the United States and is a single corporation doing business under New York State not-for-profit corporate laws. 

Nearly 1 million volunteers from all walks of life give generously of their time and talents to implement the Society's programs. They provide professional guidance and help raise vitally-needed funds. The Society's activities are directed and supervised by its national and chapter boards of trustees. 

&lt;b&gt;Note: For online fundraising benefitting the Society's major campaigns (Team In Training, Light The Night Walk, The Leukemia Cup Regatta, Man &amp; Woman of the Year, School &amp; Youth Programs), please contact your local Society Chapter so that your fundraising is properly credited and recognized, as funds raised through this site will not be directly allocated towards your efforts.  If you have any questions, please contact (800) 955-4572 or &lt;a href="http://www.leukemia-lymphoma.org//all_page.adp?item_id=353528"&gt;complete our Contact us form&lt;a/&gt;. 
 

1. Ensuring patients access to high quality healthcare

2. Creating a positive climate for research into leukemia, lymphoma and myeloma</description>
  <mission>Cure leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin's disease and myeloma, and improve the quality of life of patients and their families.</mission>
  <name>The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/37</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">317879</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">70493.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/K8/kK/Va/YT/Bt/bc/Js/gHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
