<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>New York&#8217;s Rockefeller Drug Laws, which require extremely harsh prison terms for the possession or sale of relatively small amounts of drugs, are the basis for the drug war in the U.S. Most of the people incarcerated under this war are convicted of low-level, nonviolent offenses, and many of them have no prior criminal records. Today over 14,000 people are locked-up for drug offenses in NY State prisons, comprising nearly 38% of the prison population. Nationally, nearly 500,000 people are locked up in prisons and jails for drug offenses. This costs taxpayer billions of dollars.

The Rockefeller Drug Laws and the drug war use mandatory minimum sentencing laws, which strip judges of their discretion. Harsh mandatory minimum sentences are based solely on the quantity of a drug involved in the offense, regardless of the individual&#8217;s background, character, role or the circumstances of the offense. Because of this, judges can&#8217;t utilize more effective, cheaper programs as alternatives to incarceration. And prosecutors are given unparalleled power to determine a defendant&#8217;s fate. This distorts and often undermines due process in our criminal justice system. Most states, and the federal government, continue to use mandatory minimum sentencing schemes for low-level drug offenses.

The Rockefeller Drug Laws are some of the harshest drug sentencing schemes in the nation. These laws are destroying communities, separating families, and failing to stop drug use and abuse in our neighborhoods. 

1. Both the draconian Rockefeller Drug Laws and the drug war are ineffective, wasteful, racist and unjust

2. Studies have found treatment to be 15 times more effective than incarceration at reducing drug addiction and related crime

3. We need real reform of these laws NOW!</description>
  <mission>End the draconian mandatory minimum drug sentencing laws in New York State</mission>
  <name>Real Rockefeller Reform Now!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/56</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">22</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0VMfDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
