<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Since 2000, more than 3,000 women and girls have been brutally murdered in Guatemala.  


Although the number of murders is alarming, the killing of women is not simply a question of statistics.  A key characteristic is the brutality with which the majority of murders are committed.  Many of the 
victims are raped and tortured first and their mutilated bodies are left in public places for members of their community to find.  The majority of the victims are young, poor women under the age of 40.  Several are students, housewives, factory workers, domestic employees, while others are professionals.  


The Guatemalan government&#8217;s inaction in the face of these brutal murders suggests a public policy of tolerance for gender-based violence.  Progress in the investigations have been fraught with numerous shortcomings, including the lack of technical capacity to preserve crime scenes, interrogate witnesses, and collect evidence, as well as a lack of political will to resolve the murders.  Less than 10% of these femicide cases have been investigated, while only 20 have resulted in prosecution.  


Through GHRC&#8217;s &#8220;For Women&#8217;s Right to Live Campaign&#8221;, we are educating concerned activists throughout the world about the daily violence against women in Guatemala, and thus providing them with appropriate avenues to pressure the Guatemalan government to do more in the face of these tragic and senseless murders.  We are striving to build a supportive community for our terrorized and silenced Guatemalan sisters and foster solidarity with Guatemalan women&#8217;s rights organizations to embolden their efforts.  

1. End violence against women and girls in Guatemala immediately

2. Urge Guatemalan government to do more for women

3. Mobilize international, grassroots pressure to end violence in Guatemala</description>
  <mission>Educate the international community about increasing violence against women in Guatemala and provide activists the avenues to pressure the Guatemalan government to bring the perpetrators to justice.</mission>
  <name>End Violence Against Women in Guatemala</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/70</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12937</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">732.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qNXfXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
