<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Kids go online to research and complete school assignments and to learn about topics that interest them. They also go online to chat with friends, play games, download music, keep a journal or web blog, create websites, shop, and more. It may seem like kids are pretty savvy web users, and many parents think that their children are better computer users than they are. But that doesn&#8217;t mean that kids understand the dangers they could encounter on the Internet or how to avoid them.

Even as kids grow savvier in their use of the Internet, it can still be a dangerous place. The good news is that most dangers can be avoided if children and their parents learn about smart Internet use.   To learn more about how to keep yourself or your children safe please visit http://www.ncpc.org/parents/Internet_Safety.php.

Usually bullying happens when adults aren&#8217;t around, like in between classes, at lunch or recess, and after school. Still, bullying rarely takes place without an audience - kids are around to see bullying 85 percent of the time. 

But even though they see it, kids usually don&#8217;t try to stop bullying. That doesn&#8217;t mean kids don&#8217;t want to help - two out of three kids want to help when they see bullying &#8211; but it means that they don&#8217;t know how.



1. &#8226;	To educate children and parents on the danger of cyber predators

2. &#8226;	To provide tips and tools to youth to help keep themselves safe online 

3. &#8226;	To provide tips and tools to parents to help keep their children safe online</description>
  <mission>To educate the public on cyber predators and give them tips on how to protect themselves or their children while online</mission>
  <name>Delete Cyber Predators</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/123</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">680</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Xa0/tR7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
