<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Young people say that bullying is one of the biggest problems they face. In fact, 52 percent of students report seeing bullying at least once a week. This negatively affects the victims and the bullies as well as the kids who witness bullying and the school environment as a whole.

The National Crime Prevention Council currently has two campaigns to help children and parents stop the bullying.     

Some parents don&#8217;t think bullying is a big deal. They think it&#8217;s a rite of passage to adulthood, that it&#8217;s just kids being kids. But for kids, bullying is one of the biggest problems they face. In fact, every day 160,000 kids miss school because they&#8217;re scared of bullying. 

 A lot of the time kids don&#8217;t tell their parents that they&#8217;re being bullied. They may be embarrassed, or they may think that telling will make the bullying worse. To help their children, parents may need to do some detective work to spot the clues that bullying is happening.  Parents can help by taking bullying seriously, talking to their children about it, and learning how to help children stop the bullying.

Kids can find more ways to step in to stop bullying on McGruff.org. They can also order a free set of collectible McGruff trading cards to be delivered to their house.


1. To educate youth and parents on the facts and dangers of bullying

2. To give youth tips and tools to prevent bullying

3. To give parents tips and tools to recognize bullying and ways to handle it</description>
  <mission>To educate parents and youth on the bullying issue and provide tips and tools for dealing with and preventing bullying</mission>
  <name>Bullying Prevention</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/124</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3151</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ALN/G2TS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
