<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The GOD'S CHILD Project, a non-profit organization, stresses health, education, and human rights. It has been serving the poor since 1991, founded by Patrick Atkinson, a Bismarck, North Dakota native.

Serving in Guatemala, El Salvador,  Malawi, and India, The GOD'S CHILD Project is currently one of Central America's fastest growing child-care programs.  Each of these children is truly from among the poorest of the poor. 

Something's Working Here.

The children have finished the school year and, as in past years, 40% of our boys and girls are honor students at their schools. These children now walk taller, cleaner, and are more helpful to others than they would have ever been before. They're not perfect and never will be, but step by step, they're getting closer to breaking their own bitter chains of poverty. 

If you can, please help us with your generous gift. Something's working here, and for the children's sake, we need to keep it going. 

Please send your contribution now to:

The GOD'S CHILD Project
721 Memorial Highway
PO Box 1573
Bismarck, ND 58504 Phone: 701-255-7956
Director@Godschild.org
www.GodsChild.org

***Also, visit The GOD'S CHILD Project group and watch a video about the Project at http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRjel7yWVAY

1. WE, The GOD'S CHILD Community, are benefactors, friends, volunteers, and children joined together to assist God's poorest children in their educationa

2. WE, The Adults, accept our youth as gifts from God given to be our teachers, students, and children. We believe in the need to stand by their side unt

3. WE, The Children, are the pride and reason why The GOD'S CHILD Project exists. We have the responsibility to behave honorably and to respect legitimat</description>
  <mission>Break the Bitter Chains of Poverty through Education and Formation.</mission>
  <name>The GOD'S CHILD Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/172</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">951</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">351.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vI/5a/uL/PQ/Yt/th/Q0/fRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
