<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Alzheimer's Research Foundation, Fisher Center is working towards preventing Alzheimer's, delaying or reversing its progression, and improving the quality of life of patients and their families.  With your support, their research can continue and we can move closer to better Alzheimer's treatments.  Alzheimer's is currently incurable and the treatments available are not able to stop the disease, only delay it, and not all patients are even significantly helped by these treatments.

Visit the Fisher Center Foundation here:
http://www.alzinfo.org/


***Just for clarification***
I've been receiving some messages asking about donations (where they go, how to know if this is legit, etc.)  When you click on the donation link, I encourage you to read the fine print on the donation website.  I have nothing to do with the money--I just set up this profile and chose the Fisher Center as the designated charity.  All donations go through the codetry website that made this Facebook application and are sent to the designated charity.  I am also not affiliated with the Fisher Center in any way.  I do Alzheimer's research at an unrelated laboratory in Rochester, NY and know first-hand that funding is tight, so that is what inspired me to set up this profile and choose a Foundation related to Alzheimer's research.  Thank you everyone for your continuing support!


***Please do not spam the discussion board with links to unrelated causes and groups!  Anything directly related to Alzheimer's is fine.  Thank you!***

1. There are more than 5 million Americans currently living with Alzheimer's Disease.

2. A cure for Alzheimer's has not been discovered yet.

3. Government funding for Alzheimer's research is not sufficient.</description>
  <mission>Raise money to fight Alzheimer's Disease.</mission>
  <name>Support Alzheimer's Research</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/177</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">413046</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">30942.63</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/J4/BF/7Z/Lo/xn/d5/zx/vTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
