<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Afghanistan Relief Organization helps those who are most vulnerable in time of war---the innocent, women, children, the elderly and disabled. We are dedicated to helping the Afghan people by directly delivering the supplies they need to survive and create a better life, the educational resources they need to build a future, and a message of hope.

====== DID YOU KNOW THAT... ========

+  1 US dollar = 50 Afghanis?
+ Afghanistan is third poorest nation in the world?
+ That the current life expectancy at birth is 47 years?
+ 69% of children are suffering from severe malnutrition and are underweight?
+ The literacy rate for females is a mere 13%
+ Because immunization coverage is still very low, preventable diseases kill thousands of children annually. Malaria (which afflicts approximately 2 million people per year), measles, and respiratory infections are the leading causes of childhood death.
+ Two million children of primary school age do not attend classes. 
+ Landmines and unexploded ordnance pose a serious risk to children&#8217;s safety.
+ Afghanistan has faced a serious drought affecting 2.5 million people, 50 percent of them children.
+ The lack of water and food will exacerbate the outbreak of disease and malnutrition among children.
+ Infant, under-five, and maternal mortality rates in Afghanistan are among the world&#8217;s highest. 
+ 25% of children die before reaching their fifth birthday. 50 women die each day from pregnancy-related complications. More than half of all children are stunted. 

&lt;b&gt;
All of these may just seem like statistics to you. These are much more than that, they are real people, real women and children suffering and dieing each day. 

A few dollars may not seem like much to us or really affect us... but those few dollars... even the spare change in your pockets... can help make a difference in childrens lives. The difference between life and death.

Please, help and give Hope&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;i&gt;Special Thanks to: Salomon Jaan

1. Dedication to helping the Afghan people, by bringing them the supplies they need to survive and create a better life, the educational assistance they need to rebuild their future, and an outstretched hand to let them know they are not alone.

2. Help those who are most vulnerable in times of war&#8212;the innocent: women, children, the elderly, and the disabled.

3. We must all join hands in the human alliance that will create a better world.</description>
  <mission>Provide basic relief supplies, medical/hygiene supplies, and school supplies.</mission>
  <name>Afghanistan Relief Organization</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/200</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1478</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">906.45</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Xtu/ssSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
