<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We work to reduce suffering and to create meaningful social change for animals by advocating for public policies to protect animals, investigating cruelty and working to enforce existing laws, educating the public about the issues, and conducting hands-on programs, such as assisting animals when disasters strike. 

https://gateway.hsus.org/hsusdev/ --&gt; for dog lovers who want to contribute!

just so everyone knows-- your money is going directly to the charity!

what does 501(c)(3) mean?

501(c)(3) &#8212; Various charitable, non-profit, religious, and educational organizations (wikipedia.com)

please read!! -&gt; "One of the best donations you can give the humane society is your time. I volunteered at my shelter for years, and I helped rehabilitate and adopt hundreds of animals. It wasn't always easy or pleasant, but it was SO rewarding, and fun too! I don't have a lot of money to donate, and like a lot of people I'm hesitant to donate money to causes because it's not always clear HOW MUCH money is going directly to the cause, but I suggest volunteering, and also donating blankets and toys to a local shelter. It's an easy way to help without necessarily asking for money. There are so many animals (not just dogs and cats) in rows upon rows of cages, just waiting to be loved. Not all can or will be saved, but I know that by volunteering I was able to offer them some comfort while they were there at the shelter." 

Thanks so much for all of you who are donating and supporting the cause!


1. Against animal fighting and other forms of animal cruelty.

2. Against factory farming.

3. Against the fur trade.

4. Against inhumane sport hunting practices.</description>
  <mission>help stop the suffering of animals</mission>
  <name>Contribute To The Humane Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/202</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">394660</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">56274.15</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/XP2/BbjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
