<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Stem cells have the remarkable potential to develop into many different cell types in the body. Serving as a sort of repair system for the body, they can theoretically divide without limit to replenish other cells as long as the person or animal is still alive. When a stem cell divides, each new cell has the potential to either remain a stem cell or become another type of cell with a more specialized function, such as a muscle cell, a red blood cell, or a brain cell.

Medical researchers believe that stem cell therapy has the potential to radically change the treatment of human disease. A number of adult stem cell therapies already exist, particularly bone marrow transplants that are used to treat leukemia.[] In the future, medical researchers anticipate being able to use technologies derived from stem cell research to treat a wider variety of diseases including cancer, parkinson's disease, spinal cord injuries, and muscle damage, amongst a number of other impairments and conditions.

Wanna get involved?
http://www.stemcellfunding.org/

http://dels.nas.edu/bls/stemcells/booklet.shtml

- go to your congressmen/senator's website and write them a letter about the importance of stem cell research


1. Stem Cell research can lead to a cure for Parkinsons, Diabetes, ALS, Alzheimer's, MS, and a host of other genetic diseases as well as certain cancers.

2. currently the United States is lagging behind other countries in research, and so it is up to private organizations and other countries.</description>
  <mission>advocate for government funding for stem cell Research, support private organizations that do stem cell research</mission>
  <name> Support Stem Cell Research</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/212</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">49868</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">4028.24</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hQY/wsNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
