<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Doctors Without Borders/M&#233;decins sans Fronti&#232;res (MSF) is a private international association. The association is made up mainly of doctors and health sector workers and is also open to all other professions which might help in achieving its aims. All of its members agree to honor the following principles: 

M&#233;decins Sans Fronti&#232;res provides assistance to populations in distress, to victims of natural or man-made disasters and to victims of armed conflict. They do so irrespective of race, religion, creed or political convictions. 

M&#233;decins Sans Fronti&#232;res observes neutrality and impartiality in the name of universal medical ethics and the right to humanitarian assistance and claims full and unhindered freedom in the exercise of its functions. 

Members undertake to respect their professional code of ethics and to maintain complete independence from all political, economic, or religious powers.

In emergencies and their aftermath, MSF provides essential health care, rehabilitates and runs hospitals and clinics, performs surgery, battles epidemics, carries out vaccination campaigns, operates feeding centers for malnourished children, and offers mental health care. When needed, MSF also constructs wells and dispenses clean drinking water, and provides shelter materials like blankets and plastic sheeting.

Through longer-term programs, MSF treats patients with infectious diseases such as tuberculosis, sleeping sickness, and HIV/AIDS, and provides medical and psychological care to marginalized groups such as street children.

[...] MSF is often one of the first humanitarian organizations to arrive at the scene of an emergency. Its large-scale logistical capacity ensures that MSF emergency teams hit the ground with the specialized medical kits and equipment they need to start saving lives immediately."

1. Deliver impartial emergency aid to people affected by armed conflict, epidemics, natural or man-made disasters, or exclusion from health care in 70+ countries</description>
  <mission>To provide impartial humanitarian action, independent from all political, economic and religious powers</mission>
  <name>Doctors Without Borders/M&#233;decins Sans Fronti&#232;res</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/234</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">194764</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">189800.39</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4V/Za/f5/r8/Go/w6/1iQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
