<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Mass murder in America -- whether it's Columbine High School or Virginia Tech -- can never and should never be regarded as "normal" or something that we simply have to live with. Those terrible events make national headlines, but everyday gun violence claims 32 lives a day in America.

The Brady Campaign to Prevent Gun Violence supports practical gun control policies to keep guns out of the wrong hands and prevent tragic gun crimes and accidents, without advocating any blanket prohibition on firearm ownership. Violence and evil will always exist, true, but if we concede that criminals will be criminals and there's nothing we can do, then why bother to have any laws at all?

It is truly a national shame that in 2006 a quarter of gun victims were under 23 years old and there were more children under age 5 killed by guns than police officers in the line of duty.

Guns are not toys, and gun ownership is a public-safety and civil responsibility for those who choose to own any. Stats show that a gun in the home is more likely to be used for an unintentional shooting, suicide attempt or assault/homicide than to injure or kill in self-defense, and a gun in the home makes it six times more likely an abused woman will be killed compared to other abused women. Only 2 percent of U.S. gun deaths are justifiable homicide by private individuals. In 2006, a gun-violence victim in America was nearly three times more likely to be killed because of an argument than robbery, burglary or rape combined.

(Any posts with profanity or ad hominem attacks will be deleted and the poster banned)</description>
  <mission>We are devoted to creating an America free from gun violence, where all Americans are safe at home, at school, at work, and in our communities. </mission>
  <name>Brady Center to Prevent Gun Violence</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/254</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1077</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">259.38</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hQ/KU/3F/ne/vJ/nN/HG/l0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
