<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Civic Enterprise Network is dedicated to community awareness, civic engagement and service to our community.  Members shall be exposed to opportunities that our organization feels will help them be not only better leaders in their workplace, families, organizations, communities, and cultural environments, but also more well-rounded individuals capable of ethical decisions, and understanding the importance of civic engagement and the value of service and responsibility.   
  
C.E.N. utilizes different programs its membership has created, each with a specific vision and means to assist the Civic Enterprise Network in promoting ethics in our world through civic and community engagement.


Our vision
Believing in a more unified and engaged society; we proclaim the importance of an involved, ethical, and dedicated individual in order to serve the greater good.  
To this end, the Civic Enterprise Network works with individuals, organizations, and communities to help educate, unite, and network in order to build a stronger community, and a more ethical, socially involved, as well as service oriented society.  


Our Creed
Civic Enterprise Network by bestowing upon me the honor of membership has invested the most noble of privileges of which I am humbly grateful.  I believe in service to my community as well as dedication to my nation, state, and organization.  I shall make duty, philanthropy and responsibility the pillars of my life, and shall conduct my affairs with integrity, ethics, and respect for all peoples.  
I shall give back to my community and to the Civic Enterprise Network, for to do so brings about positive results in my surroundings.  By keeping strong ties with the Civic Enterprise Network I build strong the bonds of comradery that act as a mentorship for all future and current leaders in all aspects of life and pledge my support for civic engagement and noble, ethical leadership.   


1. Civic engagement and responsibility should increase to better our nation! 

2. Increase voter registration and voter turnout!

3. Increase understading as to the importance of community service, community understanding, and Robert's Rules of Parliamentary Procedure, </description>
  <mission>Nonpartisan, nonprofit community building organization created to increase civic responsibility, education and ethical leadership through community service, charity, and philanthropy.  </mission>
  <name>Civic Enterprise Network</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/261</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/IVS/yhWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
