<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>World Vision International is a Christian Relief, Development and Advocacy organisation dedicated to working with children, families and communities to overcome poverty and justice.

Development - World Vision believes that the best way to improve children's lives is through child-focused transformational development. we work with families, communities, and children all over the world through a range of programmes that foster change and improve their well-being.

Relief - World Vision strives to reduce the impact of emergencies on people's lives, addressing humanitarian needs and the underlying vulnerabilities so that transformational development is possible. World Vision is responding to an increase in disasters by helping communities survive, recover and prevent future catastrophes.

Advocacy - World Vision works to empower communities to know and to speak up for their rights at local, national and international levels. through our advocacy work, we enable the voices of the poor and oppressed to reach decision-makers who have the power to change unjust policies and practices.

For more information, visit www.wvi.org 

Contribute if you're able, but even if you can't right now still join up and invite others - the more people who join the more the cause will get noticed!


1. Transformational development that is sustainable and community-based, focused especially on the needs of children.

2. Emergency Relief that assists people afflicted by conflict or disaster.

3. Promotion of Justice that seeks to change unjust structures affecting the poor among whom World Vision works. 

4. Public Awareness that leads to informed understanding, giving, involvement and prayer.

5. Through all of this to be authentically following Jesus in action as well as word.</description>
  <mission>World Vision is a Christian humanitarian organization dedicated to working with children, families, and their communities worldwide to reach their full potential by tackling the ca</mission>
  <name>WORLD VISION</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/280</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">49890</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">55911.66</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dW/LP/8Y/CZ/w8/XS/qr/hHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
