<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The National Home is a multi-faceted facility created to care for the developmental, social and spiritual needs of the children and families of the Veterans of Foreign Wars. Services are also available for children of active duty military personnel. Our facility is not an orphanage, but a neighborhood of custom homes, service buildings and recreational land administered by a highly devoted staff and fully integrated into its surrounding community.

The Veterans of Foreign Wars established the National Home in 1925 to care for the children and families of our nation&#8217;s veterans. Located on 629 acres in Eaton Rapids, Michigan, the National Home stands today as a tribute to the VFW and Ladies Auxiliary members who help support the facility and the families who call the National Home their home.

Children at the National Home come to us from all over the United States. Recently, we have housed children and families from Virginia, New York, California, Missouri, Illinois, Ohio, Florida, Maryland, Wisconsin, Michigan and many other states. We rely on our supporters from across the nation to refer children and families to the National Home. Without them to spread the message, so many children could not be served by the Home.

The goal of the National Home is to give children what they need most - a childhood. Therefore, life at the National Home is designed to mirror society, with individual family homes, community recreation opportunities, local public school attendance and community involvement. The National Home is set up like a typical American neighborhood with the added benefit of support services such as counseling, education, recreation and any other needed assistance.

The VFW National Home is truly a national gem. Let us thank our country's heroes by helping their family at the National Home.

1. Every child deserves to be able to have a childhood.

2. Our country's heroes should not have to worry about the safety and care of their family while they are away.

3. In supporting the VFW National Home, we are thanking our veterans and current soldiers for protecting us.</description>
  <mission>serve as a living memorial to all veterans by providing children and families of members of the VFW and Ladies Auxiliary opportunities for growth and development in a nurturing community.</mission>
  <name>VFW National Home for Children</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/282</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">13</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zVe/JKJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
