<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Named in honor of the late Dr. Earl S. Cummings, Jr.(Associate Professor of Secondary Education and Foundations, Eastern Illinois University), a Gentleman who kept grading papers of his college students until the very end, The Professor Earl S. Cummings, Jr. Pulmonary Fibrosis Federation is a Facebook-based service aimed at educating people about the interstitial lung diseases, specifically, idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF).

"Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a debilitating disease marked by progressive scarring of the lungs that gradually interferes with a person's ability to breathe and thus obtain enough oxygen for vital organs to function normally. IPF is one of approximately 200 diseases&#8212;collectively called interstitial lung diseases (ILDs)&#8212;in which lung scarring is found. The lung scarring that occurs in ILDs is referred to as pulmonary fibrosis. 

IPF hinders a person's ability to absorb oxygen. This makes them feel short of breath. The injury to the lungs may also cause a dry cough. As the scarring gets worse, patients become out of breath with lower levels of effort (e.g., while dressing and undressing)." (Source: Coalition for Pulmonary Fibrosis - www.coalitionforpf.org)

IPF in itself, frankly; carries a total death rate.  While people carry on a descent quality of life, especially if caught early, it is sadly, eventually, disabling and fatal.

WALL OF APPRECIATION
They gave thier lives... fighting to the end.

- PROFESSOR EARL S. CUMMINGS, JR., PH.D.
 (11/24/33 - 05/21/02)

- LYNN GILMORE
 (02/08/1953 - 06/25/05)

- ERLINDA ESTANISLAO
 (12/03/1953 - 10/04/07)

1. Promote and disseminate information on IPF and other ILDs

2. Educate those unaware of the ILDs and work with doctors and specialists to find cures

3. Spread awareness and provide fellowship for those who have lost or currently have loved ones battling IPF.</description>
  <mission>To educate, inform, debate, and disseminate information about the interstitial lung diseases, specifically IPF.</mission>
  <name>ESC Pulmonary Fibrosis Federation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/292</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1467</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">191.25</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jYs/A4VS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
