<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Bureaucrash is dedicated to fighting the increase of government control over our lives. Our international network of pro-freedom activists works to change the political ideology of our generation through creative activism. While most youth politics supports the growth of the already bloated government bureaucracy, we fight for freedom.

Our activists are of all political persuasions united by the belief that sprawling governments and the bureaucrats and politicians who control them ought to be mocked. Mercilessly.

Why? Because when governments grow, our freedom to live our lives as we see fit shrinks. Every time a new law is passed, some bureaucrat squirreled away in a cubicle somewhere gets more power to make decisions over us. And because the vast majority of people have no idea of the lives and freedoms crushed every time the government&#8217;s power grows.

We believe that, only by spreading information about this absurd arrangement can we leash the bureaucracy and restore our fundamental freedoms.

1. Individuals are sovereign and own their own bodies.

2. Every person has a right to make decisions about his or her own life, as long as those decisions do not directly harm other people.

3. No person has a right to use force against another person &#8211; to steal what they have earned or threaten their body or property.

4. When a government makes a new rule, it threatens to use force against someone (or everyone).

5. When bureaucrats and politicians have the power to make arbitrary rules, they steal our choices.

6. If governments are to exist they should be small and just have the power to protect us from force and fraud.

7. Any other arrangement breeds corruption and gives other people (bureaucrats) power over us. Any other arrangement makes us all slaves to the bureaucrats.</description>
  <mission>We fight the increase of government control over our lives.</mission>
  <name>Bureaucrash</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/302</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1388</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">349.03</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/e6T/mxaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
