<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>More than one billion people lack access to a safe water supply, and that number is growing. In times of need Oxfam helps provide those in need with that which is most necessary and vital to life: clean water.

Oxfam helps From flooding in Haiti to drought in Ethiopia, water has long been central to Oxfam's work. But in recent decades, some extraordinary pressures have emerged from dams and mining.

Oxfam helps communities affected to:

    * Understand the causes of the water problems they are facing and protect themselves from dangers.
    * Network with other affected people so they can share coping strategies, join forces, and strengthen their abilities to bring about change.
    * Voice their concerns to governments, corporations, and individuals responsible for the development projects and more.

All donations from this will go to Oxfam, who's internationally-acclaimed water and sanitation system helps prevent the spread of communicable diseases&#8212;the greatest killer in the first weeks after a disaster. Once the immediate danger has passed, Oxfam seeks to address the root causes of disaster so that many future crises, such as drought in Ethiopia or flooding in El Salvador, can be anticipated and mitigated.

Oxfam was there for relief after the Tsunami hit, and even for fellow Americans after Hurricane Katrina. 
Please donate when you can.  This won't do any good if no money is raised to support Oxfam. 

Every year, 3.4 million people, mostly children, die from water-related diseases like diarrhea, malaria, and trachoma. ~ 80 percent of these diseases are caused by contaminated water.

In emergencies, people crowd together. injuries, malnourishment, and stress make them vulnerable to disease. The 1st thing they need is water but in unsanitary conditions water can become a source of infection.

Please do what you can. The children around the world who survive from that extra glass of clean water we foot the bill for will thank you. 

1. Everyone should be able to drink clean water

2. No one should go without water

3. Provide clean water to those effected by disasters</description>
  <mission>To provide those without water with clean sanitary water in times of need, by raising money to provide water and spreading the word to others to promote awareness of the problem.</mission>
  <name>Disaster Relief and Clean Water for All</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/310</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1265</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">455.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oq/KK/78/Gq/C7/Z1/qW/CaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
