<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Ovarian cancer is known as "The Silent Killer". The famous quote: "it whispers - so listen."

Ovarian cancer starts in a woman's ovaries. There are two ovaries, one on each side of the pelvis. The ovaries produce eggs and are the main source of the female hormones, estrogen and progesterone. 

A woman's menstrual cycle is usually about 28 days. Every month, at around the middle of the menstrual cycle, an egg is released from one ovary in a process called ovulation. The egg travels from the ovary through the fallopian tube to the uterus. 

A malignant (or cancerous) tumour that begins in the ovaries is called ovarian cancer

;; STATISTICS

Statistics from the National Ovarian Cancer Survey: Perspectives of Canadian Women and Health Care Professionals (1999) 

The average age when ovarian cancer is detected in women is 56.3 years. 

Less than 1 out of 10 of the woman surveyed had no symptoms prior to diagnosis. In other words, more than 9 out of 10 women who were surveyed, had one or more symptoms before the ovarian cancer was detected. 

More than 25% of the women sought help from a mental health professional. This may suggest that women's concerns were not being fully addressed and symptoms may have been mistakenly attributed to "stress" or "depression" 

;; GRADES

-&gt; Borderline - Grade 0 - grows and spreads slowly 
-&gt; Well differentiated - Grade 1 - grows and spreads a little more quickly 
-&gt; Moderately differentiated - Grade 2 - grows and spreads rapidly 
-&gt; Poorly or undifferentiated - Grade 3 - grows and spreads very rapidly 

;; WEBSITES:

http://www.ovariancancer.org/
http://www.cancer.gov/cancertopics/types/ovarian
http://www.medicinenet.com/ovarian_cancer/article.htm
http://www.ovariancanada.org

1. Spread Awareness of Ovarian Causes, Preventions &amp; Treatment

2. To find a cure for Ovarian Cancer</description>
  <mission>To spread awareness of Ovarian causes, preventions, treatments &amp; more importantly, find a cure for Ovarian Cancer.</mission>
  <name>Ovarian Cancer Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/317</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">604020</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45468.94</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8Yx/qYJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
