<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Helping to build the sustainability movement within the United States and beyond for more than a decade, the US Citizens Network for Sustainable Development links and engages concerned citizens and civil society organizations to better understand and promote ecological health, social and economic justice, and public participation.

Created in October 1990 to coordinate civil society participation in the 1992 UN Conference on Environment and Development (the "Earth Summit"), CitNet and its members have spent a decade connecting, educating, and acting to make real the Earth Summit's vision of a more sustainable and equitable world. 


CitNet:

- Connects people and projects to resources and information

- Works locally and globally to make sustainable development a reality

- Supports citizen participation in the development, monitoring and implementation of policy and program initiatives

- Connects individuals and organizations locally, regionally, nationally, and internationally to help build an ecologically sound and socially and economically just world.

- Provides a framework for citizens and organizations to work together, from the grassroots to the global levels, to help build an economically prosperous, ecologically sound and socially equitable world.

- Connects people and projects to resources and information.

- Works locally and globally to make sustainable development a reality.

- Supports citizen participation in the development, monitoring and implementation of policy and program initiatives.


(visit citnet.org for more information)

1. strengthen sustainability movements across the US, by providing a framework for information-sharing and collaboration across issue areas, sectors, and

2. connect the US sustainability movement to the global sustainability movement

3. promote broad-based, multi-stakeholder participation in decision making on sustainable development at the local, national, regional and global levels</description>
  <mission>The Citizens Network for Sustainable Development (CitNet) is an non-profit network bringing together organizations, communities, and individuals working on sustainability issues across the world.</mission>
  <name>Citizens Network for Sustainable Development</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/318</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">278</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3i/WG/GF/3f/4G/zO/ke/f7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
