<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Grassroots Alliance for Community Education is a 501(c)(3), non-profit entity (G.R.A.C.E. USA), with headquarters in the U.S.A., and an international non-governmental organization (G.R.A.C.E. Africa), registered in Kenya. G.R.A.C.E. works with communities in sub-Saharan Africa to mitigate the effects of HIV/AIDS.

Our intent has been to support community-initiated, community-based, community-led education and training programs that reflect the expressed needs of the local community. 
		
G.R.A.C.E. carries out its work by collaborating with community-based organizations (CBOs), local non-governmental organizations (NGOs), faith-based organizations (FBOs) or informal community groups who have approached and invited us to assist them in building capacity in their communities.

To build capacity in their communities, G.R.A.C.E. helps grassroots organizations in these key areas:

    * Conduct Integrated Training for Community-Based Health Care Workers
    * Provide Technical and Financial Assistance
    * Support Orphan Education
    * Expand Youth Education Network
    * Develop Information Networks
    * Operate a Twinning Program
    * Maintain a community resource and research center

http://www.graceusa.org

1. The most effective and powerful agents for rapid and positive social change in regions of limited resources are community-based workers and community-based leaders.

2. This is especially true in dealing with issues such as HIV/AIDS, where social behavior is closely related to health status. </description>
  <mission>To help grassroots community-based organizations implement locally determined and sustainable initiatives in response to the HIV/AIDS epidemic.</mission>
  <name>Grassroots Alliance for Community Education (G.R.A.C.E.)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/327</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">17</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/UUC/yOvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
