<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>True Strength for America&#8217;s Future.

Mitt Romney has a history of fixing things. He fixed the 2002 Winter Olympics. He is a 
successful entrepreneur that has helped fix and grow companies.  As governor of Massachusetts he turned a 3 billion dollar budget deficit to a 700 million surplus by the end of his term without raising taxes. He got rid of government waste in Massachusetts and streamlined the government, as well as enacted comprehensive economic reforms to stimulate economic growth in the state.
For More information on Mitt Romney&#8217;s Accomplishments go to
http://www.mittromney.com/Learn-About-Mitt/Mittxs_Biography

-Mitts Strategy for a Stronger America -

--Keep Americans Safe at Home and Abroad

Strengthen our military and transform our domestic civilian international efforts to meet a new generation of global challenges.
http://www.mittromney.com/Issues/keeping-americans-safe

--Confronting Radical Jihad--

The consequences of ignoring this threat &#8211; such as a radicalized Islamic actor possessing nuclear weapons &#8211; are simply unacceptable.
http://www.mittromney.com/Issues/confronting-radical-jihad

--Winning the Global Economic Competition--

We must improve America's global competitiveness and unleash the American economy through lower taxes and less government.
http://www.mittromney.com/Issues/global-economic-competition

--Curbing out of control federal spending--

Politicians from both parties in Washington, D.C. have spent too much money on too many programs for far too long.
http://www.mittromney.com/Issues/curbing-federal-spending

--Ending the Tide of Illegal Immigrants--

We must secure the border, implement an enforceable employer verification system, punish sanctuary cities and reject amnesty.
http://www.mittromney.com/Issues/immigration

--Confronting Threats to American Culture, 

Values, and Freedoms--
The American values that have been at the heart of our historic rise to world leadership are being challenged everyday.
http://www.mittromney.com/Issues/american-culture

--Ending our dependence on Foreign Oil--

As long as we import much of our oil from unstable regions and countries, our national security and economic prosperity are threatened.
http://www.mittromney.com/Issues/ending-energy-dependence

--More Issues--
http://www.mittromney.com/Issues/index

-What can you do to help Mitt?-

Invite- What a better way to grow the cause as well as awareness of mitts positions? Click on &#8220;Invite People to Join&#8221; and then select all of your friends!

Inform- Tell people about Mitt; why he really is true strength for America&#8217;s future.

Donate- I know some of you may be a poor college student, but if you can, donate to the campaign. Primary Season is here and any donation will help. https://www.mittromney.com/contribution/form

---Primary Season is Here---
Everybody is all hyped up about winning states, and so on, but Its really about delegates. The person to get at least 1191 delegates, wins the Nomination

Iowa &#8211; January 3, 2008
Huckabee- 17
Romney- 12
Thompson- 3
McCain- 3
Paul- 2

Wyoming &#8211; January 5, 2008
Romney- 8
Thompson- 3
Hunter- 1

New Hampshire &#8211; January 8, 2008
McCain- 7
Romney- 4
Huckabee- 1

Michigan - January 15, 2008
Romney- 12
McCain- 9

Nevada - January 19, 2008
Romney- 18
Paul- 4
McCain- 4
Thompson- 2
Huckabee- 2
Giuliani- 1

South Carolina
McCain- 19
Huckabee- 5

Florida - January 29, 2008
McCain- 57

Total &#8211; According to CNN Election Center as of January 20, 2008 http://www.cnn.com/ELECTION/2008/ 
McCain &#8211; 95
Romney &#8211; 67
Huckabee &#8211; 26
Paul &#8211; 6

1. Defeat the Jihadists!

2. Stop runaway spending in Washington!

3. Affirm America's Culture and Values</description>
  <mission>Elect Mitt Romney the 44th President of the United States!</mission>
  <name>Mitt Romney For President</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/331</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1744</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">60.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GSq/tshS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
