<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Microcredit is the process of extending small loans and other financial and business services such as savings to very poor people, so that they can start up or expand tiny businesses, thus allowing them to care for themselves and their families.
&lt;p&gt;
The loans, often averaging less than $150, allow people to start and expand tiny businesses without depending on money-lenders who demand exorbitant interest rates. Access to the tools and credit needed to succeed allows the poor to reap the benefits of their skills and hard work.
&lt;p&gt;
Microcredit gives borrowers the capacity to improve the quality of their lives and the futures of their children. Extra money earned is used to obtain better food, housing and education. As a result, the returns to the entire society are high.
&lt;p&gt;
In developing countries, the rate of repayment of well-established microcredit programs ranges from 95 to 99 percent. Repayment rates are high because, through a system of peer support and pressure used in many microcredit models, borrowers are responsible for each other&#8217;s success and ensure that every member of their group is able to pay back her loans.
&lt;p&gt;
Despite its success, tens of millions of very poor families who could use microcredit still do not have access to this route out of poverty.

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(Source: www.results.org)

1. Congress must ensure that USAID targets 50 percent of its microenterprise assistance for very poor clients

2. The World Bank should expand investment in microcredit</description>
  <mission>reduce the number of people living on less than US$1 a day worldwide by granting small loans to start a business</mission>
  <name>Microcredit and Microfinance: Economic Opportunity for All</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/333</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">938</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">334.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gef/XOsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
