<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We are tired of Islam being exploited and misinterpreted by radicals, Islamophobes, and so called &#8220;experts.&#8221; Too many times have we seen Islam being associated with violence, terrorism, and a way of life that is seen as barbaric, backwards, and at odds with modernity on the news and print media.

We decided to take matters into our own hands by developing our own billboard, magazine, TV, and radio AD campaigns to present Islam in its true light. Love, compassion, mercy, unity, modesty, truth  - these are just some of the ingredients that make our faith.

MeccaOne Radio &amp; TV
MeccaOne Radio has been broadcasting since May of 2002. We broadcast every Thursday between 5-6pm on 90.5FM KSJS, San Jose, CA and reach 22,000 weekly Muslim and non-Muslim listeners.

Abu Huraira Project
MeccaOne records &amp; archives the scholars and teachers who bring clarity to the sometimes difficult and controversial events taking place around the Islamic world and the West. We then make the time sensitive content available for free through articles, audio/video downloads through the internet and press releases. Past events include the Danish cartoon controversy and the recent Pope comments on Islam.

1. Islam is beautiful

2. Terror has no faith

3. Muslims have become, in the eyes of the media and political elite, a security threat and a convenient vehicle for exploitation and political opportunism.

4. Educational systems throughout the world need to be injected with greater efforts to  encourage critical thinking in children, commencing at an early age.  Building bridges between different communities of young people should be a priority.

5. A mainstream understanding of Islam, for the benefit of contemporary society, especially for young Muslims in the West, needs to be articulated. 

6. Islamophobia has to be de-constructed and recognized.  Suspicions and false feelings of superiority need to be eradicated. There is a perception within the West that Islam is something foreign and unwelcome despite the historical presence.

7. Muslims are some of the most huggable cuddly wuddlies on the planet</description>
  <mission>To present Islam in its true light through mass media.</mission>
  <name>Islam is beautiful, STOP MAKING IT UGLY!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/344</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">114884</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">779.48</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/JG/dA/iI/vf/oD/bP/ty/C1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
