<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In 2004-2005, there were an average annual 200,780 victims of rape, attempted rape or sexual assault in the U.S. alone (RAINN.org). Add this to the millions of men, women and children who experience sexual violence in other countries and you begin to get a picture of the terrible tragedy of this form of violence.   We need to work to lessen rape, sexual assault, domestic violence, and other forms of sexual violence both domestically and internationally. 

What can YOU do?

- Talk about it! The more the word gets out that this DOES happen to innocent people, the less society can ignore its impact. Not to mention how inspiring sharing your support can be for survivors (see our wall!)

- Give support, financially or in the form of your time, to organizations that are already doing the hard work to end sexual violence. See our Resources list for more great places to donate. 

- Always ASK before engaging in sexual activity with someone! You can prevent sexual violence by making sure your partner is comfortable with what is going on. Consent is sexy!

- Stand up for this cause. When you see someone behaving in a way that is not OK, you have the right to say something. Of course, use your own best judgment, but don't hesitate to make your thoughts known.

           --------- RESOURCES---------
 National Sexual Assault Hotline
            1-800-656-HOPE

National Domestic Violence Hotline
            1-800-799-SAFE

National Alliance to End Sexual Violence
           http://www.naesv.org/

National Sexual Violence Resource Center
          http://www.nsvrc.org/

Men Can Stop Rape
          http://www.mencanstoprape.org/

Speaking Out About Rape (SOAR)
         http://www.soar99.org/

Faces of Survivors
        http://www.facesofsurvivors.com/

The Date Safe Project
        http://www.thedatesafeproject.org/

Please Note: image courtesy of Take Back the Night (www.tbtnnw.org)


1. There is an 'epidemic' of sexual violence in our world.

2. We serve as an open forum for victims, survivors, and their loved ones.

3. Sexual violence can and will be prevented.</description>
  <mission>Bring an end to all forms of sexual violence that still plague our world.</mission>
  <name>End Sexual Violence</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/346</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">31734</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3428.91</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0ve/1BNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
