<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For too long, the United States federal budget has been allocated in ways that are irresponsible, inappropriate and unsustainable. As of May 28th, the United States national debt exceeded 8.8 trillion dollars, and in FY 2006, interest payments on the debt exceeded 400 billion - the third largest federal expenditure by category.

Instead of addressing this impending fiscal crisis, members of Congress continue to spend money in wasteful and ineffective ways. One of the most irresponsible practices in government is pork barrel spending. In 1991, Citizens Against Government Waste (CAGW) and the Congressional Porkbusters Coalition developed seven criteria for a project to qualify as pork:

-Requested by only one chamber of Congress;
-Not specifically authorized;
-Not competitively awarded;
-Not requested by the President;
-Greatly exceeds the President&#8217;s budget request or the previous year&#8217;s funding;
-Not the subject of congressional hearings; or
-Serves only a local or special interest.

We support responsible spending in government, we stand against pork barrel spending and government waste, and we insist that members of congress take action to reign in the irresponsible spending that is ballooning federal deficits and enlarging the national debt.

1. The federal government should not run continued budget deficits.

2. Bills allocating discretional federal funds should not be omnibus in nature.

3. All government contracts should be competitively awarded.

4. Members of Congreess should not take taxpayer funded 'factfinding' junkets.</description>
  <mission>Promote responsible fiscal practices in the federal budget process</mission>
  <name>Fiscal Responsibility in Government</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/395</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">166</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tgX/KVKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
