<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The UN Millennium Development Goals (MDGs) are eight goals to be achieved by 2015 that respond to the world's main development challenges. The MDGs are drawn from the actions and targets contained in the Millennium Declaration that was adopted by 189 nations-and signed by 147 heads of state and governments during the UN Millennium Summit in September 2000. 

The 8 MDGs break down into 18 quantifiable targets that are measured by 48 indicators:

Goal 1: Eradicate extreme poverty and hunger 
Goal 2: Achieve universal primary education 
Goal 3: Promote gender equality and empower women 
Goal 4: Reduce child mortality 
Goal 5: Improve maternal health 
Goal 6: Combat HIV/AIDS, malaria and other diseases 
Goal 7: Ensure environmental sustainability 
Goal 8: Develop a Global Partnership for Development 

The MDGs:

-Recognize explicitly the interdependence between growth, poverty reduction and sustainable development; 

-Acknowledge that development rests on the foundations of democratic governance, the rule of law, respect for human rights and peace and security; 

-Are based on time-bound and measurable targets accompanied by indicators for monitoring progress; 

-Bring together, in the eighth Goal, the responsibilities of developing countries with those of developed countries, founded on a global partnership endorsed at the International Conference on Financing for Development in Monterrey, Mexico in March 2002, and again at the Johannesburg World Summit on Sustainable Development in August 2002. 

DONATIONS -- 

-Millennium Promise (www.millenniumpromise.org) is funding small-scale anti-poverty interventions such as anti-malaria insecticide-treated bed nets that cost $10 each and protect two children for five years, school lunch programs which decrease child malnutrition and increase school enrollment rates, and treatment for parasitic infections. PLEASE DONATE TODAY! A small donation can go a long way in saving lives. 

1. We must halve extreme poverty by 2015, and fully eradicate extreme poverty by 2025

2. We must practice an integrated approach to rural development

3. We must create a global partnership for development</description>
  <mission>Eradicate Extreme Poverty by 2015</mission>
  <name>UN Millennium Development Goals (MDGs)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/407</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">39069</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2306.64</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Sw/78/4p/t6/A5/Hi/ci/WuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
