<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Millennium Villages are based on a single powerful idea: impoverished villages can transform themselves and meet the Millennium Development Goals by 2015 if they are empowered with proven, powerful, practical technologies. It is simply a "bottom up" approach to lifting villages in developing countries out of the poverty trap that confines more than one billion people worldwide. 

The concept? Doing all of it at once. Goals can be achieved by bundling critical yet straightforward solutions in a comprehensive investment strategy and working directly with the poorest of the poor. 

By investing in health, food production, education, access to clean water, and essential infrastructure, these community-led interventions will enable impoverished villages to escape extreme poverty once and for all. Once these communities get a foothold on the bottom rung of the development ladder they can propel themselves on a path of self-sustaining economic growth. 

The concept was developed by a team of scientific experts at The Earth Institute at Columbia University and the UN Millennium Project. Millennium Promise is working in more than 75 villages in ten different countries: Ethiopia, Ghana, Kenya, Malawi, Mali, Nigeria, Rwanda, Senegal, Tanzania and Uganda.

For more information:

www.millenniumvillages.org
www.earth.columbia.edu/millenniumvillages
www.millenniumpromise.org

1. We must eradicate extreme poverty by 2015 through the UN Millennium Development Goals

2. We must sponsor rural integrated and sustainable development

3. We must achieve a bottom-up, community-led approach to development</description>
  <mission>Eradicate Extreme Poverty through Integrated Rural and Sustainable Development</mission>
  <name>Millennium Villages Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/409</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">763</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">210.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3qA/n7WS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
