<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Since September 11th, 2001, the United States has embarked on a long, arduous, painful, and costly battle against terrorism abroad.  First in Afghanistan, now in Iraq, and potentially in other countries such as Iran, Saudi Arabia, and North Korea, the United States has had hundreds of thousands of troops deployed to keep our country safe.

Heated debate has raged from the outset as to whether or not the United States has been justified in any of these invasions, and political subterfuge has marred the intentions of those simply trying to protect their country.  Nevertheless, the partisan issue of whether we should be fighting should not detract from our support of the men and women fighting on our behalf, and it should definitely not prevent us from lending our support to those families who have lost someone fighting terrorism.

The Patriot Fund provides much-needed financial aid to families who have lost fathers, mothers, brothers, and sisters while fighting terrorism.  The purpose of the Fund is to prevent the tragedy of losing a family member from being worsened by financial calamity.  Their long-term goal is to provide financial assistance to these families in equal amount to the aid provided to the families of firefighters killed on September 11th.

Remember, your support of the troops and their families does not equate to support of the reason for the war.  Whether or not you believe our presence in Iraq or Afghanistan is justified, these families need and deserve our support.

Thank you.

1. Set aside partisan politics and support the troops abroad.

2. Give financial aid to families who has had a family member die fighting terrorism.</description>
  <mission>aid the families of the fallen from the War on Terror</mission>
  <name>Supporters of Families of Fallen Soldiers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/460</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4532</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">490.21</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kIP/PpyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
