<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Thurber House, a literary center for readers and writers located in the historic former home of author, humorist, and New Yorker cartoonist James Thurber. Thurber House is dedicated to promoting the literary arts by presenting quality literary programming; increasing the awareness of literature as a significant art form; promoting excellence in writing; providing support for literary artists; and commemorating Thurber's literary and artistic achievements. Our programs include author readings, writing classes for children, and celebrations of Thurber's life. As the only literary center in the country to offer comprehensive literary programming for adults and children, Thurber House is a unique national treasure.

Thurber House opened its doors to the public in 1984 after extensive renovation to our historic house location in Columbus, Ohio, where Thurber lived with his family while he was a student at The Ohio State University. Since then, we have become a gathering place for readers, writers, and Thurber enthusiasts of all ages. Through our Evenings with Authors, a series of readings and receptions with nationally-known authors, we have attracted well-known writers such as John Updike, T.C. Boyle, Tracy Chevalier, and Scott Turrow. The annual Thurber Prize for American Humor has become the nation's highest designation of the art of humor writing. And our children's programs, including our popular Thurber Summer Writing Camp, have nurtured thousands of young writers.

1. We are committed to increasing the awareness of literature as a significant art form

2. We promote excellence in writer and provide support for literary artists

3. We commemorate James Thurber's literary and artistic achievements</description>
  <mission>Promote the literary arts; increase the awareness of literature; and excellence in writing; and commemorate Thurber's literary and artistic achievements.</mission>
  <name>The Thurber House</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/468</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jT/cb/b0/44/z7/7U/qX/XXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
