<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For Animals
Chickens have their sensitive beaks seared off with a hot blade, and male cattle and pigs are castrated without any painkillers. All farmed chickens, turkeys, and pigs spend their brief lives in dark and crowded warehouses, many of them so cramped that they can't even turn around or spread a single wing. They are mired in their own waste, and the stench of ammonia fills the air. Animals raised for food are bred and drugged to grow as large as possible as quickly as possible&#8212;many are so heavy that they become crippled under their own weight and die within inches of their water supply. 
By switching to a vegetarian diet, you can save more than 100 animals a year from this misery. 

For Your Health
Some of the leading killers in America today, including heart disease, cancer, obesity, and strokes, are directly linked to meat-based diets. Heart disease is the number one cause of death in America today, and it is caused by the build-up of cholesterol and saturated fat from animal products in our arteries. The only two doctors in human history who have successfully reversed heart disease have included an exclusively vegetarian diet as a part of their programs.

For the Environment
More than half of the water used in the United States today goes to animal agriculture, and since farmed animals produce 130 times more excrement than the human population, the run-off from their waste is fouling our waterways. Animal excrement emits gases, such as hydrogen sulfide and ammonia, that poison the air around farms, as well as methane and nitrous oxide, which are major contributors to global warming. Raising animals for food also requires massive amounts of food and raw materials: Farmed animals consume 70 percent of the corn, wheat, and other grains that we grow, and one-third of all the raw materials and fossil fuels used in the U.S. go to raising animals for food. In short, our country's meat addiction is wrecking the earth.

http://www.goveg.com/

1. We must save the animals now.</description>
  <mission>Save animals, help the environment, and live a healthy lifestyle.</mission>
  <name>Vegetarian</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/470</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">34869</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">394.61</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sLF/8QtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
