<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Become a Fan: http://www.new.facebook.com/pages/Water-For-People/21207514564

WATER AND SANITATION 

An estimated 2.5 billion people lack adequate sanitation and 884 billion people are without access to safe water. 

Globally, more than 125 million children under five years of age live in households without access to an improved drinking-water source, and more than 280 million children under five live in households without access to improved sanitation facili- ties. (UNICEF, 2006) 

90% of wastewater in developing countries is discharged into rivers and streams without any treatment. (UNDP, UNEP, World Bank, and the World Resources Institute, &#8220;World Resources 2000-2001&#8221;, pg. 25-26) 

Diarrhea can be reduced by 26% when basic water, hygiene, and sanitation are supplied. (World Water Day, 2001) 

WATER AND DISEASE 

4,000 children die each day as a result of water-related illnesses. (WHO 2004) 

In the past ten years, diarrhea has killed more children than all the people lost to armed conflict since WWII. (WSSCC, 2004) 

Water is implicated in 80% of all sickness and disease worldwide. 19% of deaths from infection and disease worldwide are water related and waterborne diseases contribute to nearly 4 million child deaths. (Rehydration Project, www.rehydrate.org/facts/progress ... 

At any one time, it is estimated that half the world&#8217;s hospital beds are occupied with patients suffering from water-related diseases. (WSSC, 2004) 

Diarrhea kills more than three million people each year and chronic diarrhea is a lead- ing killer of people with AIDS. (USAID, 2004) 

Major diseases transmitted by water: cholera, typhoid, bacillary dysentery, infectious hepatitis, and Giardia. (WHO, &#8220;Right to Water,&#8221; 2003) 

Major diseases caused by lack of water: scabies, skin sepsis and ulcers, yaws, lep- rosy, trachoma, dysenteries. (WHO, &#8220;World Health Report&#8221; 2002) 

The average distance that women in developing countries walk to collect water per day is 6 kilometers (4 miles) and the average weight that women carry on their heads is approximately 20 kilograms (44 pounds), the same weight as airport luggage allow- ance. (WSSCC, 2004) 

Almost 70% of the world&#8217;s citizens living in poverty are women. (World Water Day, 2001) 

WATER AND ECONOMIC GROWTH 

Over 40 billion work hours are lost each year in Africa to the need to fetch drinking water. (WHO 2004) 

Water-related illnesses cost the Indian economy 73 million working days per year. (WSSCC, 2004) 

1. An estimated 2.5 billion people lack adequate sanitation and 884 billion people are without access to safe water.

2. 4,000 children die each day as a result of water-related illnesses.

3. 90% of the wastewater in developing countries is discharged into rivers and streams without any treatment - then used for drinking and bathing.

4. Women and girls in developing countries walk an average of 4 miles every day to collect water.

5. What sacrifices would you need to make to walk 4 miles a day carrying 40 lbs of water? School? Work? Family Time? Fun?</description>
  <mission>Helps people in developing countries improve their quality of life by supporting the development of locally sustainable drinking water resources, sanitation facilities and hygiene education.</mission>
  <name>Water For People</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/509</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">906</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1699.5</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ig/hN/DQ/qT/yB/Y8/jrIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
