<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The following information is copied directly from the Locks of Love website.
http://www.locksoflove.org/

Locks of Love is a public non-profit organization that provides hairpieces to financially disadvantaged children under age 18 suffering from long-term medical hair loss from any diagnosis.


HOW TO DONATE
- 10 inches measured tip to tip is the minimum length needed for a hairpiece.
- Hair must be in a ponytail or braid before it is cut.
- Hair must be clean and completely dry before it is mailed in.
- Place the ponytail or braid inside of a plastic bag, and then inside of a padded envelope.
- If you wish to receive our personalized thank-you card, please fill out the hair DONATION FORM, or write your name and address on a full size separate sheet of paper and include inside the envelope. We cannot acknowledge donors who do not send their name and address according to these instructions.

-All hair donations must be mailed to Locks of Love at: 

234 Southern Blvd.
West Palm Beach, FL 33405


GUIDELINES FOR ACCEPTABLE DONATIONS
- Hair that is colored or permed is acceptable.
- Hair cut years ago is usable if it has been stored in a ponytail or braid.
- Hair that has been bleached (usually this refers to highlighted hair) is not usable.  If unsure, ask your stylist. We are not able to accept bleached hair due to a chemical reaction that occurs during the manufacturing process.
- Hair that is swept off of the floor is not usable because it is not bundled in a ponytail or braid.
- Hair that is shaved off and not in a ponytail or braid is not usable. If shaving your head, first divide hair into multiple ponytails to cut off.
- We cannot accept dreadlocks. Our manufacturer is not able to use them in our children&#8217;s hairpieces. We also cannot accept wigs, falls, hair extensions or synthetic hair.
- Layered hair is acceptable if the longest layer is 10 inches. 
Layered hair may be divided into multiple ponytails.
- Curly hair may be pulled straight to measure the minimum 10 inches.
- 10 inches measured tip to tip is the minimum length needed for a hairpiece.

PLEASE NOTE:
- Shorter hair will be separated from the ponytails and sold to offset the manufacturing costs. Although the shorter hair cannot be used in the hairpieces, it still greatly helps to reduce costs.
- Gray hair will be accepted and sold to offset the manufacturing costs.
- Colored hair is not usable if it is colored over bleached hair.

THANK YOU!

1. Donate hair and/or raise awareness about Locks of Love</description>
  <mission>To donate hair and/or raise awareness and funds for Locks of Love.</mission>
  <name>Locks of Love: Donate Hair for Children</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/513</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8892</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">284.66</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jEK/KS8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
