<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is a cause designed to cure America (and beyond) of its apparant apathy and indifference to its homeless.  Advocates of this cause will work toward a day when every man, woman, and child have decent living arrangements.

----------------------------------------

Here are some websites to volunteer organizations that you can join to help solve the problem of homelessness:

1. &lt;a href="http://www.porchlightinc.org"&gt;Porchlightinc&lt;/a&gt; =&gt; Porchlight provides emergency shelter, food, employment services, counseling, and affordable transitional and permanent housing.

2. &lt;a href="http://www.alphaproject.org"&gt;Alpha Project&lt;/a&gt; =&gt; Alpha Project for the Homeless is a nonprofit human services organization that serves over 4,000 men, women, and children each day. Services offered include affordable housing,  residential substance abuse treatment, outreach and prevention, etc.

3. &lt;a href="http://www.homesforthehomeless.com"&gt;Homes For The Homeless&lt;/a&gt; =&gt; Homes for the Homeless (HFH) is the nation's largest provider of residential, education and employment training centers&#8212;serving over 630 homeless families and over 1,200 homeless children each day at five separate sites across New York City.

4. &lt;a href="http://www.self-sufficiency.org/mission.html
"&gt;Building Opportunites for Self-Sufficiency&lt;/a&gt; =&gt; BOSS is dedicated to helping poor, homeless, and disabled people achieve health and self-sufficiency, and to fighting against the root causes of poverty and homelessness. Scroll down to the bottom and click on the &lt;a href="http://www.self-sufficiency.org/contents.html"&gt;table of contents&lt;/a&gt; for more information.

5. &lt;a href="http://www.studentsagainsthunger.org/mission.html
"&gt;National Student Campaign Against Hunger and Homelessness&lt;/a&gt; =&gt; The Campaign is committed to ending hunger and homelessness in America by educating, engaging, and training students to directly meet individuals&#8217; immediate needs while advocating for long-term systemic solutions.

6. &lt;a href="http://www.fullercenter.org"&gt;The Fuller Center for Housing&lt;/a&gt; =&gt; The Fuller Center for Housing builds homes in partnership with homeowner families who put in hundreds of hours of sweat equity and pay it all forward at no-profit and no-interest. It also uses The Greater Blessing Program for home rehab projects, typically for the elderly. It's at work throughout the U.S. and in a number of nations overseas.


If you have any questions or comments about volunteer opportunites in your area, please feel free to &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/p/Matt_Levenson/8645287"&gt;send me a message&lt;/a&gt;.

1. Having a home is a necessity.

2. Every person in America and the world beyond should have a home.

3. Having a home and an address makes it easier to get a job.

4. Jobs provide money for food, education, and other necessities.</description>
  <mission>To bring about a day in which there is not a  single person in United States, and eventually the world, who is without a home.</mission>
  <name>Homes for the Homeless</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/516</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1982</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">93.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0y/Ie/Bh/PV/bq/I7/o8/QdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
