<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Shaukat Khanum Memorial Cancer Hospital and Research Centre (SKMCH&amp;RC) is a state-of-the-art cancer centre located in Lahore, Pakistan. It is a project of the Shaukat Khanum Memorial Trust, which is a charitable organization established under the Societies Registration Act XXI of 1860 of Pakistan. The institution is the brainchild of Pakistani cricket superstar, Imran Khan. The inspiration came after the death of his mother, Mrs. Shaukat Khanum, from cancer.

Imran Khan made a nation-wide appeal for the collection of funds from a match between Pakistan and India on November 10, 1989 at Gaddafi Stadium, Lahore which raised Rs. 2,902,600. This was followed by a series of more than 50 successful fund raisers held throughout the world. Pakistan's win under Imran's captaincy in the 1992 cricket world cup in Melbourne helped fundraising efforts. He was able to collect one and a half million pounds in just six weeks after the World Cup when the same amount had taken 2 years to collect earlier. He donated his entire prize money of 85,000 pounds for the project. In 1994 when the project required more financing for the ongoing construction, Imran Khan launched a mass contact campaign in which he toured 27 cities in the country and collected Rs. 120 million. During the entire campaign for the construction of the hospital, over a million individual donors from ordinary citizens to the rich and famous pitched in. Everything from cash to jewelry and valuables was donated. 

SOURCES OF FUNDS - PHASE I 
Donations 67% 
Credit and Loans 33% 
  
EXPENSES - PHASE I  
Land and Building PKR 231,000,000   
Medical Equipment PKR 314,000,000   
Ancillary Equipment PKR 132,000,000   
Total PKR 677,000,000  (US$ 22,200,000)

For further info, please visit:

http://www.shaukatkhanum.org.pk/
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shaukat_Khanum_Memorial_Cancer_Hospital_%26_Research_Centre
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Imran_Khan
http://www.shaukatkhanum.org.pk/html/help_donation.html#outside

1. To sustain continued charity, donated financing for the institution, wherein more than 70% patients are treated free of cost.

2. To increase the scope of operations and facilities in the existing Lahore facility, and to finance the under-construction Karachi hospital.

3. Health care is a universal right, the provisions of which a state should guarantee. However in a country where institutions are depleting under a mili</description>
  <mission>To alleviate the suffering of patients with cancer.</mission>
  <name>Shaukat Khanum Memorial Cancer Hospital and Research Centre</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/519</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">39732</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">14722.68</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oNg/brtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
