<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>When Jewish kids turn 18 here in the USA they go off to University. In Israel however they go off to the front line to protect the country that so many of us love.

For the first time in Hillel History, we have teamed up with an elite unit of the Army to help us understand what really goes on and to help foster an individual friendship with a solider and them with you.

Every UofM Hillel student that would like to participate will receive an email and a actual dog tag of an Israeli solider from that unit. 

In Israel you usually receive 4 dog tags as standard issue. All members or Orev Golani will receive 5 with an option to send the 5th to you. 

These soldiers know that you can ask them any question and they will do their best to answer. As long as its not breaching any security.

There is no hidden agenda here. They know that tough questions will be coming about their opinions about what they do. 

We at Michigan Hilllel pride our selves on a no BS approach to dealing with the real issues. 

We think that you will learn more about the conflict through the eyes of a solider than you will on any news outlet. 

Having met the unit and spoken to them, I know they are very interested to know about your lives. This isn't a pen pal thing. This is a learning opportunity for all sides to truly understand Israeli and diaspora life.

We hope to do some fund raising here to help the unit by essential equipment such as camel packs and  and boots.

No money at all will go to the buying or supplying of weapons. This is simply to get equipment to those soldiers that cant afford their own.

We look forward to being the first Hillel in the world doing this and Orev Golani look forward to being the first unit in the IDF doing this. 

A successful program at Michigan will help the future twinning of units with Hillel's all over the world.




1. In order to apply for this unique oppertunity you must belive that you can not have a safe and secure Arab state of Palastine without a safe and secure Jewish state of Israel side by side.

2. That we should question and support the IDF and learn from eachother as best we can.

3. This is a 3 year program and we hope that you will stay in contact at least once a month.</description>
  <mission>twin UofM Hillel students to the Orev Golani unit in the IDF.</mission>
  <name>UofM Hillel and the IDF</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/531</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">59</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GqI/bp3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
