<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In 1977, a Seattle judge conceived the idea of using trained community volunteers to speak for the best interests of abused and neglected children in court. So successful was this program that soon judges across the country began utilizing citizen advocates. In 1990, the US Congress encouraged the expansion of CASA programs with passage of the Victims of Child Abuse Act. 


Today, we have grown to a network of more than 50,000 volunteers that serve 225,000 abused and neglected children through 900+ local program offices nationwide. Our advocates, also known as volunteer guardians ad litem in some jurisdictions, are appointed members of the court. Judges rely on the information these trusted advocates present. 

CASA is the only volunteer organization that empowers everyday citizens as appointed members of the court. In an overburdened social welfare system, abused and neglected children often slip through the cracks among hundreds of current cases. CASA volunteers change that. Appointed by judges, CASA volunteers typically handle just one case at a time&#8212;and commit to staying on that case until the child is placed in a safe, permanent home. While others may come and go, CASA volunteers provide that one constant that children need in order to thrive. 



1. Support and promote court-appointed volunteer advocacy for abused and neglected children so that they can thrive in safe, permanent homes. </description>
  <mission>Support and promote court-appointed volunteer advocacy for abused and neglected children so that they can thrive in safe, permanent homes. </mission>
  <name>CASA (Court Appointed Special Advocates)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/535</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">14883</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">6634.97</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Hm/UJ/tk/7u/iu/jR/z0/K3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
