<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Students for Sensible Drug Policy (SSDP) is a student-led grassroots organization working to end the failed War on Drugs. SSDP neither encourages nor condemns drug use. Rather, we seek to reduce the harms caused by drug abuse and drug policies. As young people, we strive toward a just and compassionate society where drug abuse is treated as a health issue instead of a criminal justice issue.We recognize that the very real harms of drug abuse are not adequately addressed by current policies and we advocate measures that would effectively help those who develop drug problems. Yet, we also believe that individuals must ultimately be allowed to make decisions for themselves as long as their actions do not infringe upon anyone else&#8217;s freedoms or safety.

Because the War on Drugs has historically been justified as necessary to protect youth, it is our responsibility as young people to stop this harmful war from being waged in our names any longer. As scholars, we seek solutions to society's drug problems through focused research, honest dialogue, and informed debate, instead of unquestioned extremism, punishment, and propaganda.

Four ways to get involved:

1) Join our Facebook group:  
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2204718067

2) Sign up for our e-mail action alerts:  
http://www.ssdp.org/signup/

3) Start an SSDP chapter at your school!
http://www.ssdp.org/chapters/start/

4) DONATE.  The federal govt spends more than $50 billion a year on the War on Drugs, but SSDP relies on generous contributions from supporters in order to fight back.  Please hit the "Donate" button below and make a donation if you can afford it.  Thanks!



1. The War on Drugs is doing far more harm than good and must be stopped.

2. Drug addiction is a public health issue, not a criminal issue.

3. The penalty that takes away financial aid from students with drug convictions must be repealed.

4. Student drug testing does nothing to deter teen drug use.  It only deters students from participating in extracurricular activities.

5. Young people deserve honest, science-based information regarding drugs and harm reduction - not propaganda, lies, and scare tactics.

6. Zero tolerance drug policies increase drug problems, by punishing people who need help.</description>
  <mission>We seek to end the War on Drugs by empowering young people to participate in politics, pushing for sensible policies grounded in health and human rights to achieve a safer and more just future.</mission>
  <name>Students for Sensible Drug Policy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/536</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">19814</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5527.96</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/y83/5yoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
