<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Greenpeace exists because this fragile earth deserves a voice. It needs solutions. It needs change. It needs action.

Greenpeace is an independent global campaigning organisation that acts to change attitudes and behaviour, to protect and conserve the environment and to promote peace by:

Catalysing an energy revolution to address the number one threat facing our planet: climate change.

Defending our oceans by challenging wasteful and destructive fishing, and creating a global network of marine reserves.

Protecting the world&#8217;s ancient forests and the animal, plants and people that depend on them.

Working for disarmament and peace by tackling the causes of conflict and calling for the elimination of all nuclear weapons.

Creating a toxic free future with safer alternatives to hazardous chemicals in today's products and manufacturing.

Campaining for sustainable agriculture by rejecting genetically engineered organisms, protecting biodiversity and encouraging socially responsible farming.

Greenpeace is present in 40 countries across Europe, the Americas, Asia and the Pacific. 

To maintain its independence, Greenpeace does not accept donations from governments or corporations but relies on contributions from individual supporters and foundation grants.

We exist to expose environmental criminals, and to challenge government and corporations when they fail to live up to their mandate to safeguard our environment and our future.

http://www.greenpeace.org

Please note that Facebook does not offer an option to donate to Greenpeace International.  Donations through Facebook will go to Greenpeace US.  To donate to Greenpeace International, go to http://www.greenpeace.org/international/getinvolved/donate

1. Position #1</description>
  <mission>Greenpeace exists because this fragile Earth deserves a voice. It needs solutions. It needs change. It needs action. Due to the setup of Causes application, donations go to Greenpeace US.</mission>
  <name>Greenpeace International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/544</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">302785</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">13775.24</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/YR/ao/UB/fD/CR/77/v4/yXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
