<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Sunrise Day Camp is the first and only dedicated day camp in the world designed for children with cancer, ages 3 &#189; - 16, and their siblings.  It is a very special place where children can come, free of charge, and enjoy a summer filled with fun friendship and activities &#8211; things that are often denied them because of their medical condition.  This unique camp is situated a 300 acre wooded site on Long Island servicing children throughout the entire New York metropolitan area. This outstanding camp offers swimming, sports, music, drama, and all the wonderful recreational programs that make for a terrific summer camp experience. Sunrise Day Camp also continues throughout the year with &#8220;Camp&#8221; programs once a month on Sundays, during school holiday breaks and in treatment clinics. Sunrise Day Camp and its year round programs are designed to meet the emotional, social, recreational and physical needs of these incredible children, while allowing them to enjoy the comfort and safety of home at night.

Each year in the United States, approximately 12,000 children and adolescents are diagnosed with cancer. On Long Island, there are currently 1,200-1,500 children who are either in active or follow-up treatment. These children, who sustain medical procedures and doctors appointments on a continual basis, deserve an opportunity to enjoy a summer camp experience filled with fun, friendship and hope- just like their healthy peers. Although the United States is filled with sleepaway camps for children with cancer there are virtually no day camps, and none available in the entire northeast. A day camp setting, designed to meet the emotional, social, recreational and physical needs of the child while allowing them to enjoy the comforts and safety of their own homes at night, can be a critical component to their growth, development, hope and well being. 

1. Children can come free of charge, and enjoy a summer filled with fun friendship and activities.

2. Designed to meet the emotional, social, recreational and physical needs of these incredible children.

3. We offer a wide variety of programs all year long, as well as many special fundraising &amp; social events such as our annual Walk to Help the Sun Rise!</description>
  <mission> Sunrise Day Camp, for children ages 3 -16, is the only dedicated day camp in the nation for children with cancer. </mission>
  <name>Sunrise Day Camp</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/569</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1343</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">332.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/p6/TD/w4/bQ/KG/mj/Rl/wFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
