<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our nation's most pressing problem: In America today, educational inequity persists along socioeconomic and racial lines.

Nine-year-olds growing up in low-income communities are already three grade levels behind their peers in high-income communities. Half of them won't graduate from high school. Those who do graduate will, on average, read and do math at the level of eighth graders in high-income communities.

These disparities severely limit the life prospects of the 13 million children growing up in poverty today. 

It doesn't have to be this way. 
 
Our impact: Since 1990, nearly 17,000 individuals have joined Teach For America, affecting the lives of more than 2.5 million students and leading key education and social reform initiatives.

There are currently some 4,400 Teach For America corps members working in 25 urban and rural areas profoundly affected by the achievement gap, from the Bronx and East LA to the Mississippi Delta and Native American reservations. They are working extraordinarily hard to ensure their students achieve academic success despite the inequities they face.

Teach For America alumni most of whom are still in their 20s and 30s are already at the center of the effort to realize educational opportunity for all. They are pioneering education reform initiatives, working from other sectors to marshal necessary resources and change policies, winning the highest accolades teachers can win, and running many high-performing schools in low-income communities.

It is through the combined efforts of our corps members and alumni, and by working alongside others in the communities that we serve, that we will achieve our vision: One day, all children in this nation will have the opportunity to attain an excellent education.

1. One day, all children in this nation will have the opportunity to attain an excellent education.</description>
  <mission>Teach For America enlists our nation's most promising future leaders in the movement to eliminate educational inequality.</mission>
  <name>Teach For America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/57</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">27741</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25079.74</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/y7/zU/S7/fl/qN/83/6t/8FS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
