<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> in 2010 i am planning to bike several thousand miles in the fight against aids.

here are some facts about AIDS:

Number of people living with HIV/AIDS - 34.1 - 47.1 million
Number of people infected in 2006 - 
3.6 - 6.6 million
Cumulative number of people who have died from AIDS - over 25 million

I want it to be known that I am not a professsional cyclist or anything, just an average highschool student/athlete trying to make a difference. The idea is that when the summer of 2010 comes around i will bike from a good starting point in ontario, out to B.C., down the coast of the USA, follow the border of mexico towards the east coast, go into florida, go up the coast of the east into newfoundland and bike all the way back to ontario. I understand that this would be an amazing task to take on, but I am willing to give up as long as it takes to do it.

Hopefully from now until the summer of 2010 i will be able to get enough group members so that buisnesses and sponsors are willing to donate money for a good cause and take this globally. The goal here is to help as many people as possible and earn as much money for AIDS research as possible. Please join the cause and pass it on to ALL YOUR FRIENDS in your network. 

my plan is that hopefully i will have some help of fellow cyclists and when we roll into washington we will go to the whitehouse and ask the president of the united states if he supports our cause. with the world watching him he will no doubtingly say yes and when a president has anything possitive to say about a group alot of sponsorship money goes into the group. every last penny sponsered to this group will go to aids research, and in a few years i will have the map coarse done and an account that people can start to donate to. i will try my hardest to finish aids for ever but one man cant defeat it it will take the whole world to defeat it... are you willing to be part of it? 

1. go to http://www.avert.org/worldstats.htm to find out more

2. if you would like to send money my address is:

3. 556 Highway 8, Dundas, Ontario RR#1 L9H 5E1</description>
  <mission>Raise money and awareness about aids</mission>
  <name>A Fight Against Aids</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/580</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6040</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wk/uY/fg/KV/N1/Qf/Wl/6dS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
