<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This Cause located at:
www.causes.com/AltEn

Find the full description at:
www.freewebs.com/renewableandnuclear

Lets not kid ourselves; we all know what global climate change is, and that its happening.  The question is now: How do we stop it?

The two main anthropogenic (that is, 'human caused') sources of greenhouse gasses, such as carbon, are automobiles running on gasoline and power plants burning coal and natural gas.  Automobiles and power plants are vital to civilization as we know it today, so they can obviously not change.  But what can change is what they run on.  We can begin to phase out coal fired power plants by setting a moratorium on their construction.  In their place, we can build wind farms and set up solar panels, and for baseline support, nuclear power stations.  By creating this system of carbon-free power generation, this will leave us with a clean alternative for our cars  electricity!  Automobile companies, and even start ups, are creating plug in hybrids and plug in all electric vehicles.  With gas prices as high as they are, these vehicles are actually starting to become cheaper in the long run than most traditional vehicles.  With the support from governments across the earth (in the form of tax breaks, tax incentives, or a carbon tax), electric vehicles can be the future of transportation in under a decade.

The glitch in this system seems to be nuclear power. What if terrorists attack it? What if there is a meltdown? What if the radiation leaks? What do we do with the waste? What if we run out of Uranium?
Find out at:
http://www.freewebs.com/renewableandnuclear/

Last Updated: 10/13/08
M/D/Y  -  # of members
06/07/07 - 100
06/10/07 - 150 
06/29/07 - 200 
07/30/07 - 300 
08/24/07 - 350 
09/07/07 - 400 
09/09/07 &#8211; (major update)
09/21/07 - 450
10/03/07 - 500
10/14/07 - 550
10/22/07 - 600
10/31/07 - 650
11/14/07 - 700
12/08/07 - 750
01/14/08 - 800
03/26/08 - 850
10/13/08 - 1,046 (Major Update)
11/19/08 - 1,115 (Minor Update)


1. Anthropogenic global climate change is happening.

2. We must use every technology we have to bring greenhouse gas emissions under control.

3. The best way to do this is to begin to use more alternative energy sources such as solar, wind, and nuclear energy.</description>
  <mission>To help slow anthropogenic global climate change through the use of alternative energy resources.</mission>
  <name>Stop Global Warming with Alternative Energy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/588</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1320</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mp/6S/wx/61/7B/Qa/qdiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
