<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Locks of Love is a public non-profit organization that provides hairpieces to financially disadvantaged children under age 18 suffering from long-term medical hair loss from any diagnosis. We meet a unique need for children by using donated hair to create the highest quality hair prosthetics. Most of the children helped by Locks of Love have lost their hair due to a medical condition called alopecia areata, which has no known cause or cure. The prostheses we provide help to restore their self-esteem and their confidence, enabling them to face the world and their peers.

The treatment some of these children undergo cause them to lose hair. How would you like it if you had no hair? 

All you have to do is join and try and get more people to join. The more people that are aware of the cause the more might try to grow their hair out for the cause or donate money to help in the making of these wigs.



HOW TO DONATE

-10 inches measured tip to tip is the minimum length needed for a hairpiece. 

-Hair must be in a ponytail or braid before it is cut. 

-Hair must be clean and completely dry before it is mailed in. 

-Place the ponytail or braid inside of a plastic bag, and then inside of a padded envelope. 

-Fill out the hair donation form, or write your name and address on a separate sheet of paper and include inside the envelope. 

*** Please note that bleaches and highlighted hair will not be accepted but dyed hair is!


All hair donations must be mailed to Locks of Love at: 

2925 10th Avenue N
Suite 102
Lake Worth, FL 33461 




Visit http://www.locksoflove.org for more information.



1. Children need to feel confident.

2. They have the right to look like everyone else.

3. Children do not like to be pittied, they want to be normal.</description>
  <mission>Return a sense of self-confidence and normality to children suffering from hair loss by utilizing donated ponytails to provide the hair prosthetics to financially disadvantaged children.</mission>
  <name>Locks Of Love</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/606</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">49664</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">945.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nYi/TYOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
