<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The mission of Telluride Association is to:

* Build character by giving significant responsibilities to talented young people and by requiring them to carry out their responsibilities through democratic processes in a small community. 

* Provide outstanding educational opportunities to people while giving them significant responsibilities, with an emphasis on the links between the two.

* Educate young men and women in the ways of critical thinking and democratic self-government-- promoting shared intellectual life--and to allow them to develop and utilize this experience in short- and long-term residential programs.

Telluride also sponsors the following:

* Cornell Branch of Telluride Association (CBTA) and Michigan Branch of Telluride Association (MBTA): Approximately 30 intellectually-talented, and community-minded, Cornell/UMich students are provided with renewable room and board scholarships in the pursuit of Telluride's mission.

* Telluride Association Sophomore Seminar (TASS): Each summer, forty-eight bright, motivated high school sophomores will participate in one of three challenging six-week college-level courses in African American studies and other fields at the University of Michigan and Indiana University.

* Telluride Association Summer Program (TASP): TASP is a six-week educational experience for high school juniors that offers challenges and rewards rarely encountered in secondary school or even college. It's like TASS, but more ethnically/culturally diverse and WAY cooler. Also, it's hosted at 3 different universities (UMich, Cornell, and UT Austin) though there are 4 programs; Cornell has 2.

1. Young men and women should develop critical-thinking skills.

2. Democratic self-governance is important. 

3. People have to give back to the community.</description>
  <mission>Build character, educate talented youth, foster self-governance, and (basically) rock your face off.</mission>
  <name>Support the Education of Talented Youth</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/624</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">74</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bvy/q0uS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
