<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>:  International Justice Mission is a human rights organization working to respond to human rights violations by providing legal services to people in Africa, Asia and Latin America who are victims of violence, trafficking, oppression, sexual abuse and slavery.  IJM works not only to secure immediate relief, but to hold perpetrators accountable for their abuses by representing victims in the legal system.  Through working together with local authorities to ensure the prosecution of these crimes, IJM establishes structural preventions to stop future abuse.   IJM ensures access to vital services and aftercare, helping victims to transition to new lives of freedom.  
IJM works to educate and mobilize people around the world to fight these injustices. 

The time to respond is now.  Our generation will not be bystanders as more than 20 million humans are held in slavery and one million children are trafficked into the sex trade every year; we will not sit as comfortable spectators as sexual violence continues to serve as a major engine of the AIDS pandemic, infecting girls and women unwillingly held in brothels. Nor will we stand quietly as the land rights of women are violated on a massive scale, leaving widows and other women in vulnerable positions unable to care for themselves or their children.  We will not wait for someone else to ensure that pedophiles cannot abuse the children of the poor with impunity, and we will not rest while suspects of crimes are illegally detained for years without trial. 

Now is the time to act.  Join IJM as we seek justice.

For more infomation please consult the following links.

IJM Website: www.ijm.org
IJM Facebook Page: http://www.facebook.com/pages/International-Justice-Mission/29717379728?ref=ts
IJM Store: https://secure3.convio.net/ijm/site/Ecommerce?store_id=1101
Just Courage by Gary Haugen: www.justcourage.com



1. &#8220;All that is necessary for the triumph of evil is for good men to do nothing.&#8221; &#8211; Edmund Burke</description>
  <mission>To rescue victims of slavery, sex trafficking, sexual violence and oppression, and to ensure that public justice systems work for the poor who so desperately need them.</mission>
  <name>International Justice Mission</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/631</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">41020</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25475.65</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0t/3i/aj/wP/nm/f5/oN/j7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
