<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Next Generation America is a non-political/non-religious affiliated student movement, ambitious to raise awareness to hidden social, political, and cultural oppression that exists locally, regionally, nationally, and internationally.

Our passion is to educate, enable, and effectively change the face of the Next Generation by providing support in marketing, awareness, fund raising, manpower, and prayer to pre-existing non-profit charitable organizations.

We also recognize that there are many amazing non-profits, doing amazing non-profit work&#8230;but often times they are all working hard, unaware of what the others are accomplishing. We have a goal to help unify the pre-existing non-profits in a network of help. We want to raise awareness to the non-profits of what other projects are being worked on, hoping to be a central point for those involved to meet and collaborate.

In regards to fund raising and awareness, we want to focus on the local art and music community as a key support system. Having events on and off campus, we hope to raise funds that can then be redistributed to those in need.

We would then use the funds as promotional materials, awareness materials, direct help efforts, scholarships to help fund missions work, bringing in key speakers or figures, and general operations costs.

1. Clean water for Northern Uganda to eliminate the malaria epidemic

2. leave no person without a somewhat stable living situation in the cities

3. Bridge the gap between the city and the suburbs</description>
  <mission>The Next Generation America is a student based movement ambitious to help raise awareness, funds, and relief efforts to dissolve the social injustice which still exists today</mission>
  <name>the Next Generation America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/644</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">74</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/QWv/nadS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
