<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Colon Cancer Alliance (CCA) is a national patient advocacy organization dedicated to ending the suffering caused by colorectal cancer. In order to increase rates of screening and survivorship, the CCA provides patient support, education, research and advocacy across America.

The CCA works as an advocate for colorectal cancer patients and their families. The organization offers information and support through its numerous programs, including information gained only by the firsthand experience of survivors and others whose lives have been touched by this disease. 

Today, the CCA has over 50,000 members. Our help line receives an average of 700 calls monthly, and our support networks have assisted hundreds of thousands of people. There are dozens of local chapters that engage in awareness campaigns and fundraising efforts, as well as bring the mission of the CCA to a local level. The CCA holds numerous fund raising events throughtout the country with its Undy 5000 5K walk/run events.  

For more information about the Undy 5000, visit www.undy5000.org.

The growth and success of the organization is due in large part to caring volunteers and top notch staff who devote considerable time, skill and energy to achieving the CCA's vision.

www.ccalliance.org

Become a fan of the CCA at:
http://www.facebook.com/advertising/?src=advf2#/pages/Colon-Cancer-Alliance/100438444321?v=wall&amp;viewas=2003663


The CCA establishes the following priorities: 

1. PATIENT SUPPORT SERVICES
The Colon Cancer Alliance is building a community of emotional support and disease management services to help patients and their loved ones with the tragedy of this disease.

2. EDUCATION
The CCA offers educational resources to patients and families affected by the disease. The Alliance provides to patients, caregivers and health care providers the best and most up-to-date information available about treatments and clinical trials devoted to colorectal cancer. The Alliance works to improve education and remove financial, medical and psychological barriers that hinder early detection.

3. RESEARCH
The CCA works with other organizations to increase federal, state and private funding for research of all cancers. The Alliance advocates for the necessary funding specifically devoted to timely prevention, detection and treatment of colorectal cancer.

4. ADVOCACY
The Alliance is dedicated to advancing and championing the cause of colon cancer patients and their families. The CCA helps patients get the best medical information, support and care available. The Alliance supports legislation to these ends.

We invite any and all organizations, government agencies, members of the medical community and individuals to join us in our determination to eradicate colorectal cancer. 

Please visit www.ccalliance.org 

Support: 

Our Help Line can be reached at 1-877-422-2030.

Join My CRC Connections, an online community for those affected by colorectal cancer, at www.mycrcconnections.com.


1. Every 9 minutes, someone dies of the disease. 1 out of 18 Americans will get the disease.

2. Colorectal cancer is highly preventable and treatable if caught early. Yet it is the nation&#8217;s second leading cancer killer due to lack of screening.</description>
  <mission>The Colon Cancer Alliance is the nation's oldest and largest patient advocacy group dedicated to battle colorectal cancer through patient support, education and awareness, research and advocacy.</mission>
  <name>Colon Cancer Alliance</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/653</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">43513</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15259.27</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zf/ZQ/bq/FQ/24/cE/Xe/sVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
