<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>All That is asked is that you send this to others to get the awwareness of this problem out there. those who dontate the money will be going to a youth center in Washington DC.
Bullying and Harassment in schools is a HUGE problem in our generation no matter what the age level. By sending this to your friends and getting more recutes you are letting one more person know about the harassment that is going on and can possibly help. Most of the time kids and teens going through this in schools don't speak out because they are to afraid of what is going to happen to them. By sending this to your friends, not only are you letting them know that you care and they are not alone in this battle, but you are sayingt you will be one who will step out from the crowd and help out whenever you see someone in need of some help in this situation.
FACTS:
- 1 OUT OF EVERY 4 STUDENTS AVOID COMING TO SCHOOL BECAUSE THEY ARE TO AFRAID OF WHAT WILL HAPPEN TO THEM
- 16% OF STUDENTS IN THE US DON'T PARTICIPATE IN CLASS BECAUSE THEY ARE AFRAID TO SPEAK OUT
- A MAJORITY OF THESE KIDS ALSO FEEL LIKE WHAT THEY ARE GOING THOUGH IS SOMEHOW THEIR FAULT.
-kIDS THAT DEAL WITH HARASSMENT ON A DAILY BASIS CAN END UP FORMING SOME HEALTH HAZZARDES HABBITS FOR EXAMPLE... EATING DISORDERS, CUTTING THEMSELVES, SMOKING/DRINKING/DRUGS, AND IN THE MOST SERIOUS OF SITUATIONS KILL THEMSELVES.
- HARASSMENT IS IN THE FORMS OF VERBAL SEXUAL PHYSICAL AND EMOTIONAL... ALL ARE EQUALLY AS BAD

My Name is Jessica Markovich I live in NJ. I went though all forms of harassment from the age of 12 up until the present. I'm 17 now and still go through it.I am however one of the few to speak out.
I have created a program called Harassment; Open  your eyes, a School's Best Kept Secret.
By expanding this program online would be a HUGE help to get the awareness of how serious this is.
Thanks for all your help!

1. Get awareness of Bullying and harassment out there

2. Make people want to stand up and help

3. let people that are going through it that they are not alone and the have people to turn to</description>
  <mission>Get the awareness of bullying and harassment in schools out there to kids who go through it and to help them</mission>
  <name>Harassment; Open your Eyes, a School's Best Kept secret</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/678</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2739</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.3</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/CV3/2H1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
