<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>---"If the rights of society's most vulnerable members are denied, everybody's rights are imperiled."---

The ACLU also works "to extend rights to segments of our population that have traditionally been denied their rights, including Native Americans and other people of color; lesbians, gay men, bisexuals and transgendered people; women; mental-health patients; prisoners; people with disabilities; and the poor."

"The ACLU was founded by Roger Baldwin, Crystal Eastman, Albert DeSilver and others in 1920. We are nonprofit and nonpartisan and have grown from a roomful of civil liberties activists to an organization of more than 500,000 members and supporters. We handle nearly 6,000 court cases annually from our offices in almost every state."

"The ACLU has maintained the position that civil liberties must be respected, even in times of national emergency. The ACLU is supported by annual dues and contributions from its members, plus grants from private foundations and individuals. We do not receive any government funding."


Find out more about the ACLU and how to become a card-carrying member at our website: http://www.aclu.org/

Also be sure to check out the complete list of ACLU issues, documents, and ways to TAKE ACTION!

Youth focused ACLU website can be found here:
http://aclu.org/standup/issues/

_______________________________________
If you have any suggestions. comments, or additions on the content of this cause, feel free to message the creator.


1. The death penalty is the ultimate denial of civil liberties and must be repealed.

2. The U.S. government must comply with universal human rights principles. 

3. The civil and constitutional rights of immigrants must be defended.

4. Everyone, regardless of income, has the right to effective counsel in criminal cases</description>
  <mission>To preserve the following protections and guarantees: your First Amendment rights, your right to equal protection under the law, your right to due process, and your right to privacy. </mission>
  <name>American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/689</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11168</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">4342.63</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1fj/d83S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
