<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>[As explained in the trade report on Oxfam International's www.maketradefair.com]

Trade is one of the most powerful forces linking our lives, and a source of unprecedented wealth. Yet millions of the world's poorest people are being left behind. Increased prosperity has gone hand in hand with mass poverty. Already obscene inequalities between rich and poor are widening.  

World trade could be a powerful motor to reduce poverty, and support economic growth, but that potential is being lost. The problem is not that international trade is inherently opposed to the needs and interests of the poor, but that the rules that govern it are rigged in favor of the rich.

If Africa, East Asia, South Asia, and Latin America were each to increase their share of world exports by one per cent, the resulting gains in income could lift 128 million people out of poverty. In Africa alone, this would generate $70bn - approximately five times what the continent receives in aid.

In their rhetoric, governments of rich countries constantly stress their commitment to poverty reduction. Yet in practice rigged rules and double standards lock poor people out of the benefits of trade, closing the door to an escape route from poverty. For example:

Rich countries spend $1bn every day on agricultural subsidies. The resulting surpluses are dumped on world markets, undermining the livelihoods of millions of smallholder farmers in poor countries.

PLEASE VISIT www.oxfamamerica.com!

[ T-Shirt Info! ]
-Buy Online-
http://www.maketradefair.com/en/index.php?file=tshirtshop.htm#
-Make your own!-
http://www.maketradefair.com/en/index.php?file=tshirts_diy.htm

1. Call on world leaders to change the rules of global trade so that millions of people in poor countries can work their way out of poverty.

2. Make Trade Fair!</description>
  <mission>Change world trade rules so that trade can make a real difference in the fight against global poverty.</mission>
  <name>Make Trade Fair</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/694</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12480</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">660.48</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dAB/fQgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
