<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It's a sad state of affairs. 
What once was envisioned as the greatest nation ever to grace this Earth, the US is now in the runnings for one of the biggest frauds in history. 
Federal, state and local governments continue to assault our liberties with laws and programs designed to protect us from ourselves and "help" us "help" others. 
Every day, independent thinkers like us question the government's authority to place restrictions governing our actions when those actions do not directly violate the rights of others. 
Speed limits, drug criminalization, the drinking age designed to protect us from ourselves. Gun control and so-called "assault" weapons bans designed to destroy the last defense of those who will not tolerate facism in America. Licensing requirements and laws restricting the practice of certain professions to line the pockets of current licensees to create barriers to entry and unfairly control the market. Price controls when all sales should be voluntary, designed to "protect the consumer," when really they only hurt the consumer. Selective service registration. Social security. Duty to flee. 
You get the point. These laws and programs are a result of democracy: Two wolves and a sheep voting on what to eat for dinner. 
Sometime, a long time ago, America stopped being a republic designed to protect our rights and became a disgusting heap of unbridled majority tyrrany (democracy). 
Our Founding Fathers would have rather sacrificed themselves to the King of England than to have written a document leading to the sickening culture of government control today.
It's time we make a few changes.
As government becomes more and more pervasive in our lives, as the government continues to serve the people less and people continue to serve the government more, many continue to advocate more government. 
To all of those people:
Get the hell out of my way. 

1. Government is not the answer.</description>
  <mission>Stop the government's assault on our liberties.</mission>
  <name>Returning to Liberty</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/695</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">55</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tsh/w1AS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
