<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Elliott Smith Memorial Fund has partnered with Outside In (http://www.outsidein.org). According to Sweet Adeline (http://www.sweetadeline.net/esmf.html): 

"'Outside In' is a Portland-based not-for-profit organization aimed at helping homeless Portland youth. The organization provides all kinds of very important support, such as housing, medical clinics, a needle-exchange program, transgender/sexual identity services, and scholarships, among other things, for street kids. According to their website, 80% of homeless youth who go through their transitional housing program never return to the streets. Think about that statistic- this organization is changing kids&#8217; lives in the biggest way possible- taking them off the streets and getting them started on a new, safe path through support and love. We think this organization will really benefit from our donations, and we invite you to check Outside In out for yourself. Their website is outsidein.org.

We feel that this organization is a good fit for Elliott&#8217;s fund for a number of reasons. Elliott was vocal about helping abused kids, and those are largely the population that Outside In serves, though it is not a requirement. Outside In hits close to home- their facilities are actually RIGHT across the street from Lincoln High School, where Elliott went to school. Finally, Elliott knew of Outside In and had actually agreed to do a benefit for their needle-exchange program. Sadly, he never got the chance, but now we have an opportunity to give to this organization in his name."

1. Provide support for abused children

2. Help fund substance abuse treatment programs

3. Support for needle exchange programs</description>
  <mission>Honor Elliott Smith by supporting his causes</mission>
  <name>Elliott Smith Memorial Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/698</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">412</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">410.13</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/e6/lu/og/1E/LP/15/JUNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
