<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Visit us at http://www.chernobyl-international.com

We do this through a variety of medical and community development programs that directly address the domino effect of poverty, poor health, and social impact that are the legacy of the disaster. 

Much of our work is done by volunteers who work shoulder to shoulder with their peers in Chernobyl affected regions of Belarus, Ukraine, and western Russia. 

This is how we help:

- Volunteer surgical teams travel regularly to save the lives of children in Belarus and Ukraine, who are suffering from dramatic increases in genetic heart disease since 1986. They train local physicians so that they can help their own fellow citizens.

- We send volunteer nursing and therapeutic professionals to understaffed orphanages and community centers to care for kids and provide training to their local peers. 

- We build community centers and develop programs that help locals take their destinies into their own hands. 

- We take children out of orphanages and place them in homes of their own. 

- We provide at home care for disabled children, giving their parents an alternative to putting their kids in orphanages. 

- We provide hospice services to seriously ill children and their families. 

Visit us: http://www.chernobyl-international.com

1. People in Chernobyl regions want to be independent and move on with their lives, and our activities support this desire.

2. We give special attention to families and children, who are always the most vulnerable people in times of crisis. </description>
  <mission>We help families and communities that still suffer the consequences of the Chernobyl nuclear disaster. </mission>
  <name>Chernobyl Children International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/705</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4131</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10102.88</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1X/WN/c4/0D/QT/vA/77/vtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
