<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There are four steps to granting a wish. Each step builds on the next to help create the amazing experiences that delight wish kids and their families. A wish experience is frequently a source of inspiration for children undergoing difficult medical treatments and a positive force that helps them overcome their obstacles. A wish experience is often more than a dream come true: It&#8217;s the catalyst that rekindles their belief in themselves and the promise of their future.


Step 1: Referral
We rely on medical professionals, parents and children themselves for referrals. Children who have reached the age of 2 &#189; and are under the age of 18 at the time of referral who have not received a wish from another wish-granting organization may be eligible for a wish. 

Step 2: Medical eligibility 
We determine a child&#8217;s medical eligibility with the help of the treating physician. To receive a wish, the child must be diagnosed with a life-threatening medical condition &#8211; i.e., a progressive, degenerative or malignant condition that has placed the child&#8217;s life in jeopardy.

Step 3: Finding the true wish
We send one of our enthusiastic wish teams to learn the child&#8217;s one true wish. These passionate volunteers connect with wish children and help explore their imaginations for the experience that will delight and inspire them.

Step 4: Creating joy
Our wish granters create an unforgettable experience driven by the child&#8217;s creativity. It&#8217;s an incredible experience that enriches not just the lives of the children and their families, but often an entire community.



1. Making Wishes Come True</description>
  <mission>We grant the wishes of children with life-threatening medical conditions to enrich the human experience with hope, strength and joy.</mission>
  <name>Make A Wish Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/713</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">75413</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">8292.36</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/q07/75NS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
