<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The first great Principle embodies the idea that "All is Mind." It explains that SUMMUM (which is the substantial essence underlying all the outward manifestations and appearances which you know under the terms of "the material universe," "the phenomena of life," "matter," "energy," "space-time," "distance," "speed," "relativity," and, in short, all that is apparent to your material senses) is SPIRIT. This SPIRIT may be considered and thought of as A UNIVERSAL, INFINITE, LIVING MIND.
This living MIND performs gastrulation, which is a turning of itself inside out, manifesting its esoteric NATURE outwardly. Therefore, all the phenomenal worlds and universes are simply a mental creation of SUMMUM (MIND), subject to the laws of created things, and the universes, as a whole and in their parts or units, have their existence in the Mind of SUMMUM. It is in this Mind that we "live and move and have our being." 

Another Principle embodies the idea that everything is in motion; everything vibrates; nothing is at rest; facts which science endorses and which each new scientific discovery tends to verify. Yet this Principle was enunciated thousands of years ago by masters of old. This Principle explains that the differences between various manifestations of matter, energy, space-time, mind, and even spirit result largely from varying rates of vibration. At the other end of the scale, there are gross forms of matter whose vibrations are so low as to seem at rest. Between these two opposing points, there are billions upon billions of varying degrees of vibration. From quark, squark, lepton, slepton, electron, atom, and molecule, to planets and universes, everything is in vibratory motion. This is also true in the fields of energy and force (which are but varying degrees of vibration); and also at the mental levels (whose states depend upon vibrations); and even at the spiritual levels. All the Principles of Summum have an interrelationship with Vibration.

1. ~Love

2. ~Peace

3. ~Understanding</description>
  <mission>To share Love, Peace and Understanding of the world as one with all. xXx</mission>
  <name>Peace, Love &amp; Understanding</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/718</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12617</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">57.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/EM/tt/k8/a4/PQ/Mv/M3/GuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
