<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Safe Water International's program aims to stimulate use of household level drinking water purification systems in poor rural communities. Because the global population in need is so large, no particular drinking water purification program or strategy can be relied on for success. All existing national and international programs and commitments must continue and even expand. Even so, reflection on the experience of past decades points to an initiative which focuses on the household level and relies on the principle of self-help.
	
Observations and academic study of economic behavior in poor rural areas show that the rural poor find the means to purchase water supply and purification solutions when competing costs of time and labor make such a purchase rational. In the light of these findings and its own direct observation, Safe Water International believes that a marketplace based strategy directed at the household level can attack waterborne diseases in areas that will not be served by community water systems for many years to come. Once local consumer demand has been adequately defined, millions of local entrepreneurs can be mobilized in the rural regions of developing countries to supply versions of demonstrated systems or products that have found local acceptance.

1. To aid the estimated 1 billion lacking clean and disease-free drinking water.

2. To identify and promote drinking water purification products and sytems that have utility and acceptance in poor rural areas.

3. To investigate the most effective means of distribution of candidate systems and products in rural localities of developing countries.

4. To promote the manufacture and distribution of successfully demonstrated solutions through contacts with local, national, and international manufacturers, and through distribution of technical information relating to marketable products and technologies.</description>
  <mission>To identify clean drinking water solutions for the poorest rural areas of the world and to promote local marketplace involvement in delivering those solutions.</mission>
  <name>Safe Water International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/724</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">115</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">135.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ecw/u6KS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
