<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>As college students, we are about to face big problems when we graduate - from global warming to endangered species, from the escalating cost and declining quality of health care to the plight of the hungry and homeless.

Every campus has its share of apathy, but students care about these problems. And more than any other group of people, we have the time, the energy, the intelligence, the resources and the idealism to help solve them.

But will we?

After all, colleges and universities teach students to become effective doctors, lawyers, engineers, computer programmers, entrepreneurs, managers and the like. But they don't really teach us to become effective citizens. And effective citizenship is what it takes to shake up the status quo and get decision-makers to act on big social problems.

That's where the California Student Public Interest Research Group, or CALPIRG, comes in.

For 25 years, students who have been involved with their CALPIRG campus chapter have not only learned how to investigate a problem and come up with a practical solution. We've also learned how to convince the media and decision-makers to pay attention and take action.

In other words, through CALPIRG we gain an educational experience in democratic citizenship. In addition, we get a chance to face up to society's big problems, take action, and win concrete changes that improve the quality of our lives.

In just the past year we've worked to clean up the state's most polluted rivers, lakes, and beaches. We've also worked to clean up the state's dirtiest power plants, educated the community about genetically engineered foods, exposed consumer rip-offs, won more financial aid money to make college affordable, and raised thousands of dollars for the hungry and homeless.

1. Allowing students to work together and take action to make a difference.

2. Making leaders out of our student volunteers, by teaching them the skills they need.

3. Giving students the opportunity to volunteer and make a difference in their communities and across the nation.</description>
  <mission>Standing Up to Powerful Interests.</mission>
  <name>CALPIRG</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/792</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">381</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8O4/ZylS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
