<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Gluten Intolerance Group (GIG), founded in 1974, has helped people learn to live with gluten intolerance diseases. GIG has 1.5 paid staff and hundreds of volunteers assisting in education, awareness, and outreach programs. GIG works cooperatively with many other heath organizations to bring about change and support to improve the lives of persons with gluten intolerances. GIG is proactively involved in celiac awareness through our National Celiac Awareness Campaign, nationally and internationally; with the public and health community. GIG has a dietitian on staff that provides phone and individual consultations. GIG's goal is to provide medically-accurate resources and support to anyone interested in gluten intolerance and its associated disorders.

Gluten Intolerance Group's programs include a National Awareness Program in print and radio media; Education and Support through conferences, seminars and support group meetings; GIG Branches and Partner organizations give us the opportunity to serve more people on a local basis; education materials include a quarterly magazine, numerous fliers and education materials for patients, the public and health professionals; GIG Kids Camp Program is an integrated camp experience allowing children with gluten intolerance to have a normal camp experience without worry about their diet. GIG also supports research and advocates for issues that improve living with gluten intolerances. We provide an Annual Education Conference every year, including exhibitors and programs for clients and health professionals.

*Mission, Description, and Positions from www.gluten.net and Project Agape.

&lt;b&gt;Please donate if you can!  The minimum donation is $5.&lt;/b&gt;

1. People with celiac disease must lead healthy lives.

2. People must be aware of celiac disease because it is severely under diagnosed and mimics several other diseases.</description>
  <mission>GIG of N. America&#174; provides support to persons with gluten intolerances, including celiac disease, dermatitis herpetiformis, and other gluten sensitivities, in order to live healthy lives.</mission>
  <name>Celiac Disease Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/800</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">22125</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1906.61</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eB/l5/fW/hL/bm/OQ/3JUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
