<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Alzheimer's Association of Greater Cincinnati began in 1979 as a family support group for caregivers, relatives and friends of individuals with Alzheimer's disease. We became affiliated with the national Alzheimer's Association in 1980 and now serve a 27-county area in southern Ohio, northern Kentucky, and southeastern Indiana. It is estimated that there are more than 40,000 individuals with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder within our chapter territory.

Chapter programs and services include a professionally staffed Helpline, a family support group network, educational programs for individuals with Alzheimer&#8217;s disease and their families, supportive counseling and care planning services for families, educational programs for health care professionals, a multimedia reference library, and a quarterly newsletter.

The Alzheimer's Association of Greater Cincinnati is a non-profit organization, not affiliated with United Way. Funding for programs and services is achieved through individual, foundation and corporate support, as well as special fundraising events. All services are provided without regard to race, age, color, religion, sex, disability, national origin or ancestry. Various programs and services are funded in part by the Ohio Department of Aging through the Council on Aging of Southwestern Ohio and the Area Agency on Aging, District 7.

1. With our aging population understanding dementia (including Alzheimer&#8217;s Disease) and preparing to live with and care for those with dementia is imperative.

2. The "Forgetting Project" film (being created by Cincinnati USA professionals and NKU students) is associated with the Alzheimer's Association of Greater Cincinnati.</description>
  <mission>Educate, research and prepare families for living with Alzheimer's Disease.</mission>
  <name>Alzheimer's Association of Greater Cincinnati</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/805</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">48</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bbb/U76S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
