<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Michihemp is the pro-industrial hemp campiagn for the state of Michigan.  Industrial Hemp is that little plant related to "marijuana" yet only contains 0.3% or less of THC.  This country was built on industrial hemp (guess what the Constitution is printed on) yet it is illegal to farm in the United States.  However, this country annually spends about $250 million importing ind. hemp products.

What will it mean for Michigan if industrial hemp was brought back to the farm? You know all those auto plants that are shutting down, and the thousands of people who have already lost their job and the thousands that will soon? Hemp can create a whole new industry and can bring workers back to work! For starters, Michigan farms would be a great place to grow hemp.  Industrial hemp is a hardy plant and would flourish in the fertile soil of Michigan.  Then someone is needed to transform the raw hemp into products such as plastic, paper, textile, building material, fuel. That's where those empty factories figure in.  Even the automobile industry could come back through industrial hemp!  If Henry Ford could make a car out of hemp in 1941 then we can do it again in the new millennium.  These hemp cars can even run on hemp fuel.   Finally, someone is needed to retail the hemp products and there is the basis for a new Michigan industry.  Michigan is in a budget crisis, drastic times call for drastic measures and industrial hemp can be an answer!

"Website": http://www.myspace.com/michiganhemp
E-mail: michiganhemp@yahoo.com

1. Industrial hemp is a miracle crop that can help the economy and the environment.

2. Michigan's citizens and government would profit if industrial hemp were grown in the state.

3. Industrial hemp is not the same as marijuana and should not be treated as such.</description>
  <mission>bring industrial hemp onto Michigan farms to help the economy and environment</mission>
  <name>Michihemp</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/831</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">114</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wqj/hpKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
