<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>" LIFE International is unique in that we view the global issues created by abortion as a mission field. The mission field created by abortion is enormous, impacting nearly every nation. The unborn are the largest hidden people group on earth, comprised of over 210 million conceived every year. They are also the largest persecuted people group on earth with over 46 million killed through abortion annually.

LIFE International is called to make a difference in response to the worldwide abortion epidemic, and in fulfilling the great commission. The 183 countries where abortion is being promoted are the very countries that LIFE is called to impact with the message of life. This vast mission field is virtually unaddressed, yet promises a rich reward in saved lives and reaching women and families for Christ.

Our clear vision is to establish pregnancy resource centers wherever abortion is provided worldwide. The primary purpose of these centers is to see people come to new life in Christ and to see pre-born lives saved from abortion. This is accomplished through the core components of providing pregnancy testing and counseling for women in crisis pregnancies, teaching the message of abstinence before marriage in the community, and ministering to post-abortive men and women. These overseas centers have become lighthouses of hope, truth, safety and life in their communities. The results have already been profound, and we are seeing the culture of cities being transformed."

1. Be pro-Jesus

2. Be Kingdom-driven

3. Pray before doing

4. Balance the mind and heart

5. Commit to long-term relationships

6. Be internationally focused

7. Come alongside nationals

8. Remain teachable</description>
  <mission>"We purpose to see lives saved physically and transformed spiritually through sharing the truth of God's Word and the redemptive message of Jesus Christ in the mission field by abortion."</mission>
  <name>Life International, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/850</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">456</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uVe/8DES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
