<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The mission of the SETI Institute is to explore, understand and explain the origin, nature and prevalence of life in the universe.

The SETI Institute is a private, nonprofit organization dedicated to scientific research, education and public outreach.

Founded in 1984, the Institute today employs over 100 scientists, educators and support staff. Research at the Institute is anchored by two centers. Dr. Jill Tarter leads the Center for SETI (Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence) Research as Bernard M. Oliver Chair for SETI.  Dr. Frank Drake is the Director for the Carl Sagan Center for the Study of Life in the Universe

Organization Status

The SETI Institute is a nonprofit corporation founded in 1984 (California Corporation #1261957). The Institute is a scientific and educational organization governed by the provisions of Section 501(c)(3) of the U.S. Internal Revenue Code, and the Institute's Federal identification number for reporting and tax purposes is 94-2951356.

All contributions to the Institute will be used to further the goals described above and are deductible to the donor for both State and Federal income tax purposes.

SOURCE: http://www.seti.org

** If you cannot donate, please join the SETI distributed computing network (SETI@home), which is a scientific experiment that uses  "Internet-connected computers in the Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI). You can participate by running a free program that downloads and analyzes radio telescope data." And it makes for a really cool screen saver.

Download it here FREE:

http://setiathome.berkeley.edu/index.php

1. Are we alone in the universe?</description>
  <mission>SETI, the Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence, is an exploratory science that seeks evidence of life in the universe by looking for some signature of its technology.</mission>
  <name>SETI The Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/851</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3659</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">126.16</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kfA/6jZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
