<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Their lives of Seth and Sherri Mandell were devastated on May 8, 2001, when their 13 year old son Koby was murdered by terrorists. Koby went hiking with his friend Yosef Ish Ran in a canyon near the Mandell's home. There, in a cave, Arab terrorists stoned the two boys to death. 

The Mandells, parents to 3 other younger children, knew that in order to go on, they needed to transform the cruelty of Koby's death into acts of kindness and hope. For that reason, they created the Koby Mandell Foundation which provides healing programs for families struck by terrorism.

Seth, a rabbi, and Sherri, an author and journalist, believe that the Jewish response to suffering is to live a fuller and more engaged life. Their programs help others who have suffered the trauma of loss overcome the isolation that keeps them from returning to life. Participants are helped to find meaning in their loss, so that families become stronger rather than weaker from their traumas. In this way, they keep Koby's spirit alive in the world.

Their programs include:
-Camp Koby
-Mothers' Healing Retreat
-Spiritual Healing Programs
-Womens Learning
-Big Brother/ Sister Program
-Family Healing Program
-Young Adult Encounter Project
-Friends Program

See: www.KobyMandell.org for more.

1. Instead of being destroyed by grief, families can become stronger and healthier.

2. Grief can destroy not just a family, but generations. There are ravaged societies that turn their pain into hate. But that is not the Jewish response.

3.  The terrorists will not win; a network of love and sharing is created in the wake of the terrorists' attempts to destroy the people of Israel.</description>
  <mission>Help bereaved families who have lost a parent, child or sibling to terror keep their hearts open and their spirits alive. </mission>
  <name>The Koby Mandell Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/853</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">701</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">75.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zeA/cYwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
