<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Some 2 billion people worldwide live in poverty housing. More than 1 billion live in urban slums, and that figure is expected to double by 2030. By working in partnership with low-income families to build decent homes they can afford to buy, Habitat helps to break the cycle of poverty and hopelessness.

Habitat for Humanity at the University of California, Davis is a small part of this goal and has been established to increase awareness about the need for affordable housing, raise funds for building Habitat homes and to build houses along side future Habitat homeowners.
	

Additionally, the chapter hopes to engage deeper into the community by mentoring kids of the families who move into the new houses and offer services at the local homeless shelters and food banks. By doing so, we advocate for an end to substandard housing and aspire to achieve a better understanding of problems faced within their community. 

Our dream goal is to raise enough funds to be able to fund our own Habitat house. To reach this goal, we will need the assistance of individuals and organizations like yourself and encourage you to donate so we can make this a reality!

1. Believes that every person deserves, at least, a simple and decent place in which to live and grow.

2. Builds or renovates houses in partnership with families who qualify for homeownership based on three criteria: need, a willingness to partner with HFH and an ability to repay a no-interest mortgage.

3. Works with people of all faiths and people of no faith.

4. Sells its houses at no profit, with no interest charged.</description>
  <mission>make affordable housing a matter of conscience</mission>
  <name>UCD Habitat for Humanity Dream House</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/879</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cGW/ogwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
