<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>From prostatecancerfoundation.org

&#8226; Prostate cancer is the most common non-skin cancer in America.
&#8226; In 2006, over 232,000 men will be diagnosed with prostate cancer, and over 30,000 men will die from it.
&#8226; One new case occurs every 2.5 minutes and a man dies from prostate cancer every 17 minutes.
&#8226; After lung cancer, prostate cancer is the leading cause of cancer-related deaths among men in the U.S.
&#8226; A nonsmoking man is more likely to get prostate cancer than lung, bronchus, colon, rectal, bladder, lymphoma, melanoma, oral and kidney cancers combined.
&#8226; African-American men are 65% more likely to be diagnosed with prostate cancer than Caucasian- Americans and are more than twice as likely to die from it.  The reasons for this disparity are not yet known.
&#8226; It is estimated that there are over 2 million American men currently living with prostate cancer.
&#8226; However, every year, 70,000 men require additional treatment due to a recurrence of prostate cancer.
&#8226; Because prostate cancer is a relatively slow-growing cancer, the 5-year survival rate for prostate cancer diagnosed at all stages is 98%.  The relative 10-year survival rate is 84% and the 15-year survival rate is 56%.
&#8226; The chance of having prostate cancer increases rapidly after age 50. More than 70% of all prostate cancers are diagnosed in men over the age of 65. It is still unclear why this increase with age occurs for prostate cancer.
&#8226; The only well-established risk factors for prostate cancer are age, ethnicity and family history of the disease; however, high dietary fat intake may also be a significant risk factor. A recent study shows that the risk of dying from prostate cancer increases with body weight.
&#8226; The Prostate Cancer Foundation has raised over $245 million.

1. Prostate Cancer Sucks

2. Let's help those who have it

3. Let's try and get rid of it</description>
  <mission>Support the research and fight against prostate cancer</mission>
  <name>Fight Prostate Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/899</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">66905</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">8300.22</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ygC/J8wS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
