<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Brian was born with a ventricular septal defect, a small hole between the left and right ventricles of the heart. Although Brian was active like any other child his age, his congenital heart defect made him more susceptible to infections. At five years old, one small cut would almost cost him his life. In 1980, Brian was admitted to Saint Joseph Hospital in Lexington, Kentucky. His small cut, the byproduct of a big-wheel accident, had become infected and soon traveled to his heart, resulting in a life-threatening condition known as bacterial endocarditis. Brian would spend the summer at Saint Joseph Hospital where physicians gave him no chance of recovery. However, Brian miraculously beat the odds and by summer&#8217;s end returned home a happy, healthy child. Brian liked this idea and in May of 1999, the Brian Littrell Healthy Heart Club for Kids was established. Offers education, exercise, nutrition, and counseling to children ages 8-12 who suffer from a heart condition or have a strong disposition towards developing heart disease. Membership into the club requires a physician&#8217;s referral based upon the child&#8217;s established medical need and is free to all participants. The program consists of eight-week sessions held on Saturday mornings. Began with two club sessions per year, but has grown steadily and is now facilitating four per year with over one hundred children graduating from the program thus far. The Coordinator, board members, and the Littrell family are developing a comprehensive health education program that will serve as a complete kit for each of the eight-week sessions. This comprehensive kit will include: videocassettes, instructional manuals, workbooks, instructional models, posters, promotional materials, and t-shirts (essentially, a club that can travel anywhere). The goal is to establish the Brian Littrell Healthy Heart Club for Kids on a national level with chapters throughout the country.  

1. Read below.</description>
  <mission>The Brian Littrell Healthy Heart Club for Kids&#174; will educate children and their families regarding the benefits of adopting a heart-healthy lifestyle. Through education, promotion and caring...</mission>
  <name>Healthy Heart Club (HHC)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/907</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1842</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.08</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GKb/XVaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
