<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This non-profit group is to promote a scholarship fund for students in the Delta Pi Chapter of Alpha Kappa Psi at Creighton University. 

The Scholarship will be called the Janelle Hornickel Scholarship after a member who passed away suddenly in 2005.

"On Jan. 4, 2005, Janelle Hornickel and her boyfriend, Michael Wamsley, both 20, were heading home to their apartment in Omaha, Neb., when they got caught in a snowstorm.

Over the course of the evening, the couple made a series of bizarre, frantic phone calls to 911, asking for help in finding their way home. 

At one point, Wamsley said they had come across hundreds of bystanders who didn't speak English. Hornickel said others were taking cars apart and putting them in the trees.

The couple also left their truck, which still had a half-tank of gas, warm clothes and Wamsley's cell phone. It was minus 10 degrees with the wind chill.

Wamsley's body was found the next day. Six days later, authorities found Hornickel's body. Both had frozen to death. She was a prominent member in both her sorority and her business fraternity Alpha Kappa Psi."

Our chapter has already raised over $500 and with your help we hope to raise the necessary $5,000 to officially launch the scholarship into action. It would be a tribute to her, her family, and the leaders who are part of our chapter every year! 

Thank you for your support and contribution! Make sure if you donate to mention our chapter fund!

PLEASE INVITE YOUR FRIENDS!!!


1. Knowledge &#8211; Education and experience, whether gained in the classroom or the workplace, is emphasized and shared

2. Integrity &#8211; All actions, whether in business or in life, are guided by honesty, ethics, and fairness

3. Service &#8211; Sharing of time, talent, and treasure with both communities and with our Fraternity is a priority

4. Unity &#8211; A common understanding of our vision and values that transcends chapter, generation, and profession is utilized to anticipate and create the future</description>
  <mission>To become the premier developer of principled business leaders</mission>
  <name>AKPsi Delta Pi Chapter Scholarship Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/922</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">27</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ccB/2J0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
