<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>ProNino is a non-profit 501(c)3 located in Honduras. After working last summer at ProNino, I realized that when it came to humanitarian service, this small orphanage of sorts was where I wanted to make this impact. - In the small town of San Pedro Sula, ProNino is devoted to housing, feeding, detoxifying, educating, and most importantly, loving the street children of Honduras who come to ProNino. These have undergone immense abuse, either from their families or from life on the streets. Many have drug addictions, such as sniffing glue. ProNino's goal is to bring these kids out of this world and to give them a new life. This is where my project steps in.
 Through a partnership with the University of Georgia's Agricultural Extension agents, we plan to build, plant, and farm a sustainable organic vegetable farm (1 acre) at the center. UGA's top agronomist, Bobby Wilson, is traveling with 20 others and I from June 24-July 5 to implement this farm. Additionally, all the fruits and vegetables planted are indigenous to Honduras, key to the environmental sustainability of the farm. -  This farm will not only provide key nutrients, important to bringing some of these children back to health, but the children will be growing the food themselves! The Ag. Extension staff of 15 agents come down on July 10 to train the staff in 4-H implementation. Each child will have his own area that he grows from with his name literally staked into the land with a sign. - By doing this, the children are returning to their native lifestyle, a lifestyle abandoned in the urban sprawl of San Pedro Sula and a lifestyle that connects the children to what is most important, their land. - This farm will return the native lifestyle, the health, and most importantly, the pride and dignity of these honorable children. Help me and support our cause (www.pronino.co.nr) or simply write me an email thanking us for all that we are doing (bendtracy@gmail.com). - Wish us luck!


1. The rehabilitation of street children needs your assistance.

2. A sustainable organic farm is a project to help street children.

3. Street children working on the farm to feed themselves will help them start their new life.</description>
  <mission>Build a sustainable organic vegetable farm for the children of the ProNino non-profit organization in a 12-day trip from June 24-July 5. </mission>
  <name>ProNino Farm Project 2007</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/960</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">74</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fTO/L01S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
