<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>With each member who joins this Facebook group United Way International will receive a $1 match up to $2000.00 to aid victims of the China and Myanmar natural disasters in long term recovery efforts.

The powerful earthquake and its aftershocks in China&#8217;s Sichuan Province on May 12th along with the destructive cyclone in Myanmar on May 2nd have left communities in distress and people in great need. United Way International is responding to this natural disaster by opening the Asia Disaster Recovery Fund which will help support long term recovery and construction efforts in Myanmar and China.  

With each member who joins this cause United Way International hopes to create more awareness to aid victims of the China and Myanmar natural disasters in long term recovery efforts. Please consider making a contribution through this cause or via our website (www.uwint.org). 

Why long term recovery? Once short term disaster relief organizations have played their part, United Way&#8217;s work is critical in helping communities get back on their feet. United Way stays involved at the local level to provide continued assistance to victims, their families, and communities. By opening a fund for long term recovery now while public awareness is at its highest point, we can raise much needed funding which will be crucial in our ability to help sustain efforts of reconstruction for years to come. Then once the media spotlight fades, United Way is still able to continue our work and help make sure the people in need are not forgotten.

An example of this has been seen with our response to the tragic South Asia Tsunami in 2004. United Way International mobilized its world wide network to leverage funds and aid in India, Indonesia and Thailand. After careful assessment by members on the ground as well as international support staff, the following are few examples of the type of projects United Way International undertook:


 
Community Infrastructure Rebuilding, Livelihood Restoration, and Medical Care in:
	 
Samsung Community Center - Thailand
Yayasan Mitra Mandiri's Project - Indonesia
	
School Construction

United Way Lake County Auditorium - India
Samsung United Way "School of Hope" - India
Aceh School Building Project - Indonesia

Housing Construction

AIG 100 Homes for Tsunami Victims - India
United Way International &amp; United Way Mumbai "Rebuilding Together" - India



Find this information and more at:
http://www.uwint.org
http://www.unitedway.org

1. Change should be brought about through the power of local community involvement.

2. International relief comes through working with local leaders and strengthening local NGO's. 

3. Self-sufficiency is a key addition to core strength, especially when in crisis.</description>
  <mission>Helping build community capacity for a better quality of life worldwide through voluntary giving and action.</mission>
  <name>China and Myanmar Long Term Disaster Recovery </name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/963</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">400</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">145.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/o3/4D/aX/uM/Sg/wp/RB/f0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
