<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>READY TO GO DEEPER?

Blood:Water Mission is partnering with groups and individuals to empower Africans to build healthier communities through sustainable clean blood and clean water solutions, while developing social responsibility in the U.S. through initiatives that provoke personal engagement and ownership.



    $1 = ONE YEAR OF WATER FOR AN AFRICAN
    YOUR ONE DOLLAR WILL SAVE A LIFE



1000 Wells Project

    * Did you know that millions of Africans lack access to clean water?

    * Did you know that people living with HIV/AIDS are dependent on clean water to survive?

    * Did you know that $1 provides one year of clean water for an African?


Did you know that YOU can help save lives?

The 1000 Wells Project is building 1000 wells and clean water projects in 1000 African communities. Businesses, churches, schools, artists and individuals are collecting funds so they can sponsor the construction of wells in Africa. In the process, they are learning about how HIV/AIDS affects African communities, and what it means to partner humbly with communities to pursue transformation.

And we're doing it by asking for $1 from each person. It's that simple.


HOW CAN YOU HELP?

Visit:
http://www.bloodwatermission.com

Watch this short video:
http://www.bloodwatermission.com/bloodwater.mov

    * Check out Run A Campaign for ideas

    * Consider participating in 2 Weeks of Sacrifice

    * Read Stories from people here in the U.S. as well as in Africa

    * Check our Blog for weekly news and updates
http://blog.bloodwatermission.com

Your participation will give Africans the gift of clean water to protect them from life-threatening illnesses. Women and children will no longer walk up to 10 miles a day to get water. People with HIV will live stronger, longer lives. Communities will flourish and be changed. We know that you, too, will be changed by connecting with the people in Africa. Your partnership can help save lives.


1. Blood and water free from disease has the power to transform lives.

2. It is inexcusable that people die because they don't have access to clean water and basic health care.

3. Where you are born should not decide whether you live or whether you die.</description>
  <mission> Blood:Water Mission is a grassroots organization that empowers communities to work together against the HIV/AIDS and water crises in Africa.</mission>
  <name>Blood:Water Mission</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/968</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">30067</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">24015.86</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Tf/tM/oX/N2/Ba/YG/bn/mlS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
