<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The North Carolina Missions of Mercy (NC MOM) portable free dental program is a branch of the Open Door Dental Clinic of Alamance County, a 501(c)(3) free dental clinic begun in 1998. The NC MOM is entirely a grassroots effort, dependent on an all volunteer staff, members of which donate their time and talents tirelessly for various personal reasons and motivations, with funding from grants and donations. The services rendered include extractions, fillings, cleanings, and various minor services. During this past year the program received national and statewide recognition with an article in the American Dental Association newsletter, a national award from USA Today Weekend Magazine, and a prestigious award from the NC Association of Free Clinics. 
As the program is all volunteer, there are no personnel expenses. As the clinics are held in areas provided by the hosting organizations, there are no facility expenses. As the majority of the supplies are obtained free of charge from dental supply dealers, there are minimal supply expenses. Therefore, the program funding needs are very modest relative to an organization of this magnitude, and is dependent on grants, donations, and gifts. 



1. To provide free dental care to as many needy persons within North Carolina as is possible.

2. To educate persons in teeth, mouth, and all over health to prevent disease and death caused by infections in the mouth.

3. To involve as much of the dental community of the state in the treatment of the needy as is possible</description>
  <mission>provide free dental services to those persons in financial need with few or no other options.  </mission>
  <name>NC Missions of Mercy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/973</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">21</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/52Z/tZsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
