<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>(For more information, please visit www.housingopt.org)

Housing Options is a 501(c)(3) organization founded in 1988.  The organization provides affordable housing and health support to adults recovering from chronic mental illnesses.  For nearly 20 years Housing Options has provided permanent and transitional housing and support to more than 130 individuals, 50 of whom were homeless.  Housing Options is one of the few organizations that offers a long-term solution to homelessness and an alternative to unnecessary institutionalization for individuals with chronic mental illnesses.

Participants receive professional services from the agency&#8217;s team of social workers, counselors, case managers, psychiatrists, and a nurse, as well as a fully furnished apartment with all utilities included. Each year, the agency provides more than 20,000 days and nights of affordable housing and 10,000 hours of social work and mental health services.  Since its inception, the agency has purchased six apartment buildings and leased additional scattered-site apartments. 


1. People recovering from mental illnesses should live in an environment that enables full realization of individual potential.

2. People recovering from mental illnesses should have the opportunity to enjoy and participate in the full range of community life.

3. People recovering from mental illnesses have a right to make life choices within the same parameters as all members of the community.

4. Differences among people are a source of strength for the community.</description>
  <mission>To develop housing options for adults recovering from mental illnesses, provide support services promoting independence, advance understanding of mental illnesses and the need for supportive housing.</mission>
  <name>Housing Options</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/974</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Gwx/dOUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
