<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Please visit http://www.mlkmemorial.org/

Dr. King championed a movement that draws fully from the deep well of America's potential for freedom, opportunity, and justice. His vision of America is captured in his message of hope and possibility for a future anchored in dignity, sensitivity, and mutual respect; a message that challenges each of us to recognize that America's true strength lies in its diversity of talents. The vision of a memorial in honor of Martin Luther King, Jr. is one that captures the essence of his message, a message in which he so eloquently affirms the commanding tenants of the American Dream &#8212; Freedom, Democracy and Opportunity for All; a noble quest that gained him the Nobel Peace Prize and one that continues to influence people and societies throughout the world. Upon reflection, we are reminded that Dr. King's lifelong dedication to the idea of achieving human dignity through global relationships of well being has served to instill a broader and deeper sense of duty within each of us&#8212; a duty to be both responsible citizens and conscientious stewards of freedom and democracy.
If you do not feel comfortable donating through this group(cause) please visit the official website for more information. http://www.mlkmemorial.org/

Support the Dream if you make a $5 donation today and receive your official memorial wrist band. http://www.mlkmemorial.org/




1. A stage to honor his national and international contributions to humankind

2. Acknowledging his unbridled teachings for achieving social change through non-violent methods

3. The Memorial will remind the world of his dedication to the idea of achieving human dignity through global relationships, and instill a sense of duty within each of us to be responsible citizens and conscientious stewards of freedom and democracy.</description>
  <mission>to commemorate life/work of Dr. King by leading a collaborative funding &amp; construction process in the creation of a memorial to honor his contributions to world peace through non-violent social change</mission>
  <name>MARTIN LUTHER KING JR NATL MEM PROJECT</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/982</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">675</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">261.3</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/M76/Lg2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
