<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Arctic National Wildlife Reserve (ANWR) is one of the most ecologically diverse regions in the world. Over 19 million acres is the habitat of Sea Otters, Wolves, Bears, Birds, Whales, and many more animals. Also, the native Gwich'in settlement living off the land and the Porcupine River Caribou herd make the ANWR their home. 

In the past few decades, oil drilling has brought money to the people of Alaska, but has caused great stress on the environment. As one of the last untouched places on Earth, many are trying to save the ANWR from future oil spills, which are inevitable if oil drilling continues. Modern technology has just not advanced enough to make oil spills impossible. 

George W. Bush is fighting to drill in the ANWR and claims the drilling is in a small area that will not affect the Caribou. However, the Caribou studies that have been done to show oil drilling does not affect them were on the Central Caribou herd. The Central herd is much smaller than the Porcupine herd, which ranges over 2,000 Caribou. Also, the Porcupine herd is the main food source for the Gwich'in, and drilling upsets the migratory routes of the Caribou which directly affects the hunting of the Gwich'in. Bush wants to drill where the breeding ground of the Porcupine herd is. It provides protection from predators and biting bugs, with plenty of food for the mothers and newborns. Studies have been shown that even a 5% decrease in the number of Caribou will harm the population. If the Caribou were forced to retreat their breeding ground to the mountains, there would be less chance of survival for the Caribou, and thus the Gwich'in.

When the reserve was made in the 80's, its purpose was to protect the immense amount of amazing wildlife that thrives in the harsh conditions of the Arctic. Now, that protection is being threatened and the reserve will cease to be what it should be: a reserve.

1. Keep the Wildlife wild.

2. Protect the Porcupine River Caribou herd and the Gwich'in.

3. Create awareness of the harm oil spills cause</description>
  <mission>Stop present and prevent future oil drilling in the ANWR</mission>
  <name>Arctic National Wildlife Reserve</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/983</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3077</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">225.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4GY/CmrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
