<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;b&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Help Pass the DC Voting Rights Act!&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DC residents pay federal income taxes, serve on juries and die in wars to defend American democracy but are denied a vote in Congress. As we work to extend democracy around the world, &lt;b&gt;the time has come to bring democracy to our nation's capital&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, April 19, 2007, the &lt;a href="http://www.dcvote.org/advocacy/dcvramain.cfm" target="new"&gt;DC Voting Rights Act (H.R. 1905)&lt;/a&gt; passed the House of Representatives 241-177. This is the first time in a generation that the House has passed a bill that works toward bringing voting representation to the nearly 600,000 Americans living in the nation's capital. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 1, 2007, Senators Joe Lieberman (I-CT), Orrin Hatch (R-UT) and Bob Bennett (R-UT) introduced the DC House Voting Rights Act (S. 1257) in the Senate. A hearing on the new Senate bill was held in the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee on May 15, 2007. Chairman Lieberman announced his intentions to mark-up the bill in early June 2007. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dcvote.org/" target="new"&gt;DC Vote&lt;/a&gt; works closely with members of Congress, committee staff, local elected officials and coalition partners on the DC Voting Rights Act, the bipartisan consensus bill sponsored in the House by Representative Tom Davis (R-VA) and Delegate Eleanor Holmes Norton (D-DC).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We urge you to &lt;a href="http://www.dcvote.org/advocacy/alerts.cfm" target="new"&gt;support the DC Voting Rights Act (H.R. 328)&lt;/a&gt; by writing or calling your representative, writing letters to your local papers and volunteering in DC Vote's upcoming events. Remember to &lt;a href="http://www.congressweb.com/cweb4/index.cfm?orgcode=dcv&amp;amp;hotissue=3" target="new"&gt;contact your senator&lt;/a&gt; and demand the vote! Learn more at &lt;a href="http://www.dcvote.org" target="new"&gt;dcvote.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


1. Residents of the District of Columbia deserve full voting representation in Congress.

2. Voting representation in the House can be achieved through the passage of the DC Voting Rights Act.</description>
  <mission>To ensure full voting representation for the residents of the District of Columbia through the passage of the DC Voting Rights Act.</mission>
  <name>DC Voting Rights</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/99</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3122</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">120.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SsR/ytUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
