<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Jewish Council for Public Affairs (JCPA) is the national umbrealla organization for Jewish organizations engaged in public policy work.  Our members include 14 national organizaitons and 125 local community relations councils.  We are charged with building concensus on public policy and community relations issues in the Jewish community and coordinating our community's advocacy and activism.  

Our National Members include:
American Jewish Committee
American Jewish Congress
Anti-Defamation League
B&#8217;nai B'rith
Hadassah
Jewish Labor Committee
Jewish Reconstructionist Federation
Jewish War Veterans
National Council of Jewish Women
Union for Reform Judaism
Union of Orthodox Jewish Congregations of America
United Synagogue of Conservative Judaism
Women's American ORT
Women's League for Conservative Judaism


Below is just a small taste of what we do.  Over the past 50 years, JCPA has developed deep policy expertise and a wide range of positions.  The positions listed is just a small piece of our work.  They also are listed in no particular order.  If you are interested in our full list of policy positions check out our website, www.jewishpublicaffairs.org

Also check out our facebook groups.

JCPA WORKS TO SAVE DARFUR
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2259214654

JCPA FOR STEM CELL RESEARCH
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2262933595

JCPA FOR CIVIL RIGHTS
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2256573375

JCPA CONFRONTING POVERTY
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2256863807

JCPA SUPPORTS ISRAEL
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2257135334

JCPA SAYS NO TO TORTURE
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2257754730

JCPA WORKS TO PREVENT A NUCLEAR IRAN
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2261365646

1. A strong, stable, independent and peaceful Israel

2. A respectful, tolerant and pluralistic United States

3. Promote Religious Liberty

4. Promote Civil Rights and Civil Liberties

5. Quality, affordable healthcare for all Americans

6. Quality public education for all Americans

7. An end to the genocide in Darfur

8. United States leadership in the Global community

9. Seperation of Government and Religion in the United States

10. An absolute end to United States sponsored Torture and secret detentions</description>
  <mission>To safeguard the rights of Jews throughout the world, and to protect, preserve, and promote a just society.</mission>
  <name>Jewish Council for Public Affairs</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1000</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">123</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vne/TmoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
