<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Current reports indicate that between 1 and 4 million women are assaulted by an intimate each year. Domestic violence crosses ethnic, racial, generational, sexual orientation, religious and socioeconomic lines -- nearly one in three women will experience at least one physical assault by their partner in their lifetime. When left untreated, domestic violence ...

-	Is the single largest cause of injury to women in the United States, more common than automobile accidents, muggings and rapes combined

-	Involves half of all adult women as victims, more than once

-	Is responsible for more than one-third of all female murder victims

-	Touches one-fourth of all American families

In addition, violence in the home infects our communities by perpetuating social ills such as alcoholism, drug addiction, juvenile delinquency, suicide and runaway children. The effect on our community is devastating

Throughout our history, CAWC has relied on the support of a loyal group of individual volunteers and donors. Truly, none of our accomplishments would be possible without the help of the community.

You can also provide essential support to women and children who are victims of domestic violence by:

-	Making a donation to CAWC.

-	Having a casual day at your office. Charge a nominal fee per employee and donate the proceeds to CAWC/Greenhouse.

-	Engaging the support of your business, family, church or organization in CAWC's work to support women and children who are victims of domestic violence.

1. No one deserves to be in an abusive relationship</description>
  <mission>CAWC is committed to ending domestic violence. </mission>
  <name>Chicago Abused Women Coalition</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1001</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">107</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zH7/EzYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
