<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Friends of Sudan is a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization which aims to help the people of  the South Sudan region recover from 22 years of destructive civil war. 

The Friends of Sudan gained momentum and was inspired by the stories of a group of men who experienced this war first hand. They have been given the name 'The Lost Boys of Sudan'. If you are interested in learning more about the history behind Friends of Sudan, visit: www.lostboysofsudan.com 

Goals for the Friends of Sudan include the building of medical facilities, the establishment of schools, and improving the current standard of living for the residents of South Sudan.

Currently, a well is being drilled in the village of Tot, and planning has begun for the area's first school to be chartered. Help support these projects!

To clear up some confusion, our listed beneficiary, Congressional District Programs, is simply the oversight organization that handles the administrative tasks of Friends of Sudan. Friends of Sudan is one of their subsidiary non-profits. When you give via Facebook, the breakdown for donations is as follows:

92.5% to Friends of Sudan
6% to Congressional District Programs (administrative costs)
1.5% to Facebook (service fee)

The 6% to Congressional District Programs is a standard cost for Friends of Sudan, and is paid no matter how donors give.

Thanks for considering making a gift to Friends of Sudan!

1. Enhancing health standards: building medical facilities

2. Improving literacy rates: building schools

3. Increasing the current standard of living: digging wells

4. Raising funds and awareness

5. Spreading the love and good news of Jesus Christ</description>
  <mission>Providing aid to the Sudanese region of South Sudan</mission>
  <name>Friends of Sudan</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1003</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">451</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">635.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pB/D7/Fp/Ch/dD/w3/Pb/bdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
