<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;object width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/9Wwi87drDKk&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/9Wwi87drDKk&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;




Neuroblastoma is a solid tumor or cancer. It occurs in the immature cells, called neuroblasts, of the sympathetic nervous system. The sympathetic nervous system is responsible for involuntary actions of the body, such as blushing, increasing heart rate, and dilating the pupils of the eye.
 The disease often spreads from its "primary" location to the chest, bones and bone marrow. In fact, in most cases the disease has already spread at the time of diagnosis.There are approximately 650 new cases in the US annually. This represents 7.5% of all childhood cancers. It is most commonly diagnosed between 17 months and 2 years of age.

Facts on Neuroblastoma

Less than 4% of funds raised by the American Cancer Society go toward pediatric cancer research &#8211; and less than 10% of that will go to neuroblastoma research. That is approximately $0.40 (yes, 40 cents) for every $100.00 trickle down to NB research.

Childhood cancer kills more children per year than cystic fibrosis, muscular dystrophy, asthma, and AIDS combined.

There are 15 children diagnosed with cancer for every one child diagnosed with pediatric AIDS and yet the U.S. invests approximately $595,000 for research per victim of pediatric AIDS and only $20,000 for each victim of childhood cancer

Each year in the U.S. ~12,500 children (about 1 in 330) and adolescents are diagnosed with cancer. That is about 46 kids (2 class rooms) every day of the school year. 

Only 600-700 of these cases will be neuroblastoma (NB). But NB is the most common cancer found in infants &#8211; almost double that of leukemia &#8211; and the most common solid tumor found in children, second only to brain tumors. There is a &lt;40% chance of survival if there is evidence of metastasis at diagnosis.

The NCI federal budget for 2003 was $4.6 billion. Of that, breast cancer received 12%, prostate cancer received 7%, and all 12 major groups of pediatric cancers combined received less than 3%.


1. Raise awareness</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness and research</mission>
  <name>Fighting Neuroblastoma</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1005</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26068</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">6379.77</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ci/Qc/ie/tj/Fj/6p/DS/EyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
