<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Cabrini Partnership founded in 1987 and is a nonprofit organization licensed by Hennepin County to provide housing and comprehensive support services to adults diagnosed with mental illness and/or chemical dependency disabilities (80% of our residents are dually diagnosed) and have subsequently experienced long-term homelessness. Set in a quiet residential neighborhood in Southeast Minneapolis, the Cabrini Partnership transitional house provides housing and supportive services for up to two years in a setting that facilitates increased self-sufficiency for individuals with chemical dependency and mental illness. Cabrini Partnership also provides permanent supportive housing for individuals who are persistently mentally ill and who need a safety net of support. These residents include individuals who previously had lived in the Cabrini Transitional Housing Program, as well as long-term homeless adults and families who come directly from &#8220;the street&#8221; or emergency shelters. Through transitional housing and permanent supportive housing, we serve an average of over 100 people each year, 63 at a time. The number of people we serve is growing as we add to our permanent supportive housing program. The number of people we serve grows each year. Our success is evidenced when our clients acquire the skills, find the supports and gain the confidence they need to manage living as independent adults." http://www.cabrinipartnership.org/

1. Accountability, compassion, connection, courage, dignity, faith and respect represent our core values. 

2. Consistent support, realistic goal setting, respect for and faith in our clients. 

3. There are no shortcuts; rather Cabrini Partnership expects hard work and commitment from each resident and tenant.</description>
  <mission>Cabrini Partnership provides housing and services to support homeless adults with mental illness and chemical dependency to strengthen their lives, families and community.</mission>
  <name>Cabrini Partnership</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1007</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">18</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">60.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qv/Fw/AN/xI/E0/8V/0j/nLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
