<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Company:
As we move into a new phase in our history, we seek to create an environment that allows artists to reach their greatest potential. With a fundamental base in the classical form, we encourage talented and passionate dancers to move beyond the confines of technique to explore the fragility, power and incredible breadth of the human form. We nurture the development of choreography that transcends and defies categorization to reach directly to the soul. We believe that movement is at the root of our existence and dance should be shared with audience members in profound and transformative ways, whether they are first time viewers or ardent dance lovers.

The School:
Our school provides exceptional dance training that is rooted in a ballet syllabus that uses the best of the French, English and Italian methods. We train students of all ages, abilities and aspirations, developing versatile and kinesthetically healthy dancers. We support and care about our students, challenging and helping them reach their technical and artistic potential and individual goals. Our teachers share a passion for our mission, and we provide a variety of performing opportunities for students of all ages.

Outreach:
Our outreach programming brings exceptional, top-quality arts experiences to our community at little or no cost to participants. Outreach programming is based on established best practices and research, reaches a diverse audience of underserved individuals, including a significant number of public school students, and is regularly measured and evaluated to ensure its effectiveness. Signature programs include Title I elementary school partnerships and the Ugly Duckling Anti-Bullying Program.


1. Give all people in Colorado access to the arts regardless of age, skill, race, financial position.

2. Arts in our schools help our students learn basic skills.

3. We provide conservatory level training at an affordable, below market price.</description>
  <mission>&#8220;With passion, integrity and artistic excellence, we create inspiring, life-changing experiences through dance."</mission>
  <name>Ballet Nouveau Colorado</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1009</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">66</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DIX/ApQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
