<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.dil.org 

The Developments in Literacy organization (DIL) is a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization launched in February 1997 in Southern California. Its main purpose is to work for the eradication of illiteracy, in the remote and neglected areas of Pakistan, by establishing primary and secondary level non-formal schools for underprivileged children, primarily girls. DIL schools educate students using a broad curriculum that covers a wide variety of subjects.

DIL, a nonprofit, voluntary organization has succeeded, in a period of five years, at establishing 200 schools.  

DIL currently has offices in Los Angeles, Toronto, and Islamabad and chapter-boards in Los Angeles, New York, San Francisco, Washington, Houston, San Diego, Toronto, Ottawa and Singapore.

Youth Outreach, Developments in Literacy (YOUR DIL) is an initiative aimed at promoting awareness and encouraging support for DIL's objectives amongst a younger generation.

Contact Info:
Developments in Literacy  
12062 Valley View Street, Suite 218 
Garden Grove, CA 92845 
USA

Tel  714-895-5345 
Fax 714-895-6345 
Email:  office@dil.org



1. In Pakistan, more than 100 million people are illiterate.

2. Less than 50% of the population over age 15 able to read and write. 

3. Literacy is even lower amongst women - only 30% of women over age 15 are able to read and write.

4. The galloping population growth, which is the direct result of illiteracy, lack of awareness of civil and political rights, and inadequate government </description>
  <mission>promote literacy in the rural, underdeveloped areas of Pakistan</mission>
  <name>DIL - Developments in Literacy - www.dil.org</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1017</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1574</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5r/6u/QA/Wx/Jy/cX/uF/HYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
