<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Listen to the song Where is the love? by the Black Eyed Peas. Think about it.  Make the world a better place. : )

But if you only have love for your own race
Then you only leave space to discriminate
And to discriminate only generates hate
And if you hatin you're bound to get irate
Yeah madness is what you demonstrate
And that's exactly how anger works and operates
You gotta have love just to set it straight
Take control of your mind and meditate 
Let your soul gravitate to the love y'all

It just ain't the same all ways have changed
New days are strange is the world the insane?
If love and peace so strong
Why are there pieces of love that don't belong
Nations dropping bombs
Chemical gases filling lungs of little ones
With ongoing suffering
As the youth die young
So ask yourself is the loving really strong?
So I can ask myself really what is going wrong
With this world that we living in 
People keep on giving in
Makin wrong decisions 
Only visions of them livin and
Not respecting each other
Deny thy brother
The wars' going on but the reasons' undercover
The truth is kept secret
Swept under the rug
If you never know truth 
Then you never know love 

Most of us only care about money makin
Selfishness got us followin the wrong direction
Wrong information always shown by the media
Negative images is the main criteria
Infecting their young minds faster than bacteria
Kids wanna act like what the see in the cinema
Whatever happened to the values of humanity
Whatever happened to the fairness and equality
Instead of spreading love, we're spreading anomosity
Lack of understanding, leading us away from unity
That's the reason why sometimes I'm feeling under
That's the reason why sometimes I'm feeling down
It's no wonder why sometimes I'm feeling under
I gotta keep my faith alive, until love is found


1. If you never know truth, you never know love.

2. If you are hating, you are bound to get irate.

3. Humanity, equality, and love.</description>
  <mission>Spread the love.</mission>
  <name>Where is the love?</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1041</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">345</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/YCl/ey8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
