<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Len Duong International Vietnamese Youth Network (Vietnamese: M&#7841;ng L&#432;&#7899;i Tu&#7893;i Tr&#7867; Vi&#7879;t Nam L&#234;n &#208;&#432;&#7901;ng) is an international non-profit network comprised of Vietnamese student and youth organizations for the purpose of networking as well as philanthropic and political work related to the Vietnamese youth. Bloc 8406 is the group for which the Raise Your Voice campaign is taking measures in awareness.

What is Bloc 8406?

Bloc 8406 is a political group advocating democracy in Vietnam through non-violent means. On April 8, 2006, 118 Vietnamese citizens signed a Manifesto for Freedom and Democracy. This historic Manifesto has since attracted the public support of thousands in Vietnam and launched the Bloc 8406 democracy movement, named after the date of the document.

The manifesto goals are to reestablish fundamental rights for the Vietnamese People and are listed in this cause's positions list.


--------------------------------------------

Did you know what $1 is worth to a human rights activist? 
1 Minute international call to report human rights violations to news agencies.
3 hours of internet usage to write emails and publish photos of human rights abuses on the internet. 
8 pens to write down human rights abuses. 
3000 pages to write down human rights violations.



1. Freedom of speech in accordance with the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights

2. Freedom of meeting, of creating associations and political parties, and voting in and running for electionsin accordance with the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights.

3. Freedom to organize trade unions and legitimate strikes in accordance with the International Covenant on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights.</description>
  <mission>To promote awareness on human rights abuse in Viet Nam.</mission>
  <name>Raise Your Voice: Youth for Human Rights</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1044</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">79</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/08Y/bceS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
