<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Mission of the Alpha Epsilon Pi Foundation, Inc. is to promote the ideals and values of the Alpha Epsilon Pi Fraternity through leadership development; to partner with educational and Jewish communal organizations; and to provide scholarships, financial support and programming for the betterment of our brothers and our community.

Our Objectives are:

-Promote and encourage conduct and ideals consistent with Fraternity's values and Jewish traditions;
-Develop a fundraising program that meets the Mission;
-Support programs for alumni involvement and development;
-Recognize academic, campus and community achievement among our brothers; 
-Encourage training for Jewish communal services; -Create and support educational projects;
-Partnership with College and Universities as well as Jewish educational organizations; 
-Support Fraternity projects including chapter libraries, study rooms in chapter houses,
educational facilities for chapters; 
-Enable programs that enhance leadership development within the North American Jewish community; 
-Participate in programs of Interfraternity interest and education;
-Develop partnerships with other North American Jewish organizations; 
-Participate in programs related to Israel and the Diaspora; 
-Assist brothers in need through a "benevolent brothers" program;

1. Alpha Epsilon Pi is the only National Jewish Fraternity.

2. Alpha Epsilon Pi's aims and ideals are supportive of the Jewish community, those in need and our brothers.

3. Alpha Epsilon Pi serves a crucial role in the Jewish community through its' public service, charity and tikkun olam.</description>
  <mission>to promote the ideals and values of the Alpha Epsilon Pi Fraternity</mission>
  <name>Alpha Epsilon Pi Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1053</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">980</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">258.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hJz/kc7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
