<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The importance of high quality private schooling in South Africa is critical. This, coupled with the need to imbue our children with strong Jewish values has convinced more and more Jewish parents to consider KD, whether or not they can afford it. As community schools, we must make provision to assist Jewish learners whose parents cannot afford the fees. Currently just under 10% of full paid school fees are allocated to a subsidy fund that affords over 500 children the opportunity to attend our very special schools. However, we cannot continue to rely solely on tuition fees from full-fee payign parents to fund our subsidy programme, educational advancement and infrastrustural improvement. We therefore need to secure ongoing financial independence and sustainability - and we are launching a new campaign called "Dor le Dor" in which we aim to build an endowment fund. Capital growth and income generated from the endowment fund will be applied to 1. Continuation of our subsidy programme 2. Enhaced development of our teaching programme 3. Expansion of our learning programme 4. Improvement of our infrastructure 5. Support of our Outreach programme.
We aim to raise an initial R100m for the Endowment Fund. Any contributions to this fund are valued. All donations made in South Africa are eleigible for Section 18a tax certificates. Donations made in the US are also eligible for tax certificates if made through the American Friends of South African Jewish Education (AFSAJE) or EuroChai. For more information please write to info@kdsf.org 

1. Reconnect and involve KD alumni

2. Raise funds for the sustainability of the KD schools

3. Ensure that Jewish children whose parents cannot afford to educate them at KD are given the opportunity to benefit from a KD education</description>
  <mission>Reconnect King David alumni and ensure the sustainability of the King David Schools</mission>
  <name>King David Schools Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1058</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">36</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1880.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ys/Js/Ji/7i/yj/Ya/ND/FDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
