<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Art Party is the burgeoning political party that&#8217;s also a PARTY!  We are a non-profit organization interested in global change through art and community.  The Art Party follows seven tenets:
1! Stay up late making art for hours. 
2! Explore, explore, explore. If you are not learning, you are not living.
3! Document your existence through art, poetry, photography, music, anything. Make your mark. 
4! Respect and offer constructive criticism. 
5! Respect the greatest work of art of all: our world. Gather in parks and forests, and embrace nature and one another. 
6! Love all you can. 
7! Create. Collaborate. Connect. Communicate. 

We believe in love, peace, equality, freedom, and the power of art.  We recognize that an individual can make a difference, but that a group of individuals can make an impact. We invite anyone and everyone to join our cause and help build a community with us -- change is coming! To join, email us at crayonsnotbombs@gmail.com or visit our website at http://doy.dreamomens.com/Art  ...the Art Party believes in you...

Please remember, the Art Party DOES NOT WANT YOUR MONEY. If you choose to donate to this cause, you are supporting Art Party members &lt;a href="http://ourownvoice.org/"&gt;Our Own Voice Theatre Troupe&lt;/a&gt;. Based in Memphis, Tennessee, OOV is a nonprofit organization dedicated to community awareness of mental health and social issues, who "use the theatre as a forum for exploring issues that affect the psychological and social well-being of all of us."

Also check out the &lt;a href="http://loyno.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2218766928"&gt;official Art Party facebook group&lt;/a&gt;.

1. Every person deserves equal rights.

2. Every person is responsible for his/her community, but is mostly responsible for him/herself--the highest authority.

3. Every person is an artist; within you is the Revolution.</description>
  <mission>support art and revolution through the Art Party.</mission>
  <name>ART!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1074</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4745</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Pn1/ikLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
