<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Delaware Shakespeare Festival is the only professional Shakespeare Festival bringing classical theatre to our friends in Delaware. Our efforts include:

Annual Summer Festival - 
The flagship of all our cultural initiatives, the Festival is held over three weeks in the summer on the lush grounds of Rockwood Mansion Park. Audience members pack a picnic and bring their family and friends to experience the outdoor professional theatre that has been called, &#8220;Winning theatre with a generous sense of humor.&#8221;   Beyond the main-stage production, other elements of the experience include the comedic pre-show, show orientation, live minstrels and children&#8217;s corner.

In-House Seminar - 
Too often, members of the general public build a resistance to Shakespeare because they experienced an initial difficulty comprehending the language or feel detached from the classic works. This seminar seeks to increase interest in classical literature, to remove the &#8220;Shakespearean&#8221; language barrier, and expose participants to the richness of Shakespeare&#8217;s text and the vast potential for literary analysis and language interpretation therein. 

Summer Intensive and Internship -
Professional actors will lead high school interns in Acting, Voice, Shakespeare Text and Performance classes as well as an abridged version of one of Shakespeare&#8217;s works.  Then the students will become interns with the professional company as a part of the main-stage production where they will be educated in all aspects of how a professional Shakespeare Festival Production runs.

College Apprenticeship -
These apprentices will be able to gain experience and practical application of their education and art form in a professional setting.  These apprentices will assist on various area of the main-stage production, from marketing to technical aspects building their resume by working with a professional company even before graduation.


1. 1.	The Delaware Shakespeare Festival fills an artistic need by providing a beacon of culture in the months of the year overrun with blockbuster movies and reality television. 

2. 2.	The Delaware Shakespeare Festival is cost-effective allowing more individuals, students, and families are able to enjoy the evening of Shakespeare than would be possible at higher rates.

3. 3.	Being able to clearly follow the story, while listening to what is essentially a forgotten language, is one of the most innovative aspects of the Delaware Shakespeare Festival.</description>
  <mission>enlighten, educate, and entertain through the experience of live theatre by producing classic plays in an engaging, energetic, and innovative manner.</mission>
  <name>Delaware Shakespeare Festival</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1078</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/EMP/cdnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
