<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Citizens can and should play an active role in shaping the future of our global economy. Currently, the rules of the global economy are written by institutions such as the World Trade Organization, the World Bank, and the International Monetary Fund. These institutions have written global policy with input mainly from multinational corporations and very little input from citizens. Here are some of the ways in which we can work together to reform global trade rules, demand that corporations are accountable to people's needs, build strong and free labor and promote fair and environmentally sustainable alternatives. Our various campaigns seek to build alternatives to the economic status quo by linking global analysis with local action. Please help us spread the message that the current system does not have to be tolerated--we can and must change it!

Global Exchange believes that peace and security are fundamentally essential to a vibrant democracy. Unfortunately, the relationship between peace and democracy has become increasingly confused in the minds of many Americans as the Bush administration has carried out military interventions in various parts of the world using "democracy" as a rationale.
Global Exchange's campaigns explore the real reasons for these militaristic policies and their consequences for the world's people and environment. We promote policies that will expand rather than curtail people's right to a peaceful existence and freedom from US intervention. We also work to ensure the health and vitality of our own democracy here in the United States. 

1. End Our Dependence on Oil

2. End Child Labor Slavery, Support Fair Trade

3. Demand An End to the Occupation of Iraq Now

4. Take Action to Prevent War on Iran

5. Take Action Against Conflict Diamonds

6. Take action to change U.S. policy towards Cuba

7. End Sweatshops Now</description>
  <mission>promote social, economic and environmental justice around the world. </mission>
  <name>Global Exchange</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1082</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">366</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">950.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8ke/E0KS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
