<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>EVERY male has a chance of about 1 in 250 of developing testicular cancer at some point throughout his life.
&lt;p&gt;
That represents a real risk, but not a risk you have to fear.
&lt;p&gt;
Why?
&lt;p&gt;
30 years ago, the survival rate for testicular cancer was very low. TODAY, the survival rate is much HIGHER due to research and advanced medicine.
&lt;p&gt;
If testicular cancer is caught in an early stage, before it spreads elsewhere in the body, your survival rate is 99%, according to the American Cancer Society.
&lt;p&gt;
If it's caught early but has spread to the lymph nodes, your survival rate is STILL 96%. That's a very optimistic number and it should encourage you to stay aware of your own body and keep tabs on YOUR self.
&lt;p&gt;
If there is a tumor in your body, it is much better to find it and deal with it promptly than it is to be afraid of what you'll find and let it linger. Tumors down there can double in size every 10 to 30 days.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Males - examine yourself at least once a month.&lt;/b&gt; See the website &lt;a href="http://tcrc.acor.org/tcexam.html"&gt;http://tcrc.acor.org/tcexam.html&lt;/a&gt; for a very informative guide of how to properly examine yourself.
&lt;p&gt;
Early detection helps to SAVE LIVES, and it also helps to prevent tumors from moving into later stages. Later stages may require chemotherapy treatments that may result in infertility. If caught very early, it may be as simple as just removing the testicle, which does NOT affect any of your bodily functions, and does NOT affect your ability to reproduce.
&lt;p&gt;
See the Testicular Cancer Resource Center (TCRC) at &lt;a href="http://tcrc.acor.org/"&gt;http://tcrc.acor.org/&lt;/a&gt; for more information on Testicular Cancer. Proceeds for this cause will go to their website.

1. We believe that if males know the facts and routinely perform a self-exam, we can stop living in fear of what we may find and face it head on.</description>
  <mission>Make young males aware of the benefits of a monthly testicular self exam</mission>
  <name>Testicular Self Examinations SAVE LIVES</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1084</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">164</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hGX/r4gS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
