<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Thoza Embangweni Adopt A School Program (TEASP) was created in the spirit of giving to help the children of Malawi in Southern Africa (which is one of the ten poorest in the world). TEASP was originally formed about ten years ago by an Ohio elementary school to donate used textbooks to the two schools, but it is now funded by an OSU professor. We have chosen to adopt the two preschools, which are in the most underdeveloped part of Malawi, specifically the villages of Embangweni and Thoza. 

The school has become severely overcrowded, with over 65 students all attending class within a one classroom block. The school has two teachers and only one bathroom. Two current OSU students were made aware of this situation and decided to do whatever they could to help. 6 other students have since joined in, and they are all currently engaged in various fundraising endeavors to raise money for the building of a new three room classroom block and an additional bathroom. The students will travel to Malawi from July to August to physically build the school, interact with the community, and bring desperately needed school supplies, clothing, and books to the community. About 60% of the children at the school are orphans; they all pay 36 cents per term to attend

1. The value of education must be instilled at a young age.

2. We all have the opportunity to make a positive impact on the lives of others. 

3. Creating opportunity for those who have the ambition is more successful than attempts at "teaching ambition" to individuals. </description>
  <mission>Build new classroom blocks for an overcrowded preschool in Embangweni, Malawi. We hope to eventually build boarding rooms for the orphans and a library.</mission>
  <name>From the heart if it all to the heart of Africa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1085</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">174</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qJ4/Xh1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
