<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There are currently over 27 MILLION slaves around the world. PLease do your part by donating some money to free the slaves today :)
Here's what Free The Slaves Does to Help Slaves Around the World:
1. Supporting grassroots anti-slavery organizations around the world who are literally kicking down doors, freeing slaves and helping them rebuild their lives; we provide funding and technical assistance and enable local movements to learn from each other.

2. Conducting social science-based research on the nature and scope of modern slavery in order to formulate targeted ways to combat it.

3. Increasing awareness of contemporary slavery to empower Americans and others to help. We utilize a video library, web site, educational materials for schools and community groups, and public presentations to engage thousands of people in the anti-slavery movement each year.

4. Working with businesses, labor unions, human rights and consumer organizations to eradicate slavery from product supply chains and building a consumer movement that chooses slave-free goods.

5. Working with governments to enforce effective anti-slavery and anti-trafficking laws, and where necessary, help create improved laws. 
Our Beginnings: Free the Slaves was formed in response to Dr. Kevin Bales' groundbreaking book, Disposable People. The award winning book introduced much of the world to modern-day slavery, including a business strategist and a television producer.

Jolene Smith and Peggy Callahan joined Bales to form the organization in 2000.

They dreamed big around a kitchen table in Mississippi; that dream has grown to encompass thousands of other dreamers&#8230;and doers.

To this day FTS combines their original ideas of great research on the ground with grassroots movements, strategic thinking on how to leverage power and sharing the stories of slavery with the world. 

Source: FreeTheSlaves.org

1. help end slavery

2. give oppurtunities to previous slaves

3. educate others</description>
  <mission>stop slavery around the world</mission>
  <name>Stop Slavery</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1086</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">224</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8Wq/b8wS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
