<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is it?

Youth Alive was established in 1979. It is a campus ministry strategy designed to build students&#8217; hope by presenting Jesus Christ, the message of hope, to every student on every campus. It is a combined effort of students and local youth leaders across the nation.

Youth Alive&#8230;

    * CHALLENGES students to adopt a personal plan of action for sharing their faith and establishing a campus ministry for every middle and senior high school campus.
    * PROVIDES encouragement, resources and training for students, teachers, counselors and administrators.
    * CELEBRATES greatness found in students, teachers, counselors and administrators.
    * OPERATES as a multi-denominational, multi-church based ministry.

From its beginning, Youth Alive has been careful to operate locally as a multi-denominational effort. Students from various denominations and churches are members and leaders in local Youth Alive chapters. As a show of goodwill toward Christian fellowship and service, nym stewards the framework of product development and resource support through national and district staffing for Youth Alive.

Youth Alive is esteemed by many in the campus community and has a growing team of nationally-appointed home missionaries who serve as district Youth Alive directors. Hundreds of campus Youth Alive clubs, thousands of Campus Missionaries and Prayer Zone Partners, dozens of franchises of The Seven Project and a grand host of local leaders comprise the ministry of Youth Alive.

1. Train and equip students, youth leaders, churches and communities to reach the campus</description>
  <mission>Reach the youth of Minnesota</mission>
  <name>Minnesota Youth Alive</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1089</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4aU/NSZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
