<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The American Cancer Society predicts that there will be about 11,150 new cases of invasive cervical cancer in the United States in 2007. About 3,670 women will die from this disease that same year. Some researchers think that non-invasive cervical cancer is about 4 times as common as the invasive type. When found and treated early, cervical cancer often can be cured.  

In many developing countries, cervical cancer is the major cause of cancer deaths in women. This is largely because they do not have access to Pap tests. Even in the United States, between 60% and 80% of women with cervical cancer have not had a Pap test in the past 5 years. Many have never had the test at all. This is especially true of the elderly, African-Americans, and women with low incomes.

 Research is under way to find new ways to prevent and treat cancer of the cervix. There are vaccines to help prevent cervical cancer have been developed.  These vaccines produce immunity to certain types of HPV so that women who are exposed to these viruses will not get infections. Vaccines are being developed to prevent some of the other HPV types that also cause cancer. Vaccines are also being studied for women who already have HPV infections. These vaccines could help their immune systems destroy the virus and cure the infection before it becomes cancer. Still other vaccines are meant to help women who already have advanced cervical cancer that has recurred or spread.  

Many clinical trials are taking place to test new chemotherapy drugs, new ways of giving radiation therapy, and new ways to combine treatments. 

http://www.cancer.org



1. Promote awareness of cervical cancer and the importance of early detection through pap tests.

2. Provide support for those affected. 

3. Encourage and support research through funding for those that may, are currently, and have suffered from cervical cancer.</description>
  <mission>Promote better awareness of cervical cancer amongst women and support those who have been affected.</mission>
  <name>Cervical Cancer Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1091</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1665902</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">18825.5</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Gu/ib/OO/nV/eJ/Hf/uV/4LS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
