<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Young Judaea is a peer-led Zionist youth movement.  It is pluralistic  (open to any sect of Judaism) and is sponsored by Hadassah, the woman's Zionist organization of North America.  Hadassah is associated with woman's health and progress in many medical fields and was started by a nurse named Henrietta Szold.  
Young Judaea is broken down into 15 regions which combine to create 5 districts and one national movement that includes Canada.  Young Judaea is part of ATID, a combination of organizations that create a coalition that proudly bears the name future yielding triumphant Jewish leaders and community members.  The other organizations in ATID are the Federation of Zionist Youth (FZY) in England and the Tsofim (scouts) in Israel.
YJ actively uses its partnership with ATID to launch amazing Israel discovery programs that range from summer programs to a year long program aligned with the American Jewish University called Year Course.  The 2007-2008 Year Course group will mark the begining of the Olami programs which offer different tracks of world travel to discover Judaism and Zionism in an international setting.
Young Judaea has five pillars of belief that they hold of high regard in their constitution which is often changed by the members of the movement.  The five pillars are Zionism, Jewish Identity, Social Action, pluralism and peer-leadership.
Peer leadership has 4 different levels of function.  Most important is club, then regional, district (merchav) and national.

To donate money to Young Judaea, please write a check to Young Judaea and send it to Attn: National Mazkirut 50 West 58th Street New York, NY 10019

1. Zionism

2. Social Action

3. Jewish Identity

4. Pluralism

5. Peer leadership</description>
  <mission>To spread a passion for Israel and social action as far as Zionism can take us.</mission>
  <name>Young Judaea</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1093</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1448</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">169.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8zu/sKuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
