<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Act For Armenia (formerly Fast For Armenia) aims to secure a brighter tomorrow for Armenia by educating the youth of today. Proceeds are used to empower schoolchildren in Armenia's border villages with textbooks, maps, supplies and other learning tools, in addition to funding critical school improvements.

The organization facilitates a healthier educational atmosphere conductive to cultivating the great, untapped intellectual potential of the future Armenian generation.

Since its conception by Armenian students at Stanford University, act For Armenia has involved Armenian youth at Harvard, U.C. Berkeley and other colleges, as well as St. Ignatius High School in San Francisco and Crescenta Valley Hish School in Los Angeles.

In the U.S. the American Engineers and Scientists of America (AESA) helps manage logistics and enables tax-deductible donations.

In Armenia the National Foundation for Science and Advanced Technologies (NFSAT) carries out the purchase and distribution of school materials, ensuring that every dollar reaches its proper destination.

Through its partnership with these two reputable organizations, the support of the Armenian community, and the support of the public at large, Act For Armenia continues its quest to equip the students of Armenia with the tools necessary for a brighter future.

1. "If you want to predict and see the future of a people, look at its youth." - General Karekin Njdeh

2. Our goal is to strive to secure a brighter tomorrow for Armenia through educating the youth of today. 

3. All proceeds will be used to empower the schoolchildren in Armenia with learning tools and facility improvements</description>
  <mission>Raise funds for schools in Armenia.</mission>
  <name>Act For Armenia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1095</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">586</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">401.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vC/IC/Nx/Ky/8h/4K/Hi/wtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
