<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A spin off of my Facebook group "Save the Wombats from Extinction" and off the recommendation of one of its members I decided to start a cause so that the members of the group could donate to help Wombat Conservation as well. Though there wasn't a wide selection of groups out there Steve Irwin's Wildlife Fund has as part of its active funding a section for Northern Hairy Nosed Wombat conservation. It plays a key part in other conservation efforts for Australian Wildlife.  The info below is from my facebook group:

	
The Northern Hairy Nosed Wombat is one of the most endangered animals in the world. The current population estimate is around 113 individuals, the actual number is thought to be lower than this. Though they were present in Western New South Wales, South-Western Queensland, and Epping Forest, they are now only found on 300 hectares of bush in the last one of these areas. Efforts at Zoos throughout the world but most specifically at the Australia Zoo (Steve Irwin's Zoo), Melbourne Zoo, The Western Plains Zoo, Rockhampton Zoo (home of the Wombat Research Centre) and the Brookfield Zoo ( In Chicago) are attempting to bring all populations of wombats Common, Southern Hairy, as well as the Northern Hairy to be sustainable in the wild. Through their conservation and breeding programs this is evermore a possibility.


1. Conserving the habitat of the Northern Hairy Nosed Wombat, increasing their population beyond the 113 that are estimated now

2. Increase the Population of Southern Hairy nosed wombats and continue reproductive research to help sustain the Northern Hairy

3. To better the habitat and environmental condition of the Common Wombat to extend its habitat beyond the eastern coast </description>
  <mission>to provide for the Conservation of the Northern Hairy Nosed Wombat and a better existence for all wombat species</mission>
  <name>Save the Wombats from Extinction</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1098</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1030</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/VqF/uXyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
