<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Racism IS a problem in America.  It can bee seen in the smallest of ways.  From a simple look, so a seemingly harmless joke, racism has not gone away, despite the end of slavery and segregation.  And it's not just white and black, black and white.  We should not be racially blind, we should be racially open.  

When one says that he or she is Hispanic, what does that mean?  Define Asian.  Describe someone who is African American.  What are the qualities of a White person?  Who knows.  You cannot define these things.  There are stereotypes associated with all of these groups, and other groups.  These stereotypes are wrong.  

The next time you watch TV, pay attention to the commercials that portray families.  Do you EVER see a mixed family?  No.  It's either an all White family, or an all Black family.  Rarely do they use other races, and NEVER do they mix.  This is not how America is now.  People are so mixed in their cultures and ethnicities. It is a beautiful thing.  

So why should applications and official forms be asking what race you are?  What are they getting from this information??  It doesn't mean anything!  Yes, many of us have pride in the culture of our parents and forefathers.  And many of us still practice cultural traditions.  But that does not define who we are as a whole.  

Diversity is a great thing.  So why is the government trying to classify us?  

Join me in making our world aware of this problem.  Fight racism.  Protest classification.  Love all. 

1. Racism is still a big problem throughout the world, and must be fought.

2. Diversity is wonderful, and should not be avoided.  It should be welcomed and loved. 

3. Applications and forms that ask for race are classifying us into certain groups.  In a way they are conforming us to a mold that they created.  Be who you are.  Your skin color does not mean you act or were raised a certain way.  And the government should</description>
  <mission>show everyone how wrong it is to ask "What race are you?" on applications or official forms.</mission>
  <name>Students Against the "Race" Question</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1100</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">66</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/N5P/MhyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
