<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Michigan Youth Leadership, or MYLead for short, is incorporated in the state of Michigan as a non-profit organization for the purpose of developing leadership potential in the youth of Michigan. MYLead meets the criteria necessary to be federally recognized as a charitable organization as defined in article 501(c)3 of the Internal Revenue Code.

The primary program offered by MYLead is an annual youth leadership conference. Nomination forms for the MYLead Conference are sent to nearly four-hundred and seventy-five high schools across the state. MYLead is focused completely on providing youth leadership programs within the state of Michigan.

MYLead is operated entirely by volunteers; not a single member of our staff is paid. Our current volunteer base numbers approximately seventy-five, and is growing as we expand the conference to include more students, as well as increased programming components.

MYLead is funded through donations from community groups, businesses, and individuals. The dedicated team of MYLead volunteers fundraise all the money necessary to host our programs. 

1. Leadership Skill Enhancement. Through question-and-answer sessions with community leaders, small group peer discussions, and leadership-building exercises, participants discover their own leadership strengths and weaknesses as they grow to better understa

2. Critical Thinking Development. Themed question-and-answer sessions, with community leaders, include often-conflicting viewpoints and opinions, allowing small peer discussion groups to not only explore the facts of an issue, but also raise the level of awa

3. Creative Problem-Solving. Through leadership-building exercises, participants will learn to develop creative solutions while considering multiple viewpoints, respectfully forming responses to issues about which others may or may not share the same views.

4. Positive Peer Interaction. Participants meet motivated sophomores from throughout the state of Michigan who, like themselves, have a desire to make their schools and communities a more positive environment. Meeting and interacting with these peers is a va</description>
  <mission>Motivate and enable the youth of Michigan to continuously make a positive impact on their communities through leadership and service.</mission>
  <name>MYLead</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1106</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">75</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ms2/yE2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
