<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Pro-ana and Pro-mia are, hopefully, things you haven't heard much about.  Ana is a term of endearment for anorexia, Mia a term of endearment for bulimia.  This movement has grown largely online, and although popularrity is currently declining, it is still absolutely terrifying.  Websites full of quips like "The thinner is the winner" and forums full of girls supporting each other, and encouraging them to stay strong on their fasts.  Shrines to Mia and Ana, who are almost goddess-like, and are the girls' best friends even when there is no where else to turn to.  Does this scare the shit out of you?  It should.  Truth be told, I don't have a plan of action or an actual organization in mind.  But this is a cause I believe in so I'm starting it.  


http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pro-ana
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pro-mia

While it would be unfair to say that all pro-ana groups support EDs vociferously or vocalize it, the fact of the matter is that being pro ED is never right.  

The number one problem with the pro-ana/pro-mia movement is that it creates an environment where individuals do not want to seek help.  If it is not a disease, it is a lifestyle choice, why see a doctor?  Many, perhaps even most, girls on these sites do not like their EDs.  But the fact that they accept them as unchangeable circumstances in their life that they cannot control is the true tragedy.  EDs are treatable, and so many people who suffer from them go on to live normal healthy lives.  But only if they seek help.  Talking about thier problems and realizing that there are other girls out there who feel the same way may at first seem healthy or even therapeutic (although there is definitely a huge percentage of sites that are not supportiveof girls, but encouraging the disease), this comraderie is at best sick, at worst deadly.


1. Eating disorders are a disease, not a "lifestyle choice"</description>
  <mission>Educate about pro-ana/pro-mia movements to stop some from becoming willing victims and to aid those spiralling downwards to climb back up</mission>
  <name>Education against Pro-ana/Pro-mia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1112</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">707</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/YWL/226S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
