<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;font class="text" face="arial, FontName" size="2"&gt;The Hidden Potential Project is a groundbreaking educational program that leads at-risk teenagers to discover &amp;amp; realize their potential in life. &lt;b&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; Every young person has a unique potential waiting to be discovered &#8211; a doctor, teacher, scientist, artist, world-leader&#8230;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; Those who are lucky enough to discover and pursue their potential, have the best chance of achieving success, happiness and health in life.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; Millions of young people throughout the United States are failing to discover and realize their potential.
&lt;br /&gt; In many inner-city schools across the nation:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;font class="text" face="arial, FontName" size="2"&gt;As few as 40% of students graduate&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;font class="text" face="arial, FontName" size="2"&gt; African American and Hispanic male students are statistically more likely to go to prison than college&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;font class="text" face="arial, FontName" size="2"&gt; Lower-income students who get A&#8217;s on standardized tests go to college at the same rate as top-income students who get D&#8217;s&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;font class="text" face="arial, FontName" size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Empowering our at-risk youth with the opportunity to discover and realize their potential will play a significant role in solving many of our country&#8217;s most pressing socio-economic problems, including: drug-use, crime, school drop-out and depression.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, please see http://www.hiddenpotentialusa.org
&lt;/p&gt;

1. Everyone has the right to fulfill their potential in life

2. At risk youth in particular have few opportunities to realize their full potential.

3. At-risk youth in particular need mentors and a program that can lead them to fulill their goals and ambitions in life.</description>
  <mission>lead at-risk teenagers to discover &amp; realize their potential in life.</mission>
  <name>The Hidden Potential Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1120</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">13</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3af/jAHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
