<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Thank you for visiting my AIDS Marathon Donation Page. As you can see, I am training for the 2007 Honolulu Marathon, which will take place on December 9, 2007. From From May until December, I'll be logging nearly 500 miles in this six-month training program put on by the National AIDS Marathon. It's an exciting journey. And even though I'll be getting up at the crack of dawn, and I may have my share of aches and pains, I know it will be worth it.
Did you know that more than one million Americans, and 40 million others around the world, are now living with HIV -- the virus that causes AIDS?
And Los Angeles has the second highest number of people living with AIDS in the nation. So the money I raise will benefit AIDS Project Los Angeles. APLA provides food banks, transportation, home health care and other vital services - to help keep people alive until there's a cure.
This is such a worthy cause, and I would like to ask for your support. I have made a personal commitment to raise at least $3,500 by Saturday, August 25, 2007 - and I hope to raise even more. Any contribution you can make would mean a great deal to me. Contributions are tax-deductible and will make a huge difference in the lives of thousands of people living with AIDS.
Thanks for your generous support.
Sincerely,&#8232;Samantha Salk

To make a donation please visit my website at: 
http://www.aidsmarathon.com/participant.asp?runner=LA-5564&amp;EventCode=HN07


note: PLEASE PAY NO ATTENTION TO THE DONOR FORM ON THIS PAGE, PLEASE USE THE WEB SITE LISTED ABOVE OR BELOW IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO DONATE.

http://www.aidsmarathon.com/participant.asp?runner=LA-5564&amp;EventCode=HN07 


1. Keeping people alive until there's a cure!

2. You can join the cause, but you gots to donate the money!</description>
  <mission>Raise $3,500 by August 25th</mission>
  <name>Aids Marathon</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1127</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/MIG/fCxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
