<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>How many times do you check Facebook?

How many times have you stalked a person of the opposite sex on Facebook?

Do you often feel depressed when no one has made a new post on your wall?

If your reading these questions then you must understand the intent of this group. Facebook has deviated far from its original purpose of keeping college students connected with both new and old friends. With the gowth of its original success Facebook has expanded with picture sharing, you-tube video links, instant mini-feeds and now these absurd applications like causes (as if college students actually care about something besides getting drunk and or high). Worst of all, a college email is no longer requried to join facebook meaning my parents can view all the pictures of me passed out. While its original purpose was good, Facebook has sold out at every posibility yet its commercialization is not the real concern. Facebook has become a monster that corrupts our youth. Not only do we all have to worry every second of every day being "hot" and desireable in life but now we must worry of our appearance in the internet world. Posting pictures of ourselves with attractive people, de-taging the undesirables. I have much more important things to worry about in life that what Facebook is telling me whats hot.

Facebook must die before it kills you

i'm to lazy to type anymore

also don't be retarted and donate to the betty ford clinic

(and yes you should probably just accept the irony  and join anyway)

1. Facebook must stop expanding, it is not the only site on the internet

2. Stop carring about Facbook

3. Facebook needs to stop being so greedy</description>
  <mission>Prevent Facebook from destroying the minds of our generation</mission>
  <name>Stop Facebook</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1128</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">25</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/x8k/R6MS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
