<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Just to clarify: I do not work for the National Marfan Foundation. I originally created this cause because I noticed that there wasn't one listed in the search and I wanted to help out. Although this cause wasn't officially endorsed by the National Marfan Foundation, I still had that organization as the beneficiary of all donations. There is now an "Official" Cause on this application called *OFFICIAL* National Marfan Foundation Cause that was actually created by people who work at the National Marfan Foundation. http://apps.facebook.com/causes/244658/772553?m=611088da

I'm going to keep this cause going, but I encourage everyone to actively participate in the official cause as well as this one. Please be aware that no matter which cause you donate to, the money is going to the same place.

I hope this clears everything up.

I'm really proud of how well this cause has done. Thanks to everyone who has helped out!


What's Marfan syndrome? The Marfan syndrome is a heritable condition that affects the connective tissue. The primary purpose of connective tissue is to hold the body together and provide a framework for growth and development. In the Marfan syndrome, the connective tissue is defective and does not act as it should. Because connective tissue is found throughout the body, the Marfan syndrome can affect many body systems, including the skeleton, eyes, heart and blood vessels, nervous system, skin and lungs.

The Marfan syndrome affects men, women and children, and has been found among people of all races and ethnic backgrounds. It is estimated that at least 1 in 5,000 people in the United States have the disorder.

The National Marfan Foundation is a non-profit voluntary health organization dedicated to saving lives and improving the quality of life for individuals and families affected by the Marfan syndrome and related disorders.

The Foundation, which was founded in 1981, accomplishes these goals by:

* Educating patients, family members and the health care community about the syndrome.

* Advocating and funding clinical and molecular research into the syndrome&#8217;s detection and treatment.

* Providing national support services and a network of local and special interest support groups for patients and relatives to share experiences and improve their medical care.



I DID NOT WRITE THIS! ALL INFORMATION CAME FROM WWW.MARFAN.ORG! :)

1. Educating people including doctors, patients, and the general public about Marfan Syndrome is absolutely necessary to save lives.

2. Funding for research about Marfan syndrome including treatment and diagnosis is extremely important.</description>
  <mission>The National Marfan Foundation is dedicated to saving lives, and improving the quality of life for individuals and families affected by the Marfan syndrome and related disorders.</mission>
  <name>National Marfan Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1131</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4387</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1108.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/u4o/FqxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
