<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In today's world, the masses condemn and vilify the very system which allows the bulk of those poorly informed individuals to walk this earth. Why is it that so many people fail to grasp the stark difference between the terms coercion and voluntary, force and freedom? The reason: society has completely corrupted and confused the meaning of such terms. Today, coercion goes by the name of "common good," voluntary by "exploitation," force by "justice," and freedom by "submission."

This is the cause of liberty and freedom: the promotion and extension of the philosophy of the unhampered market!

Ludwig von Mises writes:

"Capitalism is essentially a system of mass production for the satisfaction of the needs of the masses. It pours a horn of plenty upon the common man. It has raised the average standard of living to a height never dreamed of in earlier ages. It has made accessible to millions of people enjoyments which a few generations ago were only within the reach of a small elite." - The Anti-Capitalistic Mentality

It is truly astonishing how fervently the opponents of capitalism decry its many supposed misdeeds. It is a fact that capitalism is the sole reason behind the massive increase in the human population -- thanks to the division and specialization of labor -- and the high standard of living for the vast majority of people, as opposed to those dark times when the market did not exist. So, how do those opponents of capitalism know that they would be one of the few individuals allowed to live on the basic hand-to-mouth system that would exist in the absence of capitalism? Simply, they do not. For most of the opponents of capitalism, the advocation for the elimination of the market process is fundamentally an advocation for their own death. This reality must be known for the resentment towards the free market to cease.

As for us, we are determined that liberty will eventually attain its day of glory, and we press onward until then.

1. End government intervention in the economy, completely!</description>
  <mission>To promote the logic and benefits of unfettered capitalism</mission>
  <name>Advocate Free Markets</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1132</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">776</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7h/1s/dd/za/Pk/d4/6XnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
