<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>$240 changes the life of a person. Hopefully we can help atleast one person.

Operation Smile is a private, not-for-profit volunteer medical services organization providing reconstructive surgery and related health care to indigent children and young adults in developing countries and the United States. It provides free cleft lip and cleft palate surgeries for children in the countries in which it works, along with training for health-care professionals to improve local capacity in partner countries.

The organization spent $13 million on fundraising and administration last year 

Operation Smile coordinates more than 25 medical mission sites in 24 countries annually. In 2005, medical volunteers provided free surgeries for 8,359 children through international and local, in-country medical missions. Operation Smile&#8217;s partner countries include Bolivia, Brazil, Cambodia, China, Colombia, Ecuador, Egypt, Ethiopia, Gaza Strip/West Bank, Honduras, India, Jordan, Kenya, Mexico, Morocco, Nicaragua, Panama, Paraguay, Peru, Philippines, Russia, Thailand, Venezuela, and Vietnam.

More than 450 Operation Smile Student Associations in the United States and around the world build awareness, raise funds and educate students about the values of commitment, leadership and volunteerism.

The International Student Leadership Conference (ISLC) is a big aspect of Operation Smile Student Programs. The 2006 ISLC was held at Weber State University in Utah, and the 2005 ISLC was held at William &amp; Mary in Virginia. The 2007 ISLC will be held at the University of Limerick, and details can be found on the Operation Smile website.

1. Everyone that is capable of helping the less fortunate is entitled to do so.</description>
  <mission> To help finance Operation Smile and their goal of repairing childhood facial deformities</mission>
  <name>Operation Smile; Help Others Smile</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1161</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1639</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">110.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cex/CbQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
