<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>NF is short for Neurofibromatosis. Neurofibromatosis is a genetic disorder of the nervous system that primarily affect the development and growth of neural (nerve) cell tissues. These disorders cause tumors to grow on nerves and produce other abnormalities such as skin changes and bone deformities. Although many affected persons inherit the disorder, between 30 and 50 percent of new cases arise spontaneously through mutation (change) in an individual's genes. Once this change has taken place, the mutant gene can be passed on to succeeding generations. Scientists have classified the disorders as neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1) and neurofibromatosis type 2 (NF2).NF1 is the more common type of the neurofibromatoses. In diagnosing NF1, a physician looks for changes in skin appearance, tumors, or bone abnormalities, and/or a parent, sibling, or child with NF1. Symptoms of NF1, particularly those on the skin, are often evident at birth or during infancy and almost always by the time a child is about 10 years old. NF2 is less common. NF2 is characterized by bilateral (occurring on both sides of the body) tumors on the eighth cranial nerve. The tumors cause pressure damage to neighboring nerves. To determine whether an individual has NF2, a physician looks for bilateral eighth nerve tumors and similar signs and symptoms in a parent, sibling, or child. Affected individuals may notice hearing loss as early as the teen years. Other early symptoms may include tinnitus (ringing noise in the ear) and poor balance. Headache, facial pain, or facial numbness, caused by pressure from the tumors, may also occur.

1. We raise Awarness- not to many people know about this disorder

2. Help raise money </description>
  <mission>We are trying to raise money to help find a cure for NF</mission>
  <name>Help Find a cure for NF</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1162</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1127</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">352.15</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Lme/ClES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
