<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Did you know that between 300,000 and 800,000 child farm workers are laboring under dangerous and grueling conditions here in the United States?  The United States government has put tremendous effort to eradicate child labor abroad; however, it has failed in protecting the lives and working conditions of hundreds of thousands of children that work under dangerous conditions in our own backyard

Abusive child labor does not only occur in developing nations; here in the United States hundred of thousands of children work under dangerous conditions to harvest vegetable and fruits normally working more than twelve-hour days often for as little as $2 an hour.  These children laboring in the agriculture face serious illness including brain damage and cancer form being exposure to pesticides.  Because of long hours and arduous work in the field, many young workers drop out of school; only 55 percent of them graduate from high school, which make contribute to the family poverty circle.

LCLAA views child labor as an economic activity or work that interferes with the completion of a child&#8217;s education and it should be eradicated in the United States and abroad.  In an effort to eradicate child labor in the United States, LCLAA urge you to take action and help us to spread the word and to build community awareness regarding oppressed and labor standards conditions of children working in America.  LCLAA is working on bringing awareness of this issue, and therefore we are seeking your help to HELP us to reach out a wide audience.    Unfortunately, hundred of thousands of children are not privileged as other children.  However, you can make a different in their life. Together we could move these children out of these hazardous jobs and place them into school.           

1. Children deserve the right to get an education, the right to health and more importantly the right to safety.</description>
  <mission>To End Child Labor in America through Community Awareness in Social Mobilization</mission>
  <name>HELP ending child labor in America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1163</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">288</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">95.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/LKA/jSfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
