<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our mission is two-fold:

    *
      To provide kids whose parents have or have had cancer with a summer camp experience that gives them a chance to be kids
    *
      To allow college students to channel their passion for making a difference, while developing critical leadership skills for long term social impact

The Need

There are 1.3 million cancer cases a year in the United States that affect individuals and their families. The support is there for grown-ups; but the special emotional needs of children of adult cancer patients have been overlooked. Simply put: kids are often left to deal with these personal tragedies on their own; and if parents themselves are struggling with illness, their sons and daughters frequently miss the simple joys of childhood.

Our Values

Camp Kesem has several values that guide every aspect of our camp programs. 

    *
      Compassion
    *
      Community
    *
      Safety
    *
      Confidence
    *
      Leadership
    *
      Magic

Giving Kids the Opportunity to Be Kids

Since 2000, Camp Kesem has given children affected by a parent&#8217;s cancer the opportunity to just be kids.  The ever-expanding Kesem community engages in camp activities like sports, arts and crafts, and drama to give campers a fun-filled week.  Campers also participate in &#8220;Cabin Chats&#8221; with fellow campers and counselors, giving children the chance to share their experiences with each other.  There are plenty of laughs and lots of emotional support, but Camp Kesem does not provide therapy.  The tremendous fun and support campers experience is what makes Camp Kesem a transformative, magical week for campers and counselors alike.



1. To provide kids whose parents have or have had cancer with a summer camp experience that gives them a chance to be kids

2. Provide a safe environment for kids to share and relate to other kids who have been through or are going through similar situations.</description>
  <mission>Give kids who have a parent (or primary caregiver) with cancer a weeklong fun and safe overnight camp experience with other kids who have had similar experiences.</mission>
  <name>Camp Kesem at UC Davis</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1191</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">95</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dqo/jKmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
