<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Around the world, one in three women have suffered through some form of abuse, whether it be beatings, 
forced sexual encounters, or another type of abuse. In a 
national survey, fifty percent of men who abused their wives also abused their children. People around the world need to be able to recognize the signs of domestic violence, so everything can be done to help the victims.

The abused woman:

-shows guilt, ambivalence, and fear over living conditions. 
-feels isolated and untrusting of others, even though she may be involved in the community. 
-is emotionally and economically dependent. 
-has a poor self-concept (this may not have been true BEFORE the relationship). 
-has observed other women in her family being abused or may have been abused as a child. 
-feels angry, embarrassed, and ashamed. 
-is fearful of being insane. 
-has learned to feel helpless and feels powerless. 
-has unexplained injuries that may go untreated.

The abusive man:

-shows extreme jealousy and wants to keep the woman isolated. 
-has an inability to cope with stress and shows a lack of impulse control. (This may not necessarily appear outside the home) 
-has a poor self-image and blames others for problems. 
-shows severe mood swings. 
-may have a history of abuse in his own family and may have been abusive in courtship. 
-presents a history of personal and/or family discord; unemployment, cruelty to animals, abuse of alcohol or other substances, and other unexplained behavior.

Some signs of child abuse: 

-Burns, bite marks, cuts, bruises, or welts in the shape of an object. 
-Resistance to going home. 
-Fear of adults.
-Apathy, depression. 
-Hostility. 
-Difficulty concentrating.
-Avoidance of things related to sexuality, or rejection of own genitals or body. 
-Either overcompliance or excessive aggression. 
-Fear of a particular person or family member.

If anyone you know is exhibiting the signs listed above, take action.


1. Position #1</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to help people recognize the signs of abused women and children, and to help them in every way possible.</mission>
  <name>Help Fight Domestic Abuse</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1198</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4302</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">75.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cLx/7PzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
