<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Transhumanists view human nature as a work-in-progress, a half-baked beginning that we can learn to remold in desirable ways. Current humanity need not be the endpoint of evolution. Transhumanists hope that by responsible use of science, technology, and other rational means we shall eventually manage to become posthuman, beings with vastly greater capacities than present human beings have."

Taken from the World Transhumanist Association website.

We are all human. But we could all be so much more. Technology is moving, and the only way we can catch up is if we embrace it.

Please join and donate today, and recruit anyone you know!



1. Humanity will be radically changed by technology in the future. We foresee the feasibility of redesigning the human condition, including such parameters as the inevitability of aging, limitations on human and artificial intellects and unchosen psychology.

2. Systematic research should be put into understanding these coming developments and their long-term consequences.

3. Transhumanists think that by being generally open and embracing of new technology we have a better chance of turning it to our advantage than if we try to ban or prohibit it.

4. Transhumanists advocate the moral right for those who so wish to use technology to extend their mental and physical capacities and to improve their control over their own lives. We seek personal growth beyond our current biological limitations.

5. In planning for the future, it is mandatory to take into account the prospect of dramatic progress in technological capabilities. It would be tragic if the potential benefits failed to materialize because of technophobia and unnecessary prohibitions.

6. We need to create forums where people can rationally debate what needs to be done, and a social order where responsible decisions can be implemented.

7. Transhumanism advocates the well-being of all sentience (whether in artificial intellects, humans, posthumans, or non- human animals) and encompasses many principles of modern humanism. Transhumanists do not support any particular party or politician.

8. The Declaration was modified and re-adopted by vote of the WTA membership on March 4, 2002, and December 1, 2002.</description>
  <mission>support the technological improvement of mankind.</mission>
  <name>Transhumanists Of Earth</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1205</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">129</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mAv/z2yS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
