<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>M.E./Chronic Fatigue &amp; Immune Dysfunction Syndrome (formerly known as Chronic Fatigue Syndrome) affects over 1,000,000 Americans. It is a complex and debilitating illness that affects the brain and multiple body systems and can cause a wide range of symptoms. Many individuals who are developing this illness are not aware of what is happening to their bodies and lives. There are many misconceptions regarding M.E./ Chronic Fatigue and Immune Dysfunction Syndrome, including that is is the "yuppie disease", that the disease is not real, or that it is a mental health problem.

Symptoms:

CFIDS is characterized by incapacitating fatigue (experienced as profound exhaustion and extremely poor stamina) and problems with concentration and short-term memory. Flu-like symptoms such as pain in the joints and muscles, unrefreshing sleep, tender lymph nodes, sore throat and headache of a new kind. A distinctive characteristic of the illness is post-exertional malaise, a worsening of symptoms following physical or mental exertion occurring within 12-48 hours of the exertion and requiring an extended recovery period.
 
The symptoms of CFIDS are highly variable and fluctuate in severity, complicating treatment and the person&#8217;s ability to cope with the illness. Most symptoms are invisible, which makes it difficult for others to understand the vast array of debilitating symptoms with which people with the illness must contend. 

Other Common Symptoms include:  

Word-finding difficulties, inability to comprehend/retain what is read, inability to calculate numbers and impairment of speech and/or reasoning. Visual disturbances (blurring, sensitivity to light, eye pain, need for frequent prescription changes); chills and night sweats; shortness of breath; dizziness and balance problems; sensitivity to heat and/or cold; alcohol intolerance; irregular heartbeat; irritable bowel; low-grade fever or low body temperature; numbness, tingling and/or burning sensations in the face or extremities; dryness of the mouth and eyes; PMS and endometriosis; chest pains; rashes; ringing in the ears (tinnitus); allergies and sensitivities to noise/sound, odors, chemicals and medications; weight changes without changes in diet; light-headedness; mental fogginess; fainting; muscle twitching; and seizures. 
A worsening of symptoms with stressors, e.g. new infection, travel, anesthetic. 

Please go to www.CFIDS.org for more information.

1. M.E./Chronic Fatigue &amp; Immune Dysfunction Syndrome is a real disease increasingly affecting people from all age, racial &amp; socioeconomic backgrounds.

2. More than one million people have M.E/CFIDS in America alone.

3. More research, community &amp; medical attention is needed to develop appropriate health care for patient recovery.</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness about M.E./Chronic Fatigue and Immune Dysfunction Syndrome.</mission>
  <name>M.E./Chronic Fatigue and Immune Dysfunction Syndrome Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1209</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5965</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">596.29</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oPo/JlCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
