<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Reconciling Ministries Network (RMN) is a growing movement of United Methodist individuals, congregations, campus ministries, and other groups working for the full participation of all people in the United Methodist Church.

As of December 2006, the RMN encompasses 227 Reconciling Congregations, 28 Reconciling Campus Ministries, and 39 other Reconciling Communities and Ministries. There are over 18,000 Reconciling United Methodists.

We grew out of Affirmation, United Methodists for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Concerns.

The Reconciling Ministries Network (RMN) is a growing movement of United Methodist individuals, congregations, campus ministries, and other groups working for the full participation of all people in the United Methodist Church.

As of December 2006, the RMN encompasses 227 Reconciling Congregations, 28 Reconciling Campus Ministries, and 39 other Reconciling Communities and Ministries. There are over 18,000 Reconciling United Methodists.

We grew out of Affirmation, United Methodists for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Concerns.

The RMN is an independent, not-for-profit organization with no official ties to The United Methodist Church. The RMN is overseen by a national board of directors and guided by staff persons in the RMN office in Chicago, Illinois, USA.

Having said that we're not officially United Methodist, however, we are a part of the Methodist tradition of social concern and action, a justice-seeking, Spirited people.


1. All people are of sacred worth

2. Sexuality of any kind is a gift from God

3. All should be welcomed to be full members of God's church and accepted as a loved child of God</description>
  <mission>enable full participation of people of all sexual orientations and gender identities in the life of the United Methodist Church, both in policy and practice.</mission>
  <name>Reconciling Ministries Network of The United Methodist Church</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1210</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2106</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3253.14</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1gY/BCqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
