<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Novartis was one of the 39 companies that took the South African government to court five years ago, in an effort to overturn the country's medicines act that was designed to bring drug prices down. Now Novartis is up to it again and is targeting India. 

India is a major source of affordable medicines, such as antiretrovirals to treat HIV/AIDS. 

Over half the medicines currently used for AIDS treatment in developing countries come from India and such medicines are used to treat over 80 percent of the 80,000 people living with HIV/AIDS who are enrolled in Doctors Without Borders/M&#233;decins Sans Fronti&#232;res projects. 

But World Trade Organization rules now require India to grant drug patents, which could lead to India drying up as a source of affordable medicines. 

Fortunately, India designed a patent law that aims to protect public health by stating that patents should only be granted on medicines that are truly innovative. 

Now Novartis is taking the Indian government to court, challenging this safeguard of India's law. 

If Novartis gets its way and the law is changed there is likely to be more patenting of medicines in India, which will in turn restrict the availability of affordable generic versions of essential drugs produced in India. And this would be detrimental for the millions of people worldwide who depend on them.  (Info taken from Doctors Without Borders' website)

Sign the petition!!!!

1. Sign the petition on Doctors Without Borders website

2. http://www.msf.org/petition_india/usa.html</description>
  <mission>Help stop pharmeceutical companies from putting money before the health and well-being of people worldwide.</mission>
  <name>People Before Patents: Increase Access to Antiretrovirals and other Lifesaving Medicine</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1216</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">128</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1sp/APTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
