<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Shortly after three eight-year-old boys were found mutilated and murdered in West Memphis, Arkansas, local newspapers stated the killers had been caught. The police assured the public that the three teenagers in custody were definitel responsible for these horrible crimes. Evidence?

The same police officers coerced an error-filled &#8220;confession&#8221; from Jessie Misskelley Jr., who is mentally handicapped. They subjected him to 12 hours of questioning without counsel or parental consent, audio-taping only two fragments totaling 46 minutes. Jessie recanted it that evening, but it was too late&#8212; Misskelley, Jason Baldwin and Damien Echols were all arrested on June 3, 1993, and convicted of murder in early 1994. 

Although there was no physical evidence, murder weapon, motive, or connection to the victims, the prosecution pathetically resorted to presenting black hair and clothing, heavy metal t-shirts, and Stephen King novels as proof that the boys were sacrificed in a satanic cult ritual. Unfathomably, Echols was sentenced to death, Baldwin received life without parole, and Misskelley got life plus 40. 

For over 13 years, The West Memphis Three have been imprisoned for crimes they didn&#8217;t commit. Echols waits in solitary confinement for the lethal injection our tax dollars will pay for. They were all condemned by their poverty, incompetent defense, satanic panic and a rush to judgment.

Funds go to legal fees and ongoing investigation. Please make your check or money order payable to:

Damien Echols Defense Fund 
PO Box 1216 
Little Rock, AR 72203

Unfortunately there is not a beneficiary we can donate to that would go directly to the case, but if you visit the website there's more than enough information on how to make a donation. Not only to the Defense Fund but to their Commissary Fund aswell. This provides Damien, Jesse and Jason their daily supplies such as soap, toothpaste, stamps, etc. Things we would normally take for granted. 

Please visit their website 
www.wm3.org

1. Free The West Memphis Three

2. Stop Stereotypes

3. Justice!</description>
  <mission>Free Damien Echols, Jessie Misskelley and Jason Baldwin</mission>
  <name>FREE THE WEST MEMPHIS THREE</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1218</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3481</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/JA/o8/k3/yn/ut/2N/VB/D8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
