<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Female genital mutilation (FGM), also known as female circumcision, refers to all procedures which involve partial or total removal of the external female genitalia or other injury to the female genitals.

The World Health Organisation (WHO) has identified four types of FGM which vary in severity.

Type I: clitoridectomy (circumcision) the most common form of FGM, consists of the removal of the prepuce with or without excision of part or the entire clitoris.

Type II: excision, consisting of the removal of the prepuce and the clitoris along with partial or total excision of the labia minora.

Type III: infibulation,the form of FGM most common in the countries of the Horn of Africa, consisting of the partial or total removal of the external genitalia. The two sides of the vulva are then sewn with a suture or thorns, reducing the size of the vuval opening and leaving only a small hole for the passage of urine and menses.

Type IV: includes various practices of manipulation of the female genital organs - piercing or incision of the clitoris and/or labia; cauterization by burning of the clitoris and surrounding tissue; scraping of the vaginal opening (angurya) or cutting of the vagina (gishiri); introduction of corrosive substances in the vagina to cause bleeding or introduction of herbs with the aims of narrowing the vagina.

The majority of females who have undergone FGM are from 28 countries in Africa, however, FGM does exist in Asia, the Middle East, Europe, Australia, Canada and the USA.

It has been associated with many religions and cultures and is often part of a "rite of passage" ceremony marking the initiation of a female into a community, tribe, society or adulthood.

http://www.stopfgmc.org/

About 100/130 million females throughout the world have been subjected to some form of FGM and approximately two million girls are at risk every year.


1. Create awareness of the existance of FGM

2. Provide relevant information on FGM

3. Help prevent FGM and ultimately make it History

4. Correct any misconceptions that people have regarding FGM</description>
  <mission>Put an End to Female Genital Mutilation (FGM)</mission>
  <name>Stop FGM Now!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1228</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15642</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">870.39</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/EPc/tasS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
