<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Embracing and Encouraging the Philanthropic Spirit:


The Foundation for Community Betterment is a national organization dedicated to community enhancement by creating an immediate, positive impact on the lives of individuals or organizations that share our philanthropic vision, but who currently lack the means to succeed. The recipients may be individuals who are having difficulties in life, be it from illness, natural disaster, poverty or just simple bad luck but have also demonstrated generosity, courage and commitment to charitable causes and community generosity, even in the face of their troubles. The foundation also supports organizations that are striving to make a philanthropic impact in their communities and neighborhoods. Our hope is that support from Betterment will be a gift that keeps on giving -- when our recipients continue to positively impact those around them.


Having Fun - Giving Back:


Betterment hosts a series of fundraising events each year that link our network of supporters with individuals or communities in need. We raise money through weekend activities that include golf outings, paddle races, happy hour parties, etc. Those funds have been used to support recipients from diverse geographic locations and backgrounds as well as build our Betterment Immediate Need Fund. For a complete list of our recipients to date please click here. 


Young People - Helping Others:


Betterment was established in August of 2000 by a group of eight young professionals between the ages of 25 and 35 who are eager to have an impact on their communities.  Since the Foundation's inception, the board has expanded. 

1. Embracing and Encouraging the Philanthropic Spirit

2. Having Fun - Giving Back

3. Young People - Helping Others</description>
  <mission>Enhance communities by creating an immediate, positive impact on the lives of individuals or organizations that share our philanthropic vision, but who currently lack the means to succeed</mission>
  <name>Community Betterment</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1231</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">291</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">70.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/k1/N4/wY/zH/Gb/Co/Ti/0qS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
