<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>As horrifying reports continue to emerge, and as a humanitarian emergency grows, there is no indication that the United States or the United Nations is prepared to intervene--despite promises of "never again" and explicit obligations under the 1948 Convention on Genocide. For more than a year, the Khartoum government has systematically obstructed access to Darfur and blocked international efforts to establish a relief program. More recently, it has failed to honor the cease-fire it signed in April. As a result, Darfur now faces the worst humanitarian crisis in the world, with 30,000 people already killed and more than a million internally displaced. International aid agencies say that even if humanitarian relief arrives now, 350,000 people may still die. 
Sudan, geographically Africa's largest country, has experienced civil war with only a ten-year pause since independence in 1956. More than 2 million people have been killed and twice that many displaced in the long-running war between successive governments of the north and peoples of the south. Recent progress toward peace has brought hope that this troubled history will finally come to a close, but the growing crisis in Darfur, which began last year, casts a dark shadow. In Darfur, the Sudanese government is destroying African Muslim communities because some among them have challenged Khartoum's authoritarian rule. As in the conflict between north and south, in Darfur ethnic and racial identities have also been part of the conflict. But at its heart is a repressive minority Arab-centric regime in Khartoum that rules by force, cannot even claim to represent a majority of northerners and has relied on religious fundamentalism to maintain its power. 


1. The ongoing Darfur Genocide is no accident

2. Donate Money so we can help educate children in Darfur.</description>
  <mission>save Darfur.</mission>
  <name>Genocide in Darfur</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1232</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2500</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">92.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4D/j4/RA/m2/B4/bL/IexS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
