<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Every 21 seconds a person in the world is diagnosed with either Type 1 or Type 2 Diabetes. I was one of the 10% who were diagnosed with Type 1 about 2 months ago. Type 1 is when your body completely stops producing insulin, a hormone that enables the body to use glucose (a form of sugar) found in foods for energy. This means all the sugar in my body stays there and there is no way for it to go away. This is usually triggered by a viral infection in the body, but it is mostly inheirited by other family members. People with Type 1 have to take daily shots injecting insulin into their body. There is no way to get rid of Type 1 diabetes, so this is why we must find a cure. 90% of people get Type 2. With Type 2 diabetes, the body has/produces insulin, but it doesn't use it properly. This type of diabetes usually occurs in people over the age of 40 and in people who are overweight. People with Type 2 can take pills to help their diabetes, but others sometimes take insulin. There are people out there working on easier ways for diabetics to get their insulin other than by using shots. I am currently on a pump called the OmniPod. It includes a pod and a PDM (what controls the insulin in the pod and is also a BG meter). It has helped make living with diabetes soo much easier, feel free to check it out! www.myomnipod.com 

1. To learn more about diabetes.

2. Donate money if you can, it will go to the American Diabetes Association and they will use it for more research for a cure!

3. Please invite more people to join so they can learn more and share their thoughts and stories about diabetes.</description>
  <mission>Help find a cure to Type 1 and Type 2 Diabetes.</mission>
  <name>*Cure and Learn About Diabetes*</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1240</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">39318</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2298.24</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3yf/PgOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
