<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Imagine not having a home, no bed, nearly naked and starving, no family, and all alone &#8211; imagine you are 5 years old. Sadly, that is the life of too many children in Haiti, the poorest country in the western hemisphere. In Haiti, half of the people are under 14 years of age, and the many abandoned children need our help &#8211; now. 

Hands &amp; Feet is an autonomous ministry which was founded by members of Audio Adrenaline and the leadership of Flicker Records. To maintain the proper spiritual guidance, structure, and accountability, Hands &amp; Feet will operate under the guidance of its own board and the oversight of Franklin Christian Church.

Hands &amp; Feet is a non-profit organization dedicated to the health, welfare, and education of the orphaned children of Haiti. Based on the teachings of James 1:27, and the heart of the whole of scripture, Hands &amp; Feet is dedicated to the construction and operation of a children&#8217;s village to provide for these needs.

Haiti is the poorest nation in the western hemisphere, and nearly 50 percent of the population is under the age of 14 years, the need for such a ministry is clear and evident. Moreover, whereas Voodoo has become the religion of dominant influence in Haiti, the orphaned children lack a credible Christian witness in the family setting.

This mission will be accomplished under the leadership of Drex and Jo Stuart, parents of co-founder Mark Stuart, and lifetime missionaries who have previously served in Haiti. The outworking of the children's village will be to provide for the family nurturing of a loving home, a viable Christian witness, attention to the medical needs of the children, and the proper education of each child. Children accepted in the home will all be orphans.

For more information, go to http://www.handsandfeetproject.org

1. Children in Haiti deserve to have a healthy, and educated life.</description>
  <mission>build a Children's Village for orphans in Haiti</mission>
  <name>Hands and Feet Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1245</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1120</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">745.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/lih/RftS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
