<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Coca-Cola company has comitted an unforgivable human rights crime. For the past 13 years, the company and its affiliates have repeatedly put down all attempts of their own workers to unionize. Union leaders "disappear", never heard from again, or are brutally murdered.

How can we let this happen? How can we support every day a product made by the blood of its own workers? We can not allow such shameless violation of international humanitarian law. In addition, we can not live ourselves knowing that what we do supports such a vile deed.

We are not alone in our refusal to support the Coca-Cola company. Many organizations, including Amnesty International, have declared a boycott of all Coca-cola products. Universities across the nation are increasingly banning Coca-cola on campus or refusing to deal with the company.

International pressure, too, is being placed on the company. The topic has been mentioned more than once in the United Nations. Some nations are currently conducting their own investigations of the company.

As information about this cause spreads, it will also get more media coverage. The information will spread quicker with each passing day. We will succeed; given enough time, the company will fall under pressure and change its ways. This process has already started, and this cause is just another part of the process.

For more information see http://www.killercoke.org/

1. End the killing of unionizers in Columbia and the various other situations worldwide

2. Fully investigate the murders of the victims

3. A formal apology from the Coca-cola company</description>
  <mission>end the killing of union leaders in Columbia by the Coca-Cola company and stop its other human rights abuses</mission>
  <name>Boycott Coca-Cola</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1257</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2789</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/E82/wIsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
