<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>On the morning of May 30th, 2007, Mt. Nyiragongo in the Democratic Republic of Congo erupted. As the morning advanced, early reports were received by HEART&#8217;s national field operatives from communities near the mountain, indicating that Goma would not be affected by the eruption as lava flow fell towards the north side of the volcano.  

The situation however changed as HEART national operatives working in the town of Kibati reported at 11:00 am that lava began to flow from the southern side of Mt. Nyiragongo.  Reports were received at 2:00 pm from UNICEF field staff in the town of Munigi indicating the progress of lava directly towards the centre of Goma.  Lava poured through the eastern town of Goma and into Lake Kivu.  UN agencies estimated that up to 300,000 people have been driven from their homes as molten lava swept through the region, and that the eruption has led to the destruction of homes, businesses, and health care facilities. As a result, thousands of families have been living under precarious conditions, crowding in unprepared centres, where they are highly susceptible to epidemics and malnutrition. 

HEART&#8217;s assessment reveals that the situation in Goma is complex and there are varying degrees and types of needs amongst the affected population. Most families lack adequate food, water and shelter. All but 250 families (totalling 1250 people) within the affected populations have no connections within the community and have been unable to find accommodations with family or friends.  There is an immediate and pressing need for this population to have access to shelter. Those that have been able to live with host families temporarily require non-food items of various kinds as well as aid with food and sanitation. Due to its expertise, HEART is focusing on providing shelter and non-food items for these families. 



1. a)	Residents of Goma are in extreme need for shelter and assistance in the form of non-food items as a result of the disaster. 

2. b)	HEART is a leading agency in the area and an expert in shelter. Contributing to HEART will improve the conditions of approximately 300,000 people in the region of Goma.

3. Donations not only contribute to meeting the basic needs of the region&#8217;s affected groups but also to improved physical security, better living conditions, and improved health while strengthening individuals&#8217; coping capacity in the long term and restor</description>
  <mission>Provide the people of Goma (DRC) affected by the Mt. Nyiragongo eruption with shelter and non-food items.</mission>
  <name>HEART Goma Emergency Response</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1260</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wNz/ZFKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
