<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Wrestlers and wrestling have existed almost since the dawn of civilization. Before them, the world was a frozen, desolate place without a moral code or even the faintest trace of humanity. Then came man, who summoned fire, not just from sticks and twigs, but from within, from his most carnal instincts, and from this fire came the heat that stirred and summoned the very Gods themselves - the professional wrestlers. 

Wrestlers are the most perfect organic specimens we can hope to study and look upon for the purpose of mimicking. They're unrestrained in their aggression, yet controlled to an amazing degree, as they only fight to a manner which is pleasing to watch and admire. Even with their most carnal emotions on display, they move and react according to a script throughout the entire deed. It is the equivalent of a porno film where all the actors stay in character *convincingly* throughout the entire emotional deed - except of course there is a wider range of emotions and morals to be taught.  

The emotional and mental value of wrestling is easily identified, and can be easily applied to ourselves. Wrestling teaches valuable morals - the good guy/face always triumphs in the end, but the bad guy/heel looks more appealing throughout the whole experience. These are valuable lessons other religions refuse to acknowledge. We can therefore look to wrestling to strengthen our spiritual side, and identify with a wide range of values. We look to wrestlers to see how we should live our own lives. All hail the mighty Wrestling Gods!

1. wrestling is performance art and the visual and auditory aspects are far more sensually stimulating than any bible

2. wrestling repeats storylines that were used back in its' inception - multiple times - but always appeals to a younger generation because of its' endless pool of talent and their evolving sense of style

3. wrestling sets the standard for the perfect male and female forms and notes that progress can only be attained by embracing, not abhoring new technologies (as is the case with plastic surgery and performance enhancers)

4. &#8220;The art of living is more like wrestling than dancing. The main thing is to stand firm and be ready for an unseen attack&#8221; - Roman Emperor Marcus Aurelius

5. "a man's body is temporary, but his championship is his legacy" - John Bradshaw Layfield

6. &#8220;There are people who think that wrestling is an ignoble sport. Wrestling is not sport, it is a spectacle, and it is no more ignoble to attend a wrestled performance of suffering than a performance of the sorrows of Arnolphe or Andromaque.&#8221; - Roland B

7. "If the Gods could build me a ladder to the heavens, I'd climb up the ladder and drop a big elbow on the world" - Mick Foley

8. "We are a different breed and put up with it because we love it." - Konnan</description>
  <mission>spread the word - wrestlers are GODS!!</mission>
  <name>Make Pro-Wrestling an Official Religion</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1264</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">456</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uZ/DU/jX/OY/5R/vR/2F/7fS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
