<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The average air temperature has risen approximately 1.3 degrees in the past century.

"Most of the observed increase in globally averaged temperatures since the mid-20th century is very likely due to the observed increase in anthropogenic greenhouse gas concentrations,"  Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change

The average air temperature is projected to rise at least 2 more degrees in the next century.

"An increase in global temperatures can in turn cause other changes, including sea level rise, and changes in the amount and pattern of precipitation. There may also be changes in the frequency and intensity of extreme weather events, though it is difficult to connect specific events to global warming. Other effects may include changes in agricultural yields, glacier retreat, reduced summer streamflows, species extinctions and increases in the ranges of disease vectors." (Wikipedia)

&lt;b&gt;"But the scientific consensus[9] identifies increased levels of greenhouse gases due to human activity as the main influence." (Wikipedia)&lt;/b&gt;

Attributed and Expected Effects
-Melting of the polar ice caps
-A rise in the sea levels from 110 mm to 770 mm
-More numerous and more extreme weather events (strong hurricanes, tornadic storm systems, droughts, floods...)
-Water scarcity in some regions, increased precipitation in others
-reduced mountain snowpack (causing more avalanches, mudslides...etc)
-More rapid spread of diseases such as malaria
-More than 1,000 species of plants and animals may become extinct
-


1. Greenhouse gas emmision is a leading cause of global warming.

2. Global warming is real and will greatly damage the earth in the next century.

3. The world leaders need to recognize this problem and do something about them.</description>
  <mission>Prevent Global Warming From Devastating the Earth Any More Than It Already Has.</mission>
  <name>Reduce Greenhouse Gas Emmisions</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1277</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2648</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">120.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fls/LXiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
