<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 1973 by teenagers, TreePeople staff and volunteers continue to plant trees and restore the pollution-damaged mountains of Southern California. TreePeople has pioneered more than 200 tree-planting groups worldwide, and as one of the largest environmental educators in the U.S., TreePeople has initiated numerous large-scale public and youth education programs. The result: millions of people caring for their local environment by planting trees, recycling and preventing the pollution of stormwater. 

Both regionally and nationally, TreePeople is helping to promote integrated watershed management practices through education, planting projects, policy development and research. 

With over 15,000 members, 2,000 volunteers and 40 full-time and part-time staff, TreePeople is one of the largest independent environmental organizations in California. We are a private nonprofit, 501(c)3 that&#8217;s financially supported by the public and private sector, including individual donors, foundations, the entertainment industry, government contracts and memberships.

TreePeople&#8217;s mission is to inspire, engage and support people to take personal responsibility for the urban environment, making it safe, healthy, fun and sustainable and to share the results as a model for the world.

**Visit our main website to learn more and get involved!
www.treepeople.org

**Register with TreePeople and find out what you can do to help the urban forest!
http://www.plantla.com/



1. Training and supporting communities to plant and care for trees

2. Educating school children and adults about the environment

3. Working with government agencies on critical water issues</description>
  <mission>Helping Nature Heal Our Cities </mission>
  <name>TreePeople</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1287</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">768</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">90.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xU/8Z/zY/jh/MD/PV/eu/2YS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
