<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Republican Party is the more socially conservative and economically libertarian of the two major parties. The party generally supports lower taxes and limited government in some economic areas, while preferring government intervention in others. In the 1980s, the Republican Party was more strongly conservative than before. In his 1981 inaugural address, Republican President Ronald Reagan summed up his belief in limited government when he said, "In the present crisis, government is not the solution to our problem; government is the problem."[1] Since 1980, the GOP has contained what George Will calls "unresolved tensions between, two flavors of conservatism -- Western and Southern." The Western brand, wrote Will, "is largely libertarian, holding that pruning big government will allow civil society -- and virtues nourished by it and by the responsibilities of freedom -- to flourish." The Southern variety, however, reflects a religiosity based in evangelical and fundamentalist churches that is less concerned with economics and more with moralistic issues, such as opposition to abortion and same-sex marriage. Noting the waning influence of libertarian philosophy on contemporary Republican ideology, Will describes the current Republican Party as "increasingly defined by the ascendancy of the religious right.

1. Defeating the Jihadist

2. Economic and Developmental Competition with Asia

3. Simplyfing Tax System (Flat Tax)

4. Stop Runaway spending(pork spending)

5. Rebuilding a stronger Armed Forces

6. Reform Education (Vouchers, Tax Credits)

7. Increase Border Security

8. Right to Life Amendment or Overturn Roe v. Wade

9. Protect 2nd Amendment

10. Achieve Energy Independence</description>
  <mission>Elect a conservative in 08</mission>
  <name>Maintain Stability Vote Republican in '08</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1299</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">562</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tAw/nTES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
