<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Gumball Capital is a non-profit that seeks to engage college students in microfinance through innovation and entrepreneurship. We plan to launch annual &#8220;Gumball Challenges&#8221; in November (International Microfinance Month) across college campuses in the United States to raise student awareness and funds for microfinance.

Solution:

We envision the Gumball Challenge to be a competition between rival colleges (this year: Stanford vs. Cal, Harvard vs. Yale, MIT vs. Caltech) to see who can raise the most money for the Gumball Fund. It is a social entrepreneurship competition where we provide multiple teams at each college with &#8220;microloans&#8221; of about $20 -$50 and a box of Gumballs, and give the teams a week to create the most value. The profits from these teams are then deposited into the Gumball Fund, which is a revolving loan fund that is lent to developing world entrepreneurs via Kiva.org. When the loan is repaid to the Gumball Fund, Gumball Capital re-loans it to another developing world entrepreneur, thereby creating a sustainable cycle of lending, and hopefully engaging many generations of college students in microfinance.


Why Gumballs?

It is a metaphor for change. By placing a small amount of money in a Gumball Machine you allow a gumball to roll out. That one released gumball shifts all the remaining gumballs, moving them one step closer to the exit tunnel. This is similar to microfinance. Each developing world entrepreneur lifted out of poverty through microfinance helps other members of his or her community by providing jobs and goods and services. The entrepreneurs&#8217; increased income also goes into increased health and education for his or her family, thereby breaking the intergenerational cycle of poverty. 


1. To engage many generations of college students in poverty alleviation through microfinance.</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness and funds for microfinance through student entrepreneurship</mission>
  <name>Gumball Capital </name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1300</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/e16/CwSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
