<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Cato Institute is a libertarian think tank headquartered in Washington, D.C.

The Institute's stated mission is "to broaden the parameters of public policy debate to allow consideration of the traditional American principles of limited government, individual liberty, free markets, and peace" by seeking greater involvement of the "lay public in questions of public policy and the role of government."

Since its founding in 1977 by Edward H. Crane, the Institute has grown to be an internationally recognized institution of research and policy analysis. Its 2006 budget is $21 million, and it has approximately 90 full-time employees, 60 adjunct scholars, and 15 fellows, many of whom are among the country's leading advocates of individual liberty, free markets, peaceful international relations and limited government. 

The Cato Institute maintains the following Web sites: 

www.cato.org 
www.elcato.org (Spanish)
www.cato.ru (Russian)
www.misbahalhurriyya.org (Arabic)
www.socialsecurity.org 
www.freetrade.org 
www.libertarianism.org 
www.individualrights.org 
www.cato-university.org 


1. Strengthened civil liberties, including privacy protections, freedom of speech, freedom of association, and sexual freedom.

2. Adoption of laissez-faire principles which will result in the complete separation of state and economics. This will include, among other things, enormous reduction in taxation, privatization of Social Security and welfare.

3. A foreign policy of free trade and non-interventionism.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to promote the principles of free trade, limited government, individual liberty, and peace.</mission>
  <name>Cato Institute: Support Libertarian Principles</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1303</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4335</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">485.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kpA/qKHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
