<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Romance Of Apollyon is a rock band based out of Ottumwa, Iowa!

Band Members:

Vocals: Nathaniel Al-Khanfar

Bass/Vocals: Cory Bedford

Guitar/Vocals: Charlie Shivvers

Guitar: Josh Mcall

Drums: Phil Thompson

With this fund we intend to pursue our music carreer and give back to all the communities that we grew up in. Local music is a good thing if we all come together and make it good! But it takes hard work, and dedication. And with that and a little bit of faith we can be an inspiration for young generations through our music.

Your kind donation will help us and many others by keeping the doors of the Ottumwa Teen Center Open and help other local artists get on their feet and on the ball!

The Ottumwa Teen Center is a NON-Profit hang out spot for kids. The founders of this establishment are two school teachers by the names of Sean, and Jill. They opend the doors of the OTC after alot of hard work to get the place just for the youth in the community, and they still run it today with the help of many other great people.

The OTC not only gives kids a great place to hang out with their games, pool table, food, computers w/ internet, etc... but a great place to do homework, get free tutering, to study, etc... The OTC provides a clean safe environment for our youth to make friends. The OTC also supports local artists by opening the doors for them on any avialable date to play a show in there establishment. They're always there to lend a helping hand.

Romance Of Apollyon is also known for holding non-profit benifits. We have done alot of free open-doors shows, and shows with a cover charge that we donated to non-profit centers, venues, etc... 

We really hope you show your support to our local artists, and our new generations, by joining and donating today.

                                  Thank You &amp; God Bless.

FOR MORE INFORMATION VISIT:

romanceofapollyon.com

ottumwateencenter.org

1. Music is an expression from the heart and an Inspiration

2. Artists must be supported in order to survive

3. Our communities music scene must be saved

4. Our Youth must have the support from their communities</description>
  <mission>Help keep the teen center open.</mission>
  <name>Romance Of Apollyon Support The OTC Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1319</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GHJ/nsPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
