<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is Islamophobia?
A contemporary and emerging form of prejudice Islamophobia can be described as stereotypes, bias or acts of hostility towards individual Muslims or followers of Islam in general. In addition to individual acts of intolerance and racial profiling, Islamophobia leads to viewing Muslims as a greater security threat on an institutional, systemic and societal level and perceiving their views to be intrinsically problematic, violent or unethical. 

Islamophobia is a phenomenon that is spreading. Every time you pick up a mainstream newspaper, you find depictions of Islam that are not true.

What the media and politicans do is provoke situations, making headline stories out of thin air about us, and whilst doing so, they devilishly claim it to be independent and impartial. Every single day, there is one story or another in the media picking on Muslims, making us look as if we're some kind of abnormal inhumane creatures living amongst them.

How many times have you heard the word extremist, fundamentalist or militant when referring to Islam? It has come to the stage where people only use these words in reference to Islam and nothing else simply because of the media. It also does not help when every time a Muslim does something wrong; it is associated with Islam.

It's time to say enough is enough!

Case Study: 
One organisation that puts great efforts to eradicate Islamophobia is The Islamic Human Rights Commission. They were set up in 1997 and are an independent, not-for-profit, campaign, research and advocacy organization based in London, UK.

If you wish to support their efforts, you can do so by going to their website:

http://www.ihrc.org.uk/catalog/

I do encourage discussions - however please keep them on the topic of Islamophobia. For example: Discussions should NOT be about which religion is better, neither should they be about the Palestine/Israel conflict. Any irrelevant posts, or posts that are not in English will be deleted.

1. Respect Islam as a Religion

2. Stop stereotyping about Islam

3. Stop using offensive language when referring to Islam (eg militant, extremist etc)</description>
  <mission>Stop Islamophobia Worldwide</mission>
  <name>Stop Islamophobia Worldwide</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1323</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">53016</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">570.29</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mw5/kUwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
