<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There are close to 50,000 abortions in Israel every year.  Many of these abortions could be prevented, if only the woman was provided some basic social and financial support.

Since its inception in 1977, Efrat-C.R.I.B. has saved the lives of over 20,000 Jewish children in Israel!

Efrat's approach has proven to be successful. Women who register for an abortion are asked why they want to terminate their pregnancy. If they cite financial reasons, they are given Efrat's phone number and told to call us. Efrat has over 2,800 volunteers throughout the country who also refer cases to us. Once the pregnant woman calls, and if found to be in real need, we offer them three things:

1. Monthly food and baby supplies delivered every month to their door, which includes diapers, formula, canned and dry foods for a year and which is worth over $700

2. Free baby equipment, includes a crib, bassinet, stroller, baby bath and a baby kit (which includes blankets, baby clothes, bottles and other items) which is worth about $300

3. We match each woman with one of our over 2,800 volunteers who provide social support throughout the pregnancy.

Last year alone, Efrat saved the lives of 1,806 Jewish children in Israel.  If we had twice our budget we could have saved twice as many children.

To learn more about Efrat-C.R.I.B., please visit http://www.friendsofefrat.org/

1. No Jewish child should be lost to the Jewish People due to the economic concerns of the parents

2. No Jewish woman should have to go through an abortion due to financial concerns</description>
  <mission>To strengthen Israel &amp; the Jewish People by limiting abortions through financial incentives.</mission>
  <name>Bring a baby to Israel!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1325</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">336</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">172.5</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0U/JL/Eo/w8/Rf/DA/V5zS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
