<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Foreign aid has proven to be an ineffective remedy for poverty in the Americas.  Often, it fills the pockets of corrupt politicians and does not reach those for whom it is intended. Leading economists argue that free trade stimulates sustained economic development and leads to shared prosperity.  Free trade allows for the most efficient use of resources, encourages entrepreneurism and self-sufficiency, and creates reliable revenue streams.
 
Developed countries can help less developed ones by opening their markets to textiles, agricultural goods, and other products produced in less developed countries.  Trade liberalization will increase production, spurring growth and solving the problems of unemployment.  The increase in jobs will elevate living standards in the Americas and therefore reduce the severe poverty that is partly responsible for illegal immigration and trafficking in persons and narcotics.

The Hispanic American Center for Economic Research (HACER) is a Washington DC-based think tank that promotes the study of issues pertinent to Latin America as well as Hispanics living in the United States.  The organization upholds the values of personal and economic liberty, limited government under the rule of law, and individual responsibility. 

HACER seeks to increase the awareness of the benefits of free trade and costs of protectionism through its &lt;i&gt;Weekly News Report&lt;/i&gt; distributed once a week to over 12,000 people in the U.S. and Latin America.  The report&#8217;s web page gets over 300,000 hits per month.
 
&lt;b&gt;How can you help?&lt;/b&gt;
- Join the Free Trade in the Americas cause.
- Invite all your friends to join the cause.
- Donate as little as $5.
- Request a free email subscription to our news report by sending a message to andres@hacer.org

&lt;b&gt;HACER IS A 501(c)(3) AND ALL DONATIONS ARE TAX-DEDUCTIBLE&lt;/b&gt;

Suggestions: andres@hacer.org


1. Free Trade is key to sustained economic development.

2. Foreign aid feeds up corrupt politicians.</description>
  <mission>Increase public understanding of the benefits of free trade and costs of protectionism</mission>
  <name>Free Trade in the Americas (HACER)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1329</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">702</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ESH/ihMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
