<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Catalyst Foundation helps build communities in Vietnam to fight trafficking.

We are passionate about utilizing a community development approach to address poverty. We firmly believe in working collectively with local communities in raising awareness, providing access to education, increasing economic opportunities, and generating a sense of empowerment.

Our goal within each target community is twofold: to equip families with the tools to get out of poverty and to raise awareness of human trafficking at the grassroots level in order to strengthen community protective mechanisms.

Scholarship Program
Catalyst scholarships enable children to enroll in school and receive an education. $240 per year covers the costs of a student&#8217;s tuition, uniforms &amp; shoes, school supplies, textbooks and 10kg of rice per month for her family.

Community Education
Community Education workshops are delivered to Catalyst&#8217;s target communities. These workshops build core life skills ranging from decision making and problem solving, and developing self-lf-awareness and empathy, to raising awareness of child trafficking, and household financial literacy. Our culturally competent trainings strengthen families and develop community capacities.

Vinh Quang School
In 2007, with the support of college students with the UNAVSA and generous donors, we built our first primary school and library for children living on the garbage dump. The school offers a safe environment for children to play and learn how to read, write and expand their horizons.  In 2009, in partnership with Habitat for Humanity Vietnam, the first houses in the "Rainbow Village" were built for our families.

Vocational Training
In 2008, Catalyst began vocational trainings for community members for the purpose of providing skills to earn a sufficient living for families.  Trainees will move from trainings to apprenticeship, and ultimately receive microloans to develop small businesses.


1. Give the Gift of Hope

2. We build communities to become self-sufficient.

3. Positive Change for the Children of Vietnam</description>
  <mission>Catalyst Foundation helps build communities in Vietnam to fight trafficking.</mission>
  <name>Catalyst Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1332</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1367</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">9254.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/p2/Mh/XI/dK/2Y/C4/pX/kSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
