<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Islamic Relief USA is a non-profit 501(c)(3) humanitarian organization, incorporated in the state of California in 1993. We are a member of the Islamic Relief Worldwide family, which is an international relief and development organization, striving to alleviate the poverty and suffering of the world&#8217;s poorest people. Islamic Relief Worldwide was established in 1984 in response to the widespread famine in Africa. Since its establishment, Islamic Relief Worldwide has expanded greatly, with permanent locations in 37 countries worldwide.

Islamic Relief Worldwide is a member of the U.N. Economic and Social Council (special category), and is a signatory to the Code of Conduct for the International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement and NGOs in Disaster Relief. It is committed to implementing the Code of Best Practice in the Management and Support of Aid, as stated by &#8220;People In Aid.&#8221; Islamic Relief Worldwide always aims to meet U.N. standards in all of the projects it implements.

For four years in a row, Islamic Relief USA has been recognized as a 4-star charity by Charity Navigator, its highest rating. Of the 5,131 charities evaluated by Charity Navigator, only 4% have received this prestigious distinction.

Your general donation will help Islamic Relief's projects worldwide including:
-Water and Sanitation
-Health and Nutrition
-Vocational Training
-Education
-Income Generation
-Orphan Sponsorship and Welfare Program
-Providing rapid assistance in times of emergency
-The annual &#8216;Humanitarian Day' program held in over a dozen U.S. cities


1. We must support the impoverished and the suffering people in this world with our donations and by volunteering our time.

2. We must encourage finding sustainable solutions to help people help themselves.</description>
  <mission>To alleviate suffering, hunger, illiteracy, and diseases worldwide regardless of color, race, religion, or creed, and to provide aid in a compassionate and dignified manner.</mission>
  <name>Islamic Relief USA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1337</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3730</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2145.34</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SE/c7/EL/Kb/T0/wV/APfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
