<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Bushmeat, is a term used to distinguish between wild animals, such as chimpanzees, and gorillas, that are eaten and domesticated animals, such as pigs or cows, that are raised, then eaten.

For centuries, Africans have lived off the wild animals that inhabit the region. These villagers have hunted the animals in their forests solely to provide sustenance for themselves. Now, though still with the end result being sustenance, the path to it is long and winding due to the added influence of money. Killing wild animals is a quick and simple way to raise money for one&#8217;s family, especially with high demand; they can sell meat to all levels of society, families, and businesses.

Recently there has been a connection found and somewhat established between European logging companies and the bushmeat trade. When studying logging roads throughout the lush forest of the Congo, numerous hunting camps are peppered along the route.Logging companies bring revenue and people to the areas of logging, providing funds and labor to hunt animals in the area. A Congolese survey observed that in terms of bushmeat consumption, logging villagers ate two to three times the amount that nonlogging villages consumed. However, the impact of the logging companies is far from indirect. To provide food for their workers, logging supervisors have been known to hire professional hunters or to supply guns and other hunting devices to local people. 

In the Congo Basin, apes only account for 1% of the total biomass of the region. However, apes are not killed in proportion to the biomass ratio so their decline in numbers has been more severe.

To learn more about the bushmeat trade and it effects visit these websites:

http://karlammann.com/ 
http://www.janegoodall.org/chimp_central/conservation/issues/default.asp

or read the book by Karl Ammann and Dale Peterson, Eating Apes.

1. &#8220;the very people who can afford these extra emotions about charismatic megafauna are the same who can afford to do something constructive. "

2. The bushmeat trade is an ignored issue that should be brought to the forefront of people's mind.

3. Many infant apes are left orphaned after their parents are killed, soon to die or to be taken in as black market pets.</description>
  <mission>end the now comercialized trade of bushmeat in Africa</mission>
  <name>Help end the Bush Meat Trade</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1345</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2644</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">285.72</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kYg/jaHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
