<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dogs for Diabetics is an innovative non-profit organization that provides quality medical alert assistance dogs to youth and adults who are insulin-dependent type 1 diabetics through a program of training, placement, and follow-up services.

Dogs4Diabetics dogs have been specifically trained to identify, and more importantly, act upon the subtle scent changes that hypoglycemia (low blood glucose) creates in body chemistry, changes undetectable to their human companions.

Our non-profit organization was established and operates to do the following:

&#8226; Training and certifying dogs for hypoglycemia (low blood glucose) medical alert.

&#8226; Studying and developing training protocols for the Dogs4Diabetics program.

&#8226; Training diabetic youth and adults for the proper use and care of our dogs.

&#8226; Qualifying diabetic youth and adults for placement and service of our dogs.

&#8226; Placement follow-up services.

&#8226; Educating the businesses, organizations, and the public to the uses and rights of certified Dogs for Diabetics medical alert dogs.

Dogs4Diabetics dogs are currently only being placed with Type I (insulin-dependent).

Unfortunately, the Dogs4Diabetics purpose and mission does not include the training and/or consultation with pet owners or professional dog trainers.  We are committed to our mission and unable to assist private parties, professional dog trainers, or other assistance dog schools in training dogs for hypoglycemia detection.

www.dogs4diabetics.com

1. Dog's are a wo/man's best friend.

2. A dog can still be playful and have fun even if it's on the job.</description>
  <mission>be able to graduate more dogs from this amazing program.</mission>
  <name>Dogs4Diabetics</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1349</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">708</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">70.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/z2o/UMVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
