<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Who we are:
Founded in 1963, the American Veterinary Medical Foundation (AVMF) is a national, not-for-profit, 501 (c)(3), charitable organization that raises and disburses funds for programs supporting its mission statement.

The AVMF, as the LARGEST NATIONAL VETERINARIAN-DIRECTED ANIMAL CHARITY, has access to more veterinarians than any other charity, thanks to its affiliation with the 75,000-member American Veterinary Medical Association (AVMA).

What we do:
The Oklahoma City bombing, September 11th, and the 2005 hurricane season - these are just a few of the times the AVMF&#8217;s disaster preparedness initiatives were instrumental in aiding animals who were impacted by disaster. The AVMF has stressed the importance of animal disaster preparedness and relief for the past 10 years. In 2003, animal disaster preparedness and response became the AVMF&#8217;s primary focus, with the goal of delivering a uniform and consistent level of animal care in the face of disaster on national, state, and local levels. 


Your donation today will further initiatives to:

 - Fund current disaster relief efforts 
 - Fund national Veterinary Medical Assistance 
  Teams (VMATs) 
 - Build infrastructure so that states may become
  animal disaster-ready 
 - Provide disaster preparedness and response 
  materials to veterinarians and pet owners
  nationally  

* For more information, visit us at www.avmf.org *

1. Through education and training, emergency responders will more confidently and effectively save animals and humans when disasters strike.</description>
  <mission>&#8220;Advancing the care of animals, with an emphasis on animal disaster preparedness and response, and animal health studies.&#8221;</mission>
  <name>Help the AVMF Help Animal Disaster Victims</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1351</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">181</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/QXi/QIzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
