<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>(Please Scroll Down BELOW to read the Daily Hukamnama posted on the WALL)


The Siri Guru Granth Sahib is a supreme treasure for all mankind. It is the true and permanent Spiritual Guide of the Sikhs. The Siri Guru Granth Sahib transcends creed and caste, cant and convention. It does not belong to the Sikhs alone. It consecrates the sayings of 11 Hindu bhakats and as many bard poets and seven Muslims, along with the teachings of six Sikh gurus. No other religion has included in its holy book the sayings of others, however revered. The Guru Granth Sahib provides unique and unequalled guidance and advice to the whole of the human race. It is the torch that will lead humanity out of Kaljug, (the dark era) to a life in peace, tranquillity and spiritual enlightenment for all the nations of the World.

This is what Max Arthur Macauliffe writes about the authenticity of the Guru's teaching:
The Sikh religion differs as regards the authenticity of its dogmas from most other theological systems. Many of the great teachers the world has known, have not left a line of their own composition and we only know what they taught through tradition or second-hand information. If Pythagoras wrote of his tenets, his writings have not descended to us. We know the teachings of Socrates only through the writings of Plato and Xenophanes. Buddha has left no written memorial of his teaching. Kungfu-tze, known to Europeans as Confucius, left no documents in which he detailed the principles of his moral and social system. The founder of Christianity did not reduce his doctrines to writing and for them we are obliged to trust to the gospels according to Matthew, Mark, Luke and John. The Arabian Prophet did not himself reduce to writing the chapters of the Quran. They were written or compiled by his adherents and followers. But the compositions of Sikh Gurus are preserved and we know at first hand what they taught.

The Daily Hukamnama and it's translations are taken from the following website:

http://hukam.sikhnet.com/2008/03/03/hukamnama-translation-march-3-2008/

To read the Siri Guru Granth Sahib, here is a        good website:

http://www.sikhnet.com/sggs/translation/

The first printed copy of Sri Guru Granth Sahib was made in 1864

The Guru Granth Sahib is given the honorific prefix "Sri" which denotes its holiness for Sikhs.

The Guru Granth Sahib became the Guru of the Sikhs and successor to Guru Gobind Singh on October 1708, when the 10th Guru made Sri Guru Granth Sahib the 11th and final eternal Guru.

Punjabi: "&#2616;&#2604; &#2616;&#2623;&#2673;&#2582;&#2595; &#2581;&#2635; &#2617;&#2625;&#2581;&#2606; &#2617;&#2632; &#2583;&#2625;&#2608;&#2626; &#2606;&#2622;&#2600;&#2607;&#2635; &#2583;&#2637;&#2608;&#2672;&#2597;"
Transliteration: "Sab sikhan k&#333; hukam hai gur&#363; m&#257;ny&#333; granth"

English: "All Sikhs are commanded to regard the Granth as their Guru" - Guru Gobind Singh, October 7th 1708.


Granth Sahib contains over 5000 Shabhads or hymns which are poetically constructed; and set to classical forms of music Ragas; can be set to predetermined musical Talas (rhythmic beats).

The word "Guru" is said to be made up of two words: GU meaning DARK and RU meaning LIGHT. The word Guru means from darkness to light or from ignorance to enlightenment. The one who enlightens is called GURU. &#8212; Granth is Punjabi for "scripture"; Sahib is Hindi meaning "master", from Arabic, meaning "companion", "friend", "owner", or "master". Sri Guru Granth Sahib is the perpetual Guru of the Sikhs. It has 1430 'limbs' and contains the actual words spoken by the Gurus and various other Saints from other religions including Hinduism and Sufi Islam.

English and other translations of the Sri Guru Granth Sahib Ji should be considered as just another "style" (language) of talking/deitating/praising the guru. While some Sikhs believe that it is necessary to learn Punjabi/Gurmuki to understand and appreciate the Sikh texts, many do not hold this view. However, the nuances of Guru ji's words can only really be understood in their original form.


1. Siri Guru Granth Sahib </description>
  <mission>Spread the knowledge of the Siri Guru Granth Sahib </mission>
  <name>The Daily Hukamnama</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1364</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2193</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">146.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DN0/A56S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
