<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Body of Christ Online is a website (www.boc.org) that attempts to strengthen Christian unity across geographic locations and denominational barriers. We are attempting to build a social networking site like facebook that will provide helpful tools to Christians, churches, and church groups.   

We currently have a facebook group: 
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2213827416  
We encourage Christians from all denominations and backgrounds to join. We believe by coming together and working as "The Body of Christ" as the Bible instructs us, that we'll be able to have a greater impact on the world. 

We're currently trying to build a new site that has improved features and has many of the networking tools that are featured here on Facebook. Though we graciously accept donations to fund the development of the new website, WE MOSTLY NEED EXPERIENCED WEB DESIGNERS AND PROGRAMMERS to help us build the site. We are using the Drupal open source system to build the site. Please contact us if you are interested in volunteering or working part-time. We are also looking for passionate Christians who would like to serve as a manager or an intern as we try to get this project started.

The Body of Christ Online is currently a subsidiary of the Reconciliation Resource Ministries, a 501c3 nonprofit organization based out of Chicago, IL USA. 

1. Assisting Christian collaboration and networking. 

2. Supporting the fundamental principles of Christianity, while not criticizing certain groups because of a specific belief. 

3. Helping local churches by giving them online tools to reach their members, while also giving tools that will streghten the Worldwide Church.</description>
  <mission>To unite Christians by means of the Internet. </mission>
  <name>The Body of Christ Online</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1370</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">175</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/R3y/pVzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
