<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Along with their book bags, iPods, microwaves, and laptops, students come to us each fall with lofty dreams. They tell us they want to be teachers or preachers; they say they&#8217;re interested in music or medicine; they hope for careers in business or technology. Some confide that their test scores point to the sciences, but their hearts are set on the arts. They ask good questions: "Are my dreams realistic?" "How can I discover God&#8217;s call on my life?" "Which direction should I take?" Even after they&#8217;ve determined where they want to go, they wonder, "How do I get there from here?"

And that&#8217;s where we come in. All of us.

Anderson University has been listening to dreams, encouraging discovery, and offering direction for almost a century. In our classrooms and labs, at chapel and worship, over lunch in the cafeteria, and during late-night discussions in the dorms, our students share their dreams, discover their purpose, and find their direction. Our piece in this process is to ensure the kind of environment that invites debate, teaches discernment, and supports growth &#8212; both academic and spiritual.

Each of us &#8212; faculty, staff, alumni, parents, and friends &#8212; has a role in preserving and strengthening this unique environment. On the pages of this report, we offer an aggressive plan to enhance many facets of the campus. We hope you&#8217;ll discover a sense of direction as you preview our dreams for the future. If you share the goals that we&#8217;ve set, we invite you to join us as we answer the question, "How does Anderson University get there from here?"

Because that&#8217;s where we come in. All of us.

http://www.anderson.edu/campaign

Discuss your thoughts and memories of times on campus and the impact that AU has made on your life by joining the group page discussion:

http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2575310085 



1. Preserving and strengthening Anderson University</description>
  <mission>The campaign for Anderson University</mission>
  <name>Dreams. Discovery. Direction.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1373</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">39</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wg0/oU2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
