<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Los Angeles Mission is a nonprofit 501(c)(3) agency, supported 100% by gifts from the private sector. As we receive no government funding and are not a United Way agency, we depend completely on generous individuals, foundations, corporations and churches for our total support.

Our life saving programs, offered free of charge to any in need, are widely recognized and respected in our greater Los Angeles community &#8211; by both our supporters and those who come to us for help.

That's why the faithful funding that we receive from our generous partners is the very lifeblood of our existence. Lives are changed at and through the Los Angeles Mission and we owe it all to our donors, who are used by God to restore hope to a hungry and hurting community.

We feel strongly about both our stewardship to our donors, who so generously provide the funds for our outreach to the homeless and destitute, and to God, through Whom all things are made possible.

www.losangelesmission.org

1. Los Angeles Mission is a non-profit, privately supported, faith-based organization established to serve the immediate and long-term needs of homeless and disadvantaged men, women and children.

2. Having begun as a small rescue mission, it is now among the nation&#8217;s largest service providers to the homeless.

3. The Los Angeles Mission continues to provide, on a large scale, hot meals, safe shelter, clothing, personal care and life-transforming long-term rehabilitation to hungry, hurting and homeless men, women and children.</description>
  <mission>The Los Angeles Mission is a nonprofit organization serving the homeless living on the streets of downtown&#8217;s Skid Row.</mission>
  <name>Los Angeles Mission</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1376</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">176</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">545.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/EHO/AgcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
