<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What Is Miklat-Bat Melech?

Founded in 1996, Miklat-Bat Melech is the only network of shelters in Israel that addresses the needs of observant women and children &#8212; caught in the vise of domestic abuse.  

In 2004, Miklat-Bat Melech founded the Israel Center for Family Justice, to provide representation in secular and religious courts, as well as free legal services for women of all backgrounds in need of guidance through the maze of Israeli family law.  

In 2006, Miklat-Bat Melech has given shelter to 60 women and 270 children, legal advice to more than 1000 women and initiated court proceedings for 500 of them.

In an effort to expand its reach, Miklat-Bat Melech opened a second women&#8217;s shelter in Israel in late 2005.

Miklat-Bat Melech also operates Nigunium, a shelter for religious teenage girls at risk.

Unlike some other shelters that separate mothers from their children, Miklat-Bat Melech  keeps families together. Religiously appropriate schooling and summer camp programs are provided to each child.
 
Families that come to Miklat-Bat Melech stay longer and leave stronger. There is no time limit for how long a family can reside in the Miklat-Bat Melech shelters although the average stay is half a year. For this reason, the return rate at Miklat-Bat Melech is one-third that of other shelters.

Miklat-Bat Melech  also manages several transitional apartments where women and their children can stay if they are ready to leave the shelter, but not yet ready to resume independent living.
 
Miklat-Bat Melech  has strong relationships with social and educational institutions and works closely with Israel&#8217;s Welfare Ministry.
 
Miklat- Bat Melech fosters financial independence with vocational guidance and training.
 
www.miklat.org

1. Every year in Israel an average of 17 women are murdered by their spouses; 1,500 women arrive at the ER annually due to domestic violence disputes.

2. In 2004, 20,553 complaints were filed of violence between spouses &#8211; an increase of 0.7% compared to the previous year, a fact which increases continuously.

3. There are 14 shelters in Israel for abused women and 10 assistance centers for the sexually abused &#8211; most referrals are due to rape, sexual harassment and adultery. Most acts are committed by those known to the victim.

4. 1 in every 3 women goes through sexual harassment in her life. Israeli police report that every 12 hours a woman is raped and every 4 hours sexual harassment is committed.</description>
  <mission>provide relief, support, shelter, and protection for observant Jewish women and children caught in the vise of domestic abuse.</mission>
  <name>Miklat</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1382</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">172</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">397.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/RYM/6jvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
