<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We are a non-profit Christian urban ministry organization dedicated to showing the love of Jesus Christ to the inner city community of Southeast Washington, DC, particularly the children.

The greatest need in the inner city is not money, job training, education, but rather, love. Agape love.

We envision people obeying God's command to love our neighbor as themselves. For some of us, this may mean giving our time as volunteers, or financial giving, or perhaps even to move into the inner city to serve.

We envision ministry houses where love can grow and bless those who live in the community. We see these houses being houses of prayer, houses of hope, and a place where genuine reconciliation can occur.

We imagine in the future, high-tech education centers where youth and adults can receive up-to-date practical computer training as well as have the opportunity to take Bible study classes.

We see communities transformed by dedicated and caring groups of people committed to seeing change in our cities -- people willing to give and make sacrifices so that the future will be a brighter and better place.

May God be glorified by the sacrifice of His people.

http://www.littlelights.org

1. Compassion: We believe that God calls us to live compassionately and help those in need. Thousands of children and youth of Washington DC grow up in broken homes, often in financial hardship, and their spiritual needs are often ignored by the society a

2. Prayer: We believe in the power of prayer (James 5: 17) and that God still answers the prayers of Christians whose hearts are broken and contrite. (Psalms 34:18) We believe that no (lasting) real change can happen without prayer.

3. Diversity: We believe in the strength of diversity. God created diversity and made different parts to work together. (Romans 12:4 5)

4. Authenticity: We believe in avoiding false pretense of spirituality. We believe in admitting weaknesses and being humble. (Luke 18:13)

5. Action: We believe that action often speaks louder than words. We believe that we must patiently listen for God's will but be willing to act as well. (1 Corinthians 4:2, James 2:17)

6. Innovation: We believe in trying new ways to reach people who are un-churched. We believe in creativity as a strength and that new ideas are often needed to reach the lost. (Colossians 2:8)

7. Transformation: We believe that God has the power to transform not only lives, but also entire communities and cities. It is our desire to participate in God's desire to save communities and cities.

8. Incarnational: It is our desire to live among those whom we are serving. Our full-time missionaries reside in the ministry house, to live in the neighborhood of the children we serve.</description>
  <mission>provide places of learning, hope, and empowerment of children and youth from the Potomac Gardens housing project through academic assistance, enrichment and recreation, and character formation.</mission>
  <name>Little Lights Urban Ministry</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1386</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">499</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1853.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/TmH/IKzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
