<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Atlas Service Corps, Inc. (Atlas Corps) addresses critical social issues by developing leaders, strengthening organizations and promoting innovation in the nonprofit sector through an overseas fellowship of skilled nonprofit professionals.

Our signature program brings nonprofit leaders from the developing world to volunteer at U.S. nonprofits for one year to learn skills, share their perspectives and then return home.  We currently have 13 Fellows from 8 different countries at outstanding Host organizations such as Ashoka, Grameen Foundation TechnoServe, Service for Peace, Asian American Lead, Oxfam and more.

Atlas Corps has a unique sustainable model where Host organizations pay a cost share that covers 70% of the program expenses. We also receive support from over 2,000 individuals, corporations, governments, and foundations.

We have been recognized by the Brookings Institution as a "best practice" in international exchange and featured in the Washington Post and the New York Times. To learn more, please visit:
http://www.atlascorps.org
http://www.causes.com/atlascorps
http://www.facebook.com/atlascorps
http://www.youtube.com/atlascorps
http://www.twitter.com/atlascorps

Thank you for your support!

1. No one society has a monopoly on good ideas.

2. The global south should be a partner in global development and not just a destination for support.

3. If the corporate sector can benefit from the free flow of ideas and people across borders, so should the citizen sector.</description>
  <mission>To integrate a global citizen sector in order to develop a global partnership for development.</mission>
  <name>Atlas Corps = International Cooperation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/139</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2283</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">43312.25</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8Xz/g0AS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
