<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In many poor countries, women do the bulk of the work and are most likely to invest their income in their families. But because they are at a greater risk of being poor, they face the unequal barriers to supporting their families. Simply by considering women in foreign assistance programs we are already running, the U.S. can help remove these barriers and empower millions of women to lift themselves and their families out of poverty.

&lt;a href="http://www.womensedge.org"&gt;The Women's Edge Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is leading a campaign to  shape American policy to benefit women and girls in poor countries. 

&lt;img src="http://www.womensedge.org/images/stories/subpage_images/get_involved.jpg" width="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;align="center"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.democracyinaction.org/dia/organizationsORG/edge/signUp.jsp?key=1084&amp;t=NewDesign.dwt&amp;key=22123840&amp;"&gt;
Sign up for updates from the Women&#8217;s Edge Coalition and to learn what you can do to help women in developing countries!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;

We are a  diverse, non-partisan, group of women, men, and organizations committed to:

1. &lt;b&gt;Recognizing Women&lt;/b&gt;: Encouraging the U.S. government to recognize women, and the role they play in development, in its trade and foreign assistance programs and policies.

2. &lt;b&gt;Investing in Women&lt;/b&gt;: Increasing US funding for local women&#8217;s organizations and poor women and girls in poor countries. Ensuring that U.S. foreign assistance reaches women who need it the most.

3. &lt;b&gt;Making Women&#8217;s Voices Heard&lt;/b&gt;: Bringing the voices and input of poor women and their organizations to U.S. policymakers.

There is alot YOU can do to empower fellow mothers, sisters, and daughters around the world. At &lt;a href="http://www.womensedge.org"&gt;www.womensedge.org&lt;/a&gt; you can buy fairly-traded products made by women around the world, sign up for updates and spread the word to friends, and email your representatives to support policies that help women worlwide.  &lt;a href="http://www.womensedge.org/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=365&amp;Itemid=4&amp;key=20284586&amp;message=Successfully+updated+Supporter+information"&gt;Click here to learn how you can help!&lt;/a&gt;

Photo Credits: Poala Gianturco and Toby Tuttle



1. Investing in women is the surest way to reduce poverty worldwide. 

2. Trade should be fair and benefit everyone, including women. 

3. Ending violence against women is a priority for peace and development.  </description>
  <mission>Empower women around the world to lift themselves and their families out of poverty</mission>
  <name>Ending World Poverty Begins with Women: Women's Edge Coalition</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1396</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">81</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ky4/BM5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
