<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We are a welcoming group of Witches, Wiccans, Pagans, Shamans, Druids, and followers of other Neo-Pagan religions, as well as people who are interested in the cause, while not necessarily falling under those labels (friends or family members or people who are curious about these religions).

We hope to raise a positive awareness of our religions, which are often misconstrued as being "evil".

We are, in fact, a peaceful group of people who have pledged to help their fellow humans, animals, and the Earth, while living our lives as harmoniously as possible. =)

Our religious beliefs vary widely; similar to the many different sects of Christianity, there are many different ways we practice our religion. We do, however, generally practice in accordance with these 13 Wiccan Principles, as set by the American Council of Witches in 1974. If you're curious about these principles, feel free to visit our discussion group (link below) and read them in the group description. =)

In addition, the majority of us practice our lives in accordance with the Wiccan Rede and the Three-fold Law.

The Wiccan Rede:
An it harm none, do as ye will.
(If it harms none, do as you will. This obviously should not be misinterpreted as a blessing to do whatever you want, so long as you can justify it!)

Three-fold Law:
Ever mind the rule of three, what you give out comes back to thee.
(Whatever you give, whether it be positive or negative, in words or actions, will come back to you three-fold. This means that negative actions haunt you, while positive actions help you.)

For more information on Wicca, Witchcraft, and Neo-Pagan religions, please see these websites:
http://www.witchvox.com
The Witches' Voice

FAQ's about Wicca/Witchcraft
http://www.religioustolerance.org/wic_faq.htm


DISCUSSION GROUP IS LOCATED AT:
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2405230966

1. Wicca/Witchcraft/Neo-Paganism are acceptable, rapidly-growing religions that should be recognized as such.

2. The practitioners of Neo-Pagan religions have a right to practice their religion safely and freely, without fear or discrimination.

3. WWNPU is an accepting and open Facebook cause which welcomes all supporters and aims to become a </description>
  <mission>to raise a positive awareness of the Neo-Pagan religions</mission>
  <name>Witches, Wiccans and Neo-Pagans United</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1398</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11341</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">72.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vV/kn/O7/Mr/7b/2w/PJ/U7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
