<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Surfers Against Sewage (SAS) is a not-for profit environmental pressure group focused on the protection of the UK&#8217;s oceans, waves and beaches for all to access, use and enjoy safely and sustainably, via campaigning, volunteering, conservation, education and scientific research.

http://www.sas.org.uk/join/

Campaigns

SAS campaigns cover six main areas: sewage, marine litter, climate change, toxic chemicals, shipping and protecting the recreational wave resource including access to waves for surfers.

The recently launched Protect Our Waves campaign strand, helps protect surf spots from environmental damage, negative impacts on wave quality and to safeguard water users right of access to ensure sports such as windsurfing, surfing, kayaking and others can benefit from the very best sporting wave resources the UK offers.

SAS represents all recreational water users in the UK, from surfers and sailors, through to bodyboarders and windsurfers. The campaigns protect the coastal environment for all to enjoy, and promote a clean and safe water environment for people to enjoy and practice a wide variety of sports that rely on these marine resources.




1. Reducing manmade impacts on UK coastlines &#8211; including sewage discharges, climate change, marine litter, toxic effluents, shipping, &amp; development.

2. Protecting the UK&#8217;s natural, coastal environment, including wildlife

3. Improving coastal water quality for all to enjoy nationwide in a safe &amp; sustainable way

4. Developing the recognition of surfers/water users as important coastal stakeholders amongst policy makers 

5. Ensuring uninhibited, sustainable access to the coastline (particularly surf spots)</description>
  <mission>Surfers Against Sewage (SAS) is a not-for profit environmental pressure group focused on the protection of the UK&#8217;s oceans, waves and beaches"</mission>
  <name>Surfers Against Sewage</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1400</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">14554</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ai/EE/Vz/th/4n/EV/QO/v8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
