<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Since its inception in 1993 The Breast Cancer Research Foundation&#174; (BCRF)  has raised more than $255 million &#8211; over $33 million in fiscal year 2009 alone &#8211; to support the most advanced and promising breast cancer research that will help lead to prevention and a cure in our lifetime. In 2009-2010, our grants are supporting 173 dedicated researchers at major medical institutions across the United States, Canada, Latin America, Europe, the Middle East, and Australia.

 

If not for BCRF, many facts about genetic basis of breast cancer wouldn&#8217;t be known, breast cancer stem cells would still be a mystery, and personalized, targeted therapies wouldn&#8217;t currently be available.  BCRF-funded scientists are responsible for these and many other critical achievements. 

 

We continue our pledge that at least 85 cents of every dollar raised for BCRF will support breast cancer research and awareness programs.  And for the eighth consecutive year, BCRF received Charity Navigator&#8217;s highest rating, four stars, thus outperforming over 99.8% of the evaluated charities, while the American Institute of Philanthropy has awarded the Foundation its highest possible rating of A+.  BCRF is the only breast cancer organization in the U.S. to receive these accolades.  

From: http://www.bcrfcure.org/ab_mission.html

The Breast Cancer Research Foundation is a 501 (c) (3) Not for Profit organization, ID# 13-3727250.

1. Provide critical funding for innovative clinical and genetic research at leading medical centers worldwide.

2. Increase public awareness about good breast health.</description>
  <mission>To achieve prevention and a cure for breast cancer by providing funding for innovative clinical &amp; genetic research at leading medical centers, and increasing public awareness about good breast health.</mission>
  <name>Breast Cancer Research Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1404</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">59417</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">7902.01</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/CrZ/e0SS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
