<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The classical form of Tay-Sachs disease (TSD) is a fatal genetic disorder in children that causes progressive destruction of the central nervous system. Tay-Sachs disease is a terminal metabolic (degenerative) disorder with a life expectancy of 2-5 years. This lipid storage disease attacks the Central Nervous System resulting in blindness, deafness, retardation, paralysis, and ultimately... DEATH! By about two years of age, most children experience recurrent seizures and diminishing mental function. The infant gradually regresses, losing skills one by one, and is eventually unable to crawl, turn over, sit, reach out, and show the symptoms of increasing loss of coordination, progressive inability to swallow and breathing difficulties. The child soon becomes blind, mentally retarded, paralyzed, and non-responsive to his or her environment. To date, there is no cure or effective treatment for TSD. However, there is active research being done in many investigative laboratories in the U.S. and around the world. The use of enzyme replacement therapy to provide the Hex-A which is missing in babies with TSD has been explored. Unfortunately, obstacles have occurred regarding the blood-brain barrier and its prevention of Hex-A from entering the brain from the blood. Bone marrow transplantation has also been attempted but to date has not been successful in reversing or slowing damage to the central nervous system in babies with TSD. DJ (a.k.a Dylan James Manning) is a young boy near and dear to my heart. For four years, he suffered from the disease of Tay-Sachs. Close to his fifth birthday, DJ lost his battle to Tay-Sachs on August 2, 2006. His family, friends, and myself strongly encourage the support of this foundation to enhance your education and get tested for the disease, NO MATTER your religion or background. It is believed that only Eastern European Jews can be born with Tay-Sachs. This is not true, for DJ was Christian and his parents were both unknowingly carriers. 

1. Get tested, NO MATTER your religion or background!</description>
  <mission>raise money for education and testing for Tay-Sachs</mission>
  <name>DJ's Foundation for Tay-Sachs Disease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1410</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1446</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.02</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wqc/LeiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
