<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The causes of Commercial Sexual Exploitation of Children (CSEC) are complex and patterns differ among countries and regions. For example, in some areas the commercial sexual exploitation of children is clearly related to foreign child sex tourism, in others it is associated with the local demand. In most countries, girls represent 80 to 90% of the victims, although in some places boys predominate.

As is the case for other worst forms of child labour, severe poverty, the possibility of relatively high earnings, low value attached to education, family dysfunction, a cultural obligation to help support the family or the need to earn money to simply survive are all factors that make children vulnerable to CSEC.

There are other non-economic factors that also push children into commercial sexual exploitation. Children who are at greatest risk of becoming victims of CSEC are those that have previously experienced physical or sexual abuse. A family environment of little protection, where caregivers are absent or where there is a high level of violence or alcohol or drug consumption, induces boys and girls to run away from home, making them highly susceptible to abuse.

NOTE ON DONATING: Donations made by US citizens or residents to this Facebook Cause are tax deductible.  Non-deductible donations may also be made to ECPAT International at: https://www.paypal.com/th/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_flow&amp;SESSION=MmS1D7HVi966WrAZYiv6e2_QQawyV-HgpcxDlF7GLRRUQDCSE7QsG-Uc9LS&amp;dispatch=5885d80a13c0db1f9fecf49521b3f5af727cc8f9db6c1fecf4abf56207eb6b8e


1. Children should not have any part in the sex trade

2. People who exploit vulnerable children should be found and locked away

3. Resources should be available for exploited children for mental and physical help</description>
  <mission>Protect children from the sex trade</mission>
  <name>End Child Prostitution, Child Pornography and Trafficking of Children for Sexual Purposes</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1413</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1390293</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">40607.39</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/si/Zk/Ul/H8/ft/XT/gl/GXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
