<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There are about 4 million leprosy patients in India. The scourge and agony of the disease is very Well Known and it is for this reason that the Mass Scale Treatment and Rehabilitation. With a view to tackling the problem of leprosy, the Delhi Pradesh Branch of Hind Kusht Nivaran was established in the Year 1961, This was a first leprosy NGO in India which offered free leprosy treatment in Delhi, India, Its a unique leprosy treatment clinic NGO, as a registered body under the Societies Act of 1860.  	

At the beginning of 2002, the number of leprosy patients in the world was around 635000 leprosy cases, as reported by 106 countries. About 760 000 new cases were detected during 2001

"Donation required for Tempo Traveler Ambulance van for use of Leprosy patients numbering about 1300 living in 9 leprosy colonies of Delhi being looked after by Hind Kusht Nivaran Sangh a reputed N.G.O All donations exempt from income Tax under Section 80 G"

Program of Leprosy Affected persons was launched with the establishment of Hind Kusht Nivaran Sangh, on all India level in the Year 1949.It acts as a useful bridge between the Government and non-governmental organizations engaged in leprosy elimination, to strengthen collaboration and coordination for a common goal i.e. prevention and treatment of Leprosy and rehabilitation of the cured person. 

At the, National level, Hon&#8217; ble President of India Dr. A.P.J Abdul Kalam is the President of the Sangh and the Union Minister of Health and Family Welfare is the Chairman. 

The Delhi branch of the Hind Kusht Nivaran Sangh was established in 1961 under the guidance of prominent freedom fighter and social worker Later Dr. Yudhvir Singh. The Hon&#8217;ble Lt. Governor of Delhi is the Patron of the Delhi branch of the Sangh and the Hon&#8217;ble Minister for Social Welfare Delhi Government is its Chairman.


Website: http://www.leprosyindia.com/

1. Leprosy is curable

2. The disease does not spread by contact

3. Mother Teresa worked for this cause all her life</description>
  <mission>Ban injustice and social qualms towards lepers and to help them live with dignity in society.</mission>
  <name>Leprosy in India</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1415</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">41</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/l3Q/mQdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
