<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>On saturday Dec. 1st, 2007 we will host an exciting 15-hour event that will promote student leadership in the community, health awareness, and lay the foundation for a strong NDSU tradition. We believe that together, the community of North Dakota State University can dedicate itself to raising at least $10,000 in donations.

Children's Miracle Network is a non-profit organization dedicated to saving and improving the lives of children by raising funds for children's hospitals across North America.

A founding commitment is to keep funds within the community in which they are generated. The average distribution of funds is as follows.

Charitable Care: 			    30%
State-of-the-art Equipment:	       11%
Preventative Education:		         5%
Other Immediate Medical Needs:	   39%
Life-saving Research:			  15%

Across the nation over 80 Dance Marathons occur annually. The event takes a dedicated team working year-round to generate community awareness, fundraising, and plan for the event itself. A Dance Marathon is a day-long event where students are entertained by local bands, student performing groups, and other volunteers. It is typically accompanied by a signature line dance, created specifically for the event, to boost morale and provide a source of confidence for students dancing throughout the night. There will be a &#8220;family hour&#8221; where representatives from Children's Miracle Network  as well as children and families receiving support thank the participating students for their efforts. The Dance Marathon will provide a way for students to enjoy themselves and relieve stress before the end of the semester and finals. There will be a number of different incentive levels for acquiring donations as well as prizes for attendance.

***SIDE NOTE***
This event can't happen without an excellent committee to make it so. We are looking for dedicated individuals to help plan the event. If you're interested, e-mail @ stephen.boss@ndsu.edu
***************

1. Children are our future and each one deserves excellent medical care

2. May our dancing set an example to the community. We dance because we can stand for others.</description>
  <mission>The NDSU Dance Marathon Committee is devoted to bringing the campus of North Dakota State University together in a philanthropic push to benefit Children's Miracle Network (CMN)</mission>
  <name>NDSU Dance Marathon</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1416</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">268</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">80.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/aLR/mk0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
