<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>FeelGood is committed to the end of hunger; the fact that one billion people on this planet are currently suffering from the conditions of chronic, persistent hunger is an unacceptable waste and injustice. We are committed to empowering youth as changemakers; we believe this generation has the potential to create lasting social change. That is why we have designed a movement to powerfully contribute to the eradication of hunger and effectively empower this generation as changemakers.

FeelGood students across the country are running non-profit delis to raise money and awareness for the sustainable end of hunger. At these delis they are learning the skills of a changemaker and running profitable social enterprises. 100% of these profits are is invested in the most cutting edge work to eradicate hunger from our planet. For every $40 raised at a deli, one precious life is permanently empowered out of chronic hunger and into self-reliance. Another way to look at it...for every 10 grilled cheeses, an invaluable life is permanently transformed.

Our 5-year vision is to have FeelGood chapters on 20% of all college campuses in the U.S. by 2016. Why 20%? Because research shows that when 20% of a population adopts a new idea, that idea becomes &#8220;unstoppable&#8221;&#8230; meaning it has the momentum it needs to spread through the rest of the population.

By 2016 we'll have FeelGood chapters on 534 campuses across the country, every year graduating 5,000 students as changemakers and mobilizing $8 million for the eradication of hunger. 5,000 changemakers means 5,000 creative and confident individuals committed to making this world a better place today, and for all future generations. $8 million for the end of hunger means 200,000 people permanently out of chronic hunger and living lives of self-reliance.

For more info visit:

www.feelgoodworld.org

or email: kristin@feelgoodworld.org




1. Hunger can be ended in OUR lifetime!

2. We empower students as changemakers and social entrepreneurs

3. To raise awareness and substantial investment for the end of global hunger (All through a grilled cheese!)

4. Want to learn more? Send us a facebook message! </description>
  <mission>Ending world hunger, one grilled cheese at a time!</mission>
  <name>FeelGood</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1417</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3367</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">14368.76</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Jo/UZ/BS/hm/hB/hC/Pl/gaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
