<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Which of the following does not belong?
a. Extraterrestrials
b. Teleportation
c. Fusion power

The answer is (c): the one option that is NOT just something out of a sci-fi movie! 

Believe it or not, research in nuclear fusion has been vastly successful over the past couple of decades, and scientists have made great improvements and advances in the efficiency and output of experimental nuclear fusion reactors. We are fast approaching a commercially viable nuclear fusion power reactor, and hopefully ITER will be the last step before we get there.

When we finally achieve the level of technology necessary to use fusion power, we will finally have an energy source that is: clean and abundant, unlike fossil fuels; reliable, consistent, and scalable, unlike "green" sources of energy; and not nearly as radioactive as nuclear fission (tritium has a 12.3-year half life). We must all support nuclear fusion as the energy source of the future!

Find out more! Online resources:

http://fusionpower.org/
http://www.iter.org/
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fusion_power
-Will fusion fill the gap left by peak oil?: http://europe.theoildrum.com/node/2164

1. Fossil fuels are every day more expensive to burn, environmentally, economically, and politically.

2. "Green" sources of energy are expensive, inconsistent, and exhibit diminishing returns to scale.

3. Nuclear fission produces radioactive waste that takes tens of thousands of years to safely decay.

4. Nuclear fusion requires only hydrogen, can be utilized in as many plants as needed, and its radioactive waste decays safely away in a matter of decades.

5. Nuclear fusion is the energy source of the future!</description>
  <mission>Garner support for increased public awareness and funding towards research into the potential of nuclear fusion for generating commercial electricity.</mission>
  <name>Support Nuclear Fusion!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1418</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">320</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qTw/MMBS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
