<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It is unfair that there is such inequality in the education system.  Schools in poor communities such as the inner cities and out in the country do not get enough money to fund education; whereas the some suburban schools get more than enough.  As a result, students from those suburb schools get a better education, get accepted into better college and have a BETTER opportunity at a happy &amp; healthy life than those who live in the inner cities or in the country.

It is not right that one school might have 1,000 brand new computer &amp; another school has 200 old computers that don&#8217;t even connect to the internet.

There are even some schools that have flat screen TV's in their cafeterias.  WHAT?  How can this be when there are other schools that don't even have TV's in their classrooms?

This inequality in the education system is just the start of the bigger problem, the inequality in our society.


1. All students should have an equal opportunity at a good education, no matter where they live or how rich or poor their parents are.

2. The government should offer incentive to teachers who teach in school districts that continue to perform poorly (and I mean some good incentives, like pay off student loans, or an increase in salary or pay to further the teacher&#8217;s education).

3. The government should distribute money and resources evenly amongst school districts.

4. We must start to close the education gap between rich schools &amp; poor schools.  ***Please consider donating your time and/or money to help close this gap***</description>
  <mission>Draw attention to the fact that poor children, often times are cheated out of a good education &amp; that is unfair to them!</mission>
  <name>EQUAL EDUCATION FOR THE RICH &amp; THE POOR</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1422</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5045</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">40.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GvZ/RkUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
