<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I started this cause, because I have moderate asthma myself and got digonosed with it when I was 5 but probobly have had it all my life. Listed are true facts about asthma.


Asthma is an inflammatory condition of the bronchial airways. This inflammation causes the normal function of the airways to become excessive and over-reactive, thus producing increased mucus, mucosal swelling and muscle contraction.

In 2004, an estimated 4 million children under 18 years old have had an asthma attack in the past 12 months, and many others have "hidden" or undiagnosed asthma.

Asthma is the most common cause of school absenteeism due to chronic disease and accounted for an estimated 14 million lost school days

WHAT USUALLY TRIGGERS ASTHMA?

Episodes of asthma often are triggered by some condition or stimulus. Common triggers of asthma are:

Exercise
Infections
Allergy
Irritants
Weather
Emotions (infrequent)

About 1-2 million adults ages 18 and over have asthma, and has progressed into adulthood, after having it in childhood as well. There are some adults who dont develop asthma until they are well into middle age.

Approximately 5000 people die of asthma each year in the United States.

Asthma attack symtpoms include Wheezing, Breathlessness,Chest tightness,Coughing and Difficulty speaking 

Come on people, cant we please blow the whistle on asthma? 50 THOUSAND people dieing a year from asthma, particially children under 18 NEEDS to stop. Asthma IS a deadly disease and often gets pushed off as nothing. It IS something and it needs to be recognized. I personally know what its like to have moderate asthma and it is not fun. This NEEDS to happen, this needs a cause benefit.


1. Help fight asthma

2. Make Life Easier for those children and adults with asthma

3. Aware other just how DEADLY asthma can be</description>
  <mission>Help Fight Asthma</mission>
  <name>Blow The Whistle On Asthma</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1424</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9193</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">133.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/si1/Va7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
