<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This cause is dedicated to the 1,500,000 Armenians who were killed in the Armenian Genocide of 1915 in Ottoman Turkey.

This cause was formed a year after the group: 

http://berkeley.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2204932127

To this day, the government of Turkey publicly DENIES THE FIRST GENOCIDE OF THE TWENTIETH CENTURY.

It is extremely difficult to stop and prevent genocides today and tomorrow if we do not recognize those of the past.

During the onset of the mission to exterminate the Christian population of the Ottoman Empire, starting in 1914, 400,000 Greeks were slaughtered and deported to Greece. On April 24, 1915, the Armenian intellectuals were rounded up and executed; more than a million soon followed. Along with Greeks and Armenians, hundreds of thousands - more than 2/3 of Assyrians (Syriac and Chaldean Christians) at the time - were also exterminated by the nationalist "Young Turks" movement which gained political prominence at the time.

The official stance of the Turkish government is that people simply died during war (WWI). War was a great distraction to carry out something they had been planning for years. The official governmental documentation of the times leading up to, during, and after this "solving of the Armenian Question" kept in the archives is getting 'taken care of' as we speak. The children of modern-day Turkey are taught a re-written version of history in textbooks that either ignore or deny the issue.

Yet, every year, the world community observes gradual movement of the genocide issue towards becoming a national agenda item in Turkey. Only then, when the taboos are lifted, the Turkish citizens will start learning what actually happened in the streets and deserts at the dusk of the Ottoman Empire. Why the Tigris river turned red.

Mainly due to political, geopolitical, and economic (U.S. military bases in Turkey) reasons, THE UNITED STATES government is NOT on the list of countries governments of which accept and denounce the genocide.

We in this cause hope that the truth of history will prevail over the hypocricy of politics.

Denial is killing twice.

==========================================
Survivors:
http://ermeni.org/turkce/vkayutyunner.php?tp=ea&amp;lng=eng

-RESEARCH LINKS-

http://20voices.com/
http://www.inhomage.com/
http://www.genocide1915.info/
http://www.zoryaninstitute.org/
http://www.theforgotten.org/intro.html
http://www.crag.org.uk/
http://www.never-again.com/home.php
http://www.armeniangenocideposters.org/index2006.html
http://www.armenians.com/Genocide/index-main.html
http://www.imprescriptible.fr/
http://www.genocideevents.com/
http://www.arminco.com/livewebcam.html
http://www.hyeetch.nareg.com.au/genocide/genocide_p1.html

-BOOKS- 

"The 40 days of Musa Dagh" by Franz Werfel (excerpts on http://books.google.com/)

"A Shameful Act: The Armenian Genocide and the Question of Turkish Responsibility" by Taner Akcam

"The Burning Tigris" by Peter Balakian

"The Great Game of Genocide" By Donald Bloxham

"Three Apples Fell from Heaven" by Micheline Aharonian Marcom

"At the Crossroads of Der Zor: Death, Survival, and Humanitarian Resistance" by Hilmar Kaiser

Other: http://www.gomidas.org/books/index.htm

-MOVIES-

La Masseria Delle Allodole (The Lark Farm) 2007 Italy
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0854672/
Le Voyage en Armenie (Armenia) 2006 France
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0491901/
"Screamers" (2006) http://www.screamersmovie.com/
"Mayrig" (1992) http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0102421/
"Ararat" (2002) http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0273435/

-VIDEO-

ARTE France Documentary (in English, Feb. 2007): 
http://vids.myspace.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.individual&amp;videoid=2033350847

A short film made in April of 2006: http://www.current.tv/studio/media/3403882

Orhan Pamuk Documentary:
http://vids.myspace.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.individual&amp;videoid=2025415948
PBS Documentary "Armenian Genocide" (2006)</description>
  <mission>Urge an end to state-sponsored denial</mission>
  <name>RECOGNIZE THE ARMENIAN GENOCIDE</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/143</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">74926</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1309.36</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gB/QV/mA/Br/7K/cC/l1/C4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
