<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>SenseCorp Texas 4000 for Cancer is a student-organization at the University of Texas at Austin. Each year, starting 2004, around 40 passionate students, mainly from UT, set their sights on raising $350,000 towards Cancer Research, and on completion of the monumental ride, donate it all to the American Cancer Society. To date, the SenseCorp Texas 4000 for Cancer has raised about $740,000. Help us make that over $1,000,000 in the next 2 years!

To donate, please follow the directions below:
1) Make a check payable to "Texas 4000 for Cancer"
2) If sponsoring a specific rider, please include the rider's name on the "For" line, so that they may show their own appreciation
3) In the same envelope, please include your name, address, and phone number so that we may personally thank you for your support. In addition, since Texas 4000 is a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization we will send you a receipt for your donation for tax purposes.
4) Mail check to: 
Texas 4000 for Cancer
P.O. Box 202315
Dallas, TX 75230-2315

In addition, to pay by credit card, you can visit the Texas 4000 for Cancer donation page at http://www.texas4000.org/t4k/main/donate, and click on "Make a Donation" under the "By Credit Card" section.

1. Spread Hope for finding a way to ultimately stop Cancer.

2. Spread Knowledge about how to fight cancer through prevention and early detection. 

3. Raise funds through Charity for the purpose of funding research to find the cure(s) to this terrible disease.</description>
  <mission>raise over $1,000,000 towards Cancer Research and spread hope and knowledge by cycling across the continent from Austin, TX to Anchorage, AK.</mission>
  <name>SenseCorp Texas 4000 for Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1435</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">149</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yQJ/mk2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
