<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>NIF is in the vanguard of fighting for social change in Israel. NIF grantees work in three core areas:

    * Civil and Human Rights : Flagship NIF grantees such as B'Tselem and the Association for Civil Rights in Israel have won court battles on issues ranging from the prohibition of torture in civilian interrogations to changes in the route of the separation fence to respect humanitarian concerns. Other grantees work on issues ranging from evenhanded urban planning and land sales to women's and minority rights.
    * Social and Economic Justice: As a nation with many disadvantaged minority groups, from citizen Arabs to Ethiopians to Mizrachim, Israel has a special responsibility to observe its founders' vision and values of "freedom, justice and peace as envisaged by the prophets of Israel." Racism, injustice and extremism defile Jewish values and threaten Israel's long-term security. NIF grantees organize communities, advocate for equitable government policies and empower disadvantaged Israelis to help their communities and themselves.
    * Religious Pluralism and Tolerance : NIF has long been a principal supporter of a pluralistic and tolerant Israeli culture that includes diverse approaches to Judaism and Jewish identity. NIF grantees are in the forefront of the struggle for civil marriage and other life-cycle events, recognition of non-Orthodox conversions and the equal and unbiased allocation of government resources.


1. Help Support Israel</description>
  <mission>The New Israel Fund believes that ensuring Israel's peaceful and democratic future means building a society dedicated to equality, pluralism, and the rule of law.</mission>
  <name>We Stand With, and Support Israel</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1439</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">27</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/e40/6JUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
