<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dihydrogen monoxide is colorless, odorless, tasteless, and kills uncounted
thousands of people every year. Most of these deaths are caused by
accidental inhalation of DHMO, but the dangers of dihydrogen monoxide do
not end there. Prolonged exposure to its solid form causes severe tissue damage.
Symptoms of DHMO ingestion can include excessive sweating and urination, and
possibly a bloated feeling, nausea, vomiting and body electrolyte imbalance. 
For those who have become dependent, DHMO withdrawal means certain death.

Dihydrogen monoxide:

   * is also known as hydroxl acid, and is the major component of acid
      rain                
   * contributes to the "greenhouse effect."
   * may cause severe burns.
   * contributes to the erosion of our natural landscape.
   * accelerates corrosion and rusting of many metals.
   * may cause electrical failures and decreased effectiveness of 
      automobile brakes.
   * has been found in excised tumors of terminal cancer patients.

Quantities of dihydrogen monoxide have been found in almost every stream,
lake, and reservoir in America today. But the pollution is global, and the
contaminant has even been found in Antarctic ice. DHMO has caused millions
of dollars of property damage in the midwest, and recently California.

Despite the danger, dihydrogen monoxide is often used:

   * as an industrial solvent and coolant.
   * in nuclear power plants.
   * in the production of Styrofoam.
   * as a fire retardant.
   * in many forms of cruel animal research.
   * in the distribution of pesticides. Even after washing, produce remains
      contaminated by this chemical.
   * as an additive in certain "junk-foods" and other food products.

Companies dump waste DHMO into rivers and the ocean, and nothing can be
done to stop them because this practice is still legal. The impact on wildlife is
extreme, and we cannot afford to ignore it any longer!

1. It is a threat to all citizens.

2. It comes in many forms.

3. It can be found all over the world.</description>
  <mission>Ban the threat to humanity known as Dihydrogen Monoxide</mission>
  <name>Ban Dihydrogen Monoxide</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1451</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1463</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6LI/8GmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
