<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The founders of Attitude Media Corporation have commenced Attitude Media's next community project: Granting the wishes of 10 children from the Make-A-Wish Foundation (http://metrony.wish.org).

Project Shooting Star&#8217;s foremost purpose is to give children with life threatening medical conditions an opportunity to experience their dream. The goal of Project Shooting Star is to grant wishes as small as seeing a Broadway show for the first time, which many take for granted, through allowing these children to live out their dream of performing on stage before a supportive audience.

During the children's one week stay in NYC, they will be paired with Broadway actors and celebrities and go through training in workshops. By the end of the week, the children would have learned the ropes and will be ready for their moment to shine.

This year, the program will grant 10 children from the Make-A-Wish Foundation wish by bringing them and their families to New York City, allowing them to see a Broadway show, and allowing them to perform on stage mentored and paired up with either a celebrity or Broadway star. The project has already received an outpour of support from the Broadway community, including current and past RENT cast members. Various fundraising avenues are in the works for this event, including a benefit concert scheduled for July or August of this year. The children&#8217;s visit and performance is slated for December 2007.  We need to raise at least $100,000 to make this event happen.  Please join our volunteer mailing list to be kept up to date with the latest information about Project Shooting Star. Sign up at http://www.attitudemc.com/mailing.html.

1. Grant the wishes of ten children with life-threatening illnesses.

2. Opportunity to live out their dreams in New York City!

3. We need to raise at least $100,000!</description>
  <mission>grant the wishes of ten children from the Make-A-Wish Foundation with life-threatening illnesses and give them the opportunity to live out their wishes.</mission>
  <name>Project Shooting Star</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1460</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">149</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GWK/hYxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
