<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.militaryfreezone.org 
^ check here for more information

"Who We Are?

A coalition of musicians and punk activists that want to take action and empower others to stand up and speak out against our government that is abusing its power by granting military recruiters access to students&#8217; private information. We also want to put an end to the system allowing these recruiters to use our public schools and institutions for recruiting students. We want to see recruiters stop misleading students with false promises of huge financial rewards for joining the armed services.

In the USA, under the No Child Left Behind Act, if you attend a high school that receives federal funding your school system is required to turn over your private information to the U.S. military for recruitment purposes. (With the exception of a few private schools, almost every school in the USA receives federal funding.) Your school is NOT required to tell you that they are giving your private information to the military."

This is NOT anti-military.  This group wishes for an education system in America free of pressure put on students (particularly those of lower income families) from military recruiters.

1. Providing a safe and peaceful learning environment.

2. Protecting our rights to privacy and keeping personal information private.

3. Preserving the freedoms that allow students to express all viewpoints.

4. An end to the use of lies, misinformation, and predatory recruitment tactics.</description>
  <mission>stop military recruiters from preying on students and taking students&#8217; private information without permission</mission>
  <name>Military Free Zone</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1464</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">380</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vmr/TvuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
