<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Every day we compare ourselves to those around us. 

Some of us attend school, others work, some neither. 

Why should it matter if we attend school or not? 
Why should it matter if we play sports or not?
Why should it matter if we earn good grades or not?
Why should it matter if we are seen as pretty or not?

Why allow ourselves to be judged by such a criteria?

It's important to be the best version of ourselves, I believe. Sometimes people are trying so hard to be that very thing, but all the world might see is someone failing at everything else. What is failure? Another topic aside from this cause. When we judge others based on only what we can observe with our senses, we end up missing out on worthwhile, enriching relationships. 

We should be able to choose, for ourselves, how the world sees us.

We should be able to choose, for ourselves, what we do, and how we do it. 

We should be able to choose, for ourselves, what is in our best interest. 

We should be able to choose, for ourselves, how to experience life in the best manner.

Some may agree, some may disagree. But isn't that the beauty of independence? The right to think and act and behave according to our own criteria? Agency allows independence, and sometimes, vice versa.

True freedom is born by our ability to choose and think for ourselves. 



1. Consider others' feelings, but follow through on what is in our best interest.

2. Think for yourself. Do not deny yourself the opportunity to freedom by thriving on others' opinions and patterns of behavior.

3. Enjoy who you are. Allow yourself to just BE.</description>
  <mission>Abandon the World's Obsession with Comparison</mission>
  <name>Freedom by Independence</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1477</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">17</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/17n/6vMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
