<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The National Association of the Deaf (NAD), established in 1880, is the oldest and largest constituency organization safeguarding the accessibility and civil rights of 28 million deaf and hard of hearing Americans in education, employment, health care, and telecommunications.

A private, non-profit organization, the NAD is a dynamic federation of 51 state association affiliates including the District of Columbia, organizational affiliates, and direct members.

Programs and activities include grassroots advocacy and empowerment, captioned media, certification of American Sign Language professionals; certification of sign language interpreters; deafness-related information and publications, legal assistance, policy development and research, public awareness, and youth leadership development.

Your donation of any amount can make a difference in NAD's work on behalf of deaf and hard of hearing people. 

We all know the importance of having auto, health and home insurance. When you join or support the National Association of the Deaf, you are literally buying &#8220;civil rights insurance&#8221;, so the NAD will have you &#8220;covered&#8221;.

http://www.nad.org

1.  NAD has changed America and the way it serves deaf and hard of hearing Americans. 

2. We now enjoy the right to drive, closed captioned TV/cable programs, sign language interpreting services, telecommunications relay services, and much 

3. the fight is clearly not over. Barriers remain. </description>
  <mission>NAD is to promote, protect, and preserve the rights and quality of life of deaf and hard of hearing individuals in the United States of America.</mission>
  <name>National Association of the Deaf</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1479</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">16215</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1501.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bph/KyVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
