<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We remember the Sabbath day not only as a memorial of creation, but also as a symbol of divine justice in the face of political and economic oppression. We hold fast to the faith of Jesus not only by proclaiming his Advent, but by refusing violence and coercion as tools to establish God's kingdom. 

We therefore appeal to all Adventists, as fellow disciples and followers of Christ, to join us in reclaiming our church's historic commitment to social action and radical dissent. We urge all Adventists to re-covenant to obey the high ethical call of the center cross: the call to active, nonviolent resistance to evil. And we challenge all Adventists to engage in the vital work of restoring community through active service to society.

As there is a word limit imposed on this description, please visit some of our links for more on the Adventist Peace Fellowship- &lt;a href="http://www.adventistpeace.org"&gt;main website&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href="http://adventistpeace.typepad.com/peacemessenger/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.adventistpeace.org/templates/System/details.asp?id=39491&amp;PID=465527 "&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;!


1. Offer resources for exploring the significance of Adventist beliefs and heritage for peacemaking in a violent world.

2. Provide a forum for interchange and advocacy on how Adventist faith speaks to current issues of peace and peacemaking.

3. Connect Adventists with other peacemaking resources and organizations.</description>
  <mission>To explore the meaning of the Adventist commitment to &#8220;the commandments of God and the faith of Jesus Christ&#8221; for peacemaking in a world rent by violence.</mission>
  <name>Adventist Peace Fellowship</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1489</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">848</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">55.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2pN/HkJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
