<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Money raised for this cause will go towards holding discussion and debate events, chapter training workshops, creating materials to spread information about safe and responsible drinking, provide seed money for campus chapters, and most importantly, an advertising budget.  Without the ability to get the word out on the radio, newspapers, blogs, Google, or TV spots -- something our opponents have money for in abundance -- we will always be fighting against the current.

If just 10% of our current supporters on this cause donated just $10 each, we would easily smash through our current fundraising goal.  So give what you can, get involved, and help the cause.

It's become a consensus: everyone knows that the drinking age is not working.

The 21-year-old drinking age is at the very least ineffective, and more troublingly, counterproductive.  It has forced drinking underground, and a dangerous culture has formed around binge drinking.  Because it is necessarily secretive, there is no way of curbing this.  And when a young person has had too much to drink, they find themselves afraid to seek medical attention.  This futile law has created a generation that treats alcohol as something to be abused, rather than enjoyed in moderation.

People aged 18 serve on juries in the courtroom.  They vote in our elections, and they volunteer for good causes.  They are old enough to be held accountable for their actions in a court of law, and they fight and die in the service of our country.  They are adults, in every sense, and it's long overdue that they be treated as such.

As a nation, we need to reexamine our unhealthy attitudes towards drinking and our culture of alcohol abuse.  This cause is for those who understand that this has its roots in an over-reliance on abstinence and puritanism.

Get more information on lowering the drinking age:
http://www.youthrights.org/drinkingage.php

1. Help us reach our goal of recruiting 1,000,000+ in support of a lower drinking age!

2. 18-year-olds are adults in the eyes of the law.

3. Lowering the drinking age will make young people safer.

4. Prohibition did not work in the 1920's, and does not work now.

5. www.youthrights.org</description>
  <mission>Lower the drinking age to 18 in the United States</mission>
  <name>Lower the drinking age!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/149</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">47812</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1009.85</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yTZ/uOdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
