<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dear friends, ( queridos amigos mios buenos )

In these difficult times that we are now living, we need to join for a good cause.

The planet&#180;s global warming has produced a Murcian summer that is becoming a hell itself ( Verano en Murcia = infierno ).  A lot of suffering is approaching due to the high temperatures that have been predicted for these next few months.  

Due to this, I have created a noble cause of collecting money so that your good friend ( amigo bueno ), LoLo, from Murcia can go on vacation in Hawaii and escape this uncertain future full of fears and tears.

Your help is extremely necessary since the low-cost airlines like Easyjet and Ryanair, refuse to operate under this territory, making the mission very difficult. Furthermore, large amounts of money are also important in order to obtain the material supply crucial for the mission (sangria, hula-hoop, surf board, beach chair, hotel, limosine to travel around in, etc...). 

As compensation ( regalo ) for your help, I promise to deliver you a souvenir for your generous contribution for this trip, a magnificant commemerative magnet from Hawaii for your refridgerator.

Also, you can add to this good cause to all of your facebook contacts, as well as talking about it to all of your friends, family and people that you know ( lama a tus amigos ).  They will be very grateful to you and will be very proud ( muy orgulloso )  to see that you are doing something useful for humanity in your life.

Don&#180;t fail me.  Your help is very important (importante).

Thank you, friends. Gracias amigo

LoLo Murcia



1. LoLo Murcia needs a holidays

2. Save LoLo Murcia from hottest Summer in history

3. LoLo Murcia is a very good friend ( amigo bueno )</description>
  <mission>Save LoLo Murcia from Summer hell</mission>
  <name>Holidays in Hawaii</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1498</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Khw/5vtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
