<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.savetibet.org

At ICT, we fundamentally believe that there must be a political solution based on direct dialogue between the Dalai Lama and his representatives and the People's Republic of China. Just as leaders from virtually all the protracted struggles on this planet have met to talk about their differences, so too the Chinese leaders can meet with the Dalai Lama. Without a negotiated solution for Tibet, China will never legitimize its role there. 

Moreover, to ensure peace and stability in the region, Tibetans must feel that their rights as a people have been acknowledged and understood.

ICT has a 20-year record of achievement advancing the Tibetan cause - and the vision and leadership of the Dalai Lama - in the halls of Congress and in international forums. We strive to mobilize international goodwill in support of the Tibetan people. Our focus today is centered on working with governments to demonstrate meaningful support for Tibet, reaching out to Chinese all over the world, and monitoring conditions inside Tibet.

The International Campaign for Tibet works to promote human rights and democratic freedoms for the people of Tibet. 

ICT:

- monitors and reports on human rights, environmental and socio economic conditions in Tibet,
-advocates for Tibetans imprisoned for their political or religious beliefs,
- works with governments to develop policies and programs to help Tibetans,
- secures humanitarian and development assistance for Tibetans,
- mobilizes individuals and the international community to take action on behalf of Tibetans, and
- promotes self-determination for the Tibetan people through negotiations between the Chinese government and the Dalai Lama.

http://www.savetibet.org

1. China should end human rights abuses in Tibet

2. China should directly engage the Dalai Lama to find a negotiated solution for the Tibetan people</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to return self-determination to the people of Tibet and encourage China to reach a negotiated solution with His Holiness the Dalai Lama.</mission>
  <name>International Campaign for Tibet</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/150</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">110745</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">12297.33</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/B2I/vTHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
