<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Who are the Forgotten Voices?   ORPHANS

Forgotten Voices international (FVI) is a 501(c)(3) international, nonprofit organization that is demonstrating the love of Jesus Christ by equipping local churches in southern Africa to meet the physical and spiritual needs of children orphaned by AIDS in their communities.

Forgotten Voices is about Partnership, Orphans and Hope.

In southern Africa, 500 people die everyday from AIDS related illnesses, creating 1,000 new orphans EVERY DAY. With over 80% unemployment in Zambia &amp; Zimbabwe, there is a need to develop willing leaders ready to serve.  Churches deliver over 50% of social services and are uniquely qualified to deliver local care in a way that gets to the heart of the challenges these children will face. 

Forgotten Voices works with leaders in Africa to develop Local Action Plans.  These plans are sending orphans to school, starting farms, providing HIV tests, offering grief counseling, supplying vitamins, and developing skills in the local community, etc. 

Forgotten Voices is spreading hope by empowering people to believe that they can be a part of painting a more promising picture for orphans in their community!

1. AIDS orphans must be protected &amp; empowered

2. Local people leading local projects is the most effective

3. Empowering people brings hope

4. Asking questions 1st, acting 2nd will help change money waste</description>
  <mission>demonstrate the love of Jesus Christ by equipping local churches in southern Africa to meet the physical &amp; spiritual needs of children orphaned by AIDS in their communities</mission>
  <name>Forgotten Voices: Empowering Local Churches to Care for Orphans</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1509</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1923</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1358.15</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ii/7e/yE/YE/kA/Fm/CG/psS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
