<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>-According to the American Cancer Society's: Cancer Facts &amp; Figures 2006, "Cancer is a group of diseases characterized by uncontrolled growth and spread of abnormal cells.  If the Spread is not controlled, it can result in death."


-Cancer of all types is one of the leading causes of death in the U.S. and throughout the world.


-But, it can be prevented "scientific evidence suggests that about one-third of the 564,830 cancer deaths expected to occur in 2006 will be related to nutrition, physical inactivity, and overweight or obesity." Eating right and exercising are not the only ways to prevent the onset of cancer, "all cancers caused by cigarette smoking and heavy use of alcohol could be prevented completely.  The American Cancer Society estimates that in 2006 about 170,000 cancer deaths are expected to be caused by tobacco use.


-Anyone can develop cancer, that means you and me are at risk, and as you age, your risk increases.


-You, as I do, probably know someone who has battled cancer.  Some of them are not able to beat it, but others have survived and are living perfectly healthy lives today, in part by the contributions to research and treatments made by the American Cancer Society.


-Visit www.cancer.org to learn more.


-Popular news items:
-Cervical cancer, caused by the HPV. http://www.fda.gov/bbs/topics/NEWS/2006/NEW01385.html


-Skin cancer, caused by excessive exposure to the Sun's radiation. http://www.skincancer.org/prevention/index.php


-Breast cancer. http://www.breastcancer.org/prevention.html


-Lung Cancer. http://www.cdc.gov/cancer/lung

1. Help out by volunteering to further cancer research; educate the public about early detection and prevention; advocate for responsible cancer legislat

2. Invest in cancer research by donating to the American Cancer Society, and participate in activities such Relay for Life.

3. Knowing the facts about cancer can save lives. What you eat and drink, how you live, where you work . . . all these factors can affect your risk for c

4. Advocate for increased federal funding for cancer research, government spending on prevention, early detection, treatment, improved navigation through</description>
  <mission>eliminating cancer as a major health problem by preventing cancer, saving lives, and diminishing suffering from cancer, through research, education, advocacy, and service.</mission>
  <name>Join the Fight Against Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1512</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">405184</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">12794.01</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qr/mf/MH/Ti/ls/Zj/fZ/t8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
