<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Do you grow weary of sitting down at your television to eat your microwaved dinner in front of the 8,543,445th repeat of your favourite episode of "Friends" only to find yourself faced with a broadcast about the dangers of global warming and the impact you're having on our fragile environment?

Do you lack the altruism to have even the stirrings of guilt when CAFOD appeals for two pounds a month to sponser a child in Africa to dig a fish pond?

Would you rather gnaw your own arms off than listen to a discussion about who's a more suitable candidate for the 2008 US Presidency?

Does the phrase "nuclear proliferation" contain a few too many syllables for you to be able to really get to grips with?

Us too.

Here at OAS we are commited to one virtue and one virtue alone; Apathy.

We believe that if people cared a good deal less then there would be considerably fewer problems in today's society, mainly because they will no longer be problems.

Don't just take our word for it.

100% of all people surveyed who had never heard of Darfur answered "I don't know" to the question "Is there a crisis in Darfur?"

Is ignorance bliss? We think so.

So join with us. Form a united front in the name of apathy and together we shall make the world a better place.

1. All protests should cease immediately regardless of what they are concerning. All OAS members should be pro-active in ensuring that any know protestors should have spoons waved at them in a threatening manner untill they have no choice but to disperse.

2. Discussing religion and politics is in terribly bad taste. Did your parents teach you nothing?

3. The world "environment" should be removed from the Oxford English Dictionary with immediate effect. Legislation should be introduced to maintain that the phrase "global warming" must be immediately followed by an expression of glee.

4. Trevor MacDonald is amazing. OAS suggests that listening to what he says may be foolish and lead to the unwanted formation of opinions. We are advocating that all news programmes should be axed and replaced by inoffensive pictures of Sir Trev.</description>
  <mission>Educate all people on the futility of their beliefs and re-educate them on the issues that are truly important.</mission>
  <name>Opinions Are Stupid (Particularly When They Belong to Others)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1513</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hW2/JFzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
