<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>DONATING ONLINE THROUGH CANADIAN DIABETES ASSOCIATION

Ways to Give Online

http://www.diabetes.ca/Section_donations/givingonline.asp

    Donating online is quick, easy and absolutely secure. And it is very cost-effective, so your donation goes straight to work helping Canadians with diabetes.

One-time general donation
Make a one-time gift in support of diabetes research, education, service and advocacy.
	
In Memory donation
Express your sympathy to friends and family by making a special gift in memory of a loved one.
	
In Honour donation
Honour someone special by donating to celebrate a birth, a birthday, a wedding, an anniversary or any other special occasion.
	

Monthly donation
An easy, automatic way to provide ongoing support of the work of the Association.
	
Team Diabetes - Pledge a participant online
Participate in a high-performance international event as a Team Diabetes Canada participant, raising money for the Canadian Diabetes Association.
 
Other Ways of Giving
	

Planned giving
Make your gift of a lifetime - a legacy of hope for the future. Planning such an ultimate gift can be one of the most satisfying and exhilarating experiences of your life.
	

Clothesline
Contribute clothing and usable household items supporting the environment and the Association.
	

Diabetes Recycle Ink.
A FREE, convenient way to recycle your printer cartridges, diverting them from landfill while supporting the diabetes cause.
	
Charity Drive
Used Vehicle Donation Program



If you have any questions or comments, you can email the Canadian Diabetes Association at onlinegift@diabetes.ca, or call toll-free.
1-800-BANTING (1-800-226-8464).


1. All people affected by diabetes attain an optimal quality of life. 

2. All people in Canada realize that diabetes is a major health issue. 

3. Ultimately, diabetes is eliminated.</description>
  <mission>To promote the health of Canadians.  </mission>
  <name>Canadian Diabetes Association</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1526</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">18654</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">175.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/NO/uf/Mv/Vx/6I/mq/17eS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
