<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"We are on a journey with the people of Kenya.  They select the destination."- Emely Silver, Executive Director

By listening to their needs, our contacts and partnerships in Kenya and our Kenyan Board members, Irene and Samson Kimenyi, we are able to best allocate our resources and efforts.
 
We are a 501c3 Public Charity regsitered in the state of CT with a chapter in Chicago.  I lead the Chicago Chapter since January 2007.

Our major activities and projects are:

-To send 2 to 3 shipments a year of books, school supplies, medical supplies, assistive devices, computers and other materials to some of the poorest schools, libraries, youth and women groups and communities in Kenya.
-Work on projects with our partners, like building community libraries accross rural Kenya as a means to improve literacy.
-We have an Orphan Support Program were we sponsor orphans and support one of our partners, the Voluntary Counselors Kenya, with their work in raising AIDS awereness and counseling.
-We give Financial and other assistance to some Youth and Women's groups in poor communities in Nairobi, like for example, SHOFCO in Kibera.
-We do mission trips bringing some of our volunteers to work hands on, meet our partners and see the fruits of our efforts.

An important fact about our organization is that NOBODY gets paid, everybody volunteers their time and efforts and 100% of our funds go to our programs and people in most need.

1. We live in a Global community were helping each other is essential

2. The people of Kenya know what they need and we listen to their needs and concerns

3. Our work is a fruit of love and compassion</description>
  <mission>Help in Kenya with Education and Literacy, Medical attention and Improve and End the AIDS Pandemic</mission>
  <name>American Friends of Kenya</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1530</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">104</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yat/szSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
