<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>RVA focuses on both social service and social change. Through our presence in Chicago area emergency rooms, we provide nonjudgmental emotional support to victims of sexual violence, enabling them to become survivors. By providing basic legal and medical information, and referrals to other service organizations, we help the survivor make informed decisions. We also offer survivors continued support through telephone follow-up and our staff of counselors and legal advocates. Through these services, we enable survivors to regain control over their lives as quickly as possible.

A BRIEF OVERVIEW OF SERVICES OFFERED BY RVA: 

For more information visit our website: http://www.rapevictimadvocates.org/

Advocacy:  The RVA medical advocacy program currently works with 12 Chicago-area hospitals. Our medical advocacy services are available 24 hrs a day, 7 days a week, at the ER of 1 of these 12 hospitals. The advocate provides emotional support, medical and legal information, referrals and initial follow-up services to survivors and their significant others. If the survivor requests additional follow-up services, a staff advocate can provide more long-term medical and legal advocacy.

Counseling:  Free and confidential counseling is provided by professional counselors to survivors of sexual assault, childhood sexual abuse, and incest. Survivors can receive individual, couple/family, and group counseling.

Education and Training: RVA&#8217;s Education and Training Department offers a variety of awareness and prevention programming throughout the city of Chicago. Most of our trainings are tailored to fit the specific needs of our audiences. 

RVA's services are free and confidential for survivors of sexual assault.

Your support makes this vital work possible. Around the clock, day after day, year after year, RVA stands ready to support and advocate on behalf of women, children, and men who have suffered sexual violence. We need your support. Please donate generously.


1. Survivors of rape deserve to be treated with dignity and compassion.

2. Services for sexual assault survivors should be free and confidential.</description>
  <mission>RVA has 2 primary goals: to assure that survivors of rape are treated with dignity and compassion; &amp; to affect changes in the way the legal &amp; medical systems &amp; society as a whole respond to survivors.</mission>
  <name>Rape Victim Advocates</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1535</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1047</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">165.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vdm/4jh/dIzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
