<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Since 1989, Trees for the Future has been helping communities around the world plant trees. Through seed distribution, agroforestry training, and our country programs, we have empowered rural groups to restore tree cover to their lands. Planting trees protects the environment and helps to preserve traditional livelihoods and cultures for generations.

Beneficial trees minimize soil erosion, supply forage for animals, and provide a source of fuelwood, but planting trees is difficult when the canopy has disappeared, topsoil has been eroded, and the climate and growing conditions have changed.

Through our network of technicians, volunteers, and community leaders world-wide, our program reaches remote areas and gives local people the knowledge and ability to rehabilitate their environment.

Since 1988, Trees for the Future has helped thousands of communities in Central America, Africa, and Asia improve their livelihoods and their environment by planting nearly 50 million trees. We calculate that these trees remove approximately one million tons of CO2 from the atmosphere each year.

We are also active locally, educating students and communities about global issues, our role in the environment, and energy efficiency.

http://www.plant-trees.org

How to Help
1) SPREAD the word about Trees for the Future! 
2) INVITE everyone you know! 
3) DONATE as little as $5.  Every 10 cents helps plant a tree!

1. It is our duty to protect the environment and work toward sustainable productivity.

2. Tree planting projects must bring immediate and long lasting benefits to the local community.

3. We work with communities to develop tree planting programs to help meet their needs while protecting and improving their environment</description>
  <mission>To help communities around the world plant trees and restore tree cover to degraded lands.</mission>
  <name>Trees for the Future</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1541</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">58800</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5987.61</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Nq/47/ui/bC/uj/qP/fo/8US.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
