<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>**In summary, for a $100 donation, $95.50 goes to the nonprofit, $3 goes to Justgive.org, and $1.50 goes to Project Agape.** &gt;&gt;&gt;you can find more details about this if you scroll to the bottom of the page on click on the word  "Causes" that is in blue and an active link&lt;&lt;&lt;

I RECOMMEND GOING DIRECTLY TO WWW.HACU.NET AND DONATING!!!

THIS IS JUST A PLATFORM OF EXPOSURE I HAVE NO PART IN ANY FINANCIAL TRANSACTIONS.

THE HISPANIC ASSOCIATION OF COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES

The Hispanic Association of Colleges and Universities (HACU) was established in 1986 with a founding membership of eighteen institutions.  Because of HACU&#8217;s exemplary leadership on behalf of the nation&#8217;s youngest and fastest-growing population, the Association rapidly grew in numbers and national impact.

Today, HACU represents more than 450 colleges and universities committed to Hispanic higher education success in the U.S., Puerto Rico, Latin America, Spain and Portugal.  Although our member institutions in the U. S. represent less than 10% of all higher education institutions nationwide, together they are home to more than two-thirds of all Hispanic college students.  HACU is the only national educational association that represents Hispanic-Serving Institutions (HSIs).


1. Financially contribute to an educational cause

2. Provide volunteerism to assist young Latino / Hispanics

3. Create awareness of the possibilities of education/internships for young Latino / Hispanics</description>
  <mission>Allow any person to assist in the advancement of education for Latinos / Hispanics (Go to HACU.net to donate)</mission>
  <name>Help HACU advance Hispanic / Latino Education &amp; Internship Opportunities</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1542</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">857</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/QNF/tcX/DVzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
