<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It is a congenital deformity (often present at birth) of the sternum, which is pressed into the chest, resulting in a caved in or sunken appearance.

Pectus excavatum has impaired cardiac and respiratory function, and sometimes caused pain in the chest and back.

The condition usually progresses during the time of rapid bone growth in pre-teen yrs. Though the cause is not certain it is believed to be genetic.

There are different surgeries for treatment:

The Ravitch technique is a very invasive surgery that was developed in the 1950s to treat the condition. It involves cracking the ribs along the sternum, and reshaping the breastbone, cartilage, and ribs. It is usually kept in place with an apparatus worn around the chest. 

Nuss procedure
Since then, Dr. Donald Nuss, based at Children's Hospital of The King's Daughters in Norfolk, Virginia, has developed a technique that is minimally invasive. The Nuss procedure involves slipping in one or more concave steel bars into the chest, underneath the sternum. The bar is flipped to a convex position so as to push outward on the sternum, correcting the deformity. The bar usually stays in the body for about two yrs, although many surgeons are now moving toward leaving them in for up to five years. When the bones have solidified into place, the bar is removed through outpatient surgery.

1. People with Pectus Excavatum aren't freaks!

2. Pectus Excavatum in most cases needs to be corrected not just for cosmectic purposes and insurance companies should realize this!

3. People should take Pectus Excavatum seriously and realize that people with this are no different from themselves.</description>
  <mission>1) to make people aware 2) for those who have it to be able to discuss their experiences with others</mission>
  <name>Pectus Excavatum Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1544</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">211</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/NLp/siU/76MS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
