<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Toronto, June 5, 2007 &#8211;Mobile Jam Fest (MJF), http://mobilejamfest.com, the world&#8217;s largest youth creativity festival announces international partnerships with Do Something.org, Taking IT Global, and the Toronto Foundation for Student Success to create a user-generated film competition for 14-18 year olds. The competition is designed to encourage youth to create dynamic films on what the Millennium Development Goals (MDG) mean to them. The goals of the MDG/MJF competition are to educate youth on the issues that affect us all at home and abroad such as extreme poverty to halting the spread of HIV/AIDS.

Launching September 4, 2007, youth from around the world will be able to create and upload their film to http://mobilejamfest.com.  Every 8 weeks they will be challenged to create a new film on one of the eight goals &#8211; Eradicate extreme poverty and hunger, Achieve universal primary education, Promote gender equality and empower women, Reduce child mortality, Improve maternal health, Combat HIV/AIDS, malaria and other diseases, Ensure environmental sustainability, Develop a Global Partnership for Development.

Awards will include tuition towards college or university anywhere in the world, as well as Xbox 360 entertainment consoles. At the end of each 8-week competition, anyone may vote for his or her favorite film for the following two weeks. People may view and vote online and with their mobile phones.

&#8220;This competition embraces the values of MJF. It provides an incredible platform for youth to express themselves and creates an excellent teaching tool for parents and teachers to engage youth via their social lifeline &#8211; the internet and their mobile phone.&#8221; Craig Goodwill, Executive Director, MJF.

The MJF website offers participants and teachers tools and tutorials on all elements of the MDG and the creative process. Through MJF, youth will collaborate and learn more about creativity, social justice and the MDG themselves.  


1. Educate youth

2. Engage Youth

3. Create platforms to promote youth creativity</description>
  <mission>To provide youth the platform to educate, inspire and create</mission>
  <name>Millenneum Development Goals Film Competition: Powered by Mobile Jam Fest</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1548</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bec/7vl/WlQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
