<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Akshaya Patra Foundation is the world&#8217;s largest NGO-run midday meal program and feeds 1.2 million underserved children daily in over 7,000 schools in eight states in India.  Akshaya Patra is a public-private partnership that combines good management, innovative technology and smart engineering to deliver school lunch at a fraction of the cost of similar programs in other parts of the world. The National Average cost of an Akshaya Patra meal to feed a child for an entire year is $31. With the government subsidy, on average, $23 feeds two children. For many of the children this is their only complete meal for the day. This gives them an incentive to come to school, stay in school and provides them with the necessary nutrients they need to develop their cognitive abilities to focus on learning.

Through kitchens specially designed by engineers to leverage technology and sourcing its food stocks from local markets, Akshaya Patra is able to reduce costs associated with transportation and food spoilage while supporting the local economy. In a short time, the foundation has grown to become the largest, and certainly most innovative, school lunch program in the world. Akshaya Patra exemplifies what can be accomplished when the public sector, private sector and the civic society collaborate - a cost effective, scalable solution with high quality service delivery. For more information, please visit www.foodforeducation.org. 

Follow us on Twitter: www.twitter.com/AkshayaPatraUSA

1. Fight Hunger

2. Promote Education</description>
  <mission>No child shall be deprived of education because of hunger</mission>
  <name>Akshaya Patra: Food for Education</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1579</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3892</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10362.73</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/TM/Y4/bU/ZE/ai/Ho/We/88S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
