<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Jewish World Watch is coalition of synagogues, churches, schools, and the community to combat genocide and other egregious violations of human rights around the world. It is the mission of Jewish World Watch to:

   1. Develop educational programs to educate the target constituencies;
   2. Activate the target constituencies to generate response from the United Nations and US policy makers; and
   3. Realize resources to provide assistance to the survivors and victims of genocide and egregious violations of human rights. 

1. U.S.:Pushing for, and diplomatically investing in, a UN Security Council resolution imposing targeted sanctions on an expanded list of key leaders of the Sudanese regime and those companies you have already targeted under unilateral US sanctions.

2. U.S.:Taking immediate and concrete action to protect civilians from aerial attack by demanding implementation of a NO FLY zone over Darfur.

3. U.S.:Prepare plans for the non-consensual deployment of hybrid UN-AU troops to protect civilians, should Sudan continue to reject calls for a 20,000 troop force.

4. UN: Please support the imposition of targeted sanctions on key military and civilian leaders in Sudan's majority Party, the NCP, who are responsible for the violence in Darfur. Sanctions should include asset freezes and travel bans, and other appropriate 

5. UN: lease support the imposition of economic sanctions against the regime's commercial entities, including the investigation of offshore accounts and taking steps to steps to close those accounts belonging to the Khartoum government, its leadership, the N

6. UN: Please support the imposition of economic sanctions on Sudan's petroleum sector

7. UN: Please commence immediate planning for enforcement of a no-fly zone over Darfur

8. UN: Please begin planning, on a contingency basis, for a non-consensual deployment of a United Nations peacekeeping force to Darfur if other political and diplomatic efforts fail to change the present government policies.

9. China: Take a public stand against the Sudanese genocide and to exert the significant influence it has over Khartoum to help end this crisis.</description>
  <mission>The mission of Jewish World Watch is to combat genocide and other egregious human rights violations around the world. Our focus at this time is on the genocide in Darfur and the conflict in Congo.</mission>
  <name>Stop Genocide - Jewish World Watch - Do Not Stand Idly By</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1585</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">531</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">614.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uhP/pqR/tzDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
