<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What are Blood Diamonds? 

Blood diamonds, also known as conflict diamonds are diamonds that originate from areas controlled by forces or factions and are used to fund military action in opposition to legitimate and internationally recognized governments, or in contravention of the decisions of the Security Council. 

Profits from conflict diamonds fuel armed conflict in impoverished countries in Africa. Blood diamonds have lead to more than 4 million deaths and the displacement of another 6 million people. The countries most notably affected by conflict diamonds are Sierra Leone, the Republic of Congo, the Ivory Coast, Angola and Liberia. 

What can YOU do? 

American consumers buy 65% of the diamonds that are produced worldwide. As an American citizen and consumer, you CAN make a difference, and you do not even have to go out of your way to do it. When you go to buy a diamond ask the jeweler some questions: 

Where was this diamond mined? 
Am I contributing to the bloodshed in Africa by purchasing this diamond? 
What are you doing, as a diamond user, to stop the conflict diamond trade? 
If the jeweler provides you with information about the diamond's authenticity, in the form of an official certificate of origin, then you can buy the diamond and rest easy, knowing that you are not funding terrorist actions.

If you want to do more to stop blood diamonds or to find out more about the problem visit one of the following websites. 
www.blooddiamondaction.org 
www.globalwitness.org 
www.amnestyusa.org/diamonds 
www.kimberleyprocess.com 

SIGN OUR PETITION!

1. To urge congress to take further steps inforcing and improving the CDTA (Clean Diamond Trade Act)

2. To urge congress to take further steps inforcing and improving the Kimberely Proce.ss</description>
  <mission>We're working on a project to raise advocacy and awareness about Blood Diamonds, and the devastating effects they have on the communities in Africa.
</mission>
  <name>Blood Diamonds</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1586</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2904</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">70.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3oE/7XZ/vUaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
