<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Your Internet provider doesn't get to tell you which websites you can access on your computer. They don't get to tell you that Yahoo will open more quickly than Google because Yahoo paid them more. Or that big business sites will open more quickly than small business sites. Or that an online music site they own will open more quickly than competitors like iTunes. 

That's because of Net Neutrality--the principle that's been in place since the Internet was created that says Internet service providers can't abuse their role as gatekeepers to the Internet by discriminating between websites. But Net Neutrality is now in jeopardy--eliminated recently by the Federal Communications Commission, it will be a thing of the past unless Congress acts quickly.

Dominant telephone and cable companies (like AT&amp;T, Verizon, BellSouth, Comcast, and Time Warner) want to permanently eliminate Net Neutrality so they can put tollbooths on the Internet and prioritize sites that pay them the most. They've been quite blatant about it--here's what one top executive told the Washington Post:

"William L. Smith, chief technology officer for Atlanta-based BellSouth Corp., told reporters and analysts that an Internet service provider such as his firm should be able, for example, to charge Yahoo Inc. for the opportunity to have its search site load faster than that of Google Inc." (Washington Post, December 1, 2005)

If a multi-billion dollar company like Google may get outbid for the right to work properly on people&#8217;s computers, one can imagine the fate of small businesses, nonprofit organizations, activist groups, religious groups, and other everyday Internet users that use the Internet to communicate. 

Congress needs to act quickly to re-instate Net Neutrality back into the law. 


1. Net Neutrality must be preserved

2. The little guy's voice online must be preserved

3. People-powered activism is the key to saving Net Neutrality</description>
  <mission>Preserve Internet freedom through people-powered activism</mission>
  <name>Net Neutrality - Preserving The Little Guy's Voice Online</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/161</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">280</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PpL/1AFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
