<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 1994, Friendship Circle is a non-profit organization with a refreshing approach to helping families of children with special needs. Our innovative programs and creative activities are designed to foster relationships between the children and community teenagers of the Fenkell Volunteer Club by drawing on the love, boundless energy and dynamism of the teenage population. 

Friendship Circle's 23,000 square-foot facility, Ferber Kaufman LifeTown on the Meer Family Friendship Center, offers a unique educational setting for over a thousand public school students with special needs, who utilize the realistic town setting of the Weinberg Village to practice life skills.

In addition, hundreds of children participate in over a dozen weekly recreational, social and educational programs offered by Friendship Circle, as well as summer and winter camps.

Daniel B. Sobel Friendship House also provides assistance, support, guidance and friendship to individuals and families struggling with addiction, isolation and other related crises.
You can learn more about The Friendship Circle by visiting our web site www.friendshipcircle.org.

Why Walk for Friendship?

Walk4Friendship is an annual vehicle for volunteers, families and friends of Friendship Circle to show their appreciation and support through an exciting fundraising opportunity.

Walk4Friendship is a fun-filled event attended by a broad cross-section of people who come together in a proud demonstration of community awareness, solidarity and support.

The money raised at Walk4Friendship supports Friendship Circle's mission to continually cultivate friendships through our wide range of ever-evolving programming.


1. Empowering community teens and adults through volunteerism

2. Raising awareness for people with special needs and influencing society to see their beauty

3. Creating a supportive community for people in recovery</description>
  <mission>bring the community together for a fun family day, while raising funds for Friendship Circle</mission>
  <name>Walk4Friendship</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1630</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">416</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">423.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2v/lE/V2/3G/yd/WK/X0HS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
