<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>1 out of 3 children are brutally murdered and ripped from their mother's womb. 
Planned Parenthood says they help women, but all they do is cause trauma and hurt in women's lives.

Become the voice for the voiceless!!!!!!

www.rockforlife.org
www.myspace.com/rockforlifevc

Over 47 million children have been killed since 1973.
Abortion is the hidden holocaust and we must do something to stop it! 

Side Effects 

-Breast Cancer

Abortion "may be associated with increased breast cancer risk." [American Cancer Society, Cancer Facts &amp; Figures -- 1996, at 12 (1996)]

Women have the right to know that 28 out of 37 worldwide studies have independently linked induced abortion with breast cancer. Thirteen out of fifteen studies conducted on American women report increased risk. 

"The results support the inclusion of induced abortion among significant independent risk factors for breast cancer, regardless of parity or timing of abortion relative to the first term pregnancy. Although the increase in risk was relatively low, the high incidence of both breast cancer and induced abortion suggest a substantial impact of thousands of excess cases per year currently, and a potentially much greater impact in the next century, as the first cohort of women exposed to legal induced abortion continues to age." J. Brind et al., "Induced abortion as an independent risk factor for breast
cancer: a comprehensive review and meta-analysis," Hershey Med. Center, J. Epidemol. Community Health, 1996

What researchers know for certain is that breast cancer is linked significantly to hormone levels in women's bodies. Abortion and contraception disturbs that delicate balance.




 



1. This brutal murder on our unborn children must end! Everyone has a right to live</description>
  <mission>Educate people on the realities of abortion</mission>
  <name>PRO-LIFE. Respect All Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1632</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3756</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">75.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ar/6O/ZJ/bd/76/Vd/IeRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
