<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Confused about who you want to lead our nation once this administration is over with?  

Do you sort of like Hilary, but like Obama or Edwards a little bit more?  

Do you not like any of the candidates, so you are being forced into choosing the "least of the evils" so to speak?

Do you really like any one of the candidates, but you aren't sure if they are quite ready to lead our nation through at least the next four years?  Maybe you like that candidate and think they would do a good job, but you don't think they are electable at all...


If your answer to any one of these questions is yes, consider a man who has already spent eight years as second in command in the White House.  

Consider a man who has already won the Presidential election once before.  Consider a man who is intelligent, experienced, and isn't afraid to speak his mind, regardless of how popular or unpopular an issue might be. 

How would you feel about a man that fits that description exactly, running our nation, and bringing our country back to where we all know it can be.

By now you might have figured out... that man is Al Gore.

Only, there's one problem.  For a number of reasons, he is not yet convinced that it is in either his best interest or our country's best interest for him to make another run for the President's office.  The good news is that he has not yet closed the doors completely on the possibility of running.  However, time is running out, and we must do our part to let him know how badly we, the American people, both want and need him to lead us.

Please join this Cause to voice your support for a Gore Presidential Campaign, and take a moment to sign the petition at http://www.ipetitions.com/petition/algore2008/ .


This is a man that can and will lead our nation in the way America deserves to be lead.  He can and will lead us out of the mess we are currently in, if only we give him the chance.

1. Al Gore should become the next President of the United States of America.

2. We must do our part to let him know we believe in him, and convince Gore to make a run for the President's office.

3. Al Gore is the best Presidential candidate for the well being of America.</description>
  <mission>Do our part in convincing Al Gore to run for President of the United States</mission>
  <name>Al Gore For President 2008</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1642</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">294</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">37.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/OY/qL/m7/Nl/Pb/HU/srVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
