<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>WHAT - Human Rights Watch is the largest human rights organization based in the United States. Human Rights Watch researchers conduct fact-finding investigations into human rights abuses in all regions of the world. Human Rights Watch then publishes those findings in dozens of books and reports every year, generating extensive coverage in local and international media. This publicity helps to embarrass abusive governments in the eyes of their citizens and the world. Human Rights Watch then meets with government officials to urge changes in policy and practice -- at the United Nations, the European Union, in Washington and in capitals around the world. In extreme circumstances, Human Rights Watch presses for the withdrawal of military and economic support from governments that egregiously violate the rights of their people. In moments of crisis, Human Rights Watch provides up-to-the-minute information about conflicts while they are underway. Refugee accounts, which were collected, synthesized and cross-corroborated by our researchers, helped shape the response of the international community to recent wars in Kosovo and Chechnya.

WHY - Human Rights Watch believes that international standards of human rights apply to all people equally, and that sharp vigilance and timely protest can prevent the tragedies of the twentieth century from recurring. At Human Rights Watch, we remain convinced that progress can be made when people of good will organize themselves to make it happen.

HOW - The hallmark and pride of Human Rights Watch is the even-handedness and accuracy of our reporting. To maintain our independence, we do not accept financial support from any government or government-funded agency. We depend entirely on contributions from private foundations and from individuals like you. Please join thousands of other concerned global citizens in supporting the work of Human Rights Watch.

Together, we can make a difference.

1. We stand with victims and activists to prevent discrimination, to uphold political freedom, to protect people from inhumane conduct in wartime, and to bring offenders to justice.

2. We investigate and expose human rights violations and hold abusers accountable.

3. We challenge governments and those who hold power to end abusive practices and respect international human rights law.

4. We enlist the public and the international community to support the cause of human rights for all.</description>
  <mission>Human Rights Watch is dedicated to protecting the human rights of people around the world.</mission>
  <name>Human Rights Watch</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1646</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20558</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">4726.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pM/vb/8k/Nc/su/PY/xE/IfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
