<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>B.S.L (breed Specific Legislation) restricts ownership of certain breeds of dogs.It is a form of racism that is put on dogs.B.S.L creates restrictions and regulations on one specific breed,most commonly the American Pit bull Terrier.
This forces a dog owner to:
-Keep their dog muzzled in Public at all times
-Purchase insurance for the dog
-Keep the dog on its owner's property at all times (no trips to the park, the store, etc.)
-Keep the dog in a specific enclosure at all times.
-Have their dog fixed and to never be breed.

Depending on your location, the restrictions vary.

This is unfair,unjust,cruel to animals and needs to be stopped. 

Breed banning is not a solution to preventing dog bites or attacks. Education of child, parent, dog owner, and the public in general is key to reducing the number of attacks.

*PUNISH THE DEED AND NOT THE BREED*

In Loving Memory of Shadow,Angel and Cyrus.Three of the best dogs ever known to me and also Pit bulls.Friendliest,most loving family members. R.I.P Forever missed and loved...


&#9829;&#9829; Life through a Pit Bull&#8217;s Eyes &#9829;&#9829;

You breed me to be strong,
Now you think you were wrong.
I am man's best friend,
Now you want me to meet my end.
I live to protect the ones that I love,
I'm the best of my breed a step above.
I'm as good as you raise me to be,
I was not born evil can't you see.
I come in different shapes, sizes, and colors,
I'm here to serve my master just like all the others.
My master loves me as if one of their own,
When I walk by there side or fetch a bone.
Here is a little history about my kind,
Always keep these facts in the back of your mind.
I lived in the white house with a President named Teddy,
During the 1st World War, I was an American symbol can&#8217;t you see.
Sgt. Stubby was the most decorated war dog and this is no lie.
I even lived with the little Rascles once upon a time,
I&#8217;ve lived with the brightest man ever known,
Thomas Edison he created the light bulb,
Now that I&#8217;ve given you some history about my kind,
Let me get back to what&#8217;s been on my mind.
I feel for people, who have been attacked,
But you can't put all the blame on my back.
For I'm a creature put on God's great earth,
No knowledge of love or hate before my birth.
Why do you blame us all for a few bad ones?
Do you hate your children because of a few bad sons?
One day I hope you&#8217;ll realize,
For it&#8217;s you that has hate in your eyes.
It&#8217;s not up to you to wipe out a breed,
For only God has the power to do that deed.
So just remember as I run along,
It&#8217;s not my breed, but your perception that&#8217;s all wrong.

(author unknown)

PLEASE IF YOU CAN A DONATION IT WOULD BE GREAT!! SO FAR WE ARE AT A $100 DONATION!!

1. Helping to Stop B.S.L!

2. Educate &amp; Create Awareness 

3. Saving dog's lives by ending ignorance</description>
  <mission>End Breed Specific Legislation Globally through education &amp; creating awareness about breeds and responsible dog ownership.Helping those effected by B.S.L!</mission>
  <name>Help Stop B.S.L Globally! (Breed Specific Legislation) </name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1651</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8934</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">165.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oc/Jn/7t/xr/nF/xA/2e/TDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
