<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society is the world's largest voluntary health organization dedicated to funding blood cancer research, education and patient services. The Society's mission: Cure leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin's disease and myeloma, and improve the quality of life of patients and their families. Since its founding in 1949, the Society has invested more than $483 million for research specifically targeting blood cancers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

Leukemia, lymphoma, and myeloma are all cancers that originate in the bone marrow or lymphatic tissues.  Anyone can get leukemia, lymphoma, or myeloma regardless of their age, gender, or ethnicity and their exact causes are currently unknown.  It is believed some people may have a predisposition to certain blood cancers based upon their exposure to certain chemicals, but even these studies have been inconclusive.  While the exact figures are not known, it is estimated that 785,829 Americans are living with blood cancers today.  In fact, every five minutes another person is diagnosed; the Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society predicts another 118,310 cases will be documented this year alone.  With such a staggering number of Americans suffering from blood cancers it should come as no surprise that a large number also die from their diseases; every ten minutes another person dies from a blood cancer.  This statistic represents 148 people a day, or six people every hour.

1. Accelerate the development of new therapies

2. Increase participation in blood cancer clinical trials

3. Provide navigation assistance to patients at all points in their cancer journeys

4. Make services and information available to 50 percent of all patients within 30 days of diagnosis</description>
  <mission>Cure leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin's disease and myeloma, and improve the quality of life of patients and their families.</mission>
  <name>Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1653</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1630</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">110.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ns/7v/wd/dA/4N/Mm/KiLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
