<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>PETA's goal is "total animal liberation," meaning little contact with humans if any at all. This includes all food products from animals, like milk, eggs, honey, cheese, and butter; any clothing products taken from animals, such as silk, wool, leather, cashmere, and angora; and owning animals as pets.

The group encourages burglary, arson, and destruction of property in order to promote their cause. Also, hardly any of their collected donations go toward saving animals. Instead, the money goes toward paying off convicted arsonists and other criminals.

Although they are radically against "unethical" treatment of animals, each year PETA kills more animals than it saves. From July 1998 to the end of 2003, &lt;b&gt;PETA killed 10,000 animals&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;b&gt;In 2005, they killed 90% of the animals they collected.&lt;/b&gt;

Ingrid Newkirk, the president and co-creator of PETA, has even gone so far as to say that "even if animal research resulted in a cure for AIDS, we would be against it."


To find out more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.animalscam.com"&gt;animalscam.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.consumerfreedom.com"&gt;consumerfreedom.com&lt;/a&gt;

To sign the petition to have PETA's tax-exemption status removed, visit &lt;a href="http://www.consumerfreedom.com/article_detail.cfm/article/154"&gt;http://www.consumerfreedom.com/article_detail.cfm/article/154&lt;/a&gt;

Also, I &lt;b&gt;would NOT&lt;/b&gt; recommend donating through this Facebook application. Instead, if you wish to contribute, you should donate here: &lt;a href="http://www.consumerfreedom.com/donations.cfm"&gt;http://www.consumerfreedom.com/donations.cfm&lt;/a&gt;

Other links to check out (i.e. resources for the description):
http://www.activistcash.com/organization_overview.cfm/oid/21
http://www.consumerfreedom.com/article_detail.cfm/article/134
http://www.consumerfreedom.com/article_detail.cfm/article/154
http://www.petakillsanimals.com/petaKillsAnimals.cfm
http://www.animalscam.com/rights_vs_welfare.cfm

1. Animal welfare, not "total animal liberation[...] by any means necessary."</description>
  <mission>To raise awareness of PETA's true actions</mission>
  <name>PETA Kills Animals</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1660</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2045</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.6</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/H3/MD/3k/PC/YG/Ih/rhDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
