<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Pi Kappa Phi&#8217;s commitment to leadership dates back more than 100 years to our humble roots at the College of Charleston where our founders exemplified leadership in the classroom, on the athletic field, in campus politics, and within the community. Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity was founded to further create leadership opportunities&#8212;by men who made the choice to lead.

Today, on more than 140 campuses across America, Pi Kappa Phi has broadened its commitment to building men who are leaders by choice. Pi Kappa Phi - Eta Sigma (UCLA) Chapter strives to exemplify this ideal by building well-rounded leaders both inside and outside the classroom. In addition to academics, UCLA Pi Kapps are actively involved in philanthropic work, intramural athletics, greek and non-greek social events, community service, and much more.

For over five decades, Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity has been recognizing student leaders for their commitment to academic excellence.  Support our chapter&#8217;s scholarship fund, and help promote academic excellence and lifetime success.

***Your donation is 100% tax deductible. After donating you will receive an e-mail that acts as your receipt, and is valid for tax deduction purposes for any donation up to $250. For any donations above $250, the IRS requires a physical receipt, which will be sent by snail mail by Justgive.org to the address you provide while donating.***

1. To promote scholastic achievement within the fraternity.</description>
  <mission>To promote scholastic achievement within the fraternity by providing financial support and/or monetary reward to those individuals that exhibit academic excellence.</mission>
  <name>Pi Kappa Phi - Eta Sigma Chapter (UCLA) Scholarship Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1672</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/65/Jc/AA/rE/3a/7J/EcZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
