<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Ever get the feeling that vegetarians consider themselves morally superior to you? Like they think that not eating meat makes them so special that their shit doesn't stink? As if when someone stops eating meat, they suddenly become holy and dignified and it excuses them for the years of inconvenience and frustration they inevitably inflict upon their friends, family and co-workers who just want to go to a restaurant and order a damn steak without constantly being reminded that they're going to hell for eating an animal that spends most of its life shitting in a field. 

What does it mean to sponsor a vegetarian? It means that you have to find someone in your life who's a really big pain in everyone's ass every time you want to go out to eat, and then you commit yourself to eating THREE times the amount of meat you'd normally consume to make up for all the meat that your vegetarian buddy isn't eating. It's that simple! That way, you can reverse the guilt trip that they've been laying on us for years by not only neutralizing their cause, but making it actually worse by eating more animals than would have ever been eaten had they not chosen to become vegetarians! 

What if vegetarians say they don't care because we'll become fat by sponsoring them? I've thought about that already. All you have to do is exercise. I know it goes against the being lazy rule that I advocate so much, but this is so spiteful that it more than makes up for the exercise you'll have to do--which means that if you choose the 3 to 1 plan and sponsor a vegetarian, you're being so spiteful that you can't lose!"

- http://www.thebestpageintheuniverse.net/c.cgi?u=sponsor
Maddox is a hero to us all.
Don't send me hate mail, this group is for fun. If you have a problem, e-mail Maddox, not me. Thank you.

1. Vegetarians are not morally superior.

2. Vegetarians shit does stink(probably more than anybodts)

3. This plan(For every animal you don't eat, I'm going to eat three) is bullet proof.</description>
  <mission>Sponsor a Vegetarian</mission>
  <name>For every animal you don't eat, I'm going to eat 3.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1674</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1702</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.01</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ey/Vz/A4/uj/Ps/8P/IkXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
