<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In solidarity with workers in the sex industry, we support sex workers rights to improved working conditions, increased safety and services for workers, and be free from discrimination on behalf of individuals working within both legal and criminalized adult entertainment industries. 

HIPS provides: Mobile Outreach and Education, 24 Hour Hotline, Peer Education and Outreach, Client Advocacy, Professional Education for Service Providers. 

You may also be interested in these links (high concentration in SF/Bay area):

http://www.bayswan.org/
http://www.spreadmagazine.org/
http://www.sexworkersartshow.com/
http://www.sexwork.com/
http://www.desireealliance.org/
http://www.stjamesinfirmary.org
http://www.bayswan.org/swfest.html
http://www.unrepentantwhore.com/
http://www.sweat.org.za/
http://www.swop-usa.org/
http://www.bayswan.org/SFTFP.html
+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

My goal is to raise $1000 for HIPS.  Every little bit helps-- from inviting your friends, sex worker allies and supporters to making a little donation to spreading the word.  Thank you for joining up and your support, whether through recruiting or donation or just being a part of it.  Thanks.  ~Michelle

1. Sex worker rights are human rights, including the freedom of speech, travel, immigration, work, marriage, and parenthood and the right to unemployment insurance, health insurance and housing. 

2. There should be no law which implies systematic zoning of sex work.

3. There should be no law discriminating against sex workers associating and working collectively in order to acquire a high degree of personal security. 

4. Since health checks have historically been used to control &amp; stigmatize sex workers and since we are generally more aware of sexual health than others, mandatory checks for sex workers are unacceptable unless mandatory for all sexually-active adults.

5. Sex workers must have the same social benefits as all other citizens according to the different regulations in different countries. 

6. Sex workers should pay regular taxes on the same basis as other independent contractors and employees, and should receive the same benefits. 

7. Develop educational programs which help the public to understand that the customer plays a crucial role in the sex industry, this role being generally ignored. The customer, like the worker, should not, however, be criminalized or condemned.

8. Organizations of sex workers and ex-sex workers should be supported to further implementation of the above rights. </description>
  <mission>HIPS' mission is to assist female, male, and transgendered individuals engaging in sex work in Washington, DC in leading healthy lives.  </mission>
  <name>Sex Workers Rights and Decriminalization</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1683</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">772</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">165.13</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vB/pU/Wt/6F/NV/5E/6I/kmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
