<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Lanshima Foundation is a nonprofit organization that utilizes sports and education as a means to inspire, educate, and empower the less privileged and disabled individuals to become effective and productive members of our society. In 1989, Vitalis Lanshima lost both of his arms in an electric shock accident but never lost his passion for life and sports. Through sports and education, he acquired a scholarship to study at Bellarmine University in Louisville, Kentucky after setting two world records at the Paralympic Games in Sydney, Australia. This dream would not have been possible without the support of Wiebe Boer, currently a consultant with McKinsey Consulting. Wiebe who studied in Nigeria provided him with a pair of training shoe and a shirt donated by student-athletes at his Alma mater, Calvin College. Today, Lanshima Foundation sets out to do the same.
You may help in many ways:

1. DONATE
-shoes (running and athletic shoes)
-athletic clothes
-textbooks/ reading books
2. SPONSOR A CHILD (list is soon to come!)
3. MONEY! DONATE HOWEVER MUCH AS POSSIBLE!

Once you raise the money you can chose which section of the charity to donate to: 

Education: 
Our mission is to provide quality, affordable education and opportunities for children, youths and adults who are underserved by making available conducive learning environments, technology, materials, scholarships and funding. 

Sports:
Our mission is to use sports as a medium to build and instill confidence and dignity among the less privileged and disabled individuals by recruiting, motivating, and training them to achieve their optimum potential through better training equipment, techniques, facilities and opportunities. 

DONATIONS ON THIS CAUSE SITE GO TO A GENOCIDE FOUNDATION! TO DONATE TO THE LANSHIMA FOUNDATION GO TO THE WEBSITE BELOW 
FOR MORE INFO:

Visit: www.lanshima.com or www.vitalislanshima.com 

Thanks,
Brian Mack
Head of Fundraising
Lanshima Foundation

1. Africa no longer will be pushed to the side, we must confront the issues of poverty, AIDS, and starvation.

2. The Handicapped will not be left out, we will allow them to flourish to what they were destined to be no matter the cost.

3. Life is a gift from God it is a gift that is to be promoted, protected, and defened.</description>
  <mission>We strive to enhance and improve the lives of the less fortunate and handicapped individuals in Africa.</mission>
  <name>Lanshima Foudation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1688</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">63</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Tw/Nt/Mu/i2/8v/SN/WPvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
