<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Believe In Tomorrow Children's Foundation began in 1982 as a non-profit organization with a mission to provide unique programs that bring comfort, joy and hope to critically ill children and their families, enabling them to renew their spirits mentally and physically.  Believe In Tomorrow provides unique, supportive programs and services to more than 38,000 children each year.  Our programs include Children's Hospital and Respite Housing and Hands On Adventures that provide ongoing support to children and families from the child's diagnosis to the end of the treatment process. 

Believe In Tomorrow owns and operates The Children's House at Johns Hopkins in Baltimore, MD, The Believe In Tomorrow House By The Sea and the Believe In Tomorrow House On the Bay in Ocean City, MD and The Believe In Tomorrow House on Fenwick Island in Delaware and The Believe In Tomorrow House on Wisp Mountain in McHenry, Md. Hospital and Respite Housing is expanding throughout the U.S. with our newest facility, The Believe In Tomorrow House at Pinnacle Falls in Hendersonville N.C. slated to open in 2009. 


1. Keep families together during a child's medical crisis and maintain the gentle cadence of normal family life to positively influence healing

2. Provide ongoing support to children and their families during the child's treatment procee, beginning immediately at diagnosis. 

3. Prioritizing service for the critically-ill children of the United States Military personnel.</description>
  <mission>We provide extraordinary hospital and respite housing services to critically ill children and their families.</mission>
  <name>Believe In Tomorrow Children's Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1689</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1303</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3215.38</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/o1/Pm/Vl/P7/bW/rX/hm/25S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
