<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>During the era in which the seal hunt was banned by the Canadian Government, the seal population in the Maritime Canadian region exploded to the point that the excessive population of seals was decimating the fish population in surrounding areas.

Had this trend continued, the endangerment of several fish species would have been guaranteed, further contributing to the poor economic conditions of the local residents as well as causing an ecological collapse on a potentially global scale.

Climate change has forced the seals only natural predator, the Polar Bear, to relocate new areas, thereby creating an ecological crisis where the seal population can go unchecked, ultimately causing such a potential ecological disaster.

Celebrities and protestors have done their fair share to ensure this problem worsens.  Traveling to Maritime Canada from Europe aboard a jet airliner causes as many Green House emissions as a single diesel powered vehicle for an entire year, so one is left to wonder, how much do celebrities like Paul Mccarthy really care about the seals if they are willing to contribute to their potential extinction.

A report prepared by the Independent Veterinarians Working Group, under the direction of the World Wildlife Foundation stated in 2005 that: &#8220;Perception of the seal hunt seems to be based largely on emotion, and on visual images that are often difficult even for experienced observers to interpret with certainty.&#8221;

People protesting the seal hunt must control their emotions and take an objective look at these issues.  To act out of emotions on issues such as the seal hunt is to make ignorant and wrong decisions that will have severe consequences on a global scale.

1. Canada's seal hunt must continue indefinitely 

2. Stop climate change</description>
  <mission>Keep the seal hunt going</mission>
  <name>Continue the Seal Hunt</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1723</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1721</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ox/7z/e1/kW/07/0e/yBxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
