<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The 1960's and 70's saw what was probably the largest and most influential youth revolution ever.  Millions of young people began trying to change the world around them and make their views known.  All across the nation, and world, young people protested and campaigned for what they believed in.  Many of them left their traditional values for more contemporary views, often settling in communes and specialized living and community projects.  Those young people shared a uniqe and inspiring passion for justice, democracy, and reform.  They left lasting impacts that our generation has failed to live up to.  In fact, we're no where close.  Today most young people are push-overs, giving in all too easily to what the government and society demand, and simply going with the flow, even if the flow goes against their true beliefs and values.  Youth today worry less and less about politics and social policy, and instead listen to what the media and society tells them, instead of thinking for themselves.  The youth of today needs to realize its value, get informed, and stand up for its beliefs.  

In 1967, some 70,000 demonstators converged on the Pentagon in an attempt to levitate it via meditation and protest.  Though radical, mass numbers of people acted on what they believed.  They banded together to show the world what peace was about.  Today this could never happen, and it's a shame.  As youth of the world, we should seek to rekindle the flame of previous youth movements and begin again the youth movement.  

One way to make a difference is to donate to our cause.  You can do so through Facebook.  The money is directy donated through Facebook to the Constitutional Rights Foundation which encourages young people to get involved and learn about their constitutional rights and freedoms.

1. Youth of the world must get informed.

2. As youth, we must stand up for our beliefs and rights.

3. World youth must rekindle the passion of previous generations and band together to promote our beliefs.

4. The summer of 2007 is the 40th anniversary of the Summer of Love, 1967.  Celebrate!</description>
  <mission>To recreate the passion of the 60's and 70's youth to possitively influence our world and make our views heard. </mission>
  <name>Youth Revolution: Make A Difference</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1735</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">164</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Sn/vY/cN/Zb/J3/Nw/FORS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
