<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"The legislation would take billions in taxpayer dollars to build up to 10 more dirty coal plants, provide taxpayer subsidies when the fuel can't compete on the open market, and guarantee that the government will buy this fuel no matter what.3

The industry promises to clean up after itself, but "clean coal" doesn't exist yet&#8212;it's pure fiction. While some technology is being tested to capture the greenhouse gas before it goes into the air, no one knows if it will work. But the plants will be built regardless.

To make matters worse, the financial outlook on this technology is shaky, which means taxpayers could be left holding the bag. According to an MIT study, we could spend $70 billion to replace just 10 percent of current gasoline use.4 And by the time we bring the technology to market, it is likely that cheaper, cleaner fuels will be available for less money.  

These snake oil salesmen are in the Capitol in force&#8212;selling Congress a line that kicking our oil habit is easy if we just commit billions in taxpayer money to coal. And some in Congress are buying it&#8212;even folks who have been with us thus far on the climate crisis. But with this bill, they're gambling with the future of our planet.

Can you sign our petition telling Congress to vote no on coal in the upcoming energy package?" 

-MoveOn.Org

1. Congress must be stopped.

2. Liquid coal would be at least 2 times worse than oil.

3. Sign the petition (no spaces) - http://pol.moveon.org/stopkingcoal/one_ click_sign.pl?id=10484- 6382502-lPBBzf&amp;t=4</description>
  <mission>stop Congress from implementing liquid coal as an alternative to oil.</mission>
  <name>Liquid coal fuel is wrong!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1737</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">286</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/YS/3l/kN/eL/0Z/Nc/skvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
