<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Project Friendship 2007: Every Nation

Greetings in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ. Campus Crusade for Christ International is an interdenominational ministry committed to taking the gospel of Jesus Christ to all nations. Our ministry began in 1951 at UCLA by Dr. Bill Bright and has now grown into a worldwide mission organization spanning to 196 countries around the world. currently, 30,000 full-tie staff workers, and 200,000 associate volunteers are serving in CCC, and they are all fully dedicated to the cause of fulfilling the Great Commission. We cooperate with millions of Christians from churches of many denominations, and hundreds of other Christian organizations around the world, and we are helping Christians grow in their faith and share the Gospel message with others.

Our goal for this decade is to give every person an opportunity to find new life in Jesus Christ. Our commitment is based up our Lord's command:

"All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the son and of the Holy Spirit, and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age." (Matthew 28:18-20)

Over 500 students and 40 staff will be sharing the gospel of our risen Lord Jesus Christ in 10 countries through KCCC Summer Mission "Project Friendship 2007." This summer we will be sending students to Japan, Mongolia, East Asia, Central Asia, Asia Minor, Cambodia, Indonesia, Laos, Thailand, and Hawaii. I would like to challenge you to help fulfill God's Great Commission by support our mission project through your prayers and financial support. Join with us in this great time of harvest and help us change the world for Christ.

Korea Campus Crusade for Christ, L.A.
Dong Whan Kim, Director

You will be donating to my mission team going to Thailand this summer. We will be leaving on June 28, 2007.

1. To fulfill the great commission.</description>
  <mission>spread the gospel in Thailand this summer.</mission>
  <name>KCCC Thailand missions (Team #29)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1740</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ue0/UuK/zblS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
