<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>From younglife.org:
"Picture a sea of teenage faces in a crowded school hallway. Some kids are trying to blend in; some are being carried along by the crowd; others are deliberately swimming against the tide. All of them are trying to find their way in a culture that is crowded with the noise and glare of media messages and peer expectations.

Young Life seeks to carry the message of Jesus Christ into that tumultuous tide and points teenagers toward life as they were created to live it. Since 1941, the dynamic that has characterized Young Life is its commitment to relationships &#8212; Young Life leaders meeting kids on their turf in the interest of friendship. As leaders get to know teenagers, they are able to share the love of Jesus Christ through platforms like Young Life club, Campaigners and trips to camp.

Whether kids are seeking answers or just acceptance, Young Life is there for them, armed with a desire for fun and the ultimate message of hope."

1. Every adolescent will have the opportunity to meet Jesus Christ and follow Him.

2. Living according to and communicating the whole Gospel of Jesus Christ.

3. Carrying out our mission under the authority of Scripture and relying on the Holy Spirit to empower our ministry.

4. Encouraging the welfare and spiritual health of those who do this ministry, that they may minister out of a consistent and growing relationship with Christ and His followers.

5. Researching and developing innovative approaches to reaching uncommitted, disinterested kids around the world.

6. Reaching adolescents of all social, cultural, economic and ethnic backgrounds throughout the world.

7. Working with followers of Christ from a variety of traditions and local churches around the world.

8. Welcoming all those whom God calls to our mission -- men and women of all races, staff and volunteers -- who are linked to a common purpose of introducing adolescents to Jesus Christ.

9. Observing the highest standards of stewardship of all the resources placed in our trust.</description>
  <mission>Introducing adolescents to Jesus Christ and helping them grow in their faith.</mission>
  <name>Global Young Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1747</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8788</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">344.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GA/PM/W1/fV/tu/Bm/a0LS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
