<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>United States of America, Bill of Rights, Amendment One says:
"Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press; or the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress of grievances."

"Did you ever hear anyone say, 'That work had better be banned because I might read it and it might be very damaging to me'?"
-Joseph Henry Jackson

"I hope people realize that banning the truth, as well as fiction, is proof that ignorance is dangerous to freedom."
-Jen

"You have not converted a man because you have silenced him."
-John Morley

"I never knew a girl who was ruined by a book. "
-James Walker

"The most common examples of book censorship are in schools and public libraries, and all those examples are most often involving children's literature. Political groups attempt to remove books from library shelves because those books use 'naughty' words, do not have happy endings... or because they have too many rainbows."
-Herbert Foerstel

People are banning books to try to keep the minds of others, mainly children, innocent and unharmed from things in the real world, such as the worlds we see in books. 

Please, don't ban our books, for it is like banning enlightenment.  The truth, no matter how scary, brings understanding. The more we understand, the more unafraid we are, which brings us to be more prepared to face the things that life throws at us.

1. Most threatened books have no good reasons to be taken off the shelves.

2. People should be able to explore the world of books without being told what they can and can't read

3. Banning books is against the US Constitution's 1st Amendment</description>
  <mission>Keep banned and challenged books in our library!</mission>
  <name>I Love Banned Books</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1750</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">35518</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">823.03</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DD/oG/KA/Pl/Ul/h0/t7YS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
