<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Little Brothers programs are offered free of any charges to elders without benefit of family or adequate social supports. The following programs are offered: Intergenerational Matching Program, bringing elders and volunteers together in one-on-one friendly and supportive relationships; Holiday Visitation/Meal Programs, providing companionship and nutritious home delivered meals on 6 major holidays annually as well as hosting sit-down dinners; Special Events Programs, providing monthly opportunities for elders and volunteers to gather for socialization, recreation and good food; On-Call Services, providing such needed services as home-delivered food packages from our pantry and medical transportation/escorts; Telephone Reassurance Program, maintaining frequent contact with frail elders. Little Brother's staff and volunteers also advocate on behalf of the elderly friends, helping them secure services that our organization does not provide. And through our Volunteer Program we offer people the opportunity to share their lives with older persons and to offer service to their community.
&lt;br&gt;
The elderly women and men who turn to us for support are met as friends, not as clients of the organization. Since we are not a United Way or government agency, we rely solely on the support of individual donors, volunteers, foundations and corporations. Little Brothers strives to work with each individual elder in a compassionate, loving manner, offering services to help the elder live independently and with dignity. 

1. Assist low-income isolated elderly who are 70 years or older, live on less than $8,000 a year,  living alone in the city of Boston and have little to no friends or family

2. Advocate on behalf of the elderly friends, helping them secure services that our organization does not provide

3. Providing such needed services as home-delivered food packages from our pantry and medical transportation/escorts

4.  Strive to work with each individual elder in a compassionate, loving manner, offering services to help the elder live independently and with dignity

5. Providing monthly opportunities for elders and volunteers to gather for socialization, recreation and good food

6. LBFOE has committed itself to enriching the lives of the elderly and their volunteers by fostering friendships that celebrate life.</description>
  <mission>Assist low-income isolated elderly living alone in the city of Boston. Our elders are 70 years or older, live on less than $8,000 a year and have little to no friends or family</mission>
  <name>Little Brothers Friends of the Elderly</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1760</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">94</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">70.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Bp/8i/uD/T1/Bh/zO/TD6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
