<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>When we are knowledgeable about problems in the world, then we can fully understand what is at stake and have the passion to fix them and improve the quality of life for others. 

The Facts:
~Every 3 seconds a child dies from extreme poverty.

~Every week AIDS claims as many lives as ALL of the American fatalities in the Vietnam war

~6,000 children are orphaned by AIDS everyday

~16,000 children die everyday from starvation

~Men worldwide: One out of every four are illiterate (870 million)
  Women worldwide: Higher than men at 33%

~1.2 billion people (20%) of the world's population live on less than one dollar per day. 

~20% of the world's population (1.2 billion people) controls less than 1% of the world's wealth.

What can I do to help?
There is a lot that can be done. The number one thing is telling other people. There are a lot of people who are  oblivious to the problems happening in Africa. Secondly, have fund raisers to inform others and make money for donation.  The Third thing is donate. Lastly, Join and get involved with organizations such as The One Campaign, Unicef, Global Fund to Fight Aids, Malaria No More and Save the Children to name a few. 

Where does the money go?
$1 is the average cost of saving a life from Malaria
$3 can buy one dose of anti-retroviral drugs for an HIV positive mother AND child
$20 can cover all costs to send a child to school in an Urban Slum in Africa for a month
$40 could pay for vital healthcare for one month for African street children
$50 can provide a family of 5 in Africa with enough food to last for one week. 
$101 can provide 10 families with Basic Family Water kits for use during emergency situations.
$183 can provide a 'School in a Box' - all the supplies and materials for a teacher to teach up to 80 students.
$244 can buy an Emergency Health Kit that provides basic drugs, medical supplies, and equipment for 1,000 people for 3 months.



1. Food, water and health care are human rights.

2. There are several solutions to end extreme poverty around the world.

3. Every little contribution that someone gives, adds up to make a huge difference.

4. No one should be dieing of hunger in a world of plenty.</description>
  <mission>I want people to feel empowered to help others through the learning of issues such as AIDS, Starvation, Disease, Displacement, Genocide, Sexualized Violence, and other atrocious realities.</mission>
  <name>Compassion For Africa Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1809</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2432</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">354.04</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yz/vY/6B/3f/UK/k4/eW/nHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
