<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>When we were little, they told us we were the future. I guess I either didn't believe them or didn't care.

When I was little, I had my own ideas: I thought that everything that happened was part of a plan. I don&#8217;t even mean that in a religious sort of way, I just liked to think that nothing I did was meaningless. I&#8217;m not so sure anymore&#8230; But I&#8217;d like to be.

What we&#8217;ve been doing&#8230; It&#8217;s just not working.

We divide ourselves into little groups based on the clothes we wear and the music we listen to, and we stick to them. Those of us who care enough divide ourselves further, taking up names like &#8220;liberal&#8221; and &#8220;conservative&#8221;, because we feel the need to generalize our politics. And then, we laugh. We laugh at the other groups, we laugh at each other, we laugh at those who are different, and we laugh at the world. And if you can&#8217;t laugh&#8230; Then you&#8217;re going to get laughed at.

Well I&#8217;m tired of laughing.

What I&#8217;m asking is for us to rise above all of our stereotypical crap, and dedicate ourselves to something more important than our MP3 players.
What I&#8217;m asking is, just once, for us to care.

Think about who you are. Think about where you fit in, and the decisions you&#8217;ve made. Think about yourself as a little kid, and imagine every single one of your memories leading up to right now.

What lives have you touched?

You are not the clothes you wear, or the color of your iPod, the slang you use, or whatever you choose to poison your body with.

We&#8217;ve got to wake up. The next time you see someone who needs help, help them. The next time you see someone being a jerk, call them out on it. The next time someone tells you you can&#8217;t make a difference, you don&#8217;t need to respond. Just make it. And to do that, you don&#8217;t need to be a goth, or a prep, or an emo, or a punk, or nerd. That only makes things harder. Just be you.

Forget about all of your prejudices, and about what society has taught you.
Be a good human.

Wake up.
Change the world.
Rise above.

1. Wake up.

2. Change the world.

3. Rise above.</description>
  <mission>show the world that young people care about more than themselves.</mission>
  <name>Rise Above</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1823</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">47</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7b/8Q/00/aT/p5/6R/6OXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
