<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Please visit www.wfp.org or www.wfpusa.org to learn more.

----------------
The World Food Program (WFP) is the largest international food aid organization in the world and the United Nations&#8217; frontline agency in the fight against hunger.  Every year, WFP feeds an average of 90 million people, more than half of them children, in over 80 countries. 

WFP&#8217;s ultimate goal is to eliminate hunger.  In partnership with other organizations, WFP provides life-saving food in emergency situations, such as conflict and natural disasters.  It also provides food for development programs like school feeding and food for work projects that help promote basic education, social stability, and self-reliance. 

WFP relies entirely on voluntary contributions to operate.  It is the only United Nations (UN) agency that does not receive regular allocations from the UN budget.  Contributions come from governments, corporations, organizations, and individuals. 

WFP&#8217;s logistical capacity stretches across deserts, mountains, and oceans, deep into the world&#8217;s poorest countries, enabling it to deliver food to nearly any corner of the globe.  On any given day, WFP has 20 planes in the air, 40 ships on the seas, and over 5,000 trucks on the ground delivering food to those in need. 

NEWS

**Become a fan of Friends of the World Food Program and help end global hunger.


1. Affecting 1 in 7 individuals on the planet each day, hunger kills more people than AIDS, malaria and tuberculosis combined.

2. The world has produced more than enough food to feed itself since the 1960s.

3. Yet, around the world, nearly 1 billion people are chronically hungry.</description>
  <mission>WFP works to put hunger at the center of the international agenda, promoting policies, strategies and operations that directly benefit the poor and hungry.</mission>
  <name>United Nations World Food Programme</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1825</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">43473</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">16603.98</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ex/3b/P1/dC/iR/8U/Q8/niS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
