<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>People across the United States have bought into cultures of extremes, governed by the rule of ignorance and a tyranny of false logic.  The most dangerous of these extreme elements in the American public is the rising wave of a bourgeois cultural fad of disrespect and self-defeatism targeted at the political system of the United States, its legitimately elected leadership and the proud cultural past of our nation.  This culture is manifest in the present as the &#8220;I hate George Bush culture&#8221; which has come to grip such a large population of American youth.  Beyond any basis in logic or personal belief, large portions of the American public have simply joined a bandwagon of disrespect calling for such illogical conclusions such as the impeachment of President Bush for war crimes.  Among all the ludicrous statements made by the American left-wing, calling for the trial of the president of the United States with absolutely no logical basis is the most appalling.  These same leftists cry for the end of the &#8220;Bush Regime&#8221;; but where have the protests throughout our history been against the &#8220;Adams Regime,&#8221; the &#8220;Roosevelt Regime&#8221; and the &#8220;Kennedy Regime&#8221;; where is the current public outrage against the possible establishment of a &#8220;Clinton Regime&#8221;.  The American public has never taken issue with political involvement among in the same family because the legitimate aspiration of relations has been considered honorable.  The &#8220;I hate George Bush&#8221; culture has seriously altered the international perception of the United States and limited its foreign policy effectiveness.  Our adversaries in the modern world gain strength from the flagrant disrespect and irrationality of many Americans.  This virulent disunity has increased international scorn of the United States and encouraged Russia to withdraw diplomatic friendship and test the waters of confrontation.  Without a basis in prudence and rationalism a democratic society cannot prevent the endangerment of its political principles.

1. Democratic politicians and party leadership should denounce disrespectful and irrational actions by leftist organizations

2. Republican politicians and party members should encourage rationality in Republican politics in place of the literal religion that has so much influence currently

3. All self-respecting individuals should voice any political beliefs they hold in a respectful and decent manner</description>
  <mission>Reinvigorate the values of respect, patriotism, prudence and rationalism in American society</mission>
  <name>Americans for a Proud Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1827</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">48</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/OY/NI/km/ER/1j/W0/hT1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
