<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;b&gt;
Wherever children are suffering as a result of war, it is our responsibility to do our utmost to provide the protection and basic amenities which are every child's rights. As such is the case, we humbly request; will you please donate as much as you can. Be it your time or be it your money, for even pennies at a time can provide the building block to build a better future for these children...

All the money collected goes straight to the children by providing them with food, clothes, shelter, education and medical attention...

These children suffer everyday from hunger, disease, and without us, eventually a dark future... Imagine if one of these children were your sister, brother, niece, nephew, child, or friend...

So open up your hearts, minds, and wallets and donate. Give them a chance... A chance to enjoy a little bit of what life has to offer them instead of war, hunger and disease... 
&lt;/b&gt;

Help by donating and raising awareness about what bad circumstances our Afghan Children are in right now...

WHERE DOES THE MONEY GO ??? All the money that is donated by facebook members goes DIRECTLY to the organization called Help the Afghan Children Inc. If you look above the page which tells you which cause you have joined, it will also inform you about where your donations will go (if you grace them with such). Organization have an income tax id number. The income tax id number could be used by memebers to look up information on the organization. 

The money goes to the organization, which takes care of the rest (not the creator or Admin). We're just trying to raise awareness and donations for our Afghan children !!!

 VISIT THEIR WEBSITE: http://www.htac.org

HERE IS THE ANNUAL REPORT: http://www.helptheafghanchildren.org/images/2005%20Annual%20Report.pdf 



1. Minimize the sufferings of Afghan children...

2. Spread the word and the love...

3. Donate to the cause...</description>
  <mission>Provide children with food, clothes, shelter, education and medical attention </mission>
  <name>Afghan Children of War</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1839</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8540</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3755.03</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ks/hI/7I/ov/Ai/2P/xwyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
