<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The goal of The Children's Heart Foundation is to bring health, hope and happiness to children impacted by congenital heart defects, the number one birth defect in the United States. We accomplish this goal by funding the most promising research to advance the diagnosis, treatment and prevention of congenital heart defects. 
We believe that research is the best way to win the battle against congenital heart defects &#8211; research that will impact children now and in the future and ultimately save lives. 

- Congenital Heart Defects (CHDs) are America&#8217;s number one birth defect, affecting nearly one out of every 100 births, or 40,000 babies a year. 

- CHDs are responsible for 1/3 of all birth defect related deaths, making CHD the number one cause of birth defect related deaths. 

- More than 91,000 life years are lost each year in the United States because of CHDs.
 
- More than 50 % of all children born with CHD will require a least one invasive surgery in their lifetime. 20% of these children will not survive past their first year of life! 

- Twice as many children die from CHD each year in the United States than from all forms of childhood cancer combined. 

For more information, please visit: http://www.childrensheartfoundation.org


1. Our mission: To fund the most promising research to advance the diagnosis, treatment and prevention of congenital heart defects.

2. Please visit our website: www.childrensheartfoundation.org </description>
  <mission>The Children's Heart Foundation's mission is to fund the most promising research to advance the diagnosis, treatment and prevention of Congenital Heart Defects.</mission>
  <name>The Children's Heart Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1841</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">25522</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5414.03</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Cj/rQ/As/4l/L6/LS/ma/GWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
