<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Like so many others, I had become a slave to the IKEA nesting instinct."

"I would flip through catalogs and wonder what kind of dining set defines me as a person?"

"We used to read pornography. Now it was the Horchow Collection."

"We're consumers. We're by-products of a lifestyle obsession. Murder, crime, poverty -- these things don't concern me. What concerns me is celebrity magazines, television with five hundred channels, some guy's name on my underwear. Rogaine, Viagra, Olestra."

"The things you own, end up owing you."

"... an entire generation pumping gas and waiting tables; they're slaves with white collars. Advertisements have them chasing cars and clothes, working jobs we hate so we can buy shit they don't need. We are the middle children of history, man. No purpose or place. We have no great war, or great depression. Our great war is a spiritual war. Our great depression is our lives. We've all been raised by television to believe that one day we'll all be millionaires and movie gods and rock stars, but we won't. And we're learning slowly that fact. And we're very, very pissed off."

"In the world I see, you're stalking elk through the damp canyon forests around the ruins of Rockefeller Center. You will wear leather clothes that last you the rest of your life. You will climb the wrist-thick kudzu vines that wrap the Sears Tower. You will see tiny figures pounding corn and laying-strips of venison on the empty car pool lane of the ruins of a superhighway."

1. The first rule of Project Mayhem is you do not ask questions.

2. The second rule of Project Mayhem is you do not ask questions.

3. The Third rule of Project Mayhem is no excuses.

4. The fourth rule of Project Mayhem is no lies.

5. The fifth rule of Project Mayhem is you have to trust Tyler.

6. no questions, no questions, no excuses, and no lies.</description>
  <mission>End the consumerism and materialism and the governing institutions established to protect and to promote the said infirmities that plague our already degenerate society.</mission>
  <name>Project Mayhem</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1844</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">504</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zr/Hb/6u/Tt/XC/ND/kj7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
