<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Interstitial cystitis (IC) is a chronic and often severe inflammation and/or injury to the bladder wall. Primary symptoms are urinary frequency, urgency, and severe lower abdominal pain. IC affects mostly women but about 10% of patients are men.
  

SYMPTOMS=
Frequency: Day and/or night frequency of urination (up to 60 times a day in severe cases). 
Urgency: The sensation of having to urinate immediately, which may also be accompanied by pain, pressure or spasms.
Pain: Can be in the lower abdominal, urethral or vaginal area. Pain is also frequently associated with sexual intercourse. Men with IC may experience testicular, scrotal and/or perineal pain, and painful ejaculation.


TREATMENTS=
At this time there is no cure for IC. However, a majority of patients are helped by one/more of the following:

ORAL MEDICATIONS:
Elmiron&#174; (pentosan polysulfate sodium): Elmiron received FDA approval in 1996. It is the only oral medication approved specifically for use in IC. It is believed to work by repairing a thin or damaged bladder lining.
Antidepressants: Tricyclic antidepressants such as Elavil&#174; (amitriptyline) have been shown to help with both the pain and frequency of IC. In IC, these medications are used for their anti-pain properties, not as a treatment for depression.


BLADDER DISTENTION: The bladder is stretched by filling it with water under general anesthesia. This is part of the diagnostic procedure for IC, and may be therapeutic as well.

DMSO (dimethyl sulfoxide): This medication is instilled directly into the bladder. It is believed to work as an anti-inflammatory agent and therefore reduces pain. DMSO can be mixed with steroids, heparin, and/or local anesthetics to form a bladder "cocktail."


DIET=
Eliminating certain foods (acidic, spicy) may decrease the severity of IC symptoms. Also, smoking, drinking coffee or tea, and alcoholic beverages may aggravate IC. 

(from ic-help.org and ic-network.com)

1. Interstitial Cystitis is a disability.

2. IC affects over 1 million people in the US, mostly women.</description>
  <mission>Spread information about this debilitating bladder disease</mission>
  <name>Interstitial Cystitis Help &amp; Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1851</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2056</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">557.33</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/03/Tl/2t/Bi/O0/XI/0c7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
