<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>USA for UNHCR supports the UN Refugee Agency's (UNHCR) lifesaving operations around the world to protect refugees, internally displaced people, and former refugees who are returning home. 

In more than five decades, the UN Refugee Agency has helped an estimated 50 million people restart their lives. Today, a staff of approximately 6,300 people in more than 110 countries continue to help 32.9 million persons--providing protection, shelter, clean water, health services, education, and other humanitarian assistance.   UNHCR is working in Sudan (Darfur), Afghanistan, Iraq, Colombia, Pakistan and many other countries worldwide. 


HOW CAN YOU HELP?
- JOIN the cause
- SHARE the cause on your own wall
- INVITE your friends by signing the 'Invite Pledge'
- DONATE your status
- FEATURE the cause in your profile
- SIGN UP for notifications and emails to stay informed
- BECOME a fan of USA for UNHCR's public profile 
- DONATE to the Cause: All donations are tax deductible, processed through Network for Good, and benefit USA for UNHCR, a 501(c)3 organization dedicated to raising support and awareness for the work of the UN Refugee Agency.



The UN Refugee Agency has been quick to respond to the crisis, but the unfolding emergency requires immediate support by donors. Tents, sleeping mats, and blankets are desperately needed to shelter those innocents whose homes and possessions have been destroyed by war.


To learn more please visit us at www.UNrefugees.org.


1. Provide protection, shelter, walter, health services, and education to people forced to flee their homes due to violence, persecution, and warfare.</description>
  <mission>The UN Refugee Agency protects and assists refugees and internally displaced people in over a hundred countries around the world.</mission>
  <name>UNHCR: The UN Refugee Agency</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1860</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">27466</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">6508.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rp/so/qK/Fq/Js/VG/bc/JiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
