<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>From the Cardinal Kung Foundation:

We request your Urgent Assistance to the Persecuted Underground Church in China Which Has Been Illegal in Communist China for over 50 Years.

The promise of religious freedom in China is a false one. Despite the Chinese Government's ratification of several human rights treaties, its stated adherence to the UN Declaration of Human Rights, and a provision in the Chinese Constitution guaranteeing freedom of religion and belief, China continues to commit serious violations of religious freedom and belief.  The Chinese Government severely and systematically persecutes members of China's spiritual communities, including Roman Catholics, Protestants, Evangelical Christians, Tibetan Buddhists, Uighur Muslims, and members of the Falun Gong movement.

The widespread persecution of individuals on the basis of their religion and belief in China has been well-documented by the U.S. State Department, the United States Commission on International Freedom, religious organizations, and other non-governmental organizations.  The Secretary of State had concluded that the Chinese Government pervasively violates the right to freedom of religion and belief, and labeled China for the seventh straight year a "country of particular concern" under the 1998 International Religious Freedom Act.

China turned Communist in 1949.  Almost immediately, the new Communist government started putting pressure on the Roman Catholic Church.  By 1953, many Chinese priests and laypersons were arrested and dying in jail.  

Currently, every one of the approximately 45 bishops of the underground Roman Catholic Church is either in jail, under house arrest, under strict surveillance, or in hiding. 

AT THE SAME TIME&#8230; THE CHURCH IS GROWING. There are now an estimated 15-20 million Catholics and over 45 million Protestants in China today. Let us praise Him!

No Gift Is Too Small


1. Financial support for women and men entering ministries and seminary schools in China

2. Legalization of the Church in China and free practice of religion

3. Prayer and moral support for the millions in the underground Church</description>
  <mission>Bring relief to the millions of underground Christian sisters and brothers proclaiming the good news in Mainland China</mission>
  <name>Persecuted and Underground: The Church in China</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1866</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4502</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">175.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ha/aI/kv/A0/Kz/6E/Ca/EbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
