<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>To Write Love on Her Arms is a story and the response to a story. It began with Renee's story and the commitment to meeting her needs. Her story started a fire, and that fire is a movement of love, a commitment to begin answering these needs and offering hope to the many who struggle with depression, addiction, suicide, self injury.

TWLOHA operates as a goverment recognized 501-(c)3 non-profit organization, under the umbrella of Fireproof Ministries. (Which is where this groups donations go to, unlike the other one (but you should still join that one too, this is all about awareness!)

TWLOHA's mission is to communicate hope and love to broken people. We also aim to invite and inspire lives of compassion. We believe that "rescue is possible", that we can be rescued and we are called to live as rescuers. In the same way, we believe that all people are loved and called to love others. This is an attempt at community.

TWLOHA aims to encourage, inspire, educate and challenge. We hope to help remove the stigma often associated with these issues, to encourage hurting people to talk about broken things, to know that they are not alone, and to get help. Renee's story is one of depression, drug addiction, suicide, and self injury. Beyond those specific issues, we believe that all people experience pain and brokenness. All people can relate to fear and regret. That said, we believe that hope and love and life are for all people.

1.  It is estimated that 15% or roughly 17 million Americans suffer from depression.

2. It affects rich and poor, young and old, black and white.

3. 2/3 are never treated.

4. They do not recognize the illness, and see it as a weakness or personality flaw.

5. Untreated depression is the most common cause of suicide.

6. In Australia, New Zealand and Japan, there are more suicides than murders.

7. Suicide is the third leading cause of death among young people.

8. Depression is treatable.

9. Cutting was very much a mystery until 1996 when Princess Diana admitted that she had struggled with it.

10. Self Injurers use physical pain as an attempt to calm or numb the psychological pain or stress. They injure the outside in an attempt to release the pain on the inside.

11. Self Injury is an attempt to stop the hurting, an attempt to be clean.

12. Self injurers and addicts seek the familiar, even if its pain. This is completely foreign to most people.

13. Self injurers believe pain is their only option, using greater external pain as a relief from the pain inside.

14. There is hope.</description>
  <mission>communicate hope and love to broken people, to invite and inspire lives of compassion, and we believe that all people are loved and called to love others. This is an attempt at community.</mission>
  <name>TWLOHA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1867</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">23103</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1109.26</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ze/Jc/2n/gL/WU/Bk/2riS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
