<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our approach is simple. Assemble an experienced and dedicated team of pharmaceutical scientists. Identify the most promising drug and vaccine candidates. Develop them into safe, effective and affordable medicines. Then partner with companies, non-profit hospitals and organizations in the developing world to conduct medical research on new cures, manufacture and distribute newly approved therapies that will impact the health of millions of people.

We challenge the assumption that pharmaceutical research and development is too expensive to create the new medicines that the developing world desperately needs. By partnering and collaborating with industry and researchers, by securing donated intellectual property, and by utilizing the scientific and manufacturing capacity of the developing world, OneWorld Health can deliver affordable, effective and appropriate new medicines where they are needed most.

1. We Are One World.&#8230;and yet, too many lack access to the wonders of modern medicine.

2. Among the poorest people in the world, 6 in 10 die of infectious diseases. Half of those deaths could be prevented. 

3. iOWH challenges the assumption that pharmaceutical research and development is too expensive to create new medicines for the poor.

4. iOWH's programs are working to develop new medicines to treat malaria, diarrheal diseases, intestinal worms, and visceral leishmaniasis (black fever).</description>
  <mission>Developing safe, effective, and affordable new medicines for people with infectious diseases in the developing world with emphasis on diseases that disproportionally affect children.</mission>
  <name>Institute for OneWorld Health</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1870</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1142</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">733.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nG/Gt/BU/q4/5M/Ho/pz/4kS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
