<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Fundamental Principles of the International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement

Humanity
The International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement, born of a desire to bring assistance without discrimination to the wounded on the battlefield endeavors, in its international and national capacity, to prevent and alleviate human suffering wherever it may be found. Its purpose is to protect life and health and to ensure respect for the human being. It promotes mutual understanding, friendship, cooperation and lasting peace among all peoples.

Impartiality
It makes no discrimination as to nationality, race, religious beliefs, class or political opinions. It endeavors to relieve the suffering of individuals, being guided solely by their needs, and to give priority to the most urgent cases of distress.

Neutrality
In order to continue to enjoy the confidence of all, the Movement may not take sides in hostilities or engage at any time in controversies of a political, racial, religious or ideological nature.

Independence
The Movement is independent. The National Societies, while auxiliaries in the humanitarian services of their governments and subject to the laws of their respective countries, must always maintain their autonomy so that they may be able at all times to act in accordance with the principles of the Movement.

Voluntary Service
It is a voluntary relief movement not prompted in any manner by desire for gain.

Unity
There can be only one Red Cross or one Red Crescent Society in any one country. It must be open to all. It must carry on its humanitarian work throughout its territory.

Universality
The International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement, in which all Societies have equal status and share equal responsibilities and duties in helping each other, is worldwide.

1. Humanity

2. Impartiality 

3. Neutrality

4. Independence

5. Voluntary Service

6. Unity 

7. Universality</description>
  <mission>Guided by its Fundamental Principles of the International Red Cross Movement, will provide relief to victims of disaster and help people prevent, prepare for, and respond to emergencies.</mission>
  <name>International Red Cross, Red Crescent, Red Crystal</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1871</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">22159</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1762.6</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/FI/aM/hZ/Ec/LB/Nf/O82S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
