<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>CNEWA works on behalf of the historic Christian East &#8211; that is, those lands in which, from ancient times, Christians belonged to the various Eastern churches. We assist churches from southwestern India to Eastern Europe, from Ethiopia to Siberian Russia, and immigrant communities from the Americas to Australia.

CNEWA is concerned for the formation and support of persons, especially the leaders of the church of tomorrow. We also assist in the physical construction of the buildings and facilities needed for the Eastern churches to carry out their pastoral work, either directly or through the offices of the Holy See.

LOVE ALL - SERVE ALL

When it comes to humanitarian assistance CNEWA&#8217;s only criterion is need; a person&#8217;s nationality or religion is not a determinant.

We help not only Catholics, but Orthodox, Protestants and Evangelicals, as well as Muslims, Jews, Hindus, peoples of native religions or those with no religion at all.

We&#8217;re bridge builders, matchmakers whose job is to connect you with those throughout the Middle East, Northeast Africa, India and Eastern Europe in need of your love and concern. In return, you get to know better their histories, cultures and values, their hopes and fears.




1. Assist in the physical construction of the buildings and facilities needed for the Eastern churches to carry out their pastoral work, either directly or through the offices of the Holy See.

2. Formation and support of persons, especially the leaders of the church of tomorrow.

3. Support for the historic Christian East &#8211; that is, those lands in which, from ancient times, Christians belonged to the various Eastern churches.</description>
  <mission>support the Eastern churches of the Catholic Church in India, Egypt, Lebanon, Siberia and beyond...</mission>
  <name>Catholic Near East Welfare Ass'n - Papal Agency for Humanitarian Aid in the Orient</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1875</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">50</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/XD/fr/dh/hu/0J/JA/ybES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
