<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>THIS IS NOT THE 'DON'T BUY' GAS FOR ONE DAY, BUT IT  WILL SHOW YOU HOW WE CAN GET GAS BACK DOWN TO  $1.30 PER GALLON. 
  
This was sent by a retired Coca Cola executive.  It came from one of his engineer buddies who retired from Halliburton.  If you are tired of the gas prices going up AND they will continue to rise this summer, take time to read this please. 
 
This makes MUCH MORE SENSE than the "don't buy gas on a certain day"  campaign that was going around last April or May!  The oil companies just laughed at that because they knew we wouldn't continue to "hurt" ourselves by refusing to buy gas.  
 
Want gasoline prices to come down? Join the resistance!!!!

Since we all rely on our cars, we can't just stop buying gas.
But we CAN have an impact on gas prices if we all act together to force a price war.
 
Here's the idea: For the rest of this year, DON'T purchase ANY gasoline from the two biggest companies (which now are one),EXXON and MOBIL. Both recently showed the largest profits ever recorded in their history.  I also will not buy from Citgo because of the S.O.B. Dictator that runs the company and the country. 
 
If they are not selling any gas, they will be inclined to reduce their prices.   If they reduce their prices, the other companies will have to follow suit.
 
But to have an impact, we need to reach literally millions of Exxon and Mobil gas buyers.  It's really simple to do!  Now, don't wimp out on me at this point...keep reading and I'll explain how simple it is to reach millions of people!!  
                                  Please keep it going




1. Gas prices must come back down</description>
  <mission>Lower gas prices</mission>
  <name>Don't Buy Gas From Exxon and Mobil</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1885</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">164</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/WO/wY/Be/tf/k3/QM/4j6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
