<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>-The Rape, Abuse &amp; Incest National Network is the nation's largest anti-sexual assault organization. RAINN operates the National Sexual Assault Hotline and carries out programs to prevent sexual assault, help victims and ensure that rapists are brought to justice. 

http://www.rainn.org/

-Unfortunately, in 2004-2005, there were an average annual 200,780 victims/survivors of rape, attempted rape or sexual assault.

-About 44% of rape victims/survivors are under age 18, and 80% are under age 30.

-Since 1993, rape/sexual assault has fallen by over 69%.

-One out of every six American women have been the victims of an attempted or completed rape in their lifetime (14.8% completed rape; 2.8% attempted rape). 

-A total of 17.7 million women have been victims/survivors of these crimes.

-About three percent of American men &#8212; a total of 2.78 million men &#8212; have experienced an attempted or completed rape in their lifetime according to the 1998 Prevalence, Incidence and Consequences of Violence Against Women study.

-   * 15% of victims/survivors are under age 12
    * 29% are age 12-17
    * 44% are under age 18
    * 80% are under age 30

-Approximately 73% of rape victims/survivors know their assailant, according to the 2005 National Crime Victimization Survey (PDF, 287KB).

    * Approximately 38% of victims/survivors are raped by a friend or acquaintance;
    * 26% of victims/survivors by a stranger;
    * 28% of victims/survivors by an intimate;
    * 7% of victims/survivors by another relative;
    * in 2% of cases the relationship is unknown.


1. Every two and a half minutes, somewhere in America, someone is sexually assaulted.

2. One in six American women are victims/survivors of sexual assault, and one in 33 men.

3. Rape is forced sexual intercourse, including vaginal, anal or oral penetration. Penetration may be by a body part or an object.

4. No one should have to fight this alone.

5. Sexual assault is unwanted sexual contact that stops short of rape or attempted rape. This includes sexual touching and fondling. (But, be aware: Some states use this term interchangeably with rape.)

6. Incest is sexual contact between persons who are so closely related that their marriage is illegal (e.g., parents and children, uncles/aunts and nieces/nephews, etc.). This usually takes the form of an older family member sexually abusing a child or adole

7. Dealing with such severe struggles on your own can often be too difficult to bear. That is why it is good for victims of sexual assault to receive treatment and counseling.</description>
  <mission>take a stand against any type of sexual assault.</mission>
  <name>RAINN: Rape, Abuse and Incest National Network</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1894</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24943</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">6887.61</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hg/nj/VD/wJ/qe/dw/0GGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
