<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Evangelism: For over 20 years, PBM has been reaching out with the Gospel. Seven Presbyterian ministries from Texas to California work with 37 churches and worship sites bringing Jesus Christ to over 2000 people/families each week. Ten PC USA-sponsored mission workers direct these Presbyterian ministries alongside 7 Mexican co-directors. Worship services, Bible study, sermons and vacation Bible schools bring the grace and peace of the Presbyterian faith to thousands of individuals living in desperate conditions. With God&#8217;s grace, PBM will continue to assist the ministries in planting Presbyterian churches, providing spiritual and moral support for those seeking the love of Jesus Christ as well as providing mission opportunities for congregations wishing to reach out. 

Mission Education: PBM provides opportunities for US and Mexican Presbyterians to work together. Participants grow in faith as they experience mission, become acquainted with another culture and leave the border knowing there are no barriers between our brothers and sisters in Christ. Over 2,000 individuals come to the border each year to serve, and go home changed forever with the experience. 

Health Ministry: People in marginal neighborhoods lack basic health information and adequate care. PBM has established clinics and health programs, which serve over 10,000 people each year, focus on preventative medicine, pre- and post-natal care, and inoculations. 

Training and Economic Self-Help: There are not enough jobs in the manufacturing and assembly plants to absorb the huge growth at the border. PBM concentrates on teaching skills which bring a sense of self-worth to the unemployed. Jewelry making, cosmetology, sewing, keyboarding, and English as a Second Language are taught. Micro-credit loans are promoting self-sufficiency.

1. Serve the needs of spirit, body, and mind

2. New church development

3. Empowerment of people and communities

4. Bi-national mission education and experiences

5. Support of border churches

6. Promotion of justice in all areas</description>
  <mission>Share the Gospel in Mexican cities along the 2,000 mile border with the U. S.: serving the needs of spirit, body, and mind in 7 Ministries with multiple sites stretching from the Gulf to the Pacific.</mission>
  <name>Presbyterian Border Ministry</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1904</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">116</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xC/4V/Q3/jN/Aw/fD/sTHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
