<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This mission is to increase public support for the law enforcement profession of police officers and police officers that have made the ultimate sacrifice. To provide information that will help promote police officer safety

Its in general to show your support for the men and women in law enforcement and the police K9 dogs! 

Thanks Again

================


 	
MISSION STATEMENT:

The mission of the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial Fund is to generate increased public support for the law enforcement profession by permanently recording and appropriately commemorating the service and sacrifice of law enforcement officers; and to provide information that will help promote law enforcement safety.


GOALS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS:


1. Built the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial, which is visited by more than 200,000 people annually.

2. Established and now operate the Memorial Museum and Visitors Center.

3. Collected and catalogued information on more than 17,500 law enforcement fatalities.

4. Published the book, To Serve and Protect-A Tribute to American Law Enforcement.

5. Successfully lobbied for a federal law requiring all American flags to be lowered to half-staff on "Peace Officers Memorial Day" (May 15th each year).

6. Successfully lobbied for a federal law authorizing the U.S. Mint to issue 500,000 National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial Commemorative Silver Dollars. Approximately $1.5 million in proceeds were raised for maintenance and repair of the Memorial.

7. Created and now maintain an Internet Web Site, which includes a complete listing of all law enforcement officers killed in the line of duty ( www.nleomf.com ).

8. Conduct an annual Candlelight Vigil attended by more than 18,000 people to honor fallen officers and to announce the Roll Call of new officer names added to the Memorial walls.

9. Successfully lobbied for a federal law (P.L. 106-492) which authorizes the building of a national law enforcement museum on federal property at Judiciary Square in Washington, D.C. Construction is expected to begin in 2007, with opening scheduled for 2011. The $80 million required to build the National Law Enforcement Museum must be raised privately; as such, the NLEOMF has embarked on A Matter of Honor: The Campaign to Build the National Law Enforcement Museum. 

</description>
  <mission>Show Support For Law Enforcement Police Officers </mission>
  <name>Support Law Enforcement / Police Officers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1913</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24929</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">742.3</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2r/Ig/Kj/zR/KW/N2/Pz/8pS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
