<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>IMAGINE... if we have finally discovered vaccine for HIV but not many people use it. What would the world think?

There's a vaccine that can save a life 99% of the time for the past 25 years and we still have 350-400 million people in the world with chronic HBV today!

*** DID YOU KNOW? ***

+ Hepatitis B is 10X more common and 100X more infectious than HIV/AIDS

+ 1 in 10 ASIANS and ASIAN AMERICANS are chronically infected

+ 1 in 4 of those will die of liver cancer or cirrhosis if left unmonitored

+ Most aren&#8217;t even aware of their infections because there are usually no symptoms until it's too late

+ Vaccinations don't mean you're safe, since most API's are infected at birth unless you receive vaccination within 12 hours of birth

In May 2001, the Asian Liver Center launched the Jade Ribbon Campaign in the San Francisco Bay Area to spread awareness about hepatitis B (HBV) and liver cancer in the Asian community. Since then, the Jade Ribbon Campaign has spread across the country and the world, reaching Asian communities not only in the San Francisco Bay Area, but also in San Diego, Orange County, Los Angeles, Arizona, New York, Hawaii, as well as China, Korea, and the Philippines, uniting people from all walks of life in the fight against hepatitis B and liver cancer. 

The objective of the campaign is to increase awareness and provide ethnic-sensitive health information to the API community and health professionals in an effort to reduce this major health disparity and improve API health. 

Partners of the Jade Ribbon Campaign include over 400 groups of community organizations and federal agencies, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the National Hepatitis B Task Force for Immunization, and the Health Resources and Services Administration and its affiliated agencies in the US Department of Health and Human Services.

Learn more at http://liver.stanford.edu.

Or join our official Facebook group... "Join the fight against HBV and Liver Cancer"!

1. Learn. Educate. Eradicate HBV worldwide.

2. Reduce the incidence and mortality associated with liver cancer.

3. Outreach and education, liver cancer research, and screening and treatment.</description>
  <mission>To address the high incidence of chronic HBV and liver cancer in Asians and Asian Americans worldwide.</mission>
  <name>Jade Ribbon Campaign - To Fight Hepatitis B and Liver Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1915</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2534</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">157.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SV/HI/nS/K1/Yj/Gp/bH/EuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
