<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Philippines is reported to have the world's largest population of children living and working in rubbish dumps.  Unicef (the United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund) reports that over 9.5 million children under the age of 14 are working in the Philippines.

Life is very difficult for the children and families who make their living by collecting pieces of plastic and metal from rubbish dumps for recycling.  Charities like the Philippine Community Fund however are helping these people to be able to improve their lives.

PCF runs three of its own schools for children who live in the poorest squatters areas in their region, two schools are located on dump sites, and the other is in a cemetary.

Adult literacy and employment programmes are also being developed; helping adults to find work other than on the dump, for instance making jewellery which is sold in England.

PCF also provides a hot meal for every child, everyday; for most of them this maybe the only meal they get. Meals are designed to provide high protein, and fresh fruit and vegetables; very much needed.
Our welfare team makes home visits to families in crisis and discovered that when families were sick they were being faced with the impossible decisions between spending money on food or medicines. Families seldom chose medicines over food, and this only increases the severity of malnutrition.




1. To Free Every Filipino Child And Their Family From Poverty.</description>
  <mission>To permanently improve the quality of life for the poorest Filipino communities, through education, nutrition, medical and family programs, regardless of religion, race or political boundaries. </mission>
  <name>Philippine Community Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1919</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">221</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/HS/Xw/H3/IJ/BZ/A2/WqNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
