<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The National Right to Life Committee was founded in 1973 in response to a United States Supreme Court decision released on January 22 of that year, legalizing the practice of human abortion in all 50 states, throughout the entire nine months of pregnancy. Prior to that Supreme Court case-- Roe vs. Wade -- the abortion debate had been centered in the legislatures of the states, 17 of which had legalized abortion under some circumstances and 33 of which had voted to continue to protect human life from conception. 

Since its official beginning at that conference, the National Right to Life Committee has grown to represent over 3000 chapters in all 50 states and the District of Columbia.

*Note* while you cannot donate to the National Right to Life Committee (c)4 fund through Facebook [it is not a 501(c)3 tax-deductible fund], you may donate to the National Right to Life Educational Trust (c)3 Fund.  

The NRLC Educational Trust Fund publishes and distributes books and brochures, films and displays of audio or visual materials, holds seminars and conferences, and advertises on right to life issues through television, radio and newspaper venues.

The NRL Trust Fund handles thousands of requests for educational information on abortion, assisted suicide, euthanasia, and infanticide annually. Each year, crisis pregnancy centers across the United States use the NRL Educational Trust Fund material to help women find better alternatives for themselves, fathers and their unborn children.

1. NRLC wishes to restore legal protection to innocent human life in regards to abortion, infanticide, euthanasia, and embryonic stem-cell research.

2. NRLC believes life begins at the moment of conception and ends at natural death.

3. NRLC does not take a position on contraception, sex education, national defense or capital punishment.</description>
  <mission>To restore legal protection to innocent human life related to the issues of abortion, infanticide, and euthanasia.</mission>
  <name>National Right to Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1925</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12797</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">527.4</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/aN/jl/TK/lI/MR/JN/RIqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
