<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>About MSF:

The MSF role in emergency medical aid
M&#233;decins Sans Fronti&#232;res (MSF) is an international humanitarian aid organisation that provides emergency medical assistance to populations in danger in more than 70 countries.
In countries where health structures are insufficient or even non-existant, MSF collaborates with authorities such as the Ministry of Health to provide assistance. MSF works in rehabilitation of hospitals and dispensaries, vaccination programmes and water and sanitation projects. MSF also works in remote health care centres, slum areas and provides training of local personnel. All this is done with the objective of rebuilding health structures to acceptable levels.

Raising Awareness

In carrying out humanitarian assistance, MSF seeks also to raise awareness of crisis situations; MSF acts as a witness and will speak out, either in private or in public about the plight of populations in danger for whom MSF works. In doing so, MSF sets out to alleviate human suffering, to protect life and health and to restore and ensure respect for the human beings and their fundamental human rights.

Only a small percentage of the populations that find themselves in a situation of danger gain the attention of the media. MSF teams travel to places that many people have never heard of, to assist those who have fallen victim to natural or man-made disasters. MSF volunteers have a story to tell when they return from their missions, and they use their experiences to speak of what they have seen. MSF offices worldwide facilitate the organisation of gatherings, for individuals and groups who want to speak in their home communities. MSF also mounts exhibitions and, from time to time, releases publications, with the aim of raising awareness.


MSF has been setting up emergency medical aid missions around the world since 1971.

1. Alleviate human suffering, to protect life and health. 

2. Restore and ensure respect for the human beings and their fundamental human rights.</description>
  <mission>Help People In Need For Medical Aid.</mission>
  <name>Support MSF</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1926</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">456</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">40.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SP/17/35/p4/Ez/1C/4e8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
