<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Camp HASC is the award winning summer program of the Hebrew Academy for Special Children. Located in the scenic Catskill Mountains of upstate New York, Camp HASC provides over 300 mentally and physically handicapped children and adults with the opportunity to enjoy a seven week sleep-away camp experience, just like many of their siblings and friends. 

Camp HASC is unique in its synthesis of academic and recreational programming. At HASC we seek to maximize the development of each individual's potential by providing special education, speech, physical, occupational and music therapies as well as computer instruction, adaptive physical education and adaptive aquatics. Hand in hand with their academic program the campers are able to participate in the full range of recreational activities including (but not limited to) sports, swimming, field trips, night activities, roller skating, carnivals, concerts and mainstream social programs with other camps. 

As result, these special youngsters and adults gain skills beyond the scope of parental expectations while enjoying normalizing activities in a stress free social environment.

There is no doubt that the real secret behind the success of Camp HASC is the tremendous effort of the over 200 young men and women who function as counselors in camp. Living with the campers 24 hours a day, with their determination and love, these counselors are able to drive home lessons learned in the classroom as well as on the playground, providing a total nurturing environment in which the campers can thrive. No wonder that many visitors to Camp HASC use the word "magical" in describing what they see! It really is a special place for special people. 

(this group is not officially associated with Camp Hasc but the money donated goes directly to the camp)

1. This camp is an amazing help to the families of these children

2. The kids have so much fun, the counselors are amazing</description>
  <mission>support this amazing camp and help it maintain its facilities and improve them</mission>
  <name>Support Camp Hasc</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1938</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">158</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">99.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6U/ot/Rx/K2/ML/1A/7SwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
