<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We are dedicated to helping the people of Honduras through our love, medical and construction missions, sponsoring children and general financial gifts.

All of the money donated benefits the Honduras Relief Effort, which is based in Florida. They send every penny of your donations to Honduras!! That's right! They don't keep any for themselves!

When you donate online, through facebook, only 3% is deducted for the processing of your credit card. So if you donate $10, Honduras Relief Effort Inc. gets $9.67

Invite your friends and make this group huge! We need to get the word out!

Honduras has such amazing people and their economy and government are holding them back. 

The money sent to The Honduras Relief Effort, goes directly to families and children in Honduras. It provides for an opportunity for kids to go to school. Many children cannot go to school because they can't afford the uniform required. The money also goes to help an orphanage (Proyecto Alcance).

Even if we can't physically be there to help, any and all money sent to the relief is well used and well appreciated!

The Honduras Relief Effort will also give you a receipt for your taxes (REMEMBER!!! DONATIONS ARE TAX DEDUCTIBLE!!!)

Please visit these sites to see how you can help:

www.hondurasreliefeffort.org
www.proyectoalcance.com

Or send your donation to:

Honduras Relief Effort, Inc.
4400 Cranston Place
Orlando, Fl 32812

Reach Out Orphange, Inc. 
Correo Postal 1134 
La Ceiba Atl&#225;ntida 
Honduras, C.A.

1. To build relationships with the Honduran communities.

2. Provide hope and love.

3. Provide relief through financial gifts.</description>
  <mission>Raise money for the relief efforts in Honduras.</mission>
  <name>Honduras Relief</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1951</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5709</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">432.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7E/1r/PM/tz/Ax/Tu/rhsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
