<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>

 One Family, created by Paul and Phyllis Fireman and family, is a not-for-profit organization devoted to ending family homelessness in Massachusetts.  The statistics on family homelessness tell a grim tale: on average, families with children comprise 40% of those experiencing homelessness in America, with a 15% increase in shelter requests by families annually.  Additionally, most cities are reporting increases in the lengths of stay in shelter.   There are over 10,000 children in Massachusetts without permanent homes.  

One Family Scholars (OFS) is the centerpiece program of One Family, Inc. OFS is a national model program that has two central goals: (1) to move families up and out of poverty, and (2) to develop academic and leadership skills necessary to attain living-wage jobs.  We currently empower 125 homeless, formerly homeless and at-risk mothers. Despite familiar perceptions, homeless mothers do not have higher rates of substance abuse, mental illness or criminal behavior than other low income women. More than half of MA homeless mothers have been victims of domestic or sexual abuse.  While poverty is the primary cause of their homelessness, most are victims of events in their lives that left them without the safety net of friends or relatives that families ordinarily rely on during difficult times. 

These amazing women, our &#8220;Scholars&#8221;, access the program through 5 partnering sites: Wellspring House, Project Hope, Housing First, MainSpring Coalition for the Homeless, and Community Teamwork, Inc.  Women who do best in the program succeed in part because they feel - often for the first time in their lives part of a group committed to education, high personal goals, active citizenship and mutual support. The OFS program helps them rebuild their confidence, self-esteem, sense of hope, and pride in their future potential.  


1. End Family Homeless

2. Raise Political and Social Awareness

3. End the Cycle of Poverty Among Children</description>
  <mission>Our Mission is to End Family Homelessness </mission>
  <name>One Family, Inc</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1973</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">14</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Wz/DC/pw/UV/yl/p4/hYJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
