<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Darfur crisis is a conflict in the Darfur region of western Sudan. The two main military sides are the Sudanese Military and the Janjaweed militia, recruited mostly from tribes of the northern Rizeigat. The other side comprises a variety of rebel groups, notably the Sudan Liberation Movement and the Justice and Equality Movement, recruited primarily from the Fur, Zaghawa, and Massaleit ethnic groups. The Sudanese government, while publicly denying that it supports the Janjaweed, has provided money and assistance to the militia and has participated in joint attacks targeting the land-tilling tribes from which the Darfuri rebels draw support. The conflict began in February 2003. Unlike in the Second Sudanese Civil War, which was fought between the primarily Muslim north and Christian and Animist south, almost all of the combatants and victims in Darfur are Muslim.

The government and Janjaweed attacks upon the non-Baggara civilian populace have resulted in a major humanitarian crisis. There are many casualty estimates, most concurring on a range within the hundreds of thousands. The United Nations (UN) estimates that the conflict has left as many as 450,000 dead from violence and disease. Most NGOs (non-governmental organizations) use 200,000 to over 400,000, a figure from the Coalition for International Justice that has since been cited by the UN. Sudan's government claims that 9,000 people have been killed, although this figure is seen as counterfactual. As many as 2.5 million are thought to have been displaced as of October 2006.

&lt;wikipedia.org&gt;


Movies You Must See (About Genocide / Holocaust):
Hotel Rwanda
Black Hawk Down
Blood Diamond
The Killing Fields
Schindler's List

(About Racism):
Amistad
Glory
A Time To Kill
The Tuskegee Airmen
Remember The Titans
Glory Road

(Motivational / Overcoming Stories):
Antwone Fisher
ALI
Malcolm X
Philadelphia
Coach Carter

1. Genocide must be stopped

2. Everyone has the right to live without fear

3. Government non-action is not the way to go.</description>
  <mission>stop the genocide in Darfur and let people know that genocide is occurring</mission>
  <name>DARFUR / Abolish Racism</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1982</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">358</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DU/j6/h5/Tc/jX/gt/rrQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
