<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Many name-brand clothing stores, including Abercrombie and Fitch, American Eagle, Hollister and (to a lesser degree) Aeropostale, often price their goods far higher than they are worth.  And many of today's consumers blindly spend their own (OR THEIR PARENTS'S HARD-EARNED) money on these goods, without even thinking of the product they're buying, how often the product will be used, or the level of quality that the product has.

True, the clothing that these businesses sell look attractive and appealing.  But there are other options for buying clothing with the same look (minus, perhaps, a bird or moose on the lapel).  

Thus, the purpose of this group is NOT to boycott the goods sold by AE, Aero, A&amp;F or Hollister.  Rather it is to INFORM consumers about the products they are buying.  It encourages the use of good decison-making on the part of the buyer, and encourages the use of sales, promotions, clearance racks, and other less-expensive retailers (i.e. Kohls, Old Navy, etc.)

1. Consumers should think about the money they're spending on the clothing: (Who earned the money that I am spending?  Why am I spending it here?  Is the item I'm purchasing worth the amount I'm spending? Will the item be used often and for a long time? etc.

2. Clearance racks are our friends.

3. A&amp;F, AE, Aero, and Hollister are not the only places to find good clothing.

4. Sales and promotions are useful and should be sought out/waited for.

5. Parents should make their children (particularly pre-teens or young teenagers) aware of how much is being spent to clothe them in "popular" clothing.</description>
  <mission>make the public aware of the sickeningly high prices of name-brand </mission>
  <name>Be a smart consumer: Is that AE shirt really worth $40?</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/1985</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5H/hG/iR/LT/xM/xZ/enWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
