<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>PARKIN AR, 72373

Demographics

As of the censusGR2 of 2000, there were 1,602 people, 603 households, and 404 families residing in the city. The population density was 242.6/km&#178; (627.2/mi&#178;). There were 657 housing units at an average density of 99.5/km&#178; (257.2/mi&#178;). The racial makeup of the city was 30.40% White, 68.54% Black or African American.

There were 603 households out of which 30.0% had children under the age of 18 living with them, 38.6% were married couples living together, 22.9% had a female householder with no husband present, and 33.0% were non-families. 30.0% of all households were made up of individuals and 17.7% had someone living alone who was 65 years of age or older. The average household size was 2.66 and the average family size was 3.30.

In the city the population was spread out with 31.7% under the age of 18, 7.9% from 18 to 24, 24.5% from 25 to 44, 19.4% from 45 to 64, and 16.5% who were 65 years of age or older. The median age was 34 years. For every 100 females there were 83.9 males. For every 100 females age 18 and over, there were 79.1 males.

The median income for a household in the city was $18,669, and the median income for a family was $25,893. Males had a median income of $22,667 versus $16,413 for females. The per capita income for the city was $11,050. About 27.7% of families and 36.1% of the population were below the poverty line, including 48.7% of those under age 18 and 26.8% of those age 65 or ove

Distance Metropolitan Areas

500 miles SE to Atlanta 
552 miles NE to Chicago 
371 miles SW to Dallas 
295 miles SE to Jackson 
470 miles NW to Kansas City 
120 miles SW to Little Rock 
40 miles E. to Memphis 
436 miles SE to New Orleans 
1,343 miles NE to New York 
225 miles SW to Shreveport 
301 miles NE to St. Louis 
354 miles NW to Tulsa
 


1. save the town from its self

2. Justin Hopkins  or Alford Williams Contact Info: 870-755-5412</description>
  <mission>PARKIN COMMUNITY ASSOCIATION......
I'm working at it!</mission>
  <name>PARKIN COMMUNITY ASSOCIATION</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2003</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/y2/L5/wS/X4/34/5I/BpAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
