<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our Mission    

The Breast Cancer Research Foundation is an independent 501 (c) (3) not-for-profit organization whose mission is to achieve prevention and a cure for breast cancer in our lifetime by providing A minimum of 85% of all funds raised goes to breast cancer research grants and awareness programs.  
critical funding for innovative clinical and genetic research at leading medical centers worldwide, and increasing public awareness about good breast health. 
In 2007, in the U.S., ACS estimates that breast cancer incidence in women will decrease significantly to 178,480 (from 212,920 in 2006). This represents a decrease of slightly more than 19%. Projected mortalities in women will also decrease, but not nearly as markedly, to 40,460 (from 40,970 in 2006.) 

In men, incidence is estimated at 2,030 this year (up from 1,720 in 2006), with projected deaths almost the same at 450 (from 460 in 2006.) 
For more statistical information on breast cancer, please visit our FAQs. 

BCRF support for promising yet untried ideas is crucial at this time of reduced federal research support, when only 6% to 8% of meritorious, peer-reviewed proposals are being approved for funding by the National Institutes of Health. 

The American Institute of Philanthropy has awarded BCRF an "A" rating in its Charity Rating Guide since 2002. BCRF is recognized by AIP as one of the "Top Rated" cancer organizations, and it is the only breast cancer organization to appear on its "Top Rated Charities" list. In December 2004, Money magazine named BCRF one of America&#8217;s top eight charities. 

The Foundation welcomes and depends on contributions from all those concerned with women's health. Working together, we know we can find a cure in our lifetime. 

 


1. Help raise awareness of Breast Cancer

2. Help fund the research departments to find more or alternative drugs</description>
  <mission>Help Fund the research of Breast Cancer</mission>
  <name>The Breast Cancer Research Foundation, Inc</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2008</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">90</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/QJ/Ci/o7/SY/u2/3W/PSGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
