<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>HDSA currently supports more than 40 scientists and 17 major HD laboratories in North America and around the world through our HDSA Coalition for the Cure with annual grants which range from $40,000 to $100,000 for HD investigations. Twenty-one HDSA Centers of Excellence at locations in major hospitals and university medical centers are supported by HDSA across the continental United States. The national office also produces and distributes, free of charge, publications and informational materials on HD and maintains a toll-free information hotline to assist physicians, patients and family members. Through 12 HDSA regions, 37 volunteer-based chapters and affiliates, 150+ support groups, we reach out across the nation to offer HD patients and their families guidance, encouragement, resource information 
and leadership opportunities at HDSA events, meetings and seminars -- truly a place to care, share while we all work toward a cure. We also work towards change through our HDSA advocacy programs.

HDSA is a 501&#169;3 not-for-profit organization recognized as a charity in good standing by the IRS(EIN: 133349873) and meets all the required high Standards of Excellence of the BBB Wise Giving Alliance, Community Health Charities, National Health Council and is proud to have an A rating 
from the American Institute of Philanthropy.



1. Each child of a parent with HD has a 50/50 chance of inheriting the gene.

2. HD affects both sexes and all races and ethnic groups around the world.

3. Every person who inherits the HD gene will eventually develop the disease.</description>
  <mission>fund research that will help find a cure for Huntington's Disease</mission>
  <name>Huntington's Disease Society of America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2014</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6148</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1643.3</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Jz/T6/Sh/oi/gu/mA/mVwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
