<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>One Economy launched http://www.247townhall.org nationally in June as a unique civic engagement and social media application that uses technology to make it easy for people to share ideas and learn about national and local issues. 247townhall.org provides powerful tools, a safe environment, and an array of information that make it easy to advocate for change. The site&#8217;s content areas include: 

Civic Journalism - Civic Journalism allows users to write their own articles about issues and events that affect their neighborhoods and their lives, providing a platform for advocacy and debate. 

Open Forum - Open Forum allows users to post their opinions on a range of issues. The Open Mic section has an audio recording feature, allowing users to record themselves from their computers&#8217; browsers. 
Townhall Presents. Townhall Presents features local and national podcasts, public affairs content, and live, townhall meeting-style webcasts. 

24/7 Voter - 24/7 Voter provides a forum for users to discuss issues related to local, regional, state and national elections. This section also provides basic how-to content focused on voting. 

Available in English and Spanish, the site offers everyday citizens an opportunity to use technology as way to engage in a long-term discussion about issues of local and national importance, offering their insights and concerns. Local sites have been created to focus on issues affecting Portland and Kansas City, and are planned for communities around the country. 


1. Provide everyone an equal voice in the democratic dialogue of America

2. Technology is a democratizing force that can facilitate genuine civic dialogue that empowers individuals to express themselves.</description>
  <mission>Provide an opportunity for everyday citizens to use technology as a way to engage in a long-term discussion about issues of local and national importance, offering their insights and concerns.</mission>
  <name>Promote and Facilitate Civic Engagement </name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2021</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">83</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dX/xr/7G/QZ/Rs/Eh/suQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
