<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Trinity Christian School is a private school located in Montville, NJ. The school is committed to the education of children in a biblical and classical framework with a view to presenting facts in the light of God's truth.

The educational program includes: Elementary grades (K-6) and Secondary grades (7-12).

1. The Bible, the inerrant and infallible Word of God, is the supreme norm for all of Christian faith and life and therefore for the educational enterprise of this Christian school corporation. While the ultimate authority in all matters of faith, order and 

2. In their education, children must come to learn that the world, and man's calling in it, can rightly be understood only in relation to the Triune God who by His creation, restoration, and governance directs all things to the coming of His kingdom and glor

3. Man's sin, which brought upon mankind the curse of God, alienates him from his Creator, his neighbor, and the world; distorts his view of the true meaning and purpose of life; misdirects human culture; and therefore also corrupts the education of children

4. Our Savior, the Lord Jesus Christ, is the Redeemer of, and the Light and the Way for, our human life in all its range and variety. Only through His life and work, and the work of His Spirit, are we guided in the truth and by faith recommitted to our purpo

5. The primary responsibility for education rests upon parents to whom children are entrusted by God. They are commanded to bring up their children in the training and admonition of the Lord. Therefore, anyone whom the parents appoint to substitute in a teac

6. Since God's promises and their respective conditions embrace the whole Christian community and because Christian education contributes to the advancement of God's kingdom, it is essential that parents and the Christian community establish and maintain Chr

7. The purpose of Christian schools is to educate children for a life of obedience to their calling in the world as image-bearers of God. This calling is to understand God's revelation in His Word and His creation; to respond to His Word in faith and repenta

8. Christian schools must take into account the variety of abilities, needs and responsibilities of young persons; the endowment and calling of young persons as God's image-bearers; and the young persons' defects and inadequacies as sinners. This requires th

9. Christian schools, organized and administered in accordance with legitimate standards and provisions for day schools, should be recognized in society as free to function according to their principles.</description>
  <mission>Promote awareness and raise funds</mission>
  <name>Trinity Christian School</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2026</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">38</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/FO/7X/Li/Qd/Qh/4z/415S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
