<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hydrogen has the highest energy content per unit weight of any known fuel-52,000 Btu/lb (120.7 kJ/g). It burns cleanly. When hydrogen is burned with oxygen, the only byproducts are heat and water. When burned with air, which is about 68% nitrogen, some oxides of nitrogen are formed. The process of converting hydrogen to energy using engines or fuel cells is much more efficient than the comparable gasoline counterparts.

One of the great advantages of hydrogen is that it can be made from a variety of domestic feedstocks like water, biomass, coal and natural gas. Because hydrogen exists in many different forms, in any one region, there are a variety of local feedstocks from which the hydrogen can be extracted.

Today, over 95% of the hydrogen produced in the U.S. comes from steam reforming natural gas. As hydrogen moves from its role primarily as an industrial gas to a consumer purchased fuel, we expect other production technologies to add to the mix so that hydrogen is produced using the most cost-effective and environmentally sound method available for a specific region. Some options are: renewable or nuclear electricity and electrolysis; gasification of biomass and other hydrocarbons like coal; and using nuclear reactor heat for high-temperature electrolysis or thermo-chemical production methods.

1. Hydrogen can be totally nonpolluting (water is the exhaust).

2. Hydrogen can be economically competitive with gasoline or diesel.

3. Hydrogen can be as safe as gasoline, diesel, or natural gas.

4. Hydrogen can help reduce our dependence on imported fuels.

5. Hydrogen can be produced in any country or locale from a variety of energy sources.</description>
  <mission>Promote the transition to hydrogen in the energy field.</mission>
  <name>Support Hydrogen Power</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2033</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">280</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/V3/Zk/1l/W1/EQ/Ec/E7ZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
