<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Green America is a not-for-profit membership organization founded in 1982 as "Co-op America."  We changed our name on January 1, 2009.

Our Mission
Our mission is to harness economic power&#8212;the strength of consumers, investors, businesses, and the marketplace&#8212;to create a socially just and environmentally sustainable society.

Our Vision
We work for a world where all people have enough, where all communities are healthy and safe, and where the bounty of the Earth is preserved for all the generations to come.

What Makes Green America Unique:
~We focus on economic strategies&#8212;economic action to solve social and environmental problems.
~We mobilize people in their economic roles&#8212;as consumers, investors, workers, business leaders.
~We empower people to take personal and collective action.
~We work on issues of social justice and environmental responsibility.  We see these issues as completely linked in the quest for a sustainable world.  It&#8217;s what we mean when we say &#8220;green.&#8221;
~We work to stop abusive practices and to create healthy, just and sustainable practices.

Visit our website: www.greenamerica.org

Join us on...

Facebook: www.facebook.com/greenamerica

MySpace: www.myspace.com/coopamerica

World of Good: http://community.worldofgood.com/coop_america

Greenopolis: http://greenopolis.com/myopolis/members/green-america 

Digg: http://digg.com/users/MyGreenAmerica

YouTube Channel: www.youtube.com/user/Iamagreenamerican

1. Empowering individuals to make purchasing and investing choices that promote social justice and environmental sustainability.

2. Demanding an end to corporate irresponsibility through collective economic action.

3. Promoting green and fair trade business principles while building the market for businesses adhering to these principles.

4. Building sustainable communities in the US and abroad.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to harness economic power&#8212;the strength of consumers, investors, businesses, and the marketplace&#8212;to create a socially just and environmentally sustainable society.</mission>
  <name>Green America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2037</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">718</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">134.08</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/NX/yv/Nv/zK/bf/w0/0x/f7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
