<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Now to start off, my mom is known for her bubbly and fun-loving personality and is 
as very sociable person. She could be friends with anyone; she&#8217;s the type of person
who will be there for any person that she is friends with. Now lets rewind to about Christmas 
time, when two days after the holiday my moms business gets shutdown and every employee
is forced to leave. Then within the next couple of weeks, she finds a lump on her breast. She gets
it check out within the next couple of weeks and they indeed tell her what she is not hoping for, 
it is breast cancer. Now, soon after she goes through a couple of surgeries and she is told that the cancer cells did not spread which meant she wouldn&#8217;t have to go on the road towards chemotherapy and radiation. Within the couple of weeks she has found a new job that she loves and many of her friends work there and she was excited to go back into a job (which is odd right?). But only to her downfall is when she came back to the doctors to get the drains out, the doctor found that the cancer cells had spread and she would have to have chemotherapy and radiation. 
Now think, she hasn&#8217;t had a job since December and it is know the first of June, where does the money go? Most of it is spent on her medication and our family needs (food, bills, keeping our home). She is now down to her last 1000 dollars and is forced to pull out her investment money (which is taxed and she will be fined for). The sad part is that everything that could have gone wrong went wrong. Now the Coats family is now searching for some clarity and is looking forward for the summer because now my sister, my dad and I will be having jobs and hopefully we can survive through this awful mess. 


1. The COATS Foundation was established only to do one thing, to help my mom cope with this ordeal and hope for survival.

2. Breast Cancer sucks!

3. Because everyone loves MOMMA COATS!</description>
  <mission>help a loving mother, who is in need</mission>
  <name>The COATS Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2038</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">73</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qm/4N/3m/J6/xa/OC/xwoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
