<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Diabetes is a serious, chronic disease and a leading cause of death in Canada.
Over 2 million Canadians have diabetes. By 2010, this number is expected to rise to 3 million Canadians. These numbers most likely underestimate the prevalence of diabetes. That means thousands of people could have it and not know it.
There is no cure for diabetes but diabetes can be managed.

There are three main types of diabetes.
Type 1 diabetes is a disease in which the body mistakenly attacks and destroys the insulin-producing beta cells in the pancreas, usually as a result of an autoimmune process. Approximately 10 percent of people with diabetes have type 1. It is diagnosed most often in children and young adults. People with type 1 diabetes must take multiple daily injections of insulin. 

Type 2 diabetes is the most common form of diabetes. Type 2 diabetes develops when the pancreas is no longer able to meet the demand for insulin, or the body is not properly using the insulin produced (often referred to as insulin resistance). Insulin resistance is often made worse by excess weight. Type 2 diabetes most often is diagnosed in adults.

Gestational diabetes is a temporary condition that occurs in approximately 3.5 to 3.8% pregnancies. Among Aboriginal women, the rate of gestational diabetes increases to between 8% and 18% of all pregnancies. There is an increased risk of developing diabetes for both mother and child, later in life. Evidence suggests that up to 40% of women who have had gestational diabetes develop type 2 diabetes later in life. "

Description taken from http://www.diabetes.ca/ilt/diabetes_answers/what_is_diabetes.aspx

http://www.jdrf.ca   
http://www.jdrf.org

1. Diabetes is an epidemic that needs to be stopped through funding for research and education.</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness and fund research to h elp find a cure</mission>
  <name>JDRF ( Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation )</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2041</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1091</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1708.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3Q/Hb/js/Kn/YV/1i/PEGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
