<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>God Will Make A Way Ministries is a not-for-profit ministry designed to assist the forgotten children around the globe. This ministry partners with established ministries to provide used clothing and housing for orphans. It is made up of a group of volunteers who collect, pack &amp; ship new and used clothing in 40 foot containers (20,000 pounds) for orphans &amp; street children in Ukraine and India. Tax-deductible donations are needed to pay for shipping costs. All monies received go directly to pay shipping for clothing or to provide housing for orphans. God Will Make A Way Ministries was created in the summer of 1999 after first- hand observations by a staff member while in Russia adopting a child. This ministry is dedicated to helping children and to encouraging the spread of the gospel of Jesus Christ. The distribution of clothing to orphanages and needy children and street children serves as a vehicle for evangelical gospel presentations. Further, a one-time grant of up to $6,000 for building housing for orphans is available to a limited number of pre-approved ministries each year. 



1. To come along side of pre-existing ministries to provide clothing and grants for the construction of housing for orphans.

2. Supplies are only distributed to sites where a Christian influence accompanies the distribution of the clothing.

3. Helping poor kids come to know the love of Jesus is our highest priority</description>
  <mission>Assisting the forgotten children around the globe. To provide clothing for orphans, street kids and needy kids. Further, to provide grants for the construction of housing for orphans</mission>
  <name>God Will Make A Way Ministries</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2043</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">31</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xK/kw/IB/KE/BZ/FW/WV6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
