<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Firefly is a charity looking for ways to solve conflict in any society, but particularly in Bosnia. We run summer camps, festivals, and year-round projects such as arts, photography, music, 

Firefly's focus in Bosnia is on communities divided by ethnicity and war; we also focus on social division, in general, in other countries, whether caused by religion, economics, race, history, language, nationality or simply geographical distance.

The principle we used in Bosnia was that although there are dividing forces between individuals in a community, there will be many more links - such as shared cultural heritage, language, artistic tastes, or simply love of food. We aim to focus on and strengthen these shared interests.

Firefly's core belief is that it is vital for marginalised and vulnerable groups to become less isolated, more confident and to be given opportunities to play a greater part in society as a whole. As a result the majority of our projects focus on marginalised, vulnerable and minority groups - refugees, children, women, ethnic minorities and other such groups. Since social division is often unequal, we want to create links between grass-roots communities that allow them the strength and the support to be heard. 

If you'e like to donate, go to 

www.fireflyinternational.org/standing_order.html to

 set up a standing order, or  	 

https://www.charitychoice.co.uk/donation.asp?ref=155043 to make a one-off donation by credit or debit card. Thank you! 

1. Everyone should live in peaceful, equal societies. 

2. Young people should be supported in changing and improving their communities. </description>
  <mission>End conflict and social division, and support mid/post -conflict societies. </mission>
  <name>Firefly</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2051</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">241</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/WC/um/Y6/U8/3d/Sb/Le3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
