<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>** PLEASE READ IT**

Taj Mahal, India's most famous architectural wonder, has joined the race to be named one of the 'New Seven Wonders of the World'.

Taj Mahal symbolises India. It is a beautiful monument representing love and passion. That is why it has been included in the list of 21 finalists across the world.

The 21 finalists for the New Seven Wonders of the World, alphabetically:

    * Acropolis, Athens, Greece
    * Alhambra, Granada, Spain
    * Angkor Wat temple, Cambodia
    * Chichen Itza Aztec site, Yucatan, Mexico
    * Christ the Redeemer, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
    * Colosseum, Rome
    * Easter Island Statues, Chile
    * Eiffel Tower, Paris
    * Great Wall, China
    * Hagia Sophia Church, Istanbul, Turkey
    * Kyomizu Temple, Kyoto, Japan
    * Kremlin/St.Basil&#8217;s, Moscow
    * Machu Picchu, Peru
    * Neuschwanstein Castle, Fussen, Germany
    * Petra ancient city, Jordan
    * Pyramids of Giza, Egypt
    * Statue of Liberty, New York
    * Stonehenge, Amesbury, United Kingdom
    * Sydney Opera House, Australia
    * Taj Mahal, Agra, India
    * Timbuktu city, Mali


The New Seven Wonders of the World will be chosen on the number of votes received around the globe -- people of India, let your voices be heard in this global voting....

The results of this contest will be announced on July 7, 2007, when at an event in Lisbon in Portugal, the world will discover which monuments have been named as the new wonders. Votes can be submitted till July 6.

How you can help?

1) VOTE ONLINE

Go to www.new7wonders.com to pick and vote for the Taj Mahal of India. Be part of the making of history. Also tell your family and friends about it.

2) VOTE THRU SMS

You can vote via SMS in India too!
To vote for the Taj Mahal, send "TAJ" to 6767.

WILL YOU VOTE ??? 

2getr v can n v will make a difference.
Please forward it to more people.




1. Vote to choose the new Seven Wonders of the World, such that Taj is ranked among the top seven of 21 monuments.

2. Return TAJ its lost glory...</description>
  <mission>Vote to choose the new Seven Wonders of the World, such that Taj is ranked among the top seven of 21 monuments.</mission>
  <name>Is Taj set to enter new 7 Wonders of the World ??</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2052</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">84</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ji/s2/Cr/L6/nX/mk/5Y8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
