<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Taken from the Alpha-1 Foundation website
www.alphaone.org

To donate:
http://www.firstgiving.org/alpha-1foundation

Alpha-1 Antitrypsin Deficiency (Alpha-1) is a genetic/hereditary condition that leads to decreased circulating levels of alpha-1 antitrypsin (AAT) and significantly increases the risk of serious lung disease in adults and liver disease in infants, children and adults. 

Diseases most commonly associated with Alpha-1:

Emphysema
Chronic bronchitis
Bronchiectasis
COPD
Cirrhosis
Neonatal hepatitis
Hepatocellular carcinoma
Necrotizing panniculitis
Non-tuberculous mycobacterial infection
Increased risk of chronic/chronic active hepatitis

It is estimated that as many as 1 in every 2,500 Americans have Alpha-1.

Individuals with Alpha-1 may remain healthy throughout their lives. Early diagnosis and avoidance of risk factors, such as cigarette smoking, can help prevent Alpha-1 from causing disease.

An estimated 20 million people have one normal and one defective AAT gene (carriers). Carriers may pass the defective gene on to their children and there is evidence for some increased risk of lung and liver disease in carriers, as well.

Alpha-1 can lead to emphysema and is often misdiagnosed as asthma or smoking-related Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD).

Alpha-1 is the most common genetic risk factor for emphysema and COPD.

As many as 3% of all people diagnosed with COPD may have undetected Alpha-1.

Alpha-1 can lead to liver disease. The most serious liver diseases are cirrhosis and liver cancer.



1. Let's find a cure for Alpha-One Antitrypsin Deficiency</description>
  <mission>create awareness of this genetic/hereditary condition</mission>
  <name>Support Alpha-1 Antitrypsin Deficiency Research</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2060</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2819</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1984.23</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vL/HM/LR/jo/0v/ZQ/DC/KQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
