<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>If there are two things people are becoming more conscious about, its their health, and the environment. Well, a huge contributor to global warming is believe it or not, methane from cow farts, and other waste products from farm animals. One might say, lets eat the cows, so they dont fart anymore, well the truth is these polluting farts come from the over 41 million cows that are raised each year just for people to eat. These cows shud have never existed. Female cows are forced to be impregnated over and over again. The fact is, each time you eat meat, your contributing to global warming. The second thing people are becoming more conscious about is their health. Well, believe it or not cow meat is unhealthy. it is full of saturated fat and cholestorol. Research has shown that vegetarians are 50 percent less likely to develop heart disease than are meat-eaters, and they have 40 percent of the cancer rate of meat-eaters. Plus, meat-eaters are nine times more likely to be obese than vegans are. Every time you eat animal-derived products, you&#8217;re also ingesting bacteria, antibiotics, dioxins, hormones, and a host of other substances, some toxic, that can accumulate in your body and remain there for years. These are two reasons besides the main one not to eat cows or any other meat for that matter. The main one is because of how cruel farmers are to the cows. They are castrated, branded, and have their horns cut off all without painkillers. they have their throat slit when there killed, and most are still fully conscious for a few minutes after the slitting

1. get people to become vegetarians, or eat less meat for three reasons: its good for the environment, your health, and its not cruel to cows

2. raise money to help Peta in there efforts to stop factory farming 

3. Raise awareness of why eating meat is bad</description>
  <mission>Well... save the cows, (not exactly, read the description for more info)</mission>
  <name>Save the cows</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2088</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">193</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8Z/ED/Iu/Fu/tZ/c3/QWzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
