<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Wisemen have always said, an ounce of prevention is worth a pound of cure. How do we know that over 80% of heart disease is preventable? Through research!

Spearheading many of the cutting-edge research is Brigham and Women's Hospital, a flagship hospital of Harvard Medical School, the home of many long-running world class research in heart disease and stroke research. Donated funds will benefit cardiovascular disease prevention research to help continue their ground breaking research, world recognized in top medical journals.

Heart disease and stroke together is the #1 leading killer worldwide. Worldwide each year, over 17,000,000 people die from heart attacks and strokes. Chronic diseases like heart disease is recognized by the WHO to be the leading cause of global disease burden. Annually, cardiovascular disease all in all costs our society $1,000,000,000,000 ($1 trillion)!

Let's all pitch in an 'ounce' of donation for heart disease and stroke prevention research...

Dr. Eric Ding
Campaign for Cardiovascular Disease Prevention
Harvard Medical School
Brigham and Women's Hospital



Your Heart Disease Risk Calculator:
http://www.diseaseriskindex.harvard.edu/update/hccpquiz.pl?lang=english&amp;func=home&amp;quiz=heart

Your Stroke Risk Calculator:
http://www.diseaseriskindex.harvard.edu/update/hccpquiz.pl?lang=english&amp;func=home&amp;quiz=stroke

(Your Heart Disease and Stroke Risk calculators are derived from 30 years of research. Thank you for your continued support).


1. Heart disease should not be the leading killer of men and women worldwide

2. The #1 way to reduce cardiovascular death is through prevention

3. 80% of heart attacks are preventable

4. 60% of strokes are preventable

5. 90% of type 2 diabetes are preventable</description>
  <mission>An 'ounce' of prevention, to prevent a global burden of heart disease</mission>
  <name>Support Heart Disease and Stroke Research</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/209</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">115714</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5406.32</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rp4/wZfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
