<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>VietHope was formed in the spring of 2002 by a group of university students and young professionals in the Boston area.  In forming VietHope, we sought to aggregate our talents, energy and dedication to contribute to the building of a more prosperous Vietnam through education.

VietHope shares the dream that every child in Vietnam shall grow up with an opportunity to reach his or her full potential through education.  It is our conviction that good education is indispensable in helping Vietnam attain sustainable socioeconomic development.

Therefore VietHope primarily focuses on supporting programs and projects to promote the education of the children of Vietnam. We do so in the spirit of mutual respect and genuine commitment to work alongside the beneficiaries and partner organizations in and outside Vietnam.

Coming from many corners of the world and from various educational and professional experiences, we share the desire to contribute to Vietnam&#8217;s future. Working together in friendship and responsibility towards one another, and fully utilizing our individual as well as collective resources, we believe that VietHope can make a real difference.

As in the beginning of VietHope, everyone on our staff is a volunteer.  Everyone who shares our dream and principles is invited to join VietHope, regardless of his or her ethnicity, nationality, and political or religious preferences.

Visit www.viethope.org to learn more!

1. Provide educational opportunities for financially disadvantaged children of Vietnam.</description>
  <mission>Promote socioeconomic development in Vietnam by providing educational opportunities for financially disadvantaged children.</mission>
  <name>VietHope: Education for children in Vietnam</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2094</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6067</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2952.18</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/iX/lZ/zb/ZM/Im/5N/NI/v8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
