<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Monkeys are our friends. Too long have we let our monkeys being mistreated. Generations one after the other have supported the slave trade of our monkeys. Since year 1, monkeys have been part of our daily lives. Monkeys are our friends. They were an icon of the human civilisation for decades, and now, we are ending their existing among us, on earth, by snuggling against &#8216;them&#8217;. The following fact might offend some people. Have you ever asked yourself why your cute little stuffed monkey, looks too perfect? (...) For every stuffed monkey on the market, three monkeys are being &#8216;studied&#8217;, as stated by the UMSC (Universal Monkey Stuffing Company). What they are really trying to say, is that they are mutilating three monkeys for every stuffed one, to see how they could elaborate the resemblance of their inhuman product. Last year, stats proved that 5.1 million monkey were &#8216;studied&#8217; to make a profit of over a billion dollars. A profit that is going straight into the pockets of rich cold blooded mutilator. Monkey blood is being spilled every 10 minutes of your day, my friend. We need to save them. Monkeys are our friends. Here below are four simple but practical ways to end the monkey slave trade:

1. Buy only bananas with an I love Monkeys sticker on the package,

2. Salute the next friendly neighbourhood monkey you will pass by on the streets,

3. DON&#8217;T buy a new stuffed monkey the next time yours is sadly ripped open by your common bully. Remember, you were part of the mutilation of three monkeys already. Don&#8217;t make it double.

4. Donate your time to find out more about this cause. This is the toughest thing to do, it could be a lifetime commitment.

You are obligated to tell all your friends, not for your benefit, but for the monkeys. They too, have this deep urge inside to help their monkey friends. End the monkey slave trade, support this cause, monkeys are our friends. 

1. Monkeys should have a new (and a first) constitution

2. We believe in unity between our races

3. Monkeys have the right to freely use sidewalks</description>
  <mission>Abolish the monkey slave trade</mission>
  <name>Save your friendly neighbourhood monkey</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2096</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">62</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nL/0v/EZ/4k/mb/3h/A7NS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
