<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Campaign for Cancer Prevention aims to innovate and effectively channel the most cutting-edge research and prevention strategies against cancer. The Campaign is an official partner of Brigham and Women's Hospital, a flagship hospital of Harvard Medical school.

The Campaign supports several of the world's largest and longest-running studies into understanding cancer causes and preventions. Several of the studies has helped lead the world in finding causes, preventions, and treatments for cancer for &gt;30 years.

The Campaign was featured in NEWSWEEK Magazine and has directly supported innovative cancer research from Harvard.

HOW CAN YOU HELP?

FOLLOW on Twitter: http://www.twitter.com/campaignprevent

JOIN the Campaign's 6 million person cause: http://www.causes.com/cancer

SHARE the cause on your wall for friends to join

INVITE all your friends by signing the 'Invite Pledge'

BECOME a fan: http://www.facebook.com/cancerprevention

Thank you for supporting the Campaign for Cancer Prevention.

Dr. Eric L. Ding
Harvard Medical School
Brigham and Women's Hospital
Harvard School of Public Health

------------------------------------ ----------------------------

*YOUR DISEASE RISK calculator of different cancers (breast, colon, prostate, lung, ovarian, cervical, melanoma, uterine, etc), heart disease, stroke, diabetes, and osteoporosis
http://www.diseaseriskindex.harvard.edu/
 

Did you know: 

-1 person dies of cancer every 4 seconds in this world - every second of every day.

-1 out of 2 men, and 1 out of 3 women, will be diagnosed with cancer in their lifetime.

-Cancer the 2nd leading cause of death in the world, killing 7.6 million people each year. 

-Ending cancer would improve the economy by $50 trillion.

In essence, cancer affects us all - via a parent, sibling, child, other relative, or a friend.

1. Cancer can be preventable and treatable-- someday nobody will die from cancer.

2. We can come together to understand and overcome cancer.

3. Become a fan at: http://www.facebook.com/cancerprevention

4. Follow on Twitter: http://www.twitter.com/campaignprevent

5. (See "EXTENDED INFO" to read more about this cause)

** Any posts to the Campaign for Cancer Prevention site on Causes may be used on our website or other promotional material.</description>
  <mission>Through science and public health, we can prevent cancer. </mission>
  <name>Campaign for Cancer Prevention</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/210</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6151447</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">390280.28</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/En/KS/NK/s1/wW/Yr/Kl/3PS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
