<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Feline infectious peritonitis (FIP) is a fatal, incurable disease that affects cats. It is caused by Feline Infectious Peritonitis Virus (FIPV), which is a mutation of Feline Enteric Coronavirus.  Fewer than 1 in 20 cats survive the contraction of this disease, however its incidence rate is roughly 1 in 5000 for households with one or two cats.  
The hallmark clinical sign of effusive FIP is the accumulation of fluid within the abdomen or chest, which can cause breathing difficulties. Other symptoms include lack of appetite, fever, weight loss, jaundice, and diarrhea. 
As there is no cure for FIP, treatment is symptomatic and palliative. Typically the owner is advised to make the cat as comfortable as possible until it becomes clear that the cat is suffering.

For those who have suffered through owning a cat with FIP, and watching the cat's own suffering alongside them, there can be known no greater heartbreak, especially considering most cats who die of FIP are very young.  Anything that can be done to relieve both the suffering of FIP cats and their owners should be looked upon as a great community and medical service.  We need to find a cure!  And fast!

In November 2005, the Winn Feline Foundation announced the creation of the Bria Fund to accept donations for feline infectious peritonitis (FIP) research.  They have raised a substantial amount since then, and the more they raise, the closer to a cure we will be!
Please help!  Spread the word about FIP, keep your cats safe, and empathize kindly with those of us owners who know the heartbreak.

(I love you, Ivonna!  RIP.)

1. A cure for FIP must be found.  Encourage and support medical research on FIP.

2. Keep cat owners informed of FIP, it's causes and treatments.  We need to know as much as we can about the disease in order to keep our cats safe.

3. Support and comfort those who know the loss of a cat through the horrors of FIP.  RIP to all cats who have died from this terrible illness.</description>
  <mission>promote awareness and support medical research for Feline Infectious Peritonitis.</mission>
  <name>Find The Cure for FIP</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2100</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2662</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">541.33</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Np/cg/p0/iG/Ed/xu/SWYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
