<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>If a heinous crime is committed, the criminal should accept the punishment.  In prison, criminals are rewarded.  They don't have to work.  The taxpayers pay for their food and housing, as well as perks, such as free surgeries.  Harsher punishments are necessary to curb violent crime.  Make it easier for criminals who are proven guilty without a doubt to receive the death penalty.  Change life without parole to death.  No point keeping them alive for potentially decades, losing 70k a year if they don't even have a chance to enter back into society.  It's as pointless and wasteful as alcoholics anonymous for dead people.

If you disagree, feel free to send me a message and I'll try to argue my ideas with as much clarity as I can.  I'm not saying this is the best method, I'm saying that I would prefer this over the current system.

7/11/07: this little gem hit yahoo news
http://news.yahoo.com/s/ap/20070611/ap_on_re_us/death_penalty_deterrence
from the article
"Each execution deters an average of 18 murders, according to a 2003 nationwide study by professors at Emory University. (Other studies have estimated the deterred murders per execution at three, five and 14)."
"Speeding up executions would strengthen the deterrent effect. For every 2.75 years cut from time spent on death row, one murder would be prevented, according to a 2004 study by an Emory University professor."

We MUST get the word out.

1. Make it easier for a death penalty to be given out.

2. Lower the time needed before the penalty is carried out.

3. Change life sentences without parole to the death penalty.</description>
  <mission>prevent excess waste and just get rid of notorious criminals.</mission>
  <name>Support the Death Penalty</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2110</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">582</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wc/q3/tY/CC/Q5/yo/hZgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
