<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In 1993, the World Health Organization declared tuberculosis to be a global health emergency. By 2015, the Global Plan to Stop TB aims to save 14 million lives.

Tuberculosis is an ancient and deadly disease caused primarily by mycobacterium tuberculosis. A relative of leprosy, this disease was the leading cause of death for centuries. Although the discovery of a fairly effective vaccine and antibiotics nearly defeated tuberculosis as a health threat, the rise in HIV in the 1980s created a perfect niche in which TB could thrive. Now, antibiotic-resistant strains of TB like MDR-TB (Multi-Drug Resistant Tuberculosis) and XDR-TB (Extensively Drug Resistant Tuberculosis) threaten the world's populace once again.

Don't wait for drug-resistant TB to visit your doorstep. Industrialized nations are no more invincible than Sub-Saharan Africa.

Tuberculosis was once the world's leading killer, and it's poised to make a comeback. Let's not let it.

References:
http://www.who.int/tb/en/
http://www.lungusa.org/site/pp.asp?c=dvLUK9O0E&amp;b=35778
http://www.niaid.nih.gov/factsheets/tb.htm
http://www.umdnj.edu/globaltb/start.html
http://www.cdc.gov/tb/default.htm

1. Extend TB treatment to areas previously inadequately cared for

2. Develop a new, more effective vaccine that could be given to all children

3. Research new anti-biotic and retroviral treatments for TB

4. Work toward the eradication of HIV in order to take away TB's most common victims</description>
  <mission>Eradicate tuberculosis and save lives through improved treatments, simpler diagnostic tests, new more effective vaccines, and more extensive world-wide care.</mission>
  <name>STOP TB WORLDWIDE!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2125</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">820</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">155.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yU/J8/ly/Gb/dl/rM/RujS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
