<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Today, America's $246 billion civil justice system is the most expensive in the industrialized world. Aggressive personal injury lawyers target certain professions, industries, and individual companies as profit centers. They systematically recruit clients who may never have suffered a real illness or injury and use scare tactics, combined with the promise of awards, to bring these people into massive class action suits. They effectively tap the media to rally sentiment for multi-million-dollar punitive damage awards. This leads many companies to settle questionable lawsuits just to stay out of court. 

These lawsuits are bad for business; they are also bad for society. They compromise access to affordable health care, punish consumers by raising the cost of goods and services, chill innovation, and undermine the notion of personal responsibility. The personal injury lawyers who benefit from the status quo use their fees to perpetuate the cycle of lawsuit abuse. They have reinvested millions of dollars into the political process and in more litigation that acts as a drag on our economy. Some have compared the political and judicial influence of the personal injury bar to a fourth branch of government.

1. Health care liability reform

2. Class action reform

3. Promotion of jury service

4. Abolition of the rule of joint and several liability

5. Abolition of the collateral source rule

6. Limits on punitive damages

7. Limits on noneconomic damages

8. Production liability reform

9. Appeal bond reform

10. Sound science in the courtroom

11. Stopping regulation through litigation</description>
  <mission>Bring greater fairness, predictability and efficiency to the civil justice system.</mission>
  <name>Tort Reform</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2152</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">61</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Vj/X7/n2/Ry/FH/1l/LMPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
