<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.liferollson.org

A little bit about our flagship program, They Will Surf Again...

They Will Surf Again, a no-cost program underwritten by Life Rolls On and generous sponsors, is the flagship program of Life Rolls On. TWSA utilizes a surfing experience to push the boundary of possibility for those with SCI.

Injured athletes from around the country gather together for a day of surfing. Some have not surfed since their injury, some have never surfed, some surf all the time despite their varying mobility. TWSA connects dozens of volunteers (roughly a 7-1 volunteer to surf ratio is needed), with a handful of injured individuals, together for a day of excitement, joy, and best of all, surf! Safety precautions and experienced watermen (and women), along with lifeguards will be present. No prior surfing experience is necessary. 

Life Rolls On has several other programs and resources. Please visit the website (www.liferollson.org) to learn more.

Also, please consider installing the Life Rolls On app to your Facebook profile (http://apps.facebook.com/liferollson/)

You can also find us on Twitter, http://www.twitter.com/LifeRollsOn

MySpace http://www.myspace.com/LifeRollsOn

&amp; 

YouTube  http://www.youtube.com/lro501c3 

Why Does Life Rolls On Exist?

* 1,275,000 - Range of number of people in United States alone that have a spinal cord injury
* Approximately 12,000 new injuries occur each year
* 56% of injuries occur between the ages of 16 and 30

What Does This Mean for Life Rolls On? 

Every year, approximately 6720 (56% of 12,000) young people suffer a spinal cord injury. That means 18 youth suffer a new spinal cord injury every single day!

If you assume that even a fraction of these individuals affiliate with an action sports lifestyle, Life Rolls On can directly impact the lives of several hundred to thousands of additional people annually. Unfortunately, we need to compound this year-after-year, meaning Life Rolls On's programs stand to benefit tens of thousands of individuals. 

Your support helps Life Rolls On inspire and serve this important group of individuals.

1. They Will Surf Again - Adaptive surfing program for those with spinal cord injury and a life changing volunteer experience for all.

2. Injury Outreach and Being A Resource - LRO feels that early outreach immediately post injury can have a positive and meaningful impact.

3. Motivation and Awareness - Shifting paradigms in the general public about overcoming obstacles in the face of extreme adversity. (CLICK EXTENDED INFO)</description>
  <mission>LRO, a division of the Reeve Foundation, exists to be a resource that provides hope and is an advocate on behalf of young people whose lives have been affected by spinal cord injury.</mission>
  <name>Life Rolls On (Please join &amp; tell 10 friends!)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2154</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12351</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">6255.68</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vA/EG/PG/zu/ho/Hy/rBjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
