<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The DYF&#8217;s cornerstone program is our residential camp. Every summer, children ages 7-15 from throughout Indiana, swim, hike, explore creeks, and climb high ropes just like any other boy or girl at camp. They also poke, prick, test, count carbohydrates and learn what they need to do to live a vibrant, healthy life with diabetes. 

Camp provides a unique chance for these children to meet others facing the same problems in a "support group" like atmosphere.   The DYF provides a full camp program that involves athletic and social activities.  The only difference is that a huge volunteer staff of physicians, nurses and dietitians are closely involved with the day-to-day activities of the campers to ensure their medical well-being.  This relaxed, informal and peer-supported situation is ideal for teaching diabetes management techniques.  

Besides our residential camp, the DYF also provides several family camp weekends throughout the year. These mini retreats offer families with younger children an opportunity to &#8220;try out&#8221; camp. For older children with diabetes, the DYF offers a Counselor In Training (CIT) program and an adventure teen program. 

The Diabetes Youth Foundation is not affiliated with any national organization nor do we receive any funding from United Way. The not-for-profit organization is run solely on donations and grants. 

1. Many children are uninformed of the dangers of uncontrolled diabetes.

2. In educating children and families, the likelihood of living a complication free life is greatly increased.</description>
  <mission>To educate, support, encourage and entertain children with Type I diabetes and their families.</mission>
  <name>Diabetes Youth Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2162</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">268</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vS/UW/Em/5V/j6/RD/KXvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
