<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Drug Policy Alliance (DPA) seeks to advance policies that reduce the harms of both drug misuse and drug prohibition, and to find solutions that promote safety while upholding the sovereignty of individuals over their own minds and bodies. We work to ensure that our nation&#8217;s drug policies no longer arrest, incarcerate, disenfranchise and otherwise harm millions of nonviolent people, and to address the disproportionate impact of the drug war on people of color.

As a result of our work, hundreds of thousands of people have been diverted from incarceration to drug treatment programs, tens of thousands of sick and dying patients can safely access their medicine without being considered criminals under the law, and states like California have saved more than $1.5 billion by eliminating wasteful and ineffective law enforcement, prosecution and prison expenditures.

Few public policies have compromised public health and undermined our fundamental civil liberties for so long and to such a degree as the war on drugs.  The United States is now the world&#8217;s largest jailer, imprisoning nearly half a million people for drug offenses alone. That&#8217;s more people than Western Europe, with a bigger population, incarcerates for &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; offenses.  Roughly 1.5 million people are arrested each year for drug law violations - 40 percent of them just for marijuana possession. People suffering from cancer, AIDS and other debilitating illnesses are regularly denied access to their medicine or even arrested and prosecuted for using medical marijuana.  We can do better.  Join us. 

1. The drug war is doing more harm than good. 

2. People should not be punished solely for what they put into their bodies.

3. Government drug control resources should be redirected from criminal justice and interdiction to public health and education.</description>
  <mission>Mission: To advance those policies and attitudes that best reduce the harms of both drug misuse and drug prohibition, and to promote the sovereignty of individuals over their minds and bodies.</mission>
  <name>Drug Policy Alliance</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2166</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1903</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">533.65</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vb/8c/ML/jr/pt/t1/KC/7SS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
