<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>All of the following information is from http://www.dynakids.org

About Dysautonomia:

Dysautonomia is a medical term utilized for a group of complex conditions that are caused by a malfunction of the autonomic nervous system (ANS). The ANS regulates all of the unconscious functions of the body, including the cardiovascular system, gastrointestinal system, metabolic system, and endocrine system. A malfunction of the ANS can cause debilitating symptoms and may pose significant challenges for effective medical treatment.

Symptoms of dysautonomia may include: Tachycardia (extremely fast heart rate), bradycardia (slow heart rate), palpitations, chest pain, dangerously low blood pressure, wide swings/sudden drops in blood pressure, orthostatic intolerance (the inability to remain upright), excessive fatigue, exercise intolerance, dizziness, fainting/near fainting, gastrointestinal problems, nausea, insomnia, shortness of breath, anxiety, tremulousness, frequent urination, convulsions, cognitive impairment, visual blurring or tunneling, and migraines.

Specific conditions that fall under the category of Dysautonomia include but are not limited to: Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome (POTS), Neurally Mediated Hypotension (NMH), Neurocardiogenic Syncope (NCS), Vasovagal Syncope, Generalized Dysautonomia, Birth Dysautonomia, Non-Familial Dysautonomia, and Post-Viral Dysautonomia.

About DYNA:

The Dysautonomia Youth Network of America, Inc. (DYNA) is a 501(c) (3) non-profit organization dedicated to serving young people that are diagnosed with various childhood dysautonomia conditions.

further information on DYNA will be added once facebook actually does allow 2000 characters instead of being stupid :-/

1. Dysautonomia does not define a person.

2. Awareness is the first step in finding a cure.

3. Please join and invite all your friends!</description>
  <mission>To spread awareness of Dysautonomia</mission>
  <name>Dysautonomia Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/217</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12843</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2683.13</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/muu/TIxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
