<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> 
Cancer by the numbers:  This year, 211,000 women in the U.S. will be diagnosed with breast cancer, the most common type among women, excluding skin cancer. Another 80,000 women will be diagnosed with a cancer of the reproductive organs. According to the American Cancer Society, one-third of all women will face a diagnosis of cancer in their lifetimes. Fortunately, the odds of recovery today have increased dramatically, thanks to the medical advances and scientific breakthroughs that philanthropies such as the Mary Kay Ash Charitable Foundation are helping to support.
Mary Kay Ash believed that motivation, recognition and an unlimited opportunity could transform women, empowering them to achieve better lives for themselves and their families. Sadly, one in three women in the U.S. today will be the victim of violence during her lifetime. Domestic violence, rape, stalking and murder threaten and destroy women&#8217;s dreams, their families and, too often, their lives. 
Since 2000, the Mary Kay Ash Charitable Foundation has awarded millions of dollars to women&#8217;s shelters across the country. In 2005, the Foundation distributed $20,000 grants to 150 shelters. And again in 2006, the Foundation awarded $20,000 grants, totaling $3 million, to 150 shelters in all 50 states.

The Foundation invites you to join the effort to help women and children affected by violence. We encourage you to educate yourself about the issue. To be an informed listener. To seek help when there is a need. Most of all, we encourage you to break the silence. Only when the silence is broken can help be found and lives be changed. 

If you or anyone you know needs immediate help, call the National Domestic Violence Hotline at 800-799-SAFE (7233).

 

1. Let end Domestic Violence again Woen and Children

2. Cancers that effect Women - help find the cure

3. Break The Silence</description>
  <mission> eliminate cancers affecting womenand ending violence against women</mission>
  <name>Mary Kay Ash Charitable Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2219</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2551</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">380.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1B/4Z/2I/Zb/o7/sS/FdYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
