<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Americans have been agitating for more government control over their health care, often in the form of a single-payer system.  Under a single-payer system, the government funds all medical treatment for its citizens.  This sounds like a good idea, but it means that the government decides who gets treatment and when each person gets it.  It also means that demand for treatment rises above what is necessary, increasing costs.  Governments keep costs under control by placing patients on very long waiting lists and often denying treatment entirely.  This would persist no matter how much of the taxpayers' money the system receives.  The lack of price signals also reduces the incentive for progress and innovation.  A free market in health care drastically lessens all of these problems.

1. Health care is not a right.  Like food and shelter, it is a commodity, whether or not anyone wants it to be one.  Scarcity cannot be legislated away.

2. Health care will only become less expensive if patients have to bear more of the cost directly.  This works by forcing patients to be concious of price and to shop around, and it forces physicians to consider the ratio of cost to benefit.

3. Single payer health care systems have endangered the lives of many people in nations like Canada and the United Kingdom.  Anyone in these countries who supports the single-payer system probably hasn't been very sick and thus hasn't had to deal with them.

4. The faults of health care in the United States are largely because of too much government intervention, not too little.</description>
  <mission>support a free market in medicine and oppose a single-payer system.</mission>
  <name>Single-Payer Will Destroy Health Care</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2220</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">62</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yc/L4/Cn/E7/bG/SF/Al7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
