<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Equality Now was founded in 1992 to work for the protection and promotion of the human rights of women around the world. Working with national human rights organizations and individual activists, Equality Now documents violence and discrimination against women and mobilizes international action to support their efforts to stop these human rights abuses. Through its Women&#8217;s Action Network of concerned groups and individuals around the world, Equality Now distributes information about human rights violations, takes action to protest these violations, brings public attention to human rights violations against women.

The Women&#8217;s Action Network is committed to voicing a worldwide call for justice and equality for women. Issues of urgent concern to Equality Now include rape, domestic violence, reproductive rights, trafficking of women, female genital mutilation, and the denial of equal access to economic opportunity and political participation.

Human rights violations against women have historically been denied the attention and concern of international organizations, national governments, traditional human rights groups and the media. Meanwhile, hundreds of millions of girls and women around the globe continue to endure debilitating and often fatal human rights abuses.

Human rights violations against women must be documented, publicized--and stopped. 

We need equality, now.

-from www.equalitynow.org


1. Violence and discrimination against women must be stopped.

2. Through the education and mobilization of the public, we can do this.</description>
  <mission>End violence and discrimination against women and girls around the world.</mission>
  <name>Equality Now</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2223</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3511</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">926.36</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gG/um/U7/wk/7L/oD/0bDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
