<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>ALS is sometimes more commonly known as Lou Gehrig's disease. It is a rapidly progressive and fatal neuromuscular disease that is characterized by degeneration of a select group of nerve cells and pathways in the brain and spinal cord. This loss of motor neurons leads to progressive paralysis of the voluntary muscles. However, since breathing is controlled voluntarily by the chest muscles, death usually occurs when the chest muscles are no longer able to help the lungs achieve adequate oxygenation. Generally there is little impairment of the brain, sight, touch, hearing, or smell. 
ALS is not contagious, but it is fatal. For the most part, the battle is short, with 80% losing their lives within two to five years of diagnosis.  Research is being conducted in areas relating to genetic predispositions, viral or infectious agents, environmental toxins, and immunological changes. 
What are the early symptoms?
Some people begin to trip and fall, some may notice muscle loss in their hands and arms and some find it hard to swallow and slur their speech. 
ALS is difficult to diagnose. Unfortunately, there is no specific test available that will either rule out or confirm the presence of ALS. . Neurologists conduct a number of tests, thereby ruling out other disorders that may cause similar symptoms, such as strokes or multiple sclerosis, and if nothing else is positive and yet the symptoms continue to worsen, ALS is often the reason. 
What can be done about ALS? 
There is no known cure at this time and very little in the way of treatment that will have an effect on the disease itself.Research is looking to find not only the cause of the disease so that a cure can be developed but also other medications or treatments that can help until a cure is found.


1. 2000 Canadians and their families are living with ALS...Lets work together to find a cure

2. No-one is alone

3. Awareness brings hope</description>
  <mission>raise awareness of ALS</mission>
  <name>ALS Awareness and support</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2249</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5906</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">850.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Kx/Ul/8h/CQ/HG/kP/Pt/8QS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
