<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Why ?
Because they are the men and women going overseas to help some strangers getting basic freedoms.
Because they are the men and women fighting on a voluntary basis for the country, its interests and its values.
Because they are the men and women representing the country, both at home and abroad...that's why they're wearing a Canadian flag on their shoulder.
And mostly, because they deserve to be supported, respected and admired.


The Canadian Forces Personnel Support Agency (CFPSA) has launched, in 2006, its official &#8220;Support Our Troops" campaign, which gives Canadians easy and effective ways to support the entire CF community.

Canadians can show their support by:

- Wearing red on Fridays

- Writing to the troops on the Forces online message board :
www.forces.gc.ca/site/Community/Messageboard/index_e.asp

- Buying the official "Support Our Troops" merchandise available at CANEX or online :
https://www3.cfpsa.com/wyn/en/generalPublic/shoplist_e.asp?uid=196533&amp;location=&amp;dept=6

For you information, all proceeds from the sales of CFPSA "Support Our Troops" items are reinvested directly into morale and welfare programs for CF members and their families. 

For more information on the "Support Our Troops" programs, visit :
http://www.cfpsa.com/supportourtroops/


You can also donate to CF Personnel Assistance Fund, to the CF Hospital Comforts Program or to Operation Santa Claus.
For more info on how to do so, please visit :
http://www.cfpsa.com/en/corporate/NewsCentre/Support/index.asp

1. To show our support is to tell them we understand the hard job they do...</description>
  <mission>show our support to the Canadian troops</mission>
  <name>Support Our Troops (Canada)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2260</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">173197</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1494.53</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hX/oG/8e/Li/Lk/gM/f8KS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
