<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Ultraviolet (UV) rays are always somewhat dangerous. There are two types of UV rays, UVA and UVB. The sun emits mainly UVB rays, and they are associated with sunburn. Tanning booths emit mainly UVA rays, which are linked to deeper, more penetrating radiation and long-term skin damage.

It is true that because tanning booths emit UVA rays there is less danger of getting sunburned. But more recent evidence links UVA exposure to malignant melanoma, the most deadly form of skin cancer. Cases of malignant melanoma are becoming more common, possibly due to the increase in popularity of sun tanning booths.

Overexposure to any UV rays can cause premature aging and loss of skin elasticity. But premature aging and cancer are harmful effects of tanning booths that do not show up for many, many years, after damage to the skin is already irreversible.

There is no completely safe UV ray exposure. It is true that exposure to some sunlight is healthy, because it prompts the body to produce vitamin D, but the amount of sunlight needed for this health benefit is MINIMAL. UV rays are radiation, and over-exposure always causes damage of some kind. Both types of UV rays have been linked to immune system damage.

Tanning beds lead to all sorts of cancers. The problem with cancer research now is that a large majority of established scientists are "overlooking" tanning as a COMPLETELY PREVENTABLE cause of cancer.

Consider how large of an industry tanning is. Of course you will find bogus websites displaying sugar coated, twisted facts about the positive side of tanning - the tanning bed industry cannot afford for people to find out the truth.

..This is why artificial tanning must be stopped!

1. People must stop going to tanning beds.

2. People must be informed about tanning beds and stop ignoring the facts.

3. Everyone should know that malignant melanoma is preventable.</description>
  <mission>put an end to tanning beds.</mission>
  <name>Desist Artificial Tanning</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2272</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">89</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Q0/Rx/BC/H3/14/gB/a2QS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
