<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>SFCH is a student organization across college campuses nationwhide that works to raise money for Camp Heartland, a summer camp in Willow River, Minnesota for children affected or infected with AIDS or HIV. Camp Heartland also uses funds to bring AIDS awareness and prevention education to all parts of the world, because when truth spreads, AIDS won&#8217;t.

Yet, with all of that said, a question we tend to get is this:

&#8220;Who cares? How does this affect me? No one I know has AIDS.&#8221;

Well, for starters, on average one person a week is diagnosed HIV+ in the Madison, WI Metro Area, and the numbers are climbing. Yet, as the numbers of diagnosed people in Madison grow, there are still thousands of other citizens out there who do not know their HIV status; presumably there are countless people who are HIV+ and do not even know it. HIV and AIDS is all around us, yet unlike most killers of our youth, we all have the power to stop it. With your help, our goal of preventing the further spread of AIDS by spreading the truth about the disease can become a reality rather than a dream.

Peace. Love. and Compassion.

1. Fundraising---two thirds of our campers are below the national poverty line and camp can be expensive, so SFCH raises money for camp so all children infected with or affected by AIDS can enjoy the warm and loving place that is Camp Heartland.

2. Education---SFCH goes out into the Madison community to education the community members about how to protect themselves from the disease but also how to treat those suffering from HIV/AIDS with the respect and compassion they deserve.

3. Outreach---SFCH believes in tearing down the prejudice and stigmas that make AIDS seem to be an "evil" person's punishment for bad behavior by going out into the community and just doing plain good to better the situations of others---sort of a live by ex</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness, acceptance, and a safe haven for children with HIV/AIDS.</mission>
  <name>Students for Camp Heartland</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/228</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">798</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wOA/udhS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
