<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Mission Statement:  

The Student Global AIDS Campaign (SGAC) is a US-based network of student and youth organizations committed to the global fight against AIDS. SGAC seeks to mobilize a multi-racial student movement, in partnership with students internationally, to make claims upon governments, corporations, and civil society through education, leadership training, informed advocacy and direct action. SGAC demands sufficient resources, effective prevention, and guaranteed access to AIDS treatment and care as a matter of moral urgency.

Vision Statement:  

We envision a world in which AIDS is no longer a death sentence, in which economics and geography do not determine access to life-saving drugs, and where every woman, man, and child has the knowledge, means, and rights to protect her- or himself from infection. To achieve this world, we must remake our institutions to reflect a shared commitment to our common humanity. We must confront the underlying causes of the AIDS plague--poverty, inequalities of race, gender, and class, sexual stigmas, and a politics that allows us to deny our responsibilities to and for each other. Our global economy must be matched by a global conscience. We have the tools to fight AIDS: prevention, treatment, support for orphans and families. To succeed, we must summon the will to use these tools. We will not accept excuses for inaction; we will not accept false barriers that divide us; we will not accept the myth that any of us are powerless. We pledge ourselves to the struggle against AIDS--a struggle that becomes a fight against apathy, against indifference, against injustice. By forming a global youth movement, we will rise to the challenge of fighting AIDS. We will halt this pandemic.

AIDS is the crisis of our generation and we will be defined by our response to it. Years from now, we will have to answer our own children: did we stand by as millions died or did we take action? We will make our children proud.

1. AIDS does not discriminate based upon gender, race, socioeconomic status, sexual orientation, or age.

2. AIDS is not a punishment for sinning.

3. Every man, woman, and child should have the knowledge, means, and rights to protect him/herself from infection; geography and income should not play a role in this opportunity.</description>
  <mission>Fund the Fight. Treat the People. Drop the Debt. Stop the Spread. </mission>
  <name>Student Global AIDS Campaign</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2286</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">135</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wD/yN/ad/L7/kT/AZ/6tiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
