<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There are now more than 5 million people in the United States living with Alzheimer&#8217;s. 

Every 72 seconds, someone develops Alzheimer&#8217;s. 

The direct and indirect costs of Alzheimer&#8217;s and other dementias amount to more than $148 billion annually.

1 in 10 people over 65 and nearly half of those over 85 have Alzheimer's. A small percentage of the people in their 40s, 50s and early 60s also get the disease. All people with Down syndrome show the neuropathology of Alzheimer's disease by about age 35.

Alzheimer's is the 4th leading cause of death among adults. Typical life expectancy is 8-10 years from the onset of symptoms, although some people have lived with the disease for 20 years or more.

Over 70% of people with Alzheimer's live at home. Almost 75% of their care is provided by families and friends. Most of the rest is paid for out-of-pocket by these families at an average annual cost of $12,500.

Alzheimer's is the 3rd most expensive disease in the nation, after heart disease and cancer, with an average lifetime cost per patient of $174,000. 

Over half of all nursing home residents have Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder. The average cost of their care is $45,000 per year.

In 1997, the federal government spent about $320 million on Alzheimer's research, or about $1 for every $319 the disease now costs society. Federal investment in heart disease, cancer and AIDS is 3-5 times higher.

By 2050, the estimated range of Alzheimer's disease prevalence will be 11.3 million to 16 million Americans, with a middle estimate of 13.2 million unless a cure or prevention is found.

The federal government estimates spending approximately $598.9 million for Alzheimer disease research in FY2002.

**More can be done to help treat, and prevent his disease, Join us in the fight to cure this terrible disease, not only for our gradparents, and parents....but for us, as well as our children.

1. More federal funding and research needs to be created in order to make strides in treating Alzheimer's.</description>
  <mission>Support continued research and funding in hopes of finding better treatments, and ultimately a cure for Alzheimer's</mission>
  <name>Support Alzheimer's Research and Treatment</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2288</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1939</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1330.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5o/jW/qc/fN/WU/Ka/ZFdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
