<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Most of you know that I'm a very active person... but now I'm taking it a step further and running a MARATHON!!! Yup, that's right in October I'll be running 26.2 miles, yes 26.2!  

I am doing this for a number of reasons, one being to honor my friend, Sean Robbins, who recently passed away after his long battle with cancer. With each step I'll be remembering what an amazing person he was and how many people's lives he touched.  
  
The program that I'm doing this through is The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society&#8217;s Team In Training. Team In Training is a fundraising and training program that will prepare me for the challenges of running a marathon while fundraising. The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society is a national voluntary health agency dedicated to curing leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin&#8217;s disease and myeloma, and improving the quality of life of patients and their families.

If there is anything that you can contribute to support me as I fundraise for the Team in Training program and train for the NIKE WOMEN'S MARATHON for OCT 21st in San Francisco, I will love you forever!!!  I have made a personal commitment to raise $3,500.  Your tax-deductible donation to the Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society will further this great cause and in making a difference.  A full 80% of all donations go directly to the cause, so I&#8217;m asking you to be as generous as you can!  The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society prides itself in being rated by Money magazine as one of the top ten charities for having the highest percentage of funds raised directly benefiting research and patient services.  

My personal fundraising deadline is approaching so I ask that you send your contribution ASAP! 

All donations are 100% tax deductible, and our tax ID is 13-5644916.  PLEASE pass this along to your friends &amp; family.  

Thank you so much!

Michelle
P.S. You can also donate and see my webpage at http://www.active.com/donate/tntgla/meesh


1. We can fundraise to help find a cure!</description>
  <mission>find a cure!</mission>
  <name>Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society&#8217;s Team In Training</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2301</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/N5/Ia/rZ/T8/lL/Iw/zH0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
