<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Columbia Second Chance was founded in 1985 as a no-kill, privately-funded, all-volunteer organization dedicated to "seeking first-class homes for second-hand pets." 

Through the kindness of our volunteers and our foster homes, we care for animals of all types, either on a temporary basis while we search for a new, permanent home, or on a long-term basis while the animal is treated for illness or injury. At no time are animals euthanized just because they don't have a home - all animals have a home at Columbia Second Chance. Animals are accepted on a space-available basis.

Columbia Second Chance has two operating facilities. The dogs are housed on 60 acres of land in Moneteau County, Missouri. The cats live in an indoor/outdoor facility based in Columbia Missouri. Columbia Second Chance sponsors educational workshops in local schools and organizes weekly adoption events at participating businesses. In addition, CSC provides advice and help to frustrated pet owners. We are an all volunteer animal rescue. All donations and funds raised directly benefit the animals in our care.

For more information you can visit Columbia Second Chance on the web at http://www.columbia2ndchance.org

Columbia Second Chance is a great "no-kill" organization here in Mid-Missouri. Our boxer Duchess (the picture you see for the cause) was a rescue from Columbia Second Chance and is one of the best dogs ever. I highly recommend you help them out in anyway you can, especially volunteering your time. 

1. Finding quality homes for pets.

2. No kill facility and organization.

3. All volunteer animal rescue group.</description>
  <mission>Help find "first class homes for second-hand pets"</mission>
  <name>Columbia Second Chance</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2303</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">115</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zr/Ck/oH/bp/zt/kg/PilS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
