<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The problem just doesn&#8217;t start with one animal, or one piece of land. It&#8217;s a world wide problem, and has larger effects than most realize. If we lose just one species it can have a catastrophic down fall for all life.

People around the world do not have enough education about these animals and are killing them, whether it be for sport, fear, medicinal use, black market, or food.

&#8221;Since 1990, the elephant population in the country has plunged from 1,500 to 2,000 individuals to barely 100&#8221; &#8211;(Source: http://archives.cnn.com/2000/NATURE/12/14/asian.elephant.enn/index.html)

There are 1,178 endangered species in North America alone!

Ecuador has 240 CRITICLLY ENDANGERD species and 669 ENDANGERED species!

4,864 endangered, critically endangered, Vulnerable, Extinct, species world wide. SPECIES, not animals. 
 
What are you going to do? It's our turn to stand up and defend the defenseless.

&lt;img src="http://www.looking-glass.co.uk/animals/images/wasatch-before-rescue.jpg"&gt;
A bear cub and its leach and mussel.

&lt;img src="http://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/bigphotos/images/060522-lions_big.jpg"&gt;
Men from the Maasai people in southern Kenya killed lions these lions and more out of fear. If it keeps going this way the Lions in Kenya will vanish for good by 2009. 

&lt;img src="http://www.aapn.org/images2/hangzhoumonk.jpg"&gt;

&lt;img src="http://www.ifaw.org/ifaw/dimages/richtext_1124.jpg"&gt;

&lt;img src="http://www.tigerhomes.org/images/poaching1.jpg"&gt;

&lt;img src="http://www.tigerhomes.org/images/poaching2.jpg"&gt;

&lt;img src="http://www.ens-newswire.com/ens/sep2005/20050923_leopardskinstack.jpg"&gt;


Good Websites;

http://www.worldwildlife.org

www.wildlifewarriors.org.au

http://www.wildnet.org

http://www.iucnredlist.org




Now we are on myspace;
Group URL: http://groups.myspace.com/conserveprotectpreserve



&lt;h2&gt;If you can, DONATE to the websites I've just listed. A little can go a long way. It all adds up in the end!!!&lt;/h2&gt;

1. Conserve Protect Preserve Wildlife

2. Educate

3. Send message of CONSERVATION!

4. The dangerous animals need OUR help too!</description>
  <mission>Conserve Protect Preserve All Wildlife: From the cute and cuddlies to the dangerous ones</mission>
  <name>Conserve Protect Preserve: All Wildlife!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2311</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1930</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.15</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fJ/qI/zQ/gC/iZ/2L/ItTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
