<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This cause is to organize the public and advocate for motorists' rights.  This group will help motorists challenge unfair traffic laws that are passed in the "name of safety," but are really meant to increase the bank accounts of big insurance companies, speed detection equipment manufacturers, and of course GOVERNMENT.

All money raised will be donated to a non-profit organization called the National Motorists Association (motorists.org).

Artifically low, fixed speed limits are bad for the environment and reduce safety on the road.  Scientific studies have shown that if the majority of people are speeding (usually the case) and a few people are going the limit or 5-15mph below it, the DIFFERENCE in speed is more risky than speed itself.  Furthermore, all the stop and go (brake/accelerate) wastes gas.  This increases gas prices and harms the environment.

Benefits to joining the National Motorists Association:

1.  NMA members who plead "not guilty," fight their speeding tickets, but still lose, will have their fines paid for them.

2.  Subscription to: Driving Freedoms newsletter. 

3.  Special email alerts keep you informed of pending legislation and regulations that affect you!

4.  In addition to the ticket fighting information available to the public on our website, the National Motorists Association has premium information available for use by our members in fighting their tickets. 

5.  Access to traffic law experts/activists/coordinators to give you help in fighting your traffic tickets. 

6.  Members have exclusive access to our extensive traffic attorney referral list. 

7.  Discounted Car Rentals 

8. The Guerilla Ticket Fighter (CD-ROM) will tell you how to defend yourself against traffic tickets using strategies that have proven successful for other motorists, just like you.


1. Fixed speed limits on expressways must be raised to 80mph. 

2. Speed bumps on public roads must be removed.

3. Yield signs should replace stop signs where applicable.</description>
  <mission>Encourage the free flow of traffic by reducing or eliminating restrictions on speed.  All unreasonable traffic laws should be repealed.  It's unacceptable to use them as a way to generate revenue!</mission>
  <name>Eliminate Speed Limits</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2327</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">68</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6K/Ej/2k/CU/MI/f7/hbXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
