<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Autism rates have been rising steadily &#8212; even dramatically &#8212; in Canada. An estimated 190,000 Canadian children have the disorder. The most recent epidemiological studies suggest that the rate of autism has increased from 40 cases per 100,000 to 60 cases. 

Autism was first described in the early 1940s by two doctors who were working independently of each other. Leo Kanner and Hans Asperger identified a set of symptoms they found among the children they were studying. Both used the word autism &#8212; from the Greek word for self &#8212; to describe the children they treated who seemed enclosed in their own solitary worlds. 

Autism Spectrum Disorder is a neurological condition that causes developmental disability. It affects the way the brain functions and results in difficulties with communication and social interaction. People with the disorder also exhibit unusual patterns of behaviour, activities and interests. If untreated, the symptoms can be very persistent and difficult to change.

There are several ways people with autism are treated and there is plenty of debate over what kinds of treatments offer the most success. Applied Behavioural Analysis (ABA) and Intensive Behavioural Intervention (IBI) are designed to actively engage children with communication, socialization, learning and behavioural problems. 

Applied Behavioural Analysis (ABA) can be extremely expensive as it involves one-on-one teaching for up to 40 hours per week. Costs range from $30,000 to $80,000 a year, according to Autism Society Canada. IBI is also an intensive program that can involve either one-on-one therapy or sessions with small groups. 

Other types of therapy can combine elements of physiotherapy, counselling, development of motor and language skills, diet and medication. 


1. The government stops funding at age 6. 

2. This affects many families today. 

3. By making a donation, you can make a difference. </description>
  <mission>Raise money for Autistic research and foundations. </mission>
  <name>Raise Autism Awareness and Help Out!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2330</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2341</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">30.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/FN/ye/K5/Hm/gw/XC/wjhS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
