<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Although the Romani people are often referred to as "Gypsies" (and prefer to be called by their more proper designation, Roma), not all "gypsies" or nomadic peoples are Roma. The Roma are descendants of the ancient warrior classes of Northern India, particularly the Punjab, and they are identifiable by their language, religion, and customs, which can be directly linked to those of the Punjabi in northern India.
    Former Indian Prime Minister Indira Ghandi summarized the state of the Romani people very nicely in her opening speech at the International Romani Festival in Chandigarh, India on October 28, 1983. It is paraphrased below (by Milena Hubschmannova &amp; Jaroslav Jurasek)

    "There are some 15 million Roms dispersed across the world. Their history is one of suffering and misery, but it is also one of the victories of human spirit over the blows of fate. Today the Roms revive their culture and are looking for their identity. On the other hand, they integrate into the societies in which they live. If they are understood by their fellow citizens in their new homelands, their culture will enrich the society's atmosphere with the color and charm of spontaneity."


THE INVISIBILITY OF THIS RACE IS NO LONGER TOLERABLE

for more information visit
http://www.geocities.com/~patrin/
or check out
Bury Me Standing; The Gypsies and Their Journey
by Isabella Fonseca
and
The Gypsies
by Jan Yoors

1. the Romani people have experienced a suffering that rivals even that of the Jewish nation

2. at least half a million Rom were slaughtered in the Holocaust at the hands of the Nazi's and being a nation without a state, had no army to defend the crimes against them

3. today there is still legislation in place around the world prohibiting the migration and citizenship of the Rom, the culmination of centuries of racism and prejudice alive and well

4. the Rom were enslaved in Romania for 500 years

5. the Rom population is currently estimated at about 10 million; primarily illiterate, impoverished and unregistered</description>
  <mission>to abolish stereotypes</mission>
  <name>Rom Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2331</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1043</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/rw/cC/Ik/TS/rd/6Q/NusS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
