<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I dream of world where the artistic and intellectual minds lead all humanity into a spiritual awakening. Cast off shackles of mental oppression, and the sedation of our everyday lives.
I see so many great minds, so many beautiful ideas; suppressed. Draining what little force of resistance we have amongst each other, without realizing the counter-productivity and further sedation and oppression we suffer, and never really finding a real outlet to focus this frustration on. Even what you deem the stupidest crackhead could tell you there's a problem, I'm sure you can tell just by watching him huff that inhalant-soaked rag stuffed in his mouth. But your awareness, even though through hazy eyes, is enough for change to start happening. Question your position in life, Question your indoctrinated beliefs. Know that you're not alone, and slowly we're all waking up. We are finding like minded people, and slowly scratching at the paint of the invisible concrete trap. In numbers, we can accomplish anything. Anything. But we must ensure that no matter what happens, we will never let this happen to the world again. We must ensure that it is the artistic and intellectual minds that lead us, in unity. And so slowly, I wake 

&lt;img src="http://www.liquidenterprise.org/xx.gif"&gt;

For thousands of years, human beings had screwed up and trashed and crapped on this planet, and now history expected me to clean up after everyone. I have to wash out and flatten my soup cans. And account for every drop of used motor oil. And I have to foot the bill for nuclear waste and buried gasoline tanks and landfilled toxic sludge dumped a generation before I was born...

&lt;img src="http://www.liquidenterprise.org/mcdonalds.jpg"&gt;



&lt;img src="http://www.liquidenterprise.org/xxxx.gif"&gt;


&lt;img src="http://www.liquidenterprise.org/xxxxx.gif"&gt;

1. Youth should stop buying rebellion, and act where our parents failed.

2. Know that were already dead, just too stupid to realize. Knowing this you are completly free.

3. Question your indoctrinated beliefs.

4. Somewhere out there someone is making money of things that they tell you you like.</description>
  <mission>Prevent the spread of the poison that is North-American culture</mission>
  <name>Help Stop North-American Globalization</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2335</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">153</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8Y/dk/mN/CA/rP/IO/PycS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
