<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hats Off For Cancer is a non-profit organization that collects and distributes new hats to children who have lost their hair due to their cancer treatments. Through donations from local and national companies, public officials, celebrities, schools and civic organizations, Hats Off For Cancer has delivered hats to more than 690,000 deserving children on five continents around the world since 1996.

Celebrating its 10 year anniversary, Hats Off For Cancer was established when Tara Lawrence began volunteering with the American Cancer Society. After multiple conversations with children who were battling cancer or who were cancer survivors, Ms. Lawrence noticed that one of the most challenging issues for children undergoing cancer treatments was losing their hair. Ten years later, Hats Off For Cancer has received more than 690,000 donations for deserving children. For more information, visit www.hatsoffforcancer.org.

You can also help support Hats Off For Cancer by shopping online through Giveline.  Just click on this link:
&lt;a href="http://www.giveline.com/default.asp?v=V054738361"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.giveline.com/buttons/giveline1_120_90.gif" width="120" height="90" border="0" alt="Support Hats Off For Cancer by Shopping at Giveline"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

1. Hats Off For Cancer strives to bring awareness to childhood cancer while helping to make a childhood cancer patient's smile a bit brighter and their day a bit happier!</description>
  <mission>Hats Off For Cancer strives to bring awareness to childhood cancer while helping to make a childhood cancer patient's smile a bit brighter and their day a bit happier!</mission>
  <name>Hats Off For Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2339</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2354</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1436.74</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8B/2I/v4/VK/Le/0s/N6oS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
