<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Give a child an instrument and a stage and that child will speak louder, more intelligently and more passionately with and because of music. It is a simple truth, and the driving force behind Music is Art.

Whether or not we have had formal training, each of us is a musician. We whistle at work, we sing along to the radio in the car, we add our voice at church, and absentmindedly tap out a beat while in line. While it seems redundant too say that music is the soundtrack of our lives; imagine a world without it. From songs on the radio to music in commercials from the rousing anthems in an arena to the gentle musical ambience of a restaurant, music is everywhere. It is inextricably woven into the fabric of our existence. And, it has been that way for centuries. Long before Guttenberg, songs were ours means of communication. It was how we told our stories, how we documented our cultures, and how we passed our histories and lore from generation to generation. Even today the diversity of our culture is reflected in and documented by our music. It is no small coincidence that each generation can look to music to find an example of a seminal moment or event in their history.

Music is also the great equalizer. While race may define genres or styles of music, music is colorblind to song within each and every one of us. And unlike sports, music does not require a prototype physique to assure success. Blindness did not dim Ray Charles fire, and deafness did not silence Beethovens voice. In fact, music was the very thing that lifted them beyond those limitations.

Music is Art believes that no one should be denied his or her musical voice. As a person, as a community, and as a culture it is our need, responsibility, and obligation to pass along our history and language to those who follow.

To find out more and about more ways to help go to: http://www.musicisart.org

1. No one should be denied his or her musical voice.</description>
  <mission>keep the Arts in education alive in the Buffalo Public Schools.</mission>
  <name>Music is Art</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2344</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9140</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/BP/Y1/PS/Cy/aD/Ys/dpCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
