<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Inspired by the democratic movements of the Left and developed by scholars Michael Albert and Robin Hahnel, ParEcon seeks freedom from both Capitalism and Centralized Socialism.  

&lt;u&gt;The philosophy hinges on 5 defining components:&lt;/u&gt;
&lt;b&gt;1. Social ownership of productive assets&lt;/b&gt; -  ParEcon would abandon private property as a defining economic feature and allow communities to share every device of production.
  
&lt;b&gt;2. Self-managing worker and consumer councils&lt;/b&gt; - Vertical models of decision making are not only disempowering to the vast majority of people, but they're also inefficient.  The only way to conflate all economic, environmental and social concerns into our work and consumption is through democratic councils.

&lt;b&gt;3. Balanced job complexes&lt;/b&gt; - Things that need to be done in an economy can be broken down into tasks which can balanced across workplaces, industries and all of society.  ParEcon holds that we should share the burden of rote work and share the benefits of empowering work. 

&lt;b&gt;4. Remuneration for effort and sacrifice&lt;/b&gt; - ParEcon would only reward effort and sacrifice and accommodate anyone in need.

&lt;b&gt;5. Participatory Planning&lt;/b&gt; - For too long we've been told that only CEOs, bureaucrats or invisible appendages can make decisions for us.  ParEcon seeks to dismantle that assumption to inject democracy into economic matters.

&lt;u&gt;Learn more at:&lt;/u&gt; http://www.parecon.org.

1. Solidarity

2. Diversity

3. Equity

4. Self-Management

5. Efficiency</description>
  <mission>Bring about a movement toward a more egalitarian, decentralized, democratic form of cooperative economics to our world and communities.</mission>
  <name>The ParEcon Movement</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2348</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">459</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/j5/AS/w4/rp/r5/lY/dTpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
