<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>NetAid educates, inspires and empowers new generations of young people to fight global poverty throughout their lives.  We are creating a movement of informed youth&#8212;tomorrow's leaders and voters&#8212;who understand the root causes of global poverty and are committed to ending it.

Around the world, one out of every six people struggles to survive on less than $1 a day.  Such extreme poverty robs people of their fundamental human rights, contributes to the spread of preventable diseases, keeps children out of school, and in its most insidious form, kills the most vulnerable. 

For the first time in history, we have the knowledge and the resources to end global poverty. But reducing the growing disparity between rich and poor will take a coordinated global effort of families, communities, businesses, and governments. 

Young people, and particularly young Americans, can and must play a key role in building this partnership for a better world.  But while many young Americans are concerned about the world's poor, most don't know how they can make a difference.  That's where NetAid comes into the picture.

NetAid's innovative programs educate young people about global poverty and international development, and provide opportunities for them to take concrete actions that make a difference in the lives of the world's poor. Our programs include:

1. NetAid Global Citizen Corps: Empowers high school students in the U.S. to educate and rally their peers in efforts to end global poverty.  
2. NetAid Global Action Awards: Honors high schools students in the U.S. who take outstanding actions to improve the lives of the world's poorest people.  
3. NetAid World Schoolhouse: Connects individuals and organizations to local projects that help the world's poorest children go to school and build brighter futures. 

1. End extreme poverty.

2. Relieve 100% of highly-indebted countries' debts.

3. Improve global education and increase the number of children recieving an education. 

4. Help end the spread of HIV/AIDS and increase the availability of ARV's. 

5. End world hunger. </description>
  <mission> NetAid: Educating, inspiring and empowering young people to fight global poverty!</mission>
  <name>Net Aid</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2351</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">157</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8X/1s/kA/dG/eT/rg/uGES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
