<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I devote all my attentions to improving the welfare of my subjects, since I wish to save my soul and go to Heaven. 
King Charles III of Spain, 1750. 

Monarchy is the one system of government where power is exercised for the good of all.
Aristotle, 322-384 BC.

In republics there is not a respect for authority, but a fear of power.
Dr Samuel Johnson (Boswell&#8217;s Life, p 464).

Russia under Nicholas II, with all the survivals of feudalism, had opposition political parties, independent trade unions and newspapers, a rather radical parliament and a modern legal system. Its agriculture was on the level of the USA, with industry rapidly approaching the West European level. 
In the USSR there was total tyranny, no political liberties and practically no human rights. Its economy was not viable; agriculture was destroyed. The terror against the population reached a scope unprecedented in history. 
No wonder many Russians look back at Tsarist Russia as a paradise lost.
Oleg Gordievsky, letter to The Independent, 21 July 1998.

For every monarchy overthrown the sky becomes less brilliant, because it loses a star. A republic is ugliness set free.
Anatole France, first winner of the Nobel Prize for Literature, 1921.

[A] king is a king, not because he is rich and powerful, not because he is a successful politician, not because he belongs to a particular creed or to a national group. He is King because he is born. And in choosing to leave the selection of their head of state to this most common denominator in the world - the accident of birth - Canadians implicitly proclaim their faith in human equality; their hope for the triumph of nature over political manoeuvre, over social and financial interest; for the victory of the human person. 
Jacques Monet, Canadian historian.

Not to be a republican at 20 shows lack of heart. To be one at 30 shows lack of head.
Francois Guizot, French statesman 1787-1874.




1. we strongly suggest visiting www.monarchy.net, website of international monarchists.

2. we are open to all monarchists around the world, regardless of religion or social status.</description>
  <mission>restoration of the former monarchies</mission>
  <name>Royalist Restoration</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2355</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">299</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pf/Ah/f0/2N/aT/qS/EbeS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
