<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Regardless of any religious creed or ideological affiliation, the fundamental right to life is one that must be respected in all aspects and industries of society.  It is the obligated right - civil and moral - that the human person, as natural law tells us, is protected from "conception to natural death."  Opposing human dignity is mutually exclusive with a just and civil society, regardless of a government&#8217;s ambivalence towards infanticide.   Our mission, then, is to bring both a culture and society, familial and political, to the visage of a truly humanistic existence.  As such, we defend, promote, and give to the world what is most sacred to us, these members:  that is, LIFE!


 +  +  +

For Catholics, the Catechism of the Catholic Church presents the totality of the Church's teaching on life:

"Human life must be respected and protected absolutely from the moment of conception.  From the first moment of his existence, a human being must be recognized as having the rights of a person - among which is the inviolable right of every innocent being to life" (CCC 2270).

In addition, the Catechism states:

"The inalienable right to life of every innocent human individual is a constitutive element of a civil society and its legislation" (2273).

Donum vitae, a document published by the Congregation of the Doctrine of the Faith, equivocates the theory &#8211; rather, the reality &#8211; of &#8220;political responsibility&#8221;:

"The moment a positive law deprives a category of human beings of the protection which civil legislation accord them, the state is denying the equality of all before the law" (DV III).


 + + +

TO ALL DEFENDERS OF HUMAN LIFE, and to all those who share common values for the sustainment of the just human condition:  Welcome!  Please, invite others, spread the Good news, and relish in the fulfillment you obtain in fighting the Good fight.

Each second, one child dies from the fatal wounds of murder...what we call "abortion:" a legalized, morally evil act the United States 'constitutionally' protects.  Let us change that...let us support life in all forms!

The site is against, namely:  Abortion, Mercy Killing/Euthanasia, Suicide, the Death Penalty, all other obstructions to the right to life (e.g. forced poverty, abuse, etc.)


1. Life begins at conception and ends at natural death.

2. Abortion, mercy killing, suicide, the death penalty, and all other obstructions to the right to life are immoral by natural law.

3. Humanity must promote life, socially, politically, and economically.  Faith and reason are key to understanding our positions.</description>
  <mission>To preserve the dignity of every human life, from conception to natural death.</mission>
  <name>Right to Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2357</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6851</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">272.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Qt/78/ob/MY/SZ/Gn/l3/2rS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
