<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> The campus ministry of Campus Crusade for Christ is a network of vibrant, growing movements on 1,029 campuses in the United States and beyond. Proven and diverse outreach strategies expose millions of students to the gospel each year. Over the past five years, more than 37,900 students made a decision to become a Christian. Campus Crusade for Christ is the world's largest evangelical organization.
    Likely there is one on your Campus and I encourage you to get involved if you are not so already. It is a life changing experience and brings great fulfillment to serve the Lord in such a way and to know that their is purpose in the things you do. If you are interested in learning more please go to www.campuscrusadeforchrist.com and if you have problems having Faith or anything like that please go to www.everystudent.com
God Bless

official mission statement for CCCI

Campus Crusade for Christ International is an interdenominational ministry committed to helping take the gospel of Jesus Christ to all nations. We cooperate with millions of Christians from churches of many denominations and hundreds of other Christian organizations around the world to help Christians grow in their faith and share the Gospel message with their fellow countrymen.

Working together with these fellow believers, our goal for this decade is to help give every man, woman, and child in the entire world an opportunity to find new life in Jesus Christ. Our commitment is based on our Lord's command:

    "All authority has been given to Me in heaven and on earth. Go therefore and make disciples of all the nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit, teaching them to observe all that I commanded you: and lo, I am with you always, even to the end of the age." Matthew 28:18-20 (NAS)


1. Accepting Christ's Death on the Cross Justifys a person making them accepting to be with a Holy and Righteous God in Heaven

2. We are called to share this good news with all of creation in order to spread the Kingdom of God on this Earth

3. We believe that God created you personally and  has a wondeful plan for your life

4. We believe that all of us are seperated from God because of our sin which keeps us from being able to be with a holy perfect God, perfection cannot be with imperfection

5. We believe that God bridged that gap when Christ died and rose again because by having Faith in Christ we are made right with God 

6. You can accept Christ now by praying to recieve him into your life, if this is your wish please get in contact with me or any Campus Crusade for Christ staff member</description>
  <mission>Win students for Christ, build them in Christ and send them into the world</mission>
  <name>Campus Crusade for Christ</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2364</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5347</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">165.71</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nI/HS/CN/vy/zb/Xi/02ZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
