<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Proceeds go to the US-Afghanistan Reconstruction Council.

The U.S.-Afghanistan Reconstruction Council (US-ARC) a non-profit, non-partisan 501(C)(3) organization, was founded by a group of professional Afghan-Americans and Americans.

Five guiding principles remain steadfast in any project that US-ARC initiates:

1. The Role, Concerns and Involvement of Women: Ensure that women are included as beneficiaries, participants and advisors in each program.

2. Strengthening Civil Society: Promote institutional development and self-reliance through participatory project design and implementation as well helping communities to establish forms that facilitate dialogue on conflict prevention and mitigation, understanding changes in new constitutional and legislative laws, advocacy campaigns and effective engagement with local governments.

3. Use of Appropriate Technology: Ensure that the use of local materials, technology and project design are culturally acceptable in the recipient communities, while raising skill levels and introducing new technologies as appropriate.

4. Natural resources and Environment: Ensure efficient use of natural resources to balance the benefits of economic development with viable environmental systems.

5. Basic Skill and Capacity Building: Ensures that project implementation promotes and includes improvements in literacy levels and general aptitude.

Projects include:

Textile Art &amp; Apparel Academy for Women in Herat

Godah Girls' Primary School

Dairy Industry Revitalization in Afghanistan



1. All people on Earth deserve a decent standard of living

2. Terrorism can only be stopped by fighting its causes of poverty and extremism

3. The Bush Administration is too incompetent to correctly rebuild Afghanistan- the private sector must step up</description>
  <mission>Give Afghanis an opportunity for better lives and extend a big middle-finger to the Taliban</mission>
  <name>Rebuild Afghanistan</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2366</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">98</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7d/pM/AE/bu/yh/Ri/FUZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
