<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>DON'T

    * Post your cell phone number, address, or the name of your school
    * Post your friends&#8217; names, ages, phone numbers, school names, or addresses
    * Add people as friends to your site unless you know them in person
    * Communicate with people you don&#8217;t know
    * Give out your password to anyone other than your parent or guardian
    * Meet in person with anyone you first &#8220;met&#8221; on a social networking site
    * Respond to harassing or rude comments posted on your profile
    * Make or post plans and activities on your site
    * Post photos with school names, locations, license plates, or signs
    * Post photos with the name of your sports team
    * Post sexually provocative photos
    * Respond to threatening or negative emails or IMs

DO

    * Check the privacy settings of the social networking sites that you use
    * Set privacy settings so that people can only be added as your friend if you approve them
    * Set privacy settings so that people can only view your profile if you have approved them as a friend
    * Remember that posting information about your friends could put them at risk
    * Consider going through your blog and profile and removing information that could put you at risk
    * Delete any unwanted messages or friends who continuously leave inappropriate comments
    * Report comments to the networking site if they violate that site&#8217;s terms of service
    * Save or print questionable activity and include date and time
    * Tell your parents or guardian if anything happens online that makes you feel scared, uncomfortable, or confused

WHEN TO TELL

Trust Your Intuition: Always go with your gut feeling, and if something doesn't feel right to you or a friend, report it. You can help stop the online victimization of youth.


1. Type Smart. Post Wisely

2. Be smart. If you don&#8217;t use privacy settings, anyone has access to your blog or profile, not just people you know

3. Trust Your Intuition: Always go with your gut feeling, and if something doesn't feel right to you or a friend, report it. </description>
  <mission>You can help stop the online victimization of youth. </mission>
  <name>2SMRT4U</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/237</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">206</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1Ae/MKBS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
