<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Senator Hillary Clinton is AWESOME!!  (I have personally met her.)  I am a volunteer on her presidential campaign and a financial contributor as well.  

She is truly the right person for this time in our nation's history.  Consider all the Republican candidates--they support Bush's decision to send more of our people into Iraq (i.e.: the "surge").  They have all said they will continue the war--essentially continuing the policies of the Bush-Cheney administration.

President Hillary Clinton will end this war.  She will send her husband, Bill Clinton, around the world to repair our reputation and rebuild our alliances with the rest of the world. (By the way, Bill Clinton is also AWESOME!  He is raising soooo much money to provide AIDS medications to poor nations.  This is a former president who has made a true difference in the world.)

Don't believe the negative hype that Senator Clinton is polarizing.  During her 7 years in the U.S. Senate, she has co-sponsored bills with many conservative Republicans.  

She is a consensus builder, intelligent, articulate, and truly cares about people.  She is the POLAR OPPOSITE of this administration and the Republicans running for President.

Hillary Clinton is strong on national defense--many military generals are among her supporters.  In ancient Britain, the Iceni were lead by a woman known as Bodiaca--the Warrior Queen.  I see President Hillary Clinton fulfilling that role for 21st century America.

Go to www.hillaryclinton.com to learn more.  Also, MAKE A CONTRIBUTION!!!  Even if you only donate $10 or $20 you are making a BIG DIFFERENCE.  Especially for my under-18 friends out there who aren't eligible to vote--donating to Hillary Clinton's is a way to have your voice heard.

GIVE 'EM HELL, HILLARY!!!!!






1. President Hillary Clinton will end the war in Iraq.

2. President Hillary Clinton will do away with "Don't ask--Don't Tell" to allows gay people to serve open and honestly in our military.

3. President Hillary Clinton will fight for universal health care for all Americans.

4. President Hillary Clinton will work with Republicans, but stand strong for our values--ending one-part rule we have had for the past 7 years</description>
  <mission>Win the Democratic primaries and the November, 2008 general election</mission>
  <name>Hillary Clinton for President!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2372</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">30</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hR/pI/7m/Oj/FJ/TY/nZmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
