<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>LIFE stands for "Living in Families Effectively." The LIFE seminars were developed as a therapeutic and preventive program to address many family needs.

What do parents need in an effective parent education program? First, they need INFORMATION :
    1. About CHILD DEVELOPMENT.
    2. About HOW FAMILIES WORK.

Parents also need a VALUE BASE for their parenting strategies :
    1. A general philosophy of DISCIPLINE, which will help them distinguish between abusive punishment and encouraging training.
    2. An approach to MENTAL HEALTH : What makes a healthy family and a healthy individual? What are emotions for? What kind of family life makes children grow up emotionally healthy?
    3. A FAMILY VALUE SYSTEM, so that they can bring up children who make a positive contribution to society.

Parents also need SKILLS :
    1. Avariety of practical techniques for managing children's BEHAVIOR.
    2.Effective ways to deal with their OWN EMOTIONS.
    3. Effective ways to deal with their CHILDREN'S EMOTIONS.
    4. Effective ways to COMMUNICATE with their children, make requests, listen to feelings and negotiate family agreements.
    5. Ways of helping their children develop responsibility and maturity.

1. Each person is a growing creature with unique potential, and deserves to be unconditionally loved

2. A healthy family is a place in which each member is loved and respected for who he or she is

3. The goals of effective parenting are the development of self-esteem, empathy, responsibility, and values, rather than obedience and conformity</description>
  <mission>Empower parents and families with education so they can understand and solve their own problems. (Note: needs approval as an official cause.)</mission>
  <name>LIFE Seminars - www.LifeSeminars.com</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2373</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cc/He/kU/hF/Xg/Ky/TGVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
