<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> Push America was founded in 1977 by Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity with the purpose of instilling lifelong service in its members and enhancing the quality of life for people with disabilities. Push America is still fulfilling the purpose it was intended for, but has grown into a nationwide organization with numerous programs educating undergraduates, alumni, and communities about the abilities of people with disabilities.

The areas we focus on are service leadership, construction, and cycling.

Service Leadership &#8211; With over 6,000 undergraduates and 65,000 alumni nationwide, Push America and Pi Kappa Phi have a unique opportunity to touch the lives of many individuals and encourage them to become leaders through service on campus and in their communities. At leadership conferences every year Pi Kappa Phi leaders learn how to spread the message of acceptance and understanding for people with disabilities to their own campuses and communities.

Construction &#8211; Pi Kappa Phi is heavily involved in the construction of accessible environments nationwide on campuses, in communities, at camps for people with disabilities, and even at individuals&#8217; homes. Members of Pi Kappa Phi work year round, providing funds and man power, to help create a barrier free society for people with disabilities.

Cycling &#8211; Since 1988 Pi Kappa Phi has been cycling across the country to benefit people with disabilities. Cycling has been the best communication vehicle for the organization, taking to the roads of America and spreading a message of acceptance and understanding for people with disabilities to millions of people through special events and the media. Our cycling events raise over $500,000 every summer to build hope for the future of people with disabilities while developing tomorrow's leaders.

ABILITIES | TEAMWORK | EMPATHY | INTEGRITY



1. Volunteerism

2. Awareness

3. Fundraising</description>
  <mission>Building the leaders of tomorrow, by serving those with disabilities today.

</mission>
  <name>Push America - UMass</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2374</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">51</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/x6/wI/0H/aj/zl/Dh/sOnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
