<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I think that the death penalty should be abolished in the United States. The 38 states that still have the death penalty should follow in the footsteps of the 12 that don't. First off, some inmates who have been executed have contributed something good to the society. For example, Stanley "Tookie" Williams, a former member of the Crips gang convicted of murdering four people in California, wrote anti-gang and anti-violence books for children. Those books have saved, and are still saving, many kids from joining gangs and committing acts of violence. 

Another reason the death penalty should be abolished is that it costs more money to execute someone than to keep them in jail. In New Jersey, executions have cost taxpayers $253 million since 1983, a figure above what it would have cost to keep those prisoners in jail with life sentences without parole. 

A third reason is that some innocent inmates may have been killed for crimes that they didn't commit. For example, a man named Cameron Willingham was convicted in Texas of murdering his three children in a 1991 house fire. Arson expert Gerald Hurst said, "There's nothing to suggest to any reasonable arson investigator that this was an arson fire. It was just a fire." Less than a year after Willingham's execution, evidence that was similar to that in Cameron's case helped free Ernest Willis from Texas's death row. 

Pro-death penalty people will use the argument "an eye for an eye." That doesn't make sense because robbers don't get robbed for robbing someone else, and if someone rapes someone, their punishment isn't that they get raped in return. Still others may say that the death penalty acts as a deterrent. That is not true at all. As George Bernard Shaw once said, "It is the deed that teaches, not the name we give it. Murder and capital punishment are not opposites that cancel one another but similars that breed their kind." In Texas, studies have noted that murders increase following an execution. 



1. Abolish the death penalty.

2. Raise awareness of why the death penalty is cruel.</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness of how cruel the death penalty really is.</mission>
  <name>The Death Penalty Has To Go</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2380</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">208</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">7.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dm/Pe/kI/Wf/5G/OC/XRyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
