<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Bleed Purple Foundation was founded in 2006 by members of the Theta Zeta Chapter of Delta Tau Delta International Fraternity in order to aid one of their brothers who was diagnosed with stage III-B Hodgkin&#8217;s Lymphoma. As a sign of brotherhood and steadfast solidarity, the brothers came together and organized a head-shaving auction on the University of San Diego campus that raised more than $4,000 for their brother. Thus, Bleed Purple was born.

Since that simple act of compassion by the brothers of Theta Zeta, Bleed Purple has evolved into a recognized charitable organization under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. Bleed Purple&#8217;s mission is to support college students battling cancer. The foundation distributes funds through a simple application process. A selection committee consisting of several members from various walks of life reviews submitted applications on a quarterly basis and, pending approval, the requested funds are then donated to the applicant or to the university of medical facility of their choice to help relieve the financial burden. Bleed Purple considers itself a unique organization. Being that the foundation has zero administrative costs, it redirects 100% of its donations to students with cancer or to secure future donations for distribution. While our first priority is helping students with cancer, the foundation will also select a cancer research organization each year that will receive a portion of the proceeds if funds are available.

1. Support for College Students fighting cancer.

2. Support for cancer research.</description>
  <mission>Help members of Fraternities and Sororities fight cancer.</mission>
  <name>Bleed Purple</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2382</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2134</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">385.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/T4/nH/oq/j4/U6/0m/xRzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
