<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There are six Celtic nations in the world, each with their own, unique Celtic language. Five are under the rule of another nation, and one is broken into two pieces. This cause is an explicitly republican cause, but accepts non-republicans, in order to gain support for ultimate freedom.

Know Your Political Parties: Unlike the days of William Wallace of Scotland or Owain Glyndwr of Wales, independence cannot be won at the tip of a sword, or at the end of a rifle anymore. Politics, though as begrudging as they may be, is the only way now to win freedom.

Eire (Green): Sinn Fein is the largest nationalist party in Northern Ireland, however, this cause wishes to disassociate with more militant nationalists, so it primarily supports SDLP and Fianna Fail and its diplomatic approach. Sinn Fein is not, however being discouraged by the cause.

Alba (Blue): The Scottish Nationalist Party is the largest nationalist party in Scotland, and also the largest party in the Scottish Parliament, but only by one vote over the Labour.

Cymru (Yellow): Plaid Cymru is the second largest party in the Welsh Assembly, behind the Labour party. However, the two parties have entered a coalition in the Assembly. 

Mannin (Red): Man is very close to full independence, with a full parliament. Mec Vanin is the only political party advocating for the freedom of the Isle of Man

Kernow (Orange): There is no Cornish Parliament or Assembly at this time. There are two Cornish independence parties, the center-left Mebyon Kernow who abdicates independence based on economic grounds, and the center-right Cornish Nationalist Party who abdicates on cultural grounds.

Breizh (Purple):There is no devolved government in Brittany currently. The Union D&#233;mocratique Bretonne is the principle nationalist party in Brittany, but is currently only pushing for devolution, rather than independence.

An tAontas Eorpach: The European Union has a party in its parliament known as the Greens-European Free Alliance. It represents the SNP and Plaid Cymru and many other local parties, and adds a stronger voice to the Celtic Peoples. It currently has 42 of the 785 MEPs with 2 of those from of the SNP and 1 from Plaid Cymru.

1. Eire/Ireland: The reuinification of the Republic with Nothern Ireland.

2. Alba/Scotland: The freedom of Scotland from the United Kingdom.

3. Cymru/Wales: The freedom of Wales from the United Kingdom.

4. Mannin/Isle of Man: The freedom of The Isle of Man from the status of Crown Dependency.

5. Kernow/Cornwall: The recognisation of Cornwall as a Duchy and independence.

6. Breizh/Brittany: The freedom of Brittany from France.</description>
  <mission>See sovereignty of the six Celtic nations.</mission>
  <name>Free the Celtic Nations</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2391</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">588</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/BD/Ne/6Z/mx/Za/YS/JfYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
