<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We hold these truths to be self-evident: People have the UNALIENABLE right to life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness, endowed to them by their Creator, NOT the government said people created to protect these rights. Some of the rights we believe in are: uncensored freedom of speech and the press, freedom of religion, freedom to assemble and petition the government, freedom to own and carry weapons, freedom to not have soldiers quartered in one's home during times of peace, freedom to be secure in one's person, home, papers, and effects from unreasonable search and seizure without a warrant issued upon probable cause by a judge specifically detailing the persons and things to be seized, the right to not be deprived of life, liberty, or property without due process of law including trial by an impartial jury without having to testify against one's self, the right to a speedy and public trial, freedom from excessive bail, fines, and cruel and unusual punishment. The enumeration of These Liberties do not include all those we support. We also believe that the powers not delegated to the Federal Government by the Constitution shall be reserved for the States or the people, respectively. If you're not familiar with these ideas, or if you are, then check me out at www.theseliberties.net or www.libertyweekly.com with an open mind.

We need to abolish the Federal Reserve and return all of its assets and its powers to the US Treasury and to We The People, to whom all of this properly belongs, as Jefferson would say.

We are looking for donations, writers, cartoonists, business and law people, contributors, columnists, investors or partners who are liberty oriented and wish to help the cause by promoting liberty, knowledge, and/or peace. If you are interested please write to alex@libertyweekly.com and/or travis@libertyweekly.com. 

We dont have a non-profit set up yet, so for now donations benefit the John Birch Society.

1. Liberty

2. Knowledge

3. Peace</description>
  <mission>Promote Liberty, Knowledge, and Peace</mission>
  <name>Liberty, Knowledge, and Peace</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2398</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">93</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Lg/aT/Rr/ik/Rk/6N/OKdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
