<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There was once 8 subspecies of tiger in the wild. Today there are only 5 subspecies remaining. Our best estimates suggest that there are between 5,000 to 7,000 wild tigers remaining today. There are about 1,200 zoo tigers as well. That is as large as the numbers go for the remaining 5 subspecies of the largest cat in the world. Considering a tiger is poached everyday in India doesn't give much hope, does it? Scientists now estimate that by 2010 wild tigers will be extinct. Please don't stand idly by and watch these magnificent creatures perish...

Tigers have fascinated mankind for centuries. Two Indian epics, Mahabharata and Ramayana, dating back as far as 300 BC use the tiger as representations of beauty, power and ferocity. In Pakistan, the tiger, no longer found in this country, is scultped on seals of an ancient civilization which once thrived over 5,000 years ago. The ancient peoples of China once interpreted the markings on a tiger's forehead as meaning king. In Korea, "Land of the Blue Dragon and White Tiger," people believe a dragon guards the west while a tiger guards the east. 

The table shows the tigers scientific and common name and the most recent estimates of their numbers:  

Scientific Name - Common Name Remaining Tigers 
Panthera tigris tigris Bengal Tiger  - 3,000 - 4,700 

Panthera tigris virgata Caspian Tiger Extinct by 1970s 

Panthera tigris altaica Siberian Tiger - 160 - 450 

Panthera tigris balica Bali Tiger Extinct in 1937 

Panthera tigris amoyensis South China Tiger 20 - 30 

Panthera tigris sondaica  Javan Tiger Extinct in 1980s 

Panthera tigris corbetti Indo-Chinese Tiger-  1,100 - 1,800 

Panthera tigris sumatrae Sumatran Tiger - 400 - 500 


The current goal of the World Wildlife Fund and the groups it sponsors is to ensure the population of wild tigers makes it into the year 2010. Hopefully, the tiger will live on to see brighter days.

 


1. In October 1998, President Clinton signed into law the Rhino and Tiger Product Labeling Act. Same should be applied in Canada

2. Save the tigers from being taken away from their wildlife...which leads to many of their deaths</description>
  <mission>to increase awareness within our soceity for the tigers</mission>
  <name>Save the Tigers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2399</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">184855</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">965.29</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6d/xE/z5/Hh/JJ/NI/qd/2tS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
