<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Child abuse damages our community's most vulnerable citizens and often has generational implications. In the context of violence, child abuse is a public health problem that presents complex social and moral dilemmas concerning its cause, effect and remedy. Addressing child abuse requires a comprehensive plan with multiple, coordinated strategies.

The Child Abuse Network is Tulsa's Children's Advocacy Center. During a child abuse investigation, experts from several agencies must talk with the child. Before the Child Abuse Network existed, children were taken back and forth among child welfare offices, police departments and medical clinics. At each visit, the child was asked to retell his/her story. The process not only duplicated investigative efforts, it also made children relive their experience over and over.

The Child Abuse Network centralizes all the experts who must talk to the child. Children now need to come to only one place to talk to those investigating their abuse. The investigation is streamlined, information is shared, and decisions are based on more expert information. As a result, children are able to begin their healing process faster.


1. Child abuse damages our community's most vulnerable citizens.

2. For an abused child, adjusting to life after abuse is difficult.

3. In the context of violence, child abuse presents complex social and moral dilemmas concerning its cause, effect and remedy. 

4. Helping stop child abuse requires a comprehensive plan involving multiple, coordinated strategies.</description>
  <mission>The Child Abuse Network provides support and facilities for a multidisciplinary team approach to determine abuse and protect children in crisis.</mission>
  <name>Child Abuse Network Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2407</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1197</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">85.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5M/60/fR/Fm/2M/Zf/BXVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
