<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>!PLEASE TAKE THE TIME TO READ THIS!

Here are some quick facts about the causes of childhood obesity: 

1.  Approximately 30.3 percent of children (ages 6 to 11) are overweight and 15.3 percent are obese. For adolescents (ages 12 to 19), 30.4 percent are overweight and 15.5 percent are obese. According to the associated press, 50% of children in the US and 38% of children in Europe will be overweight/obese.

2. Excess weight in childhood and adolescence has been found to predict adult obesity, 79% of obese children are obese as adults.

3. Overweight during childhood and particularly adolescence is related to increased morbidity and mortality in later life.

4. Some health affects are: Asthma, Diabetes (Type 2), Hypertension, Orthopedic Complications (bowing and overgrowth in bones.), Psychosocial Effects &amp; Stigma, Sleep Apnea.

5. The health affects children experience, only develop into more severe cases as age progrogresses such as: Arthritis, Birth Defects, Breast Cancer,  Cancers of the Esophagus and Gastric Cardia , Colorectal Cancer, Endometrial Cancer (EC), Cardiovascular Disease (CVD) , Carpal Tunnel Syndrome (CTS) ,Chronic Venous Insufficiency (CVI) , Daytime Sleepiness, Impaired Immune Response , Infections Following Wounds , Infertility, Stroke ,Surgical Complications , and many many more.

6.  Only with YOUR help can we stop childhood obesity.. It is our mission to spread the word and create awareness of the real issue in Americal; Childhood obesity, the generation that dies before their parents....its our turn to take a stand against childhood obesity.


all opinons on how to solve this issue are welcome, however; all obscene and ridiculous comments will be erased, and if numerous comments are posted the poster will be banned.  






1. Childhood obesity is proven to lower overall life expectancy.

2. Stop obesity before it starts! Obese children have a 79% chance of being obese as adults!

3. You don't have to be a certain party to help this cause!  This is a non-profit cause meant only to spread the word of prevention!</description>
  <mission>Put an end to childhood obesity   

benefactor:  

http://www.livingheartfoundation.org/                          </mission>
  <name>End Childhood Obesity</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2412</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1343</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">245.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Af/3B/jo/Vb/so/ZZ/7RyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
