<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Guided by a shared experience of reverence for our entire planetary ecosystem, The Heart of the Healer (THOTH) is a global community of visionary women, men and children dedicated to the emergence of a sustainable sacred partnership between humankind and our Mother Earth. 

Honoring indigenous wisdom traditions, we foster the spiritual reawakening of humanity through the reenactment of earth-honoring ceremonies and healing practices at ancestral sacred sites worldwide. Acknowledging the power of consciousness and creative imagination to transform the larger social order in which we live, we embrace a path of life-affirming service that reflects unity, peace and compassionate cooperation among all people.


Our mission is to:

-Preserve and revitalize indigenous earth-honoring wisdom and ceremonial healing practices

-Protect ancestral sacred sites, pilgrimage destinations, natural landscape shrines and tribal lands

-Impart the prophetic vision and mythic reality of native peoples as expressed through their creation stories, tribal legends, ceremonial rites-of-passage, art, music, dance, song and other traditional forms of cultural identity

-Disseminate the Pachakuti Mesa tradition of cross-cultural shamanism through practitioner apprenticeships and teacher certification programs involving the nurturance of heartfelt sacred community worldwide 

1. Indigenous earth-honoring wisdom and ceremonial healing practices must be preserved.

2. Ancestral sacred sites, pilgrimage destinations, natural landscape shrines and tribal lands must be protected.</description>
  <mission>Preserving indigenous wisdom, restoring our Earth.</mission>
  <name>The Heart of the Healer (THOTH)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2415</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">959</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3363.53</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6o/aQ/Hm/Ns/B7/hU/wS/JSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
