<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>*The Problem*

HIV/AIDS is a major global epidemic affecting and killing more people each year.

In 2007, an estimated 33.2 million people lived with HIV/AIDS worldwide, and the disease claimed the lives of an estimated 2.1 million people (including 330,000 children).

The lion's share of funding for AIDS services comes from Washington in the form of the Ryan White Care Act by Congress.
 
In recent years, Congress changed the act. Under the new formula, many states have lost more than half of the annual funding, and:

-Money for emergency food has been NEARLY ELIMINATED.
-Money for emergency rental assistance has been NEARLY ELIMINATED.
-Money for emergency utility assistance has been NEARLY ELIMINATED.
-Money for emergency transportation to doctors and medical appointments has been NEARLY ELIMINATED.

Take a moment to consider that the cost of utilities has almost tripled for all of us. The cost of gas has skyrocketed. And worst of all, the cost of food has increased dramatically.

And this brings us to Bridgeport, Connecticut. Only a handful of America's communities have been more affected by HIV/AIDS than Bridgeport. In this town, a large number of families who are dealing with AIDS today were largely poor before a family member (or members) contracted the disease. In many cases, these family members have lost part of their own flesh and blood, and oftentimes their own health is very fragile. They are so depleted by the medications' side effects that they are unable to work.  And they will get little help and have less money to survive.

*Solution: The Evergreen Network*
 
The Evergreen Network (ENI), founded in 1987 by Adaline DeMarrais, helps families primarily affected by HIV/AIDS (though local families affected by other catastrophic illnesses are also aided). Through psycho-social support, case management, and education, the Evergreen Network strives to make a difference in the lives of families affected by HIV/AIDS in the Bridgeport area. Examples include weekly dinners for children in these families and weekly meetings for women in these families. In addition, the Network hosts many annual events, including:

-Birthday cards for all children in the Cause.
-Raising money for these children to go to summer camp.
-Picnic at Fairfield University in July.
-Drive for and handout of school supplies in August.
-Drive for and handout of Thanksgiving dinners.
-Drive for Christmas dinners.
-And many more!

Unfortunately, the Evergreen Network has lost thousands of dollars in funding over the past few years because the Ryan White Care Act was changed. This creates many problems, including:

-Most significantly, funding for the children to go to summer camp is extremely difficult to find now. But at camp, they get breakfast and lunch (which they might not normally have in the summer), and an opportunity to be just "normal" children. Plus, their ill guardian gets a break. The children are safe off the streets because gangs look to recruit these children and pay them $50 to $100 to deliver drugs from one street to another.  This is a huge lure for the children to join the gangs. 
-Drives for school supplies and for food during the holidays are increasingly more difficult to fund.

And so, Evergreen needs your best effort! Please help by inviting more members to Evergreen online to raise awareness of this major local problem. Also, a donation of your time or money to ENI would be greatly appreciated. Thank you!

All the best,
Peter Mattson

1. HIV/AIDS is a serious disease and those affected by it need our help. 

2. Evergreen Network is a charity whose mission is to help these victims.

3. Evergreen Network operates out of Bridgeport, CT. It uses all proceeds to buy food, clothing, etc. for victims of AIDS. </description>
  <mission>Adaline DeMarrais founded this cause to help those with or affected by HIV/AIDS</mission>
  <name>Help Victims of AIDS Now</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2421</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">177</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fh/lg/pC/Jy/YT/Rr/2BtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
