<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Love is, as far as I can tell, the most mature response to any situation - the pinnacle of what it means to be truly human. Love is a wrench in the wheels of cause and effect, of reactionary living, of casual imitation. Yes, speed and events are all around us in the information age, but motion, true motion, is rare. Love is the movement." -Jon Foreman

"Rebellion is the torch passed from the youth of one generation to the next. There is much to rebel against, but this revolution has to start from the inside. So rebel, be set apart, change the world! But be careful when you talk about the church of the living God, which is the pillar and support of the truth. For it is not you but the power of the holy spirit living in you that will ignite a fire that deserves to burn." -Jon Foreman. 

Everyday when I wake, different thoughts rush through my head. It amazes me how I can open my window and see a beautiful flawless world yet then turn on the television and see disaster sweeping across the entire world. It seems that something needs to be done. People like you and I have the opportunity and can wake up and see the beauty of this amazing world we live it and can live it to the fullest...but not everyone can. More people than we think are going to bed in fear for their lives, not knowing whether they will live another day, not knowing whether they even have a home, not knowing if they will ever eat again. Too many innocent people are dying without experiencing the greatness this world has to offer. The Revolution is about changing that. It is about coming together hand in hand and fighting for what God has called us to fight for. We are on a mission to make every man be proud to live in the world and state of living they live in. We are giving all that we can, expecting nothing in return in bringing this world together. Will you fight for the Revolution? Everyone's scared that the motion will never come...this is the Revolution...the fight of our lives.

1. Love is a movement, and is more important than materialistic success.

2. One soul can change the world.

3. Those more fortunate than others should reach out to those less fortunate.

4. Every man should have the chance to experience all that life has to offer.

5. Love never fails.</description>
  <mission>Love is the only movement worth setting in motion.</mission>
  <name>The Revolution</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2422</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">86</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dm/KW/O0/To/Uw/Cj/q7CS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
