<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hi I'm Lizzie and last summer, with an organization called Global Routes, I traveled to Ghana to build a library. For the two and 1/2 weeks I was there I lived with my new family and became one of them. The main objective of our trip was to build a library that these incredible people could use to further their education and their contact with the rest of the world. Every day from 8am-4pm we would meet at our "work site" with tons of local people mixing cement, laying bricks, carrying water on our heads and doing everything we could to build this library. Recently I received a letter from my "dad," Gabriel Aidoo, urging me to help him. Below is an excerpt from my father's letter:

&#8220;I am finally thanks you parents who gave you opportunity to come to Ghana to help ABREM ESSIAM Community. God blessed them. Again about our Library we need some amounts to complete the remaining works like ceiling, lining, doors, windows, welded mesh etc. for us to complete all the work left.
I hope that all the contents in letter would be noted in good faith and any little thing that you can do to us in Ghana God will RICHLY BLESSED YOU.&#8221;

When we were in Ghana, our biggest fear was that we would not complete the library and now it seems our worst nightmare has occured. Please help me raise money so that the people of Abrem Essiam can use the library we built for them. 

If you live in Santa Barbara, Sunday, June 17th and Sunday, July 1st I will be having car washes at the 76 station on Coast Village Road to raise money to finish our library. If you cannot attend but you still want to help ANY donations you would be willing to contribute would make me and the people of Essiam incredibly happy. Also if you don&#8217;t have a dirty car or would rather not make a donation, I am in great need of volunteers to help me wash cars.

I appreciate any help you can give me and if you would like to help please message me as soon as possible.


1. No one should be denied the right to education.</description>
  <mission>finish building a library in Abrem Essiam, Ghana.</mission>
  <name>HELP Complete a Ghanaian Library</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2424</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">114</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/h1/DL/KB/kb/Pr/ms/EKVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
