<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> The Zoological Society of San Diego's center for Conservation and Research for Endangered Species (CRES) is the largest zoo-based multidisciplinary research team in the world. Biodiversity conservation is the theme that unites the work of CRES, and scientific innovation is the means by which CRES achieves its success.

Housed in the state-of-the-art Arnold and Mabel Beckman Center for Conservation Research at the entrance to the San Diego Zoo&#8217;s Wild Animal Park, CRES scientists generate, share, and apply scientific knowledge vital to the conservation of animals, plants, and habitats, locally and internationally. CRES encompasses five research divisions: Applied Animal Ecology, Behavioral Biology, Genetics, Wildlife Disease Laboratories, and Reproductive Physiology, as well as a dedicated Conservation Education Lab. In addition, the Beckman Center supports work done by the Giant Panda Conservation Division at the San Diego Zoo, the Native Seed Gene Bank, and the Conservation Research Postdoctoral Fellowship Program.

Over the last 30 years, the work of CRES has grown to include international field conservation programs in more than 20 countries worldwide. The CRES vision is to become the global leader in applying advances in science and technology to the conservation and recovery of endangered species. CRES identifies the most pressing problems for species conservation and then applies the most innovative and creative science possible to solving them. To achieve this goal, CRES scientists have identified six key strategic areas for focused research: Sustainable Populations, Bioresource Banking, Wildlife Health, Habitat Conservation, Restoration Biology , and Conservation Education.

1. Protect existing biodiversity.

2. Rehabilitate endangered ecosystems.

3. Prevent future damage through conservation education.</description>
  <mission>To promote and protect biodiversity through public education, research, and scientific innovation.</mission>
  <name>Conservation and Research for Endangered Species (CRES)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2425</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">941</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eX/7t/07/MT/WE/SD/iZLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
