<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I am working with the Rotary Club of Naperville, Sunrise and it would be great if everyone could share this information with anyone else they know (company sponsors are also appreciated)! I will be attending the trip to the Tikondane village on June 19th with other members of this group. 


The Tikondane Community School was started in 1995 to fill the void in the locality for a school that did not charge fees. It is very difficult to provide tuition and uniforms if you are living in desperate poverty. Tikondane Community School is open to boys and girls of all ages and is run by volunteer teachers. There are no fees to attend this school. 


The Rotary Club of Naperville, Sunrise has made a multi-year committment to provide assistance to the community of Katete, Zambia.

   - We will be shipping an Ultrasound machine value $75,000 to St.Francis Hospital, which serves Katete.
   - Nearly 500 pairs of shoes are en route to Tikondane
   - We have paid for the construction of 2 wells that provide clean water
   - We will be sending 800 books to Tikondane Community School (Compliments of Anderson's Bookshop)
   - We will be bringing 400 backpacks with us containing school supplies (sponsored by Cabernet &amp; Company)
   - We have purchased 2 weaving looms to bolster their weaving industry


A proper and permanent school building will cost $50,000 US. We have secured a donation of $25,000 ourselves. We are asking for donations of $100 per person (or more if you are so inclined) and are in the process of finding 250 people who will help us deliver the dream of this school to the people of Katete. Please make checks out to "Naperville Rotary Sunrise Foundation" and please put "Tikondane School" in the memo section. Mail to Tikondane School Building, c/o Ettie Randles, 812 Ayers St. Bolingbrook, IL. 60440. For questions on the project, visit  www.NapervilleSunrise.com  or www.Tikondane.org.

1. The Tikondane Community School needs our donations and aid.

2. Education and proper supplies are greatly needed.

3. The people of Tikondane are living in very poor conditions and they require our help to better their village.</description>
  <mission>Provide assistance to the community of Katete, Zambia in giving supplies needed to stabilize the Tikondane Community School</mission>
  <name>Tikondane Community School, Zambia, Africa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2450</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">86</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/58/5p/th/0l/5O/zA/JxDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
