<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Long Now Foundation was established in 01996* to develop the Clock and Library projects, as well as to become the seed of a very long term cultural institution. The Long Now Foundation hopes to provide counterpoint to today's "faster/cheaper" mind set and promote "slower/better" thinking. We hope to creatively foster responsibility in the framework of the next 10,000 years.

The Name

The term was coined by one of our founding board members, Brian Eno. When Brian first moved to New York City he found that in New York here and now meant this room and this five minutes, as opposed to the larger here and longer now that he was used to in England. We have since adopted the term as the title of our foundation as we are trying to stretch out what people consider as now.


* The Long Now Foundation uses five digit dates, the extra zero is to solve the deca-millennium bug which will come into effect in about 8,000 years.

Other Long Now pages on Facebook:
Fan Page: http://www.facebook.com/home.php?ref=logo#/pages/The-Long-Now-Foundation/16998442867?ref=s
Non Profit Page: http://apps.facebook.com/causes/beneficiaries/1953?m=034055a2
Group Page: http://www.facebook.com/home.php?ref=logo#/group.php?gid=2268554336
Cause Page: http://apps.facebook.com/causes/view_cause/2452

1. Serve the long view (and the long viewer)

2. Foster responsibility

3. Reward patience

4. Mind mythic depth

5. Ally with competition

6. Take no sides

7. Leverage longevity</description>
  <mission>The Long Now Foundation hopes to provide counterpoint to today's "faster/cheaper" mind set and promote "slower/better" thinking in the framework of the next 10,000 years.</mission>
  <name>The Long Now Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2452</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1530</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">235.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cm/z4/tK/a1/dQ/8N/ta/eHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
