<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Sign the petition: http://www.cesarchavezholiday.org/petition.html


About Cesar E. Chavez National Holiday

The California legal holiday set into motion a wave of initiatives resulting in optional and commemorative Cesar Chavez Days in eight additional states (Arizona, Colorado, Illinois, Michigan, New Mexico, Texas, Utah, and Wisconsin.)

Cesar Chavez Day brings together hundreds of thousands who engage in celebrations, service and learning projects, and other actions that further the many causes which Cesar Chavez worked for.

The mission of Cesar E. Chavez National Holiday, a public benefit organization, is to work for national recognition of Cesar E. Chavez on his birthday March 31.  We are forming national, state and local coalitions; organizing volunteer committees; and providing education about the value to our nation of honoring Cesar E. Chavez.

Our Vision

Cesar Chavez gave our nation and each of us a unique example to live our lives by.  His selfless dedication for farm worker and worker rights, economic justice, civil rights, environmental justice, peace, nonviolence, empowerment of the poor and disenfranchised, is a monumental legacy that will inspire all and the generations to come. The winning of national recognition for Cesar Chavez with holidays, service, learning and community action events, is a fitting tribute and significant way to share his life&#8217;s work as the founder and leader of the United Farm Workers of America (UFW).

What is most important is that remembering and honoring Cesar Chavez inspires more people to become involved in the causes that continue Cesar Chavez&#8217;s extraordinary legacy. 

1. Cesar E. Chavez selfless dedication for farm worker and worker rights, economic justice, civil rights, environmental justice, peace, nonviolence, empowerment of the poor and disenfranchised, is a monumental legacy that will inspire all and the generations

2. http://www.cesarchavezholiday.org/index.html

3. http://www.chavezfoundation.org/

4. http://www.ufw.org/</description>
  <mission>To work for national recognition of Cesar E. Chavez on his birthday March 31.</mission>
  <name>Cesar E. Chavez National Holiday</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2454</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">571</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">30.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7f/AO/O5/JX/hs/11/HeOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
