<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A couple years ago men started to notice a change in the environment (a miniscule change)... we automatically assumed that it was vast global warming. Celebrities and news-casters began to show how they believe that the world is doomed to a hot cremation and what they are doing to stop it. Everyone immediately believes them, but no one is willing to accept the scientists that believe that its a hoax.
          Facts:
1. Many People have found a steady decrease in temperature worldwide
2. Global Warming is still just a theory by the way
3. The earth has been going through cycles like warming and cooling for millions of years
4. We know more about the moon then we do the earth's atmosphere
5. Scientists have no idea if this global warming thing will cause more or less hurricanes
6. The technology of weather prediction is still a very young technology that we are in the early stages of.
7. There was recently a huge storm on Saturn... so i guess we can assume that was due to the fact that there are so many hummers there and power plants?
8. Just because the media hypes it up, doesnt mean its true... Y2K: its here and we're all ok. African Killer Bees: big deal, they're in the US right now but they havent affected my life
9. The man who first suggested global warming stated that temperatures would rise about .3 degrees celcius in the next 10 years. 10 years went by, and the temperature only grew a mere .1 degrees. This suggests that the man who first noticed global warming didnt really know what he was doing...
10. ETC. 

p.s. notice that our nonprofit org. is to address the "global warming issue," but it is also for research for all atmospheric, sea-level, etc. so they will soon find the error in their ways.
p.p.s. one of the sources include the greatest book ever (State of Fear by Michael Crichton) which has tabular data from which much of the info above was generated.

1. Global Warming is currently not happening...</description>
  <mission>prove that global warming is only a theory and is not true</mission>
  <name>GLOBAL WARMING: Hoax!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2456</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">130</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1s/PK/28/mh/CD/Lu/JJnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
