<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>SAVE R US is a student run anti-violence organization dedicated to promoting nonviolence in our schools and communities.  The organization was founded by Brandon Lee Wolff at his high school in response to a string of school shootings in early 2001 and has since spread to other high schools and colleges. In July 2004, SAVE R US International was launched at the World Youth Centre in Toronto, Canada with the help of the SAVE R US International Advisory Board. 

One of the signature activities that SAVE R US coordinates is its &#8220;unity cafe&#8221; discussion groups. These discussion groups are conducted in a &#8220;cafe&#8221; style atmosphere to allow students to feel comfortable to discuss serious issues that pertain to diversity, bullying and violence. Another main activity is the planning of the   SAVE R US annual peace week. See www.PeaceWeek.org for more details.

The newest SAVE R US program is the Peacemakers program which is designed to have college and high school students become trained as Peacemakers to go into elementary schools to educate elementary students about bullying and violence. The &#8220;Peacemakers&#8221; use a variety of educational and fun activities to teach students about the harmful consequences of bullying and violence in order to prevent young students from engaging in these destructive activities. It is our hope that educating the youth of today will yield a less violent society in the future.

SAVE R US has received a prestigious Pericles Foundation grant to begin the SAVE R US expansion project of expanding SAVE R US to other schools. For more information on starting a SAVE R US chapter in your school or community, please email chapters@SAVERUSInternational.org.

SAVE R US 
Students Against Violence Everywhere Are Us
www.saverusinternational.org


1. Empowering youth against violence.</description>
  <mission>Youth Empowering Youth Against Violence</mission>
  <name>SAVE R US - Students Against Violence Everywhere Are Us</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2472</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hz/NY/j7/R8/7y/lY/zpIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
