<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It's time for our generation to take a stand and try to be apart of re-building somalia. Other Wise we'll have old bums tying to run a country and what happens when they're gone!! WHO ARE THE NEXT GENERATION OF PEOPLE THAT CARE. Our money doesn't do our starving ppl any good !!
And just because a few of us seem to be happy... PPL are still dyin and ppl still sleep on the streets. Let's not look only into our happy families.. look beyond.
somalia is an innocent old woman that has no home lost amidst tribal pressures. Let's care for this old woman that is tired of running and let's put some ideas to gether into how we can make 'HER' young again.


1. Somalia is right now too political, it seems every one is into the politics of somalia. 1st this cause is not political and getting us together.

2. Let's research our resources, and work on how to bring them to THE SOMALI PPL MICROSCOPE. 

3. BE PROUD TO BE SOMALI. or kill urself immediately. The passports we carry are just passports not tickets to heaven. Being Somali is our only ticket to heaven.

4. Stop the tears we shed for that old woman that walks in the desert, under the heat, with no house to come from and no house to go to. It's not just the Children you know

5. Let's for once, REALLY IMAGINE THEIR SITUATIONS. 

6. ORPHANS, ORPHANS.....Bullets...Bullets..Bullets.. makes my heart beat fast

7. Somali jokes, made by somalis.... it seems COMEDY is the latest source of awareness, so those of u with jokes, bring them on and use them wisely.. maybe they'll make someone laugh with tears, and do something!</description>
  <mission>Awarenes!!</mission>
  <name>Somalia-- The Secret Heaven on Earth-</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2476</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1108</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.17</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/IT/PR/mk/E7/ES/Vp/g5DS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
