<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>If you have not seen this movie yet, you MUST watch it, and you be the judge of this idea. Yes, it is inappropriate. Yes, it is rated R for language, sexual content, a tad bit of nudity, and excessive drug use. However, there is a message in this movie that must be reached to every young adult in this world!

Students must have a full understanding of drug use. They cannot be told how bad it is; they have to see for themselves. They have to witness it the way this movie portrays it. They have to be disturbed by drugs the way this movie disturbs everyone. This movie will leave you feeeling a temporary loss of life, but still shreds of hope, and the chance to make the right choice.

Some of you may say that these traits should not be provided to students by high school faculty, which is understandable. However, keep in mind that this is like a "mock" experience for every student who watches this movie. Once this experience is over, students will realize that they have a chance to avoid these drugs and to keep clean for life. All it costs for this life-changing experience is a 90 minute wake-up call.

It is practically guarenteed that anyone who watches this movie will personally vow to themselves never to even TRY drugs. If the High Schools around the world would like their students to make these personal vows, Requiem For A Dream is the answer, and action must be taken immediately.

Our goal is to reach 1000 members. Once we reach that number, this cause will be shown to highschools all over the country with formal request to finally change the youth of our country. If you have a comments or questions about the movie, please let me know. Thanks

1. Schools are obviously not doing enough to prevent drug use.

2. There is not a single soul that Requiem For A Dream would NOT personally affect to a certain degree.

3. The truth about drug use must not only be told, but EXPOSED, to the world's youth.

4. Drugs cannot be taught by a P.E. Teacher with a chalkboard on wheels. That just tells students that if they do drugs, they "wont make the basketball team". Students need a more meaningful message than this, and this film is the answer.</description>
  <mission>Convince as many public High Schools as possible to allow their students the opportunity to watch Requiem For A Dream during school hours. Our member goal: 1000</mission>
  <name>The "Requiem For A Dream" Cause</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2479</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">84</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yp/ry/zM/2t/xg/MU/Mn0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
