<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 2002, Modest Needs is an award-winning public charity with a simple but critical mission: we work to stop the cycle of poverty BEFORE it starts for the low-income workers whom conventional philanthropy has forgotten.

We do this by empowering compassionate members of the general public to safely and securely help hard-working, low-income households who make just a little bit too much to qualify for government aid. We see normally self-sufficient families through a short-term rough patch -- covering relatively small expenses like an unexpected car repair or hospital stay that could otherwise spell financial ruin.

Since 2002, by working together in this very 'modest' way, Modest Needs' donors have stopped almost 7,000 low-income individuals and families from entering the vicious cycle of poverty and a lifetime of dependence on the public welfare system for their survival.

Together, we can make sure that no hard-working person is ever forced to choose between taking a child to the doctor and putting food on the table.

Read our blog at http://modestneeds.typepad.com/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
"Small change: A world of difference."

1. Stop the cycle of poverty BEFORE it starts.

2. We welcome donations as little as $2 and believe that philanthropy is about the size of your heart, not your wallet.

3. We make the giving process a hands-on experience by asking our contributors to specify exactly which family they'd like to help.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to help hardworking, low-income families survive the kinds of unexpected financial crises we all face -- a medical bill, unusually high utility bill, or car repair, for example.</mission>
  <name>Modest Needs Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2480</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">688</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1182.3</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0K/eL/nl/bJ/6E/3n/nHwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
