<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Peter M. Goodrich Memorial Foundation, established after Peter's death on board the second plane to hit the World Trade Towers on September 11, 2001, works primarily in the Pashtun provinces of Afghanistan supporting education and addressing the fundamental needs of fragile populations.

Its purpose is to support the love of learning for its own sake, especially by those naturally curious, imaginative, dreamers like Peter, thought not well suited for it, and to encourage the search for those thin places that separate what we are taught to believe is true from what really is, give aid to those who unselfishly approach those perilous places, and help discover means of peaceful passage through them to clearer understandings of our natural world and its people.

The trustee of the Foundation is the Chittenden Bank of Vermont. All decisions concerning payments by the foundation are made by a committee consisting of Peter's widow, his Bates College roommate and his father.



HOW YOU CAN DONATE WITHOUT SPENDING A CENT:

1. Go to GoodSearch.com
2. In the text box underneath "Who do you GoodSearch for?" type "Peter M Goodrich" and click Verify.  You will only have to do this once.
3. Now whenever you use that page to search, a penny will be donated to the foundation.  It might not sound like much, but a) it's free, b) it's powered by Yahoo! so you get excellent search results, and c) if enough people do it, plenty of money can be raised.

1. We believe we can take affirmative steps to fashion a safer, more equitable world.</description>
  <mission>Start educational initiatives especially for the people of Afghanistan.</mission>
  <name>Peter M. Goodrich Memorial Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2491</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">257</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">150.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PG/g3/KM/w5/gs/CT/pmQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
