<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is for anyone who witnesses or is affected by crime from immigrants, or has had to wait or has family who has had or is continuing to wait to immigrate Canada or the U.S. legally.

This is for anyone who knows of illegal immigrants who are working construction jobs or anyother job and is sending money back home which they should have never made while you make less than them.
Even if you don't make less than them, many of them still leech onto our social programming sytems supported by your tax dollars.

They work under the table and are an excess of labour, causing wages of such jobs for everyone to decrease, as the demand for labour decreases.

They have familieis and then their children which should have never been born in either the U.S. or Canada are then born as citizens, and legitmate citizens then have to pay taxes to pay for people who were never meant to live here.

This cause, really should be a group, but what ever I was bored, and just wanted to spread my hate.


DO NOT DONATE ANY MONEY, I DOUBT ANYONE WOULD, BECAUSE THIS IS A BIT A OF A JOKE, but its linked to some whack non profit organization that i think helps illegal immigarnts etc etc


1. They are the scum of the Earth, they should be expelled from our great nations.

2. All their belongings should be ceased as they were illgotten.

3. They should recieve some jailtime first, before sent back to whereever they're from, and sent home with a one way ticket, and no other assets.</description>
  <mission>Remove anyone who illegally got into Canada or U.S.A. or any immigrant who is committing criminal acts.</mission>
  <name>The Deportation of Illegal Immigrants and Immigrants Convicted of Criminal Acts</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2493</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">111</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/r3/ju/D0/IJ/2H/1I/MgpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
