<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>WE MAKE WISHES COME TRUE

*We grant the wishes of children with life-threatening medical conditions to enrich the human experience with hope, strength and joy. 
*The Make-A-Wish Foundation is the largest wish-granting charity in the world. 
Network of 25,000 volunteers across five continents. 
*Granted more than 144,000 wishes to children around the world since 1980. 



WITH YOUR HELP, WE CAN DO EVEN MORE

*We&#8217;re getting more requests for wishes than we can grant. 
*Currently, chapter-wide we have over 600 pending wishes. 
*That means, for every wish we&#8217;re able to grant, another three children are now on a waiting list. This is unacceptable. 
*Our goal is to grant every wish on time. 
*We&#8217;re working hard to secure the support to do that. 
*The math is simple: more dollars = more wishes granted. 
*Here are ways you can help, e.g., Adopt-A-Wish&#174;. 



WE'RE MAKING A BIG DIFFERENCE HERE

The Ohio-Kentucky-Indiana chapter is one of the largest and fastest-growing in the U.S. 
There are more children in our area than in any other Make-A-Wish chapter in the U.S. 
Each year, we grant the wishes of more than 600 children, thanks to generous donors and a network of over 1000 volunteers. 
80% of every dollar we raise directly supports the wishes of these children. 


On a more personal note, I would like to encourage you to check out the Make-A-Wish page and see other ways in which you can help.  Go to: http://www.makeawishky.org/ and help make a difference.
I (Heather Horn) am a Volunteer Wish Granter for Make-A-Wish and have been volunteering with them since November 2005.  So far, I have assisted with making 2 wishes come true for kids that are in my area so it's not like I even had to go far!  Volunteering is a very rewarding experience, but seeing the difference you make in the lives of these children can change your outlook on life forever.  So check out the page today to see how you can make a difference in America.

1. We grant the wishes of children with life-threatening medical conditions to enrich the human experience with hope, strength and joy.

2. The Make-A-Wish Foundation is the largest wish-granting charity in the world.

3. Last year, over 700 wishes were granted by the Cleveland, Columbus, Cincinnati, Kentucky and Indiana offices. 80% of your donation goes directly to the funding of wishes.</description>
  <mission>The Make-A-Wish Foundation grants the wishes of children with life threatening medical conditions to enrich the human experience with hope, strength and joy. </mission>
  <name>Make-A-Wish of Greater Ohio, Kentucky, and Indiana</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2508</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1260</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1O/r5/Bj/sA/Uo/1x/kKHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
