<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>(One of the various centers we will be donating to)

About the Mitral Valve Prolapse Center of Alabama

The Mitral Valve Prolapse Center of Alabama opened in March 1987. It was founded by Dr. Phillip C. Watkins and Lyn Frederickson.

 Their mission was MVP research and education.

Staff includes four physicians, a Ph.D. psychologist, two Master's prepared exercise physiologists, a clinical nurse specialist, an echocardiographer, a patient care tech, and an administrative staff of four.
Goals of the Mitral Valve Prolapse Center

    * Educate patients, family and the general public as to the nature of mitral valve prolapse and its symptoms.
    * Help patients make healthy lifestyle modifications, which will stabilize their symptoms.
    * Prescribe the proper medication when needed.
    * Provide group support sessions for patients with similar problems for the exchange of information and emotional support.
    * Conduct meaningful research into various treatment regiments for mitral valve prolapse to provide helpful information to the medical profession and to enable them to deal more effectively with the patients who have mitral valve prolapse syndrome.


(source: http://www.mvprolapse.com/about_us.html)


Mitral Valve Prolapse is often not treated for mundane cases, like myself. Other cases, open heart surgery is needed.

With the mundane, it is accompanied with uncomfortable and worrisome chest pains, constant fatigue, and in some cases, panic attacks and anxiety.

We hope to help these institutes, by our funding, help find treatments for these symptoms since they do affect our lives everyday!

Also, we hope to find ways to treat MVP without the need of risky open heart surgery to fix these valves!

2% of our population has been diagnosed with MVP
That is 60,227,989 people!

So, please support our cause!

1. There must be more research done for MVP.

2. People with MVP deserve to live a normal, pain free life!</description>
  <mission>Donate our funds to MVP research to various institutes around the USA</mission>
  <name>Support Mitral Valve Prolapse Research!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2510</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">839</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Xu/V6/MV/7R/fa/cP/lSgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
