<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>After hearing a news report about a local soldier who ran up a massive phone bill calling home from Iraq, they decided they wanted to do something to help. Brittany and Robbie donated their piggy bank money, collected snack money from their friends at school, and with $21.00, they went to the bank to open an account. The South Shore Savings Bank of Hanover, Massachusetts donated $500.00 to help them get started.

 

Their goal is to help our soldiers serving overseas call home. They hope to provide as many soldiers as possible with prepaid calling cards for now with an ultimate goal of providing banks of satellite phones, video phones and VOIP communications. Through generous donations and the recycling of used cell phones from drop-off sites across the country, they have already distributed thousands of calling cards to soldiers in Iraq, Kuwait, Afghanistan and elsewhere.

__________________________________

_____________EASY WAYS TO HELP______________

What if Cell Phones For Soldiers earned a penny every time you searched the Internet? Well, now we can!

GoodSearch.com is a new search engine that donates half its revenue, about a penny per search, to the charities its users designate. You use it just as you would any search engine, and it's powered by Yahoo!, so you get great results.

Just go to www.goodsearch.com and be sure to enter Cell Phones For Soldiers as the charity you want to support. Just 500 of us searching four times a day will raise about $7300 in a year without anyone spending a dime! And, be sure to spread the word!


That would be awesome, I know a lot of kids use search engines for papers and stuff and it would be a huge help for us to raise money that way too. I just want to let you know again how much I really appreciate this.

Brittany
for more info-  http://www.cellphonesforsoldiers.com/

1. Soldiers need to be able to call home</description>
  <mission>help the cell phones for soldiers effort already started</mission>
  <name>Cell phones for soldiers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2519</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1569</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">260.4</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Er/Qy/QX/ss/08/pI/opgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
