<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Retinitis pigmentosa (RP) causes the degeneration of photoreceptor cells in the retina. Photoreceptor cells capture and process light helping us to see. As these cells degenerate and die, patients experience progressive vision loss. There are types of photoreceptor cells: rod cells and cone cells. Rod cells help us to see images that come into our peripheral or side vision. They also help us to see in dark and dimly lit environments. Cone cells allow us to see fine visual detail in the center of our vision, and also allow us to perceive color. Together, rods &amp; cones are the cells responsible for converting light into electrical impulses that are transmitted to the brain where &#8220;seeing&#8221; actually occurs.

The most common feature of all forms of RP is a gradual degeneration of the rods and cones. Most forms of RP first cause the degeneration of rod cells. These forms of Retinitis pigmentosa, sometimes called rod-cone dystrophy, usually begin with night blindness. Night blindness is somewhat like the experience normally sighted individuals encounter when entering a dark movie theatre on a bright, sunny day. However, patients with Retinitis pigmentosa cannot adjust well to dark and dimly lit environments. As the disease progresses and more rod cells degenerate, patients lose their peripheral vision. Patients with RP often experience a ring of vision loss in their mid-periphery with small islands of vision in their very far periphery. Others report the sensation of tunnel vision, as though they see the world through a straw. Many patients with RP retain a small degree of central vision throughout their life.

As yet, there is no known cure for RP. However, intensive research is currently under way to discover the cause, prevention, and treatment of RP. 

And if you think RP is bad, wait until you hear about Usher syndrome and macular degeneration! Read below for details. </description>
  <mission>To drive the research that will provide preventions, treatments and cures for people affected by the entire spectrum of retinal degenerative diseases.</mission>
  <name>Foundation Fighting Blindness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/252</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6301</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2367.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/MU4/M36S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
