<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>DKMS began in Germany with the mission of one man.

In 1990, Peter Harf was desperate to find a donor for his wife Mechtild, who had acute leukemia. The search seemed hopeless because, at the time, there were only 3,000 unrelated donors available in Germany. He gathered friends, family and volunteers to initiate donor drives, successfully recruiting some 68,000 donors in one year.

DKMS or "Deutsche Knochenmarkspenderdatei" (German Bone Marrow Donor Center in English) was officially founded in 1991 by Peter Harf and his wife's physician, Professor Gerhard Ehninger. Their goal was simple: build a donor center to help more patients in need. Since then, DKMS has become the largest non-profit bone marrow donor center in the world.

DKMS has facilitated more than 9,000 transplants (or approximately five a day since its founding) and now counts more than 1.5 million registered donors. Our donors are part of registries all over the world, including the U.S. DKMS' donors make up more than 13% of worldwide registered donors, more than 20% of NMDP registered donors and over 50% of ZKRD registered donors.

But we're not stopping there. DKMS is expanding into America to make it simpler for U.S. patients to gain access to DKMS registered donors. By organizing all transports from Germany to the U.S., DKMS Americas* ensures that there are now fewer worries about finding a courier between the countries. DKMS Americas is in the process of setting up donor recruitment and becoming a donor center in the U.S. 

1. To facilitate more transplants between DKMS and patients in the U.S

2. To provide the best donor available for patients

3. We work tirelessly to expand the number of donors in the registry and connect them with patients in need of blood stem cell transplants, wherever they may live</description>
  <mission>For DKMS to be the central seal of quality for successful leukemia assistance on a global level and give transplant centers the opportunity to provide the best donor available for patients.</mission>
  <name>DKMS Americas</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2527</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">967</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1225.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ip/07/5G/t1/OU/TF/38LS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
