<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Are you considering backing gun control laws???

Do you think that because you may not own a gun, the rights guaranteed by the Second Amendment don't matter?

CONSIDER THIS:

In 1929 the Soviet Union established gun control.  From 1929 to 1953 approximately 20 million dissidents, unable to defend themselves were rounded up and exterminated.

In 1911, Turkey established gun control.  From 1915-1917, 1.5 million Armenians, unable to defend themselves were rounded up and exterminated.

Germany established gun control in 1938.  From 1939 to 1945, 13 million Jews, gypsies, homosexuals, the mentally ill and others who were unable to defend themselves were rounded up and exterminated.

China established gun control in 1935.  From 1948 to 1952 20 million political dissidents unable to defend themselves were rounded up and exterminated.

Uganda establishied gun control in 1970.  From 1971 to 1979 300,000 Christians unable to defend themselves were rounded up and exterminated.


**** That places total victims who lost their lives because of gun control at approximately 56 MILLION in the last CENTURY.

Since we should learn from our mistakes of history, the next time someone talks in favor of gun control, find out which group of citizens they wish to have exterminated.

It has now been 12 months since gun owners in Australia were forced to surrender 640,381 personal firearms to be destroyed, a program costing the government more than $500 million dollars.  The results Australia-wide:  

Homicides are up 3.2% 
Assaults are up 8%
Armed Robberies are up 44%
In the state of Victoria homicides with firearms are up 300%!!!!!!!!!

Over the previous 25 years, figures show a steady increase in armed robberies and Australian politicians are on the spot and at a loss to explain how no improvement in "safety" has been observed after such monumental effort and expense was successfully expended in "ridding society of guns".





1. The Second Amendement rights of American citizens should be guarded at all costs.</description>
  <mission>show raw evidence that gun-control only affects the law-abiding citizens</mission>
  <name>"Live Free or Die"</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2528</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">802</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yC/7m/My/Hf/sD/Qv/Ce/JtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
