<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>LEAD is a diverse coalition of progressive students that work for positive change on our campus and in our community, state, and nation.

Founded in January of 2000, LEAD swept the ASUCD elections, bringing equal opportunity and access to underserved and udnerrepresented communities.

Since its inception LEAD has been committed to working on issues of diversity, social justice, ASUCD reform, Univerisyt reform, and external advocacy.

Today, LEAD continues to create positive chnage and develop student leaders in all aspects of student life. If you want to create positive change, network with diverse student leaders, and build towards your future, then Go LEAD!

1. Promote respect, equal opportunity and access and a safe environment for all indentities.

2.  Empower and connect students to leaders and groups that help the underserved and underrepresented, that promote global prosperity and that uphold human rights for all persons.

3.  Uphold environmental concerns as a significant priority in university decision making, increase student participation in groups and programs which conserve natural resources, restore environmental quality, and reduce the environmental impact of the campu

4.  Increase the diversity of the student population, mental and physical health resources, and entertainment options. Improve the resources and funding available to students and student groups.

5.  Develop and implement policies and programs that guarantee the integrity, transparency, efficiency, outreach, and access of the student government.

6.  Advocate for University policies that guarantee an affordable, diverse, safe and healthy academic and campus environment.

7.  Maintain a strong student voice in city, county and state governments through the advocacy of student-friendly policies and laws. </description>
  <mission>LEAD empowers students to become active on issues of social justice, diversity, the environment, student quality of life, ASUCD reform, and University reform.</mission>
  <name>Go LEAD!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/253</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">51</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0Bp/IpLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
