<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dreamblogue is a charity and understanding project made real by two American teachers in China and a host of caring volunteers.  One big thing you can do right now is to favorite us on Technorati by clicking the following link:

http://technorati.com/faves?add=http://blogofdreams.com

&#8220;Yanzhi&#8221; and &#8220;David&#8221; will travel the 22 provinces of Mainland China this year to: 

1. Raise funds, via advertising for partner charities: Three respected and monitored charities in Education and rehabilitation.

2. Positively record travels, hopes, dreams, and the everyday wonder of China through Stories, Art, Cartoons, Photos, History, Language and more.

3. Provide training and internship opportunities to handicapped and gifted students to assist in all phases of the Dreamblogue.

4. Give US and Chinese Students the information needed to help them study abroad. We work with Chinese and overseas colleges to create cultural/educational opportunities.  

5. Record stories of people/places in hopes of finding new cultural treasures.    

6. Create digital archives of audio, video and written dreams of people worldwide.

7. Sponsor contests to bring people to China to share in our adventures. 

We finance out trip by:

1.Offering SEM assistance, translation, keyword buys, CMS, product and promotional item sourcing.  

2. Selling ads: Companies benefit from our top rankings in Chinese Engines for Travel, Study in China, Study in the US/UK, SEO, Photos, and more... 

3. Giving Lectures at colleges and businesses (see list below). ALL proceeds go directly to charity.

4. Promoting, through ads and posts, businesses committed to cultural understanding, ethical practices, and promotion of our causes.

How to help:

1. Link to us! Links are power and authority that can bring more traffic and allow us to sell more ads to fund our charities! 

2. Favorite us on Technorati. We advocate Technorati to Chinese students as a source of humanitarian, educational and social information. 

3. Send us businesses that desire Sourcing, Search Engine marketing in China: translations, online ad and content management, business promotion, cultural training, or recruitment of students/customers.

4. Send us pictures and stories. We need positive images of China. We credit you and link back to your site.

5. Help us get materials we need: laptops, video editing software, and podcast gear. 

6. Sponsor us to speak at your school or business on humor and wellness, creativity, cross-cultural marketing, ect&#8230; 


Please write us for specifics if you think you can help. 


1. People deserve to a forum to share their dreams with others.

2. Children in rural areas and orphanages in Asia deserve books and libraries.

3. Men and women suffering from cancer and other medical problems in China need and deserve help.

4. Every child in every country deserves the opportunity to learn to read.

5. &#20154;&#20204;&#21487;&#20197;&#21040;&#35770;&#22363;&#19978;&#19982;&#21035;&#20154;&#20998;&#20139;&#33258;&#24049;&#30340;&#26790;&#24819;&#12290;

6. &#20122;&#27954;&#30340;&#20892;&#26449;&#23401;&#23376;&#21644;&#23396;&#20799;&#20540;&#24471;&#25317;&#26377;&#25945;&#31185;&#20070;&#21644;&#22270;&#20070;&#39302;&#12290; 

7. &#22312;&#20013;&#22269;&#36973;&#21463;&#21040;&#30284;&#30151;&#25110;&#32773;&#20854;&#20182;&#30142;&#30149;&#22256;&#25200;&#30340;&#20154;&#38656;&#35201;&#32780;&#19988;&#20540;&#24471;&#24110;&#21161;&#12290;

8. &#27599;&#19968;&#20010;&#22269;&#23478;&#30340;&#27599;&#19968;&#20010;&#23567;&#26379;&#21451;&#37117;&#24212;&#35813;&#24471;&#21040;&#23398;&#20064;&#30340;&#26426;&#20250;&#12290;</description>
  <mission>To positively promote Chinese culture to an international community while aiding worthy charities</mission>
  <name>A China Dreamblogue &#20013;&#22269;&#36733;&#26790;&#21338;&#23458;</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2535</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">738</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">165.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/h5/qM/lF/6J/fl/qk/FtHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
