<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Charity event that we do every year to give back to the homeless and kids. Yes around christmas time we all are excited about getting, unwrapping, and having gifts, but why dont we change it around? Still be excited, but lets give, wrap, and let someone else have gifts.Someone that wish they had the toy you had, someone that wishes to have the meal you had, or just to someone that wish they had the love you had from family. Lets give back, give to others what we've always been getting. If its 10 cetns that you had in your pocket, and you can help someone with it, do it! If its the socks off you feet that can keep someone warm, do it!If it's and old teddy bear you had in your closet that you know you'll never use again, give it to someone thats never had it, watch how much they'll cherish it! Its time for all of us young people to love, live, life! Wake up and lets change the world like we know we can. So many people doubt us, but lets turn it around and show them that we really do care, that we really want to help othet people,and that we really want to change the world. I just want us to be able to say "Hey i did my part, and i'm still doing it". Once one person see the love, the help, and the needyness in our heart to want to help, they will want to help as well! Lets wake up and take our roles! Yes everybody wants help, but we cant help others without helping ourselves ;)

VISIT THE WEBSITE

www.whitecarpetchristmas.com



1. Parks full of FEMA trailers must end immediately

2. Kids not having anywhere for recreation must come to an end.

3. The homeless rates must decrease.</description>
  <mission>To benefit the homeless and unfortunate childrenaround the world by impacting their lives.</mission>
  <name>WHITE CARPET CHRISTMAS</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2543</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">62</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/OQ/Oi/Et/yO/He/Cq/0u/wvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
