<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 1968, Reason advances a free society by developing, applying, and promoting libertarian principles, including individual liberty, free markets, and the rule of law.

Reason produces respected public policy research on a variety of issues and publishes the critically acclaimed monthly magazine, Reason. Together, our top-tier think tank and political and cultural magazine reach a diverse, influential audience, advancing the values of individual freedom and choice, limited government, and market-friendly policies.

Reason Foundation's nonpartisan public policy research promotes choice, competition, and a dynamic market economy as the foundation for human dignity and progress. Reason produces rigorous, peer-reviewed research and directly engages the policy process, seeking strategies that emphasize cooperation, flexibility, local knowledge, and results. 

Reason is the monthly print magazine of "free minds and free markets." It covers politics, culture, and ideas through a provocative mix of news, analysis, commentary, and reviews. Reason provides a refreshing alternative to right-wing and left-wing opinion magazines by making a principled case for liberty and individual choice in all areas of human activity. 

      &#8220;Reason Foundation&#8217;s tolerance, civility, and consistency in defending individual liberty make it a haven for believers in a free society of all shades of opinion.&#8221;
      - Milton Friedman, Nobel Prize-winning Economist

      "Of all the nation's conservative or free-market policy groups, it may be the most libertarian among them, the Reason Foundation in Southern California, that ends up having the most direct impact on the actual functioning of government."
      - The Wall Street Journal

Reason Foundation is a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization completely supported by voluntary contributions from individuals, foundations, corporations, and the sale of our publications. 

For more information, please visit www.reason.org.

1. Free Minds

2. Free Markets</description>
  <mission>Free Minds and Free Markets</mission>
  <name>Reason Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2572</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">161</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3E/O7/Oh/PE/SY/JN/kWAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
