<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Crohn's and Colitis Foundation of America is a non-profit, volunteer-driven organization dedicated to finding the cure for Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis.

When you or your loved one is first diagnosed with inflammatory bowel disease, you probably feel overwhelmed. You may not even have heard of Crohn's disease or ulcerative colitis until now. You may have many questions about how this disease will affect you. Learning all you can is an important step toward taking charge of your illness -- and your life. 

The American Institute of Philanthropy gave CCFA one of the only 6 "A" ratings (out of 44 charities) in its most recent watchdog report. CCFA also consistently meets the standards established by the Better Business Bureau Wise Giving Alliance.

Currently the Foundation has over 50,000 members, served by our national headquarters, as well as a over 40 chapters nationwide. As CCFA is not a government-supported agency, we rely on the support of members and donors to continue our work.

WHAT YOU CAN DO TO HELP!

RECRUIT: family, friends, your neighbor, anyone! (try 5 a day) 
REMEMBER: if we all recruited one person, the cause would double over night.
FUNDRAISE: bake sales, can drives, bowl-a-thons, talk to your schools, jeans for genes days at work
DONATE: please donate $5 minimum.
ASK FOR HELP: the majority of people you ask will not turn you down; its up to you !
REMEMBER WE CAN NOT DO IT ALONE:
we need you.

Please consider supporting the cause: all donations DIRECTLY benefit Crohn's &amp; Colitis Research for a cure **Even a small $5-$10 tax-deductible donation can drastically help toward finding a cure** Thank you for your support.

thank you agian

1. The sooner a cure is found, the sooner people can stop suffering.

2. Many IBD patients are children. They deserve better.</description>
  <mission>To find a cure and prevent Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis through research, and to improve the quality of life of children and adults affected by these diseases through education and support.</mission>
  <name>Crohn's &amp; Colitis</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2573</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">32634</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">7833.92</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Hh/4o/Oj/YE/oa/vT/VQVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
