<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Brain Cancer/Tumours kill everyday.  They are complicated and various types that are uncurable.  Life expectancies are rarely long.  A cure can save people and their families from a lot of heart ache and pain.

Every day an estimated 482 people are diagnosed with a brain tumor. That is about 20 EVERY HOUR Worldwide. Brain tumors are the SECOND HIGHEST cause of cancer deaths in adult males aged 20-39, and in females between the ages of 20-39 they are the FIFTH leading cause of cancer deaths. 

Brain tumors do not discriminate against gender, ethnicity, overall fitness or socioeconomic status. Even if you appear to be in excellent physical shape and work out daily, you could still get a brain tumor.

Brain tumors don&#8217;t discriminate against age either. Brain tumors are now the leading cause of death for all childhood solid tumor cancers, accounting for 24% of cancer-related deaths in 1997 among persons up to 19 years of age. 

You dont have to donate.. Just be aware that Brain Tumours effect the daily living of many people around the Globe.  And PLEASE do what you can to help!

Over time there has been a long of progress with treatment options in other cancers, but when it comes to brain tumours and cancers, there is very little change in treatment options and about the same ratio of people die from Brain tumours now that they did many years ago.


CANADIAN STATISTICS . . . 

It is estimated that 55,000 Canadians are surviving with a brain tumour, and each year approximately 10,000 more are newly diagnosed with a brain tumour.

Primary brain tumours (originating in the brain) occur in 8 out of 100,000 people. This number rises to approximately 32 per 100,000 when metastatic tumours (cancer originating in other areas of the body that has spread to the brain) are included. 

The most common type of primary brain tumour, glioblastoma multiforme, is also the most malignant. Average survival, even with aggressive treatment, is LESS than one year.

Metastatic brain tumours occur at some point in 20-40% of people with cancer. The incidence of metastatic brain tumours is increasing as cancer patients live longer.

Brain tumours are the leading cause of solid cancer death in children under the age of 20, now SURPASSING acute lymphoblastic leukemia. They are the 3RD leading cause of solid cancer death in young adults ages 20-39.

Because brain tumours are located at the control centre for thought, emotion, and movement, they can dramatically affect an individual's physical and cognitive abilities and quality of life.

There are over 120 different types of brain tumours, making effective treatment very complicated.

Brain tumours in children are different from those in adults and are often treated differently. Although as many as 60% of children with brain tumours will survive, they are often left with long-term side effects.

Enhancing the quality of life for people with brain tumours requires access to quality specialty care, clinical trials, follow-up care and rehabilitative services. 

PERSONAL NOTE : I would just like to thank everyone who has contacted in regards to this cause.  I have recieved many thanks, an di appreciate them all. Thank you :)


Please visit the website(s) below and be inspired by what all our fellow man our doing to help the cause:

www.voicesagainstbraincancer.org 


1. 10,000 Canadians Diagnosed a Year

2. 55,500 Canadians Living with it now

3. Imagine a Cure</description>
  <mission>Imagine a Cure</mission>
  <name>Brain Cancer and Tumours</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2582</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">77894</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">7315.26</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/HA/ZX/ql/uK/cF/SM/M2DS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
