<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Breast Cancer Foundation of the Ozarks is an organization of people reaching out to friends and neighbors in Southwest Missouri who have been affected by breast cancer. BCFO offers personal support and comfort in very real and practical ways. We offer a full range of resources, including the latest information on breast cancer treatment options, and where to find related community services and support networks. BCFO also provides financial assistance to those in need and offers community wide education and awareness programs. Any area resident impacted by breast cancer is encouraged to seek out the BCFO. All calls and requests are kept confidential. And all contributions stay in the area.

The Breast Cancer Foundation of the Ozarks, hereinafter referred to as BCFO, shall be organized to operate exclusively for charitable, benevolent, and educational purposes. Without in any way limiting the foregoing general purpose, the specific purposes of BCFO shall be to: (1) Establish a charitable fund to meet needs of individuals with breast cancer and their families; (2) Advocate for issues not currently focused on by other area resources; (3) Provide information for accessing second opinions; (3) Promote breast cancer awareness for those under 40; (4) Increase awareness of treatment options and resources for all stages of breast cancer; (5) Provide information not included in current breast health promotion.

The Breast Cancer Foundation
of the Ozarks
.
We listen
.
We care
.
We can help.


1. Promote Breast Cancer Awareness</description>
  <mission>The Breast Cancer Foundation of the Ozarks will provide resources and support for individuals and their families in the local area who are and have been affected by breast cancer.</mission>
  <name>Breast Cancer Foundation of the Ozarks</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2592</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/UG/HT/VK/EG/Qi/sL/Es/DiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
