<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>To achieve our mission we need to raise $10,000 so that we may travel to El Pedregal to help build this school and give the children a chance to succeed and receive the gift of knowledge.

Our motivation to accomplish this goal began in February 2007 when we first traveled to El Pedregal. Here, we pooled our work efforts to assist in the construction of a school so that children would not have to walk over an hour one way to get to class. We immediately grew very attached to this village. Love and kindness shone brightly through their extreme poverty. While two classrooms are completed and in full use, there are two more floors that still need our help to complete.

We need your help and support. With your tax deductible donation, we can achieve our $10,000 goal. All proceeds will be used directly towards school supplies and construction material. It will be used solely for the 2008 Project REUNITE mission trip. Help us finish the school and once again be united with our overseas Dominican family.

In America, everyone has the chance to receive an education but those in El Pedregal are not afforded this same luxury. By making a simple contribution, you will be helping these children and allow them to have that same chance to learn, grow, and prosper. Your donation will make a lasting impact for years to come on this mountainside village.

For more information or answers to any questions you may have, please do not hesitate to contact us at projectreunite@gmail.com. Or you may send your tax deductible donation, via check made out to &#8220;St. Luke&#8217;s Church East Greenwich*/memo: 2008 PROJECT REUNITE trip&#8221; (an official charitable account), to:

PROJECT REUNITE
C/O Peterson
20 Squirrel Run
West Greenwich, R.I. 02817

Remember any amount will help make a difference so thank you for your support.

Sincerely,


Adam Neupauer, Lauren Pallister, Dana Treat

Team Leaders


*Please note: St. Luke&#8217;s will be acting as our fiscal agent for this mission trip. All donations will be used only for the 2008 PROJECT REUNITE mission.

1. Members: Adam Neupauer, Lauren Pallistar, Dana Treat, Charlotte Clement, Annie Lusi, Emily Alverez, Ben Peterson, Kara McKinnon, Max Neily, Zach Fox, and Rob Laverty.</description>
  <mission>Reunite with the small mountain village of El Pedregal in the Dominican Republic and continue with the construction of a school.</mission>
  <name>Project Reunite</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2601</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">61</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hW/E7/Fv/FZ/6i/Ju/eD/sBS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
