<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There are a number of Jews still left in the Ukraine, the majority of which are very elderly. They have lived through and survived the harshness of The Pogroms, World War II and everyday Ukranian anti-semetism. These are people who have known nothing but suffering and loss. These are my people, and so many others in this Nation. Not all of us were lucky enough to make it out of that country. These people have barely any food, no money for medication, no heat in the frozen barren winter, no steady source of income, no one to come to their rescue. They live every day in strife, persecuted, trapped in a country which acknowldges them as sub-human. Imagine your grandmother or grandfather, being riduculed and abused, sick and hungry scrounging on scraps of food, outcast in your own homeland, no access to a proper physician, cold and distraught. Only clinging to memories of pain, and the death of loved ones. It's a grim picture, but its a real one. Wake up!!!! The world exists outside of America, and the situation grows dire. Please look into yourself and realize you can help these elderly jews, trapped in a living hell to escape for a moment. Your donation toward food, medicine, clothing and shelter will go directly to them, there is no middle man. These people do not feel sorry for themselves. 

These people are proud and are aware of the injustices that have been done to them, but they continue to live and strive for survival. With your help we can assure that it will be easier for them. Satisfy your soul, for It beckons for action. 

1. Equal rights for all people no matter what religion

2. Proper care of these peoples ailments and traumas

3. Try to immigrate these people to Israel or the United States</description>
  <mission>Send relief, aid and respect</mission>
  <name>Soviet Jew Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2602</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">40</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sC/zk/WJ/Wy/1g/Um/AytS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
