<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Therapeutic riding has been used since the early 1950s in Europe as a tool for improving the lives of individuals with physical disabilities. NARHA was founded in 1969 to promote and support therapeutic riding in the United States and Canada. 

Individuals with almost any cognitive, physical and/or emotional disability can benefit from therapeutic riding, driving, vaulting, competition or other purposeful, safe and supervised interaction with equines. 

Because horseback riding gently and rhythmically moves the rider's body in a manner similar to a human gait, riders with physical disabilities often show improvement in flexibility, balance and muscle strength. 

For individuals with mental or emotional disabilities, the unique relationship formed with the horse can lead to increased confidence, patience and self-esteem. 

Local, State, National and even International Competition often is the logical progression for individuals with disabilities who have mastered equestrian skills and seek to further challenge themselves. 

The sense of independence and acceptance found through these activities with the horse benefits all. 

Individuals with the following disabilities commonly participate and benefit from equine facilitated therapy and activities: 

Muscular Dystrophy 
Cerebral Palsy 
Visual Impairment 
Down Syndrome 
Mental Retardation 
Autism 
Multiple Sclerosis 
Spina Bifida 
Emotional Disabilities 
Brain Injuries 
Spinal Cord Injuries 
Amputations 
Learning Disabilities 
Attention Deficit Disorder 
Deafness 
Cardiovascular accident/Stroke 

The North American Riding for the Handicapped Association serves a membership of 4,000 individuals and over 670 NARHA programs around the country. 5000 specially screened and trained horses make safe interactions possible. 



1. Appreciating the power of the horse to change lives</description>
  <mission>NARHA is a membership organization that fosters safe therapeutic equine activities through education, communication, standards and research for people with and without disabilities</mission>
  <name>North American Riding for the Handicapped Association</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2604</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">779</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">85.29</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bj/qG/Tj/xr/cs/4d/4uUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
