<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our mission is to help at-risk youth avoid the influence of drugs, crime, and gangs by providing positive role models and alternative activities and to promote the development of self-discipline, self-confidence, self-esteem, physical fitness, and leadership qualities in the youth of the local communities.

Through our outreach program, the youth of the community are given the chance to experience the development concepts and philosophy that has taken young people off the streets and successfully challenged them to become outstanding men and women of character and achievement. The instructors and mentors at Jow Ga are committed to teaching more than just Kung Fu--they are also teaching a philosophy of life that extends far beyond the formal instruction. Character, a belief in equality, a generosity of spirit--these are just a few of the qualities that we work so hard to instill in the youth. Positive role models, who can help lead a child in the right direction, are sorely needed, especially in light of the concerns that challenge todays' youth. The Jow Ga program continues to be an excellent source of providing this much needed help. At Jow Ga, our kids have no time for crime. Jow Ga has helped many of our students mature into highly respected citizens. People like Troy Williams, now an audio-visual expert and movie producer; Eugene Mackie, now a successful business consultant; Ken Laboy, now a Navy Seal; Jesse Dubon, now a Fire Fighter; and Deric Mims, now a Senior Vice President with a regional bank.

I PROMISE TO TRY TO MATCH EVERY DOLLAR DONATED TO THE SCHOOL IF I CAN!!

I'M NOT RICH SO I MAY STRUGGLE WITH THIS PROMISE BUT I'LL TRY MY HARDEST TO KEEP UP!! I SWEAR THAT IF I CANT MATCH IT I'LL DONATE AS MUCH AS I POSSIBLY CAN AT THE MOMENT!!

Whats 5 dollars...some starbucks?
 
Please be the friends I hope you guys are and atleast join if you don't wish to donate.

Langley Park Community Center
1500 Merrimac Dr.
Hyattsville, MD 20783
(301)-445-4508

1. Anti-Drug/Anti-Crime/Anti-Gang

2. Self Defense

3. Build Character</description>
  <mission>Im hoping to raise funds to help Sifi Deric Mims, who has taken on 100% of the financial costs required to maintain the school open, as he continues to offer free Kung Fu classes to anybody interested</mission>
  <name>Jow Ga Kung Fu Cultural Association</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2609</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">40</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">345.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kw/yR/Mj/0x/jR/Yd/Ht/sSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
