<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A cause to aid people in understanding all about brain tumors. Support, knowledge, help, etc. 

-What is a brain tumor?: The growth of abnormal cells in the tissues of the brain. Brain tumors can be benign (non-cancerous) or malignant (cancerous). 

-Estimated new cases and deaths from brain and other nervous system tumors in the United States in 2007:

  New cases: 20,500 
 
  Deaths: 12,740 

-Each year more than 200,000 people in the United States are diagnosed with a primary or metastatic brain tumor.  Primary brain tumors comprise approximately 40,000 of these diagnoses. 

-Brain tumors are the leading cause of solid tumor cancer death in children under the age of 20, now surpassing acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL).  They are the second leading cause of cancer death in male adults ages 20-29 and the fifth leading cause of cancer death in female adults ages 20-39 

-There are over 120 different types of brain tumors, which make effective treatment complicated.  They can be malignant or non-malignant (benign), and in either case, can be just as injurious or life threatening.  At present, the standard treatments for brain tumors include surgery, radiation therapy, and chemotherapy.  These may be used either individually or in combination.  

-There are currently no known causes of brain tumors, however, epidemiological studies are ongoing.  Complete and accurate data on all primary brain tumors is needed to provide the foundation for investigations of its causes and research leading to improved diagnosis and treatment. 

-At this time, brain tumor research is underfunded and the public remains unaware of the magnitude of this disease.  The cure rate for most brain tumors is significantly lower than that for many other types of cancer. 

-Both Bob Marley and Lance Armstrong had metastatc brain tumors. Elizabeth Taylor is living with one...ANYONE can get it. 

*Please refer to the wall posting by me (Sara Stowell) to get information **

1. Anyone can get a brain tumor at any time; don't think you're an exception to the rule. 

2. Learning more about this will enable people to spread information. 

3. There is NOWHERE near enough awareness, don't just join because it looks good:join to be aware, care, and learn. </description>
  <mission>Spread knowledge to people regarding brain tumors; how they affect us all and how to help. </mission>
  <name>Brain Tumor Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2612</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">43851</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">4044.83</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fl/wU/dE/Mm/Xn/4A/SoXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
