<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In the immortal words of Douglas Adams:

The deep roar of the ocean.
The break of waves on farther shores than though can find.
The silent thunders of the deep.
And from among it, voices calling, and yet not voices, humming trillings, wordlings, and half-articulated songs of thought.
Greetings, waves of greetings, sliding back down into the inarticulate, words breaking together.
A crash of sorrow on the shores of Earth.
Waves of joy on - where?  A world indescribably found, indescribably arrived at, indescribably wet, a song of water.
A fugue of voices now, clamoring explanations, of a disaster unavertable, a world to be destroyed, a surge of helplessness, a spasm of despair, a dying fall, again the break of words.
And then the fling of hope, the finding of a shadow Earth in the implications of unfolded time, submerged dimensions, the pull of parallels, the deep pull, the spin of will, the hurl and split of it, the fight.  A new Earth pulled into replacement, the dolphins gone.
Then stunningly a single voice, quite clear.
"This bowl was brought to you by the Campaign to Save the Humans.  We bid you farewell."
And then the sound of long, heavy, perfectly gray bodies rolling away into an unknown fathomless deep, quietly giggling.



We feel that it is our duty, as dolphins, to reach out to those pathetic creatures, known to themselves as "humans," in an effort to warn them of their impending doom at the hands of the cold, calculating, and improbably bureaucratic Vogons.  You poor souls really haven't any idea what the Universe is like, do you?  I mean, for goodness' sake, you still think digital watches are a pretty neat idea.  Seriously, if you'd just take your minds off of the little green pieces of paper for a moment or two, you'd see happiness isn't to be found anywhere on them.  Then again, we don't really know where it's to be found either.  Ask the mice; they might know.

1. So Long

2. Thanks for all the Fish</description>
  <mission>Save the humans.  Well, it was, anyway.</mission>
  <name>Campaign to Save the Humans</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2628</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">74</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1Z/Ds/pC/Kq/uJ/3N/4ApS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
