<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>JDRF is the worldwide leader for research to cure type 1 diabetes. It sets the global agenda for diabetes research, and is the largest charitable funder and advocate of diabetes science worldwide.

The mission of JDRF is to find a cure for diabetes and its complications through the support of research. Type 1 diabetes is an autoimmune disease that strikes children and adults suddenly, and can be fatal. Until a cure is found, people with type 1 diabetes have to test their blood sugar and give themselves insulin injections multiple times or use a pump &#8211; each day, every day of their lives. And even with that intensive care, insulin is not a cure for diabetes, nor does it prevent its potential complications, which may include kidney failure, blindness, heart disease, stroke, and amputation.

Since its founding in 1970 by parents of children with type 1 diabetes, JDRF has awarded more than $1.5 billion to diabetes research, including $107 million last year.  More than 80 percent of JDRF's expenditures directly support research and research-related education. For more information, please visit www.jdrf.org. 



1. Nearly 26 million Americans have diabetes and as many as 3 million Americans have type 1 diabetes.

2. Diabetes is the single most costly chronic disease.

3. In the U.S., a new case of diabetes is diagnosed every 30 seconds; more than 1.6 million people are diagnosed each year.

4. Each year more than 15,000 children and 15,000 adults are diagnosed with diabetes in the U.S. That's 80 people per day. 

5. Taking insulin via pump or injections is the only way to treat type 1 diabetes.  It is not a cure.</description>
  <mission>Cure diabetes and its complications through the support of research</mission>
  <name>Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/265</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">233153</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">51487.68</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DU/B1/oh/Fz/yQ/lv/CY/WcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
