<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This cause dedicated to Albert Schweitzer, M.D. (right).

A society can be measured by how it treats the most vulnerable: the weak, unborn, disabled, aged, unpopular, and even the condemned.  The first among the founder's concerns was for "life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness".

Good government is limited government with limited power.  It only exists to prevent one citizen from violating the rights of another citizen.  In a world where rights run the gamut from the right to a working used car (Lemon laws) to the right to equal housing, shouldn't the basic right to life also have legal protection?

Therefore, it is our position that the following practices that end established human life -- the most basic human right -- are abolished.  Our society will be a more just and proud one if this occurs.

-- Euthanasia
-- Abortion, which has often been used to reduce the population of one race or gender
-- Wars conducted outside the Augustinian "just war" doctrine of Jus ad bellum and Jus in bello.
-- Capital punishment
-- Elimination and "weeding" out of the disabled population through prenatal exams and witholding of care

All of these practices are legal (and sometimes conducted by government), a fact while betrays our otherwise-justified sense of being an advanced civilization.  Liberals should condemn then for their illiberal nature and conservatives should condemn them for they way they violate individual rights.  Libertarians such as myself should condemn them for the enormous power they give to government.

Most importantly, we should work together to make their elimination a practical outcome.

1. Protect ALL life, from conception to natural death.

2. Eliminate capital punishment because of its finality and the power it yields to government -- the only time when government is greater than (rather than equal to) its citizenry's basic claim to life.

3. Accept the disabled (part of the natural variation of the human species) into society without thought to their elimination.

4. Euthanasia, which discards life when it is no longer useful to the larger society -- a clear violation of the conservative "principle of individuality" and the "liberal principle" of compassion.

5. Gen. Douglas MacArthur: "I know war as few other men now living know it, and nothing to me is more revolting. I have long advocated its complete abolition, as its very destructiveness on both friend and foe has rendered it obsolete."

6. Government should act to protect human life from violence, assualt, and attacks on its basic dignity when conducted by individuals.</description>
  <mission>harmonize our laws with a universal respect for what Nobel Peace Prize winner Albert Schweitzer, M.D., O.D, called a "reverence for life".</mission>
  <name>Consistent Ethic of Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2651</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">48</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ev/mN/yi/Qt/QZ/Mv/8JUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
