<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>*NEWS FLASH* WE ARE DOING GREAT THANKS ALOT AND LETS KEEP SUPPORTING THANKS ALOT* 

Doctors Without Borders/M&#233;decins Sans Fronti&#232;res (MSF) is an independent international medical humanitarian organization that delivers emergency aid to people affected by armed conflict, epidemics, natural or man-made disasters, or exclusion from health care in more than 70 countries.

Each year, MSF doctors, nurses, logisticians, water-and-sanitation experts, administrators, and other medical and non-medical professionals depart on more than 4,700 aid assignments. They work alongside more than 25,800 locally hired staff to provide medical care. 

In emergencies and their aftermath, MSF provides essential health care, rehabilitates and runs hospitals and clinics, performs surgery, battles epidemics, carries out vaccination campaigns, operates feeding centers for malnourished children, and offers mental health care. When needed, MSF also constructs wells and dispenses clean drinking water, and provides shelter materials like blankets and plastic sheeting.

Through longer-term programs, MSF treats patients with infectious diseases such as tuberculosis, sleeping sickness, and HIV/AIDS, and provides medical and psychological care to marginalized groups such as street children. 

MSF was founded in 1971 as the first nongovernmental organization to both provide emergency medical assistance and bear witness publicly to the plight of the people it assists. A private nonprofit association, MSF is an international network with sections in 19 countries.



1. Doctors without borders help people all over the world

2. Volunteer participants

3. Non-Profit organization</description>
  <mission>To provide medical care to people in crisis in more than 70 countries worldwide</mission>
  <name>Doctors Without Borders</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2659</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">58200</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">8576.31</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/N2/y1/jM/tw/K5/zM/kazS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
