<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>One of the most expensive things for people to gain is fresh produce.  For people on fixed low incomes, struggling to get the books balanced comes before growing anything for themselves.

Plants for the poor provides a few outstanding ideas;
"Waste not want not"...  Many larger companies throw out plants rather than give them TLC.  this allows for Pftp volunteers to gain them at a reduced price, and reduce the waste garnered yearly- when most plants just need water and care.
It also provides an outlet for used planters to be re-used again to pot the plants that have been given up on.  It's amazing how little a plant needs to get healthy again!
One tomato plant can provide quite a few tomatoes over the course of a year.  This boosts nutrition as well as decreases dependency upon the government for nutritional needs.
It encourages people to take responsibility for the things around them (and it may even show a few people they have a green thumb!)

Through plant, soil and container rescuing, Pftp can reduce plant-costs by 80% as well as reduce waste and encourage 'greening'  their local area.

Please contact me for more information :)

Plants rescued as of this date:  120
Soil rescued= 90 L
Spending= $50  (including popsicles for some kids that wanted to help)
Containers rescued= At least 120
People given an alternate source of food= (TBA)


Please join and make a difference in someone's life!

1. Nutrition is very important to well being

2. Fresh fruit is better than canned

3. It adds color and flavor to people's lives as well as promotes self-esteem when they find out they can grow stuff on their own!</description>
  <mission>provide fruit and vegetable plants for people unable to sustain fresh fruit and vegetables for themselves due to income.</mission>
  <name>Plants for the poor</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2660</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">46</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rd/yu/Ew/1H/nr/AB/ecsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
