<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Religion seems to be behind the works of everything. Many people view it as the sole reason and motive for living. I believe that religion is a beautiful thing, but what it has turned into has lead me to question it. People's interpretations and criticism of others has lead to massive killings and is the reason for hundreds of wars. About 95% of the world believes in a higher form than themselves...doesn't that seem like a pretty big deal? 

So why do we have to be glued down to a specific religion? I believe that religion is a personal journey between you and that special oneness, which you may refer to as God. People may say that "their way" is the only way, but there is no truth in religion. If we read some of the religious teachings we see that so many different religions are saying some of the same things. The reason we fight is because we interpret those teachings in our own specific ways. This is why religion has turned into something other than a beautiful thing. 

I dont mean to preach in any way, but it is sad to see many children around the world grow up in a religion that they know to be the truth when there may be another religion or veiwpoint that might suit them better or give them a better sense of lifestyle in their own light. Create your own way. 

1. Religion and spirituality is a personal path that you have the right to travel without others question.

2. Come up with your own beliefs and thoughts. Your family, church, or friends dont need to create them for you.

3. Religion in balance will help create a more open-minded attitude in the world of religion and in the world itself.</description>
  <mission>Let people be more open-minded in religious viewpoints.</mission>
  <name>Religion In Balance</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2666</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">30</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/WQ/fh/YZ/6Z/NE/t6/du8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
