<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Female genital mutilation (F.G.M.), often referred to as 'female circumcision', comprises all procedures involving partial or total removal of the external female genitalia. They include:
    *excision of the prepuce, with or without excision of part or all of the clitoris;
    *excision of the clitoris with partial or total excision of the labia minora;
    *pricking, piercing or incising of the clitoris and/or labia; stretching of the clitoris and/or labia; cauterization by burning of the clitoris and surrounding tissue
   * introduction of corrosive substances or herbs into the vagina to cause bleeding or for the purpose of tightening or narrowing it
       The most common type of female genital mutilation is excision of the clitoris and the labia minora, accounting for up to 80% of all cases.

Health consequences
       The immediate and long-term health consequences of female genital mutilation vary according to the type and severity of the procedure performed.
       Immediate complications include severe pain, shock, hemorrhage, urine retention, ulceration of the genital region and injury to adjacent tissue. Hemorrhage and infection can cause death.
       More recently, concern has arisen about possible transmission of the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) due to the use of one instrument in multiple operations.
       Long-term consequences include cysts and abscesses, scar formation, damage to the urethra resulting in urinary incontinence,painful sexual intercourse and sexual dysfunction and difficulties with childbirth.
       Genital mutilation may leave a lasting mark on the life and mind of the woman who has undergone it.
F.G.M. is usually performed by a traditional practitioner with crude instruments and without anesthetic.
        The age at which female genital mutilation is performed varies from area to area. It is performed on infants a few days old, female children and adolescents and, occasionally, on mature women.


1. An end to F.G.M. must be found.

2. Knowledge must be spread about first F.G.M.'s existence and secondly its serious health hazards.

3. Women deserve the most basic rights of safety, pleasure, and ability to choose. </description>
  <mission>Fight Ignorance and End Female Genital Mutilation</mission>
  <name>An End to Female Genital Mutilation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2687</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">507</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">87.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yZ/Vl/3I/Dq/4Y/P5/w3cS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
