<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What Services Does the Arthritis Foundation Provide?

Arthritis Foundation efforts center on the three-fold mission of the organization: research, prevention and quality of life. The Arthritis Foundation currently provides nearly $20 million in grants to nearly 300 researchers to help find a cure, prevention or better treatment for arthritis. The Arthritis Foundation&#8217;s sponsorship of research for more than 50 years has resulted in major treatment advances for most arthritis diseases.

The Arthritis Foundation also provides a large number of community-based services nationwide to make life with arthritis easier, including:

    * Self-help courses
    * Water and land-based exercise classes
    * Home study groups
    * Instructional videotapes
    * Public forums
    * A wide variety of free educational brochures and booklets
    * The national, bimonthly consumer magazine Arthritis Today
    * Continuing education courses and publications for health professionals

Arthritis Foundation volunteers serve as advocates to local and national governments on behalf of the nearly 70 million Americans with arthritis and chronic joint symptoms. Their successes include the federal establishment of a national institute for arthritis among the National Institutes of Health, increased federal funding for arthritis research and state funding for arthritis medications. An Arthritis Foundation telephone and e-mail information service answers questions from more than 140,000 people per year.

1. Help find a cure for arthritis.

2. Raise funds to provide better treatment for those diagnosed and suffering from arthritis.

3. To make life easier for those suffering from dibilitating arthritis.</description>
  <mission>raise money for the support and development of a cure for the nation's #1 dibilitating disease</mission>
  <name>Fight For A Cure</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/269</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">203</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/x83/sdvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
