<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>BLISS stands for Breastfeeding and Lactation Information and Support Source.

BLISS is a breastfeeding organization serving the region of Edmonton and area only. Headed by volunteers and donated services, our nursing and lactation support team has a vision for growth. We are committed to providing breastfeeding families one-on-one assistance with breastfeeding, credible resources and information. Maintaining advocacy for the rights of all mothers and their nurslings is our whole-hearted devotion.

 Acceptance:  All families requiring the services of BLISS will be unconditionally accepted, whether they choose to breastfeed for 5 years, 5 months, 5 days, or not at all.  Breastfeeding information and assistance will be provided to anyone who needs it, no questions asked. 

Advocacy: As Canadian society has changed, so have views and issues with breastfeeding.  It is our goal to promote breastfeeding in a truthful manner by consistantly placing it subtly and positively into the public eye, therefore slowly gaining societal acceptance.  It is our goal to assure breastfeeding is seen as the norm.

Support:  Support is so often crucial in a breastfeeding relationship.  BLISS aims to provide support to moms and babies who need it, for as long as they need it.  Home visits, phone and email communication, and literature will be available to all families, at no cost.  Every baby deserves to be breastfed, and we strive to make that possible. BLISS will have a unique position in this community and a unique relationship with breastfeeding families. We are committed to building that relationship and earning that trust everyday.

Information: With the right information, a breastfeeding relationship doesn't have to end until both mother and baby (or toddler) are ready for weaning.  BLISS will work to provide factual, helpful information to as many families as possible.  It is our goal for families to make the best choices they can based on the best information they have.


1. All babies deserve to be breastfed.

2. All breastfeeding families deserve support.

3. All choices are to be respected.</description>
  <mission>provide breastfeeding support for families in Edmonton and surrounding area</mission>
  <name>BLISS Breastfeeding Support in Edmonton</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2691</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">50</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5y/iF/QY/S1/mD/sR/4rwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
