<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Leading the World in Finding Breast Cancer Causes, Preventions, and Treatments for 30 years and counting..
 
Breast cancer is the second leading cause of cancer death in women, and is the leading cause of cancer death among young and middle aged women. Each year in America, more than 180,000 women are diagnosed with breast cancer, of whom 40,000 die. One in 8 women will develop breast cancer in her lifetime. 

Breast cancer kills 500,000 people a year globally, and 1.2 million are diagnosed with it every year."[The Nurses' Health Study] is one of the most significant studies ever conducted on the health of women."&#8212;Donna Shalala, Former Secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services

The Nurses' Health Study (of Brigham and Women's Hospital) has led the world in identifying causes, preventive approaches, and treatments for breast cancer for the past 3 decades. The Nurses' Health Study I and II, established in 1976 and 1989 and consisting of ~250,000 women followed for 20-30 years, is regarded as world's largest and longest running studies into breast cancer causes and preventions. 

However, due to highly limited funding for women's health research, research dollars from public donations are becoming ever more critical to continuing the vital research into women's health and breast cancer. Thus, please consider supporting breast cancer research in the Nurses' Health Study via referral to friends or donations. 

Thank you for your support.

1. 1.	Breast cancer is preventable and treatable-- no woman should die from breast cancer. 

2. 1.	Breast cancer is preventable and treatable-- no woman should die from breast cancer. </description>
  <mission>Donate Money For Cancer

Donations for Breast Cancer in Canada
http://www.cbcf.org/become/make_donation.html</mission>
  <name>Help Find a Cure For Breast Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2702</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">34551</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">427.5</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ax/in/ka/As/ll/Aa/Dc7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
