<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Vision

Zealot Movement, an underground cause dedicated to the power and love of the Gospel, protected against misuse by the core tenets of the Four Pillars.  No one can claim to be a zealot and a drug user at the same time, nor would he want to, considering the intensity of our opposition to that lifestyle.  The same goes for the lukewarm believer and his fornication.  The line has been drawn for the committed and noncommittal alike.  There is forgiveness, but God's grace is not a place to wipe your feet.

Our weapon of choice is music.  Music, a force dating before the birth of man, is a sword with which we battle the powers of this world, and great for the breaking of chains and curses.  We wage war in the underground through music and we will shatter the walls of this world's empire, dead to ourselves and alive in Christ.

We are children of the Sword, the face of Truth on a dying planet.  We are the worldwide tribe and at the feet of our King the nations will bow.  We are the pure and royal priesthood.  All that we put our hands to must prosper.  We are servants to man, relentless in our toil, driven by love of the Greatest Servant.  We are the Brotherhood of Christ.  Our family does not break like those of the fallen world.  We are the enemies of injustice and defenders of those without defense.  Our eyes are the coals of righteousness and our hearts burn with hatred for all that is evil.  We are the warriors.  We are the fearless.  We are the Zealots.


1. "He must increase, but I must decrease." -John 3:30</description>
  <mission>"He must increase, but I must decrease." -John 3:30</mission>
  <name>Christian Zealot Movement</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2704</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zX/vg/x0/Gh/QA/ys/JmdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
