<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>        In 1990 a high school art teacher in Michigan helped his students solve a problem.  They were searching for a way to raise funds to support a food drive.  What evolved was a class project to make ceramic bowls for a fund raising meal.  Guests were served a simple meal of soup and bread, and were invited to keep the bowl as a reminder of hunger in the world.
          By the following year the originators had developed this concept into Empty Bowls,  a project to provide  support for food banks, soup kitchens, and other organizations that fight hunger.  The Imagine /RENDER Group,a 501(c)3 organization, was created to promote the project.  Since then Empty Bowls events have been held throughout the world, and millions of dollars have been raised to combat hunger
          It is our intent that the Empty Bowls project maintain a high level of integrity; that it is a project of inclusion; that it cuts across social, political, racial, religious, age, and any other perceived boundaries; and that it provides a tool which we can all use in working towards the goal of ending hunger.  We ask that some aspect of hunger education be part of your project.
        Whatever you choose to do with this project, we ask  that you maintain its original name, intent, and integrity.  We endorse the use of the name and logo, Empty Bowls, only under these conditions.  All money raised under the name of Empty Bowls must be used for fighting hunger. Please help spread this project by using the name Empty Bowls and our address in all your publicity.



1. World Hunger Is an EVER GROWING problem</description>
  <mission>Raise funds for world hunger</mission>
  <name>Empty Bowls</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2706</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">334</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">122.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nY/wx/16/l4/uu/kT/El1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
