<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>To start working on the platform of Breast and Colon Cancer for the Miss Universe Organization 2008.  In other words, I would like to be Miss Illinois USA Universe 2008, and the platform for the organization this upcoming year for all state titleholders will be Breast and Colon Cancers...  Also to research, volunteer for prevention, and understand the cancers' effects on our society and to try to raise awareness through volunteer work and public relations, as the hopeful titleholder for Miss Illinois USA 2008 pageant will be working toward these goals during her year of reign!!!  Thanks for all who're supporting and joining, it means so much!  By tha way, y'all are just incredible people!!!

You may all make donations that will go straight to the Susan G. Komen Breast Cancer Foundation.  This is a great oppertunity for you all!  Susan G. Komen and her family grew up in Peoria, IL, the town in which I currently live, so I'm very lucky to be representing this platform.  The foundation itself was also founded here, so this is really a highlight in my quest for the crown.  There is a road here dedicated to Susan B. Komen, there are shops which represent her here, and there are affiliations with the hospital as well.  If you're looking to fight breast cancer, this is the place to be!  Thank you all!

PS...  Please watch the Miss USA Teen pageant on Friday, August 24th on NBC...  It's a high quality show, and will be absolutely wonderful!!!  Thank you everyone!

1. Breast cancer needs a CURE!!!</description>
  <mission>Support Breast Cancer through raising awareness, working for prevention, and by supporting the quest for the cures.</mission>
  <name>Breast Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2743</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">187</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6N/An/uj/AY/3y/zB/Rv/IxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
