<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Foundation was founded with the surplus funds from the 1994 FIFA World Cup with the goal of enriching the lives of children and their families through increased participation in the game of soccer. 

The Foundation has invested more than $40 million in the growth of the game of soccer through grants and other financial support. The Foundation has provided significant financial assistance to the 1999 and 2003 FIFA Women's World Cups, the development of the U.S. National Teams and the growth of Major League Soccer (MLS), the Women's United Soccer Association (WUSA), and the Women's Soccer Initiative, Inc. (WSII).

Through the Passback Program, the Foundation collects and distributes uniforms and equipment to those who in need. 

The Foundation has also supported programs that train coaches and referees. In the area of field development, the Foundation has partnered with the EPA to turn Brownfields and vacant areas into soccer fields where children can play safely.

But the Foundation is much more than just a grant-making organization. The Foundation also acts as a central resource for teams, clubs and organizations interested in expanding and/or renovating existing soccer fields and complexes. Through its website, the Foundation has made field building tools and materials available to provide expert assistance to those trying to expand recreational opportunities in their local communities. The Foundation's 'Partner Resource Center' allows industry-leading soccer equipment companies the opportunity to provide preferred pricing to Foundation grantees and constituents, thus allowing them to stretch limited resources farther.

The Foundation's All Conditions Fields Program provides support for the construction of lighted synthetic grass soccer fields that can be played on in all conditions.

1. Help grow the sport of soccer in the United States.</description>
  <mission>The U.S. Soccer Foundation's mission is to invest in people and projects that enhance, assist, and grow the sport of soccer in the United States.</mission>
  <name>US Soccer Federation Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2749</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">561</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">580.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uR/80/R1/QB/Yx/04/2FeS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
