<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is a company that was founded by a few indiduals not for recognition but to really meet a need thats long over do we all know the problem we face with homelessness as well as gang violence, teen pregnancy and the ratio of drop outs threwout the country. Our innercity youth and homeless people have been given almost been abanded when it comes to programs that really assist them with change and most programs that are created only a portion of the profits actually go to its initended cause.  In most cases government and non-for-profit organizations employees have a (Hell im voluntering so they lucky they are getting anything attitude towards thier clients and they usually end up suffering and getting the raw end of the deal. We at oporation we care will not only show you where your proceeds are going but rather would like you to assist us as well by not  just donating a dollar but your hearts and help someone in life remember By Gods grace you enjoy the quality of life you have and sooooo many other people are NOT so fortunate. If you are interested please contact me at info@operationwecare.com

We will film every life we touch so we are in need of 
your donations (can be time, money, food or clothing and production equipment donate new camerasor computer for our center ALL and any assistance is appreciated!) 


Thank You and God Bless you For Caring!

1. Help feed the homeless and break the stereotypical veiw most people have about homeless people

2. Help todays disadvantaged youth by profiding hope with workshops and community building

3. Provide workshops that will help the innercitys across the globe by answering a need with a realistic solution</description>
  <mission>Help The Homeless and Assisting Lower Income Youth</mission>
  <name>Operation We Care</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2752</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fg/QR/fZ/lj/wN/Na/kXbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
