<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>As we all know, John Ferguson Jr. has been steadily running the Toronto Maple Leafs into the ground. He has consistently shown that all he cares about, as far as his management goes, is making money. And it&#8217;s not even like he can use this money to better the team, since the salary cap has been put in place. Some of the more dominant examples of his incompetence have been: 
-     Signing Belfour and Domi to large contracts, only to have to buy them out
-     Trading star prospect Tukka Rask for all-time flop Andrew Raycroft
-     Signing McCabe to a long-term $5.75-million, no movement contract
-     Signing Kubina for $5/season 

There are many more examples, but these are the ones that have seriously handcuffed the Leafs&#8217; organization.  

After analyzing his moves and transactions over the last few years, it is safe to assume that for the Leafs&#8217; to become competitive again or, dare I say, make a run for the Cup, JFJ must be fired. The Leafs have THE HIGHEST profit margin in the League and, as GM&#8217;s don&#8217;t count against our salary cap, I think it&#8217;s time to go out and throw as much money as needs be at a proven top GM or an up-and-coming manager (Stevie Y anyone?) who can turn this team around.

It&#8217;s been 40 years since Toronto won the Cup. It&#8217;s time for our goal to change from Ferguson&#8217;s &#8220;male the playoffs&#8221; aspiration, where Antropov is on the top line, to a &#8220;continuous cup run&#8221; objective under new, more adequate management.

ANY DONATIONS FOR THIS CAUSE WILL GO DIRECTLY TO THE EASTERN SHORE HOCKEY ASSOCIATION, INC..

1. John Ferguson Jr. must be fired.

2. A new, much more competent General Manager must fill the position.

3. The new GM must turn around the Leafs, turning the team into a future cup contender, within the next 5 years.</description>
  <mission>Get John Ferguson Jr. fired</mission>
  <name>Eradicate John Ferguson Jr. from the Toronto Maple Leafs&#8217; Management</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2760</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3T/Za/Sn/CK/2w/UE/2LpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
