<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Free Software Foundation (FSF), established in 1985, is dedicated to promoting computer users' rights to use, study, copy, modify, and redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development and use of free software, particularly the GNU operating system, used widely in its GNU/Linux variant. 

Free software is a matter of the users' freedom to run, copy, distribute, study, change and improve the software. More precisely, it refers to four kinds of freedom, for the users of the software:

    * The freedom to run the program, for any purpose (freedom 0).
    * The freedom to study how the program works, and adapt it to your needs (freedom 1). Access to the source code is a precondition for this.
    * The freedom to redistribute copies so you can help your neighbor (freedom 2).
    * The freedom to improve the program, and release your improvements to the public, so that the whole community benefits (freedom 3). Access to the source code is a precondition for this.

The Free Software Foundation (FSF) is a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization based in Boston, MA, USA. We rely on support from individuals like you to carry out our worldwide mission to preserve, protect and promote the freedom to use, study, copy, modify, and redistribute computer software, and to defend the rights of all free software users.


All information gathered from the Free Software Foundation's website: www.fsf.org

1. Users should be free to run a program for any purpose

2. Users should be free to study how a program works, and adapt it to your needs

3. Users should have free access to a program's source code

4. Users should be free to improve the program, and release their improvements to the public, so that the whole community may benefit</description>
  <mission>To preserve, protect and promote the freedom to use, study, copy, modify, and redistribute computer software, and to defend the rights of all free software users</mission>
  <name>Free Software Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2768</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9495</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">307.28</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Pj/iR/ZK/3y/pi/6T/7u/lDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
