<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>College Students are citizens too!

At almost every university in the United States, the right of citizens other than law-enforcement officers to carry and possess firearms has been abridged - apparently, constitutional rights do not apply to college students. The intent of these laws is more than likely benevolent, and ostensibly they are designed to reduce the potential for violent crime.

However, it is nearly impossible to enforce these laws, especially at large universities - unlike in other zones where firearms are prohibited for safety, such as airports. So, in effect, the only people whom these laws affect are law-abiding citizens. Psychotic killers like Seung-Hui Cho clearly have no qualms about carrying firearms onto college campuses. 

College students who possess valid concealed carry licenses and who carry concealed weapons for self-defense should be able to do so on college campuses. Maybe the Virginia Tech massacre would not have been so deadly had a responsible citizen been carrying a firearm to defend him- or herself.

Urge the administrators at your campus and your state legislatures to allow responsible citizens to carry concealed weapons on college campuses. The old adage "when guns are outlawed, only outlaws will have guns" may be somewhat tacky, but it is as true today as ever.

1. People have an inherent right to bear arms.

2. College students who possess valid concealed weapons licenses should be able to exercise their right to carry concealed weapons on campus

3. Where guns are outlawed, only outlaws have guns.</description>
  <mission>Promote the extension of 2nd Amendment rights to College Students, Staff and Faculty nationwide</mission>
  <name>Support Concealed Carry Rights on College Campuses</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2773</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4528</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">200.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Dq/zp/Ld/QC/KK/i1/LUTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
