<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Formerly known as Hands On Ogeechee, HandsOn Southeast Georgia (SEGA) will coordinate activities for Global Youth Service Day with young people from across the region to improve their communities and recruit students to participate in the 21st Century Leaders program of the Georgia Business Forum in local high schools. The purpose of 21st Century Leaders is to increase the number, skills, and diversity of Georgia's future leaders.

For more information, visit:&lt;br&gt;
&#8226; http://www.handsonsega.org
&#8226; http://www.21stcenturyleaders.org

HandsOn Southeast Georgia began as an affiliate of HandsOn Georgia, a growing network of more than 15 affiliates changing communities in the state. HandsOn Georgia affiliates create and manage hundreds of projects each year, from building wheelchair ramps in Thomas County to teaching reading in Dalton, to rebuilding homes and lives in the coastal communities of Savannah.  We are part of a broader community of civic engagement worldwide.

HandsOn SEGA serves as a regional volunteer &amp; civic action center for rural, Southeast Georgia.  As part of a civic movement led by HandsOn Network generated by the Points of Light Institute, we are here to inspire, equip and mobilize people to take action that changes the world.

Based in Statesboro, Georgia, we connect volunteers to the causes they believe in and put people in touch with their potential to be the change and make a difference.  We also serve as a nonprofit resource center for our many community partners.

HandsOn Southeast Georgia will serve as a premiere hub for volunteer activity and
community building in Southeast Georgia. With our volunteer members and community partners, we will help people to be the change they want to see in their communities.

1. - Providing a Starting Point

2. - Equipping Citizen Leaders

3. - Structuring a Meaningful Experience

4. - Joining Together to Make a Difference

5. - A Pathway to Greater Participation</description>
  <mission>HandsOn Southeast Georgia brings people together to strengthen communities through meaningful volunteer action. We are here to inspire, equip &amp; mobilize people to take action that changes the world.</mission>
  <name>HandsOn Ogeechee &amp; 21CL Youth Action Centers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2778</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Dz/wt/dh/PM/AG/lg/XT/GsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
