<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>	
In 2000, 189 Heads of States met under the UN to discuss an urgent plan to help put an end to extreme poverty, and they came up with just the plan. They calculated that if all industrialized nations donated just .7% of their GDP by 2015 we will be able to eliminate extreme poverty.

All nations agreed to this, but only a few (Denmark, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, Norway and Sweden) have actually fulfilled their promise. They are certain a model for the rest of our countires regarding the UN promise.

The other countries are not pulling their weight and helping the world. Some countries are denying their agreement and others are avoiding the situation all together.


Please help spread the word and create awareness!


WHAT YOU CAN DO TO HELP:
According to Jefrey Saches

1. Become aware
2. Make a donation
3. Engage Others
4. Write to a congressman, or other political officials
5. Make this part of what our country stands for



Now that you have fulfilled #1, fulfill #2 and donate a bednet (JUST $10) and you will help SAVE 2 LIVES by giving them 5 MORE YEARS TO LIVE !!

If you make a donation please post on the wall with the country you stand for in the message. That way we can actually see the monetary difference we are making!
here is the link to donate:

www.millenniumpromise.org

PLEASE INVITE YOUR FRIENDS AND SPREAD THE WORD!!!

1. Become aware

2. Make a donation

3. Engage Others

4. Write to a congressman, or other political officials

5. Make this part of what your country stands for

6. Now that you have fulfilled #1, fulfill #2 and donate a bednet (JUST $10) and you will help SAVE 2 LIVES by giving them 5 MORE YEARS TO LIVE !!</description>
  <mission>Spread awareness of the UN Millenium promises and each do our part to help our world move forward together</mission>
  <name>UN Millennium Promise: I care about resolving extreme poverty &amp; u should 2</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2780</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">311</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">535.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Zd/pm/Av/xc/C7/jU/sLhS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
