<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>-Funds, and provides education, training and technical support to shantytown-based and rural community-based organizations, carrying out development, humanitarian relief and human rights projects of their own design in Guatemala, El Salvador, Honduras, Chiapas &amp; Peru.

- Educates and advocates in the US &amp; Canada about global human rights and development issues, and about how North American citizens, communities and organizations can get involved and work on these issues.

Rights Action is a multi-faceted community development, environmental and human rights organization with its main office in Guatemala City. In both Canada and the United States, Rights Action has tax-charitable status. (formerly known as Guatemala Partners).

www.rightsaction.org

watch video Canadian Mining Company Violent Evictions at El Estor, Guatemala January 8, 2007

www.youtube.com/v/Q20YxkM-CGI

Program areas, in Chiapas, Guatemala, Honduras, Peru, El Salvador, supported by Rights Action:

- Women's Economic Growth, Justice and Rights
- Integral Community Development
- Economic and Social Rights
- Cultural Rights and Indigenous Empowerment
- Political and Civil Rights and Justice
- Land and Environment
- Disaster and Emergency relief

1. provides funds directly to over 50 grassroots development, environmental and human rights organizations and projects.

2. provides technical support, popular education and organizational strengthening training to these grassroots organizations.

3. builds alliances for global justice between community-based organizations, both regionally and north-south

4. provides human rights accompaniment to persons at risk of repression for their environment, development and human rights work

5. does education &amp; activist work in the US &amp; Canada about global human rights, environmental and development issues, and about how citizens and organizations can get involved and work on these issues</description>
  <mission>education and activism work with North Americans to help form north-south alliances to address and remedy global exploitation, repression, environmental destruction and racism.</mission>
  <name>Rights Action</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2782</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">104</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Uc/dJ/D2/jc/de/sW/JLnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
