<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Pave the Way Foundation is an umbrella foundation of the National Heritage Foundation. It is in an initiative of Lambda Theta Alpha's Alumnae Association and is a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization. 

Pave the Way Foundation Donation Page: 
https://www.registrationfactory.com/v3/?EventUUID=EB1EF0D5

Sponsorship levels include:
&#8226; Burgundy and Gray - $500 or more
&#8226; Platinum - $250 - $499 
&#8226; Gold - $100 - $249 
&#8226; Silver - $50 - $99 
&#8226; Bronze - $50 or less 

----------------------------------------------
SCHOLARSHIP INITIATIVES
1. Undergraduate Scholarship
2. Graduate Scholarship
3. Alyssa Estevez Scholarship Fund
4. Study-Abroad Scholarship

As the Pave the Way Foundation continues to grow and build partnerships we hope to increase the amount of each scholarship as well as give out more academic awards.

----------------------------------------------
GRANT PROGRAMS
The Pave the Way Foundation awards grants to Lambda Theta Alpha constituencies, in order to promote activities in the areas of community service, leadership development, and academic advancement. Preference is given to programs that are unique Lambda Theta Alpha initiatives, such as start up funds for F.U.T.U.R.O. programs.

Lambda Theta Alpha Undergraduate chapters, Alumnae/Graduate chapters, and Area Boards interested in applying for grants should download the application on SHELL: 
Downloads Home &#187; Alumnae/Graduate Documents &#187;  Pave the Way Foundation

For more information, contact the Alumnae Association Board at alumassoc@lambdalady.org

1. To support philanthropy, education and civic engagement.

2. To promote activities in the areas of community service, leadership development and academic advancement.

3. An opportunity at education is key to the Universal Woman.</description>
  <mission>To support the philanthropic endeavors and civil engagement of our community and the members of Lambda Theta Alpha Latin Sorority, Inc.</mission>
  <name>Pave the Way Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2793</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1311</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">95.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oS/hK/sr/GN/3o/c3/z7HS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
