<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>As the wise man Ice Cube once said, Pimpin' ain't easy but its necessary, so I chase bitches like Tom chases Jerry. The art and style of being a pimp has been handed down from generation to generation. Grandfather pimps have passed down their wisdom from their years in dealing with the hoe's and the johns. 

The secret to success is to look the part and being a pimp is no different. You have to have the pants, the hat, the cane and enough bling to blind your enemys as they try to shoot at you. A great website has come about which offers a one stop shop for wanna be pimps. At Pimp Hats you can supply all your pimping needs. They have Hats, Pimp Suits, Canes, Bling of all kinds and All kinds of Pimp Shoes. It is important to have the proper threads, everyone wants to be respected by their peers, and nothing would be worse than having your fellow pimps look down on you. When you get dressed in the morning you have to look like it was born on ya! It has to look like you got up that morning and slapped the nanny, told her to go get ya kids up. 

Note: It is important to be sure that you get a good and solid pimp cane. Circumstances will inevitably arise where you will have to smack one of your hoes or john's and you don't want to suffer the embarrassment of having a broken cane.

Remember the golden rule, spare the cane, spoil the child. This rule is no different when it comes to keeping your bitches in line. If they think you are soft or not willing to really let them have it, they will become disobedient and hard to manage. However, keep in mind that you have to walk a fine line. If you are too rough, a ho will either be taken from the streets, or may buck the too-harsh treatment. Some pimps never need to lay a hand on their ho's: such is the power of their game. 

1. The right threads

2. Get a Gun

3. Take over another Pimps territory

4. Get yo'self some bitches

5. Charm yo Ho's

6. Have fun and keep yo Pimp Hand cocked!</description>
  <mission>Keep the tradition alive for all the playas, ballas and hos!</mission>
  <name>Support Pimpin</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2811</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">245</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8v/Ls/So/JB/i6/dS/ItqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
