<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Information literacy includes:

Traditional literacy.

Tool literacy, or the ability to understand and use the practical and conceptual tools of current information technology relevant to education and in professional life.

Resource literacy, or the ability to understand the form, format, location and access methods of information resources, especially daily expanding networked information resources.

Social-structural literacy, or knowing that and how information is socially situated and produced.

Research literacy, or the ability to understand and use the IT-based tools relevant to the work of today's researcher and scholar.

Publishing literacy, or the ability to format and publish research and ideas electronically, in textual and multimedia forms. 

Emerging technology literacy, or the ability to ongoingly adapt to, understand, evaluate and make use of the continually emerging innovations in information technology. 

Critical literacy, or the ability to evaluate critically the intellectual, human and social strengths and weaknesses, potentials and limits, benefits and costs of information technologies.

Media literacy or the process of accessing, analyzing, evaluating and creating messages in a wide variety of forms by using an inquiry-based instructional model that encourages people to ask questions about what they watch, see and read. It provides tools to help people critically analyze messages to detect propaganda, censorship, and bias in news and public affairs programming (and the reasons for such), and to understand how structural features such as media ownership, or its funding model affect the information presented. 

Visual literacy is the set of skills involved in the interpretation and criticism of images. The concept of visual literacy is also the ability to create and use images to communicate. 

Cultural literacy is the ability to converse fluently in the idioms, allusions and informal content which constitutes a culture. 

1. COMPULSORY INFORMATION LITERACY EDUCATION IN ALL SCHOOLS FROM KINDER GARTEN TO 12TH GRADE

2. INFORMATION IS POWER, BUT INFORMATION LITERACY SETS YOU FREE

3. SELF-DEVELOPMENT OF SELF-DEFENSE ANALYTICAL TECHNIQUES TO COUNTER PROPAGANDA, PUBLICITY, BIASED INFORMATION, AND OTHER TYPES OF ILL MEDIA AND DEMAGOGY </description>
  <mission>COMPULSORY INFORMATION LITERACY EDUCATION IN ALL SCHOOLS FROM KINDER GARTEN TO 12TH GRADE</mission>
  <name>SUPPORTERS OF INFORMATION LITERACY EDUCATION</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2812</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">37</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Lj/Dq/dZ/ra/7S/VI/rNUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
