<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Too many people want to destroy Big Oil because now the companies that have had a few oil spills in the past are making record profits, and the activist groups which made themselves sworn enemies of oil corporations in the late '80s and '90s look too radical and reactionary now that their "opponents" are "winning".
But, not only will boycotting one company like ExxonMobil, Shell, Chevron, ConocoPhillips, Valero or BP not do anything to lower gas prices, it will simply create a panic in the oil and gas market.  Because of a limited supply at any time in the country, the absence of sales through one vendor means that Vendor A simply sells excess product to Vendor B, who is experiencing overwhelming demand as a result of the aggregate demand staying the same.
As far as emissions standards go, these companies only regulate their emissions as much as they are required to by government.  A fix to the global warming problem needs to be addressed in government chamber, not a corporate boardroom.  Furthermore, modernized oil companies like Exxon and Shell (only to some extent BP) are some of the most efficient and cleanest in the entire industry.  Contrary to common knowledge, most of the pollution and regulation violations comes from smaller oil corporations with less standardization and less to spend on containment.
Oil companies employ, directly and indirectly, millions of American workers and account for a large portion of our economic growth.  Since 82% of the world's energy comes from fossil fuels, they still play the most vital role in the development of global economic stability.
Also, since, for example, 75% of ExxonMobil's profits come from overseas, it is also clear that these corporations play an even greater role in developing the third world and sustaining US trade ability across the globe.
Supporting the growth of these companies would not only be the best thing for our economy, but also for growth in the future across the world.

1. Big Oil is not evil and not involved in some massive conspiracy.

2. The best way to solve oil addiction is to slowly turn to other energy sources.

3. The best way to lower gas prices is to deal with demand in China, India, Russia, etc.

4. Another good way would be to stop Hugo Chavez from nationalizing Venezuelan oil.

5. Another good way would be to stop foreign policy nightmares in Iraq, Iran, and the Middle East as a whole.

6. But not by boycotting oil companies, which will only hurt the economy.</description>
  <mission>Help the Economy Grow, Provide Jobs for Millions, Sustain the Energy Market</mission>
  <name>Support the Oil Market</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2821</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">25</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jL/ke/X2/q6/nQ/Zm/kXoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
