<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Brian Deneke was killed in a shopping center parking lot on December 12, 1997. He was a victim of something called a hate crime. Yeah ever heard of one of those? Yeah?  He was killed because he was punk.

Here we go, on Friday, December 12,1997 a fight broke out between high school rivalries. Like, football players (a.k.a whitehats or jocks) and punk kids. Brian was being taunted by, 17 year old Junior varsity football player, Dustin Camp and his little jock buddys. When Brian's friends saw all the action that was going on, the came towards the brawl. They saw Brian in a fetal position as the the jocks crawled around him, kicking and punching and hitting him as if he weren't already beatin enough. Dustin was in his car at that time, he slammed on the gas , hit one punk, then took a u-turn and ran over Deneke. ON purpose by the way. Then Dustin's friends got into his car and drove them and himselve home. Brian layed there with his friends hand in his as he died. Early the next morning Dustin Camp was arrested and was counted for murder. and....went to jail. DUH.

Dustin Camp killed Brian Deneke for the sole purpose of Brian being punk. There was no reason for Brian Deneke to be killed. Its a sin to kill a mocking bird as Atticus Finch says. Meaning, if something ususal or just "normal" didn't harm you in anyway, there is no reason for that person, or any living creature to die. 

This cause is to stop discrimination towards people with different perspectives and beliefs, people who are gay, people who are a different race or color and people whose appearal are different than others.

1. Don't discriminate others of being different or who have different perspectives on life and/or beliefs as well.

2. I'm sick of the discrimination towards gays and other races. and people of different color. stop this shit NOW!</description>
  <mission>Support what IS right.</mission>
  <name>End Hatred and Discrimination</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2825</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">124</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.03</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yP/D7/CP/ip/r0/fA/VGyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
