<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For the record, it forced me to chose a non-profit, and MLA was unavailable, so please don't donate.. I'm looking for awareness, not money.


Recent laws have forced Maine Lobstermen to add break away swivels to their bouys, which makes it easier to lose gear due to a sailboat, inclement weather, and other natural and man made events, of which the entanglement of a whale and/or other aquatic life is the LEAST likely.

They have also called for the use of 100% sinking rope, which makes it easier to chafe and part off due to the jagged, rocky bottom of Central and Northern Maine waters.  In addition, it also creates a lot more tension on the rope, making it more difficult and a potential hazard to the backs and arms of the fishermen who have less slack to work with when trying to haul the gear aboard their boats.

In addition to this information, lets not forget the big headline grabbing news item from a few years ago.  The US Navy usage of SONAR caused several hundred whales to die due to beaching.  Noone is telling the Navy they are no longer allowed to use equiptment vital to their mission.  I'm not going to lead a crusade against them either.  I'm simply saying that if they are allowed to continue to do their job with the safest and most efficient equiptment, so should we.

And then their are cargo ships and oil tankers.  They are on a tight timetable, and have to time their deliveries to meet the rise and fall of tides.  If they attempt to "avoid" a whale, this alters their timetables and causes them to lose time and money.  Any oil company or shipping company that claims to be taking extra precautions to avoid whale migration zones is only telling a half truth.  They may re-route the initial plotted course, but if they encounter whales along the way, I find it very hard to believe that they will ruin their own bottom line to evade the whales in their way.

1. A Right Whale is a Right Whale, whether it lives off the coast of Maine or the coast of California.

2. The livelihood of one of our fishery and our way of life far outweighs the importance of one species of marine mammal.

3. Oil Tankers, Freighters and Naval Vessels cause more Right Whale deaths than all fisheries COMBINED.</description>
  <mission>Prove that a Northern Right Whale is the same species as a Southern Right Whale and a Pacific Right Whale, and is therefore not an endangered species.</mission>
  <name>Stop Regional Classification of Endangered Species</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2829</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">32</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gO/rh/lJ/pj/0R/NH/MbJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
