<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For more than two decades, Imam Jamil Abdullah Al-Amin has been one of the most respected leaders in the U.S.- a man whose prominence transcends the Muslim community in America. From his years of involvement in the struggle for change in America during the 60s and 70s as H &#8220;Rap&#8221; Brown - first with the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), and later with the Black Panther Party for Self-Defense - to his embrace of Islam and transition to Jamil Abdullah Al-Amin in 1976, he has been committed to the struggle for justice and the liberation of the oppressed.
  Al-Amin was convicted of murdering Deputy Ricky Kinchen and wounding Deputy Aldranon English in March 2000. They were shot while trying to serve a traffic warrant to Al-Amin at his store. Three days later, the Imam was taken into custody, where he was held for almost two years before the trial.


Some inconsistencies of the case include:

Both officers described their assailant as 5-foot-8-inches, with gray eyes. Al-Amin is 6-feet-5-inches with brown eyes.

A man fitting the description of the shooter confessed, but the confession was thrown out.

The officers said that they shot the killer. When Al-Amin was found, he had no recent bullet wound.
   


http://www.alkalima.com/?page=Archives&amp;vol=8&amp;issue=2&amp;id=106

http://www.wsws.org/articles/2002/mar2002/amin-m20.shtml


To write to Imam Jamil Al-Amim, address your letters to:

Jamil Abdullah Al-Amin
Reg. No. 99974-555
Florence ADMAX USP
P.O. Box 8500
Florence, CO 81226


1. Free Imam Jamil Al-Amin</description>
  <mission>Free Imam Jamil Al-Amin</mission>
  <name>Free Imam Jamil Al-Amin</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2831</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">766</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/17/zS/01/NC/oa/8x/DtTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
