<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>My Aunt and Uncle started a fantastic program in Guatemala which helps poor, mostly indigenous families who live in poverty. They are missionaries and they present a Christian viewpoint to the children and adults of these communties. No one is excluded based on their decision to accept or not accept the message, but this organization does believe that God has a powerful ability to help those in need. With increased donations they can help more children afford school and increase the size of their feeding program. The following is an excerpt from their website: &lt;br&gt;

Guatemala, with 12 million people, has the highest rate of malnourished children in the Western Hemisphere and ranks sixth in the world for chronic malnutrition, according to UNICEF. The economy is expected to grow after Guatemala's recent integration into the Central American Free Trade Agreement but most indigenous people still have little access to health care and education. Hearts for Heaven uses its funds to run feeding programs in several squatter settlements, help provide some basic healthcare and pay school expenses and run programs for kids and adults. Despite the saddened condition of the country, Guatemala is experiencing an underlying current of hope through a great movement of God.  An incredible need for discipling, teaching, and raising up of leadership exists.  Hearts for Heaven is making only a small differance in the overall condition of the country but we pray that the children that are being fed the Word of God and given the oppurtunity of education will make a difference in their part of the world in the future. 
&lt;br&gt;
You can also donate or check out more about the organization at: &lt;br&gt;
www.heartsforheaven.com

1. All children deserve the education and information to decide for themselves how to achieve their goals in life

2. Even helping a few children can lead to a brighter future for an entire country

3. Feeding the soul is as important as feeding the body</description>
  <mission>Help the children who live in squatter settlements in Guatemala through feeding programs and other mission work</mission>
  <name>Hearts for Heaven - Guatemala</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2834</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">147</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">75.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/NU/Mr/E6/Wt/82/vE/rAxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
