<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> In 1970 citizens stood on the lakeshore and issued a powerful proclamation: "We don't have to wait for governments or anyone else to protect Lake Michigan. We can take steps together to restore the lake we love." Thus, the original Lake Michigan Federation was formed.

Thirty-five years later, in 2005, the organization crossed another threshold. Seeing that decisions made by elected officials in other parts of the Great Lakes basin affected Lake Michigan, and vice versa, the organization changed its name to the Alliance for the Great Lakes.

The Alliance is picking up where the Federation left off, continuing to work on basin-wide policies, working in partnership with other organizations, and mobilizing local efforts on behalf of the Great Lakes. The Federation, meanwhile, remains a project of the Alliance, focusing on issues of particular concern to the largest lake within U.S. borders.

The Alliance works to conserve and restore the world's largest freshwater resource through policy, education and local efforts aimed at preserving the Great Lakes region as a national treasure. It also works with the region's residents, enhancing their understanding of how they can help, too. To that end, we draw on many resources, working with teachers, scientists, economists, legal specialists, government representatives, communities and individuals. And, year-by-year, individual-by-individual, we're getting back a healthy Great Lakes environment, thanks to supporters like you. 

1. Conserve the world's largest freshwater bodies.

2. Restore the Great Lakes.

3. Educate and enhance understanding to preserve these regions.</description>
  <mission>conserve and restore the world's largest freshwater resource using policy, education and local efforts, ensuring a healthy Great Lakes and clean water for generations of people and wildlife.</mission>
  <name>Alliance For The Great Lakes</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2835</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">815</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">180.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5K/qQ/17/xr/fP/lt/nTqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
