<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Please join and invite other people to help spread the awareness of these two diseases and help to find a cure in the near future.  All donations go to the Leukemia and Lymphoma Society to help find a cure.  Treatment nowadays can only put a person into remission.

Lymphoma is a cancer of the lymphatic system in which functionless or defective cells are produced at an alarming rate; lymphomas are classified as either Hodgkin's or non-Hodgkin's and affect both adults and children (www.leukemialymphomatreatmentfyi.com/cancer_glossary.html)

Leukemia is a cancer of developing blood cells in the bone marrow.
(www.knowledgene.com/public/glossary_content.php3)

It is anticipated that approximately 22,280 deaths in the United States will be attributed to leukemia in 2006 (12,470 males and 9,810 females). 

Join and invite all of your friends to join this cause.  Let's band together to push scientists to find a cure for these horrible diseases!  Don't forget to donate if you want to help speed things up!

For all of you who do not know Boone:  Boone was in his first semester at UVA in the FALL of 2005 when he went to the doctor and found out he had leukemia.  He fought the battle against leukemia for a year and a half and went through chemotherapy and had a white blood cell transfusion.  His condition started improving, however he did not get many more white blood cells from the transfusion.  So, the doctors decided they had to do another transfusion.  The same day he was to have the transfusion, Boone got a brain hemorrhage and lost his battle with leukemia on September 22, 2006.  This is who this group is honoring.  

There is no cure for this disease, but scientists are trying to find one.  Please donate a buck or two if you can!  $5.00 is not much and can do a lot to finding a cure for this deadly disease!  Thanks for donating and joining this cause!

1. To spread awareness of Leukemia and Lymphoma

2. To share this news to all of Facebook

3. To help fund the Leukemia and Lymphoma Society to help find a cure for these diseases</description>
  <mission>raise money to help support the Leukemia and Lymphoma Society to find a cure for these life-threatening diseases!</mission>
  <name>Let's find a cure for Leukemia and Lymphoma in honor of XBC IV (Boone)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2848</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">724</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">170.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4w/sS/kf/4P/77/mS/2a/qGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
