<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There is no known cure for ataxia. Ataxia is a progressive, degenerative disease which means with time, the persons condition can be expected to worsen.

Treatments are generally limited to softening symptoms, not the disease itself. The condition can be irreversible. A person with this disease will usually end up needing to use a wheelchair, and eventually they may need assistance to perform daily tasks.

The treatment of incoordination or ataxia, then mostly involves the use of adaptive devices to allow the ataxia individual to maintain as much independence as possible. Such devices may include a cane, crutches, walker, or wheelchair for those with impaired gait; devices to assist with writing, feeding, and self cares if hand and arm coordination is impaired; and communication devices for those with impaired speech.

Many patients with hereditary or idiopathic forms of ataxia have other symptoms in addition to ataxia. Medications or other therapies might be appropriate for some of these symptoms, which could include tremor, stiffness, depression, spasticity, and sleep disorders, among others.

Both onset of initial symptoms and duration of disease can be subject to variation. If the disease is caused by a polyglutamine trinucleotide repeat CAG expansion, a longer expansion may lead to an earlier onset and a more radical progression of clinical symptoms.


We need to help these people and find a cure. DONATE!

1. There has been no cure for this disease after many, many years.

2. Many people have been dying and suffering from this disease.</description>
  <mission>find a cure for spirocerebral atrophy</mission>
  <name>Cure for Spinocerebral Atrophy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2854</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">76</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/a4/Ve/na/Ip/Vx/q0/Qq6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
