<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&#8220;Their eyes hold a story that is indecipherable and yet intuitively we relate to them. Just one look into those eyes and you are hooked.&#8221;

Orangutans are highly intelligent with an ability to reason and think. This large, gentle red ape is one of our closest relatives, sharing 98% of the same DNA as humans. Indigenous peoples of Indonesia and Malaysia call this ape &#8220;Orang Hutan&#8221; literally translating into English as &#8220;People of the Forest&#8221;.

Orangutans once lived all the way from southern China to the foothills of the Himalayas and south to the island of Java, Indonesia. Today, the red 'man of the forest' is confined to the rapidly dwindling forests of just two islands, Sumatra and Borneo.

Tragically, they share a preference with humans for fertile alluvial plains and lowland valleys - a habitat once rich in tropical forests but now disappearing fast due to logging and agricultural schemes such as rice cultivation and palm oil plantations.

Just 100 years ago there were probably more than 230,000 orangutans in Borneo and Sumatra. In the last ten years alone their numbers have declined by 30-50%, and now just over 50,000 survive. If efforts to protect orangutans are not urgently strengthened, Asia&#8217;s only great ape may be lost from the wild forever within a few YEARS.

Orangutans are 'flagship' species for the conservation of the tropical forests of Sumatra and Borneo. Because they require large areas of good quality habitat, ensuring their conservation in the wild means that the myriad of other species that share the ecosystem - including proboscis monkeys, Asian elephant, Sumatran rhinoceros, Sumatran tigers, clouded leopard, Malayan sun bear, and Malay tapirs - will be protected.

For more information visit:  http://redapes.org




1. Time is running out, so we must act quickly.

2. Boycott palm oil and other products that are a large factor in orangutan habitat deforestation.

3. Do your part by caring and educating others.</description>
  <mission>Stop the deforestation of orangutan habitat in Borneo and Sumatra in order to prevent their extinction.</mission>
  <name>SAVE THE ORANGUTANS!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2868</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26685</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2347.41</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rr/Ay/H8/6I/Q3/g3/KX7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
