<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is nail biting?
Nail biting is the habit of biting one's fingernails or toenails during periods of nervousness, stress, hunger, or boredom. It can also be a sign of mental or emotional disorder. The clinical name for nail biting is chronic onychophagia. 

It occurs in:
28% to 33% of children ages 7-10 years old, 
44% of adolescents, 
19% to 29% of young adults and 
5% of older adults 
(It is more common in young males)


Well okay, what is so bad about nail biting?
Biting the nails can result in the transportation of germs that are buried under the surface of the nail into the mouth. In fact, nail salons use tools that potentially affect a human in a similar way. "If [nail tools, such as files] are used on different people, these tools may spread nail fungi, staph bacteria or viruses," warns Rick Lopes, a spokesperson for the California Board of Barbering and Cosmetology. Many pathogens have the ability to "live" under a nail.
Nail biting may result in the chewing of surrounding skin and cuticle. Broken skin is susceptible to microbial and viral infections. These pathogens can be spread between digits via the mouth. A normal, healthy person has a very low risk of suffering from infections.
A long-time habit of nailbiting may have detrimental effects on the substantia adamantinea of the front teeth, promoting caries in these areas.
Extreme nailbiting can be considered to be a form of masochistic self-mutilation. Bitten fingertips can become very sensitive to pain, usually at the place the skin meets the edge of the nail. If the nail surrounds have been damaged, salty foods, (such as potato chips and pickles), can get between the skin and nail and cause pain and hypersensitivity.
Nail biting is, according to Freudian theory, a symptom of oral fixation.



So yeah, you can't really help this. It's pretty much a lost cause. 

1. To educate the youth on the effects of nail biting</description>
  <mission>End nail biting</mission>
  <name>Nail Biting</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2871</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fg/Lu/eQ/TH/8N/xj/AllS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
