<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I have always thought about running a half marathon or completing a triathlon, but I have never had the time to train for either of them. I was running errands around Lincoln during the Lincoln Marathon, I saw some Team in Training runners running the marathon with their purple jerseys. People cheering the runners along the way were really cool to see and purple TNT jerseys stuck out among the group. They were running for a purpose.  After seeing the TNT runners, I decided that I should put running and improving the quality of life for others together and race for a cure. Currently, I am training for the Omaha Half Marathon that is September 23rd. My two goals I have set for myself is to fundraise $3,000 for the society and cross the finish line in honor of the many people who have been touched in one way or another by leukemia and lymphoma.The Team in Training program is part of the Leukemia and Lymphoma Society, the organization is searching for cures for blood-related cancers (leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin&#8217;s disease, and a cancer of the plasma cell called myeloma.) About 53,920 people will die of leukemia, lymphoma, or myeloma this year.  The funds raised through the TNT program are used for cancer research and patient services.   Seventy-five percent of the money that is raised is directly used to fund research, patient and community service, and public and professional education. How can you help? Please donate to the Leukemia and Lymphoma Society today, at my website 

http://www.active.com/donate/tntne/tntneEAnders

 Seventy-Five cents out of every dollar is used directly for cancer research and patient services. All donations are supporting a great cause. I have enclosed an envelope for donations, words of encouragement, and honored teammates you would like me to run in honor of as well. I am truly inspired and motivated to give my time and energy to such a wonderful cause.





1. Improving your health as well as someone else's

2. One person can make a difference, if it is someone's life it is worth it</description>
  <mission>Race for a Cure</mission>
  <name>Lymphoma and Leukemia's Team in Training</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2876</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xy/6h/2S/TX/Ey/DH/1wlS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
