<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Who can keep up these days? All of our skinny dark-tan models and celebrities with their sooty black eyelashes and digitally enhanced features and perfected noses, their plastic surgeries and personal fitness trainers...


WHO DECIDES WHAT IS BEAUTIFUL? 
well, we do! And so, this is a "beauty revolution", if you will..........

and so, my final "question" is this:
-tanning booths.
-plastic surgery.
-excessive makeup.
-tireless workouts at a gym you hate.
-competing with every woman you see on the street.
Why?


FAKE IS OUT.
let your inner beauty shine through your bare skin.

-stop killing yourself with skin cancer and soaking in excessive sun (or heat lamps, rather) why does it matter if your skin is a little pale in the winter? pale is delicate, pale is pretty :)

-your hair color at age sixteen is the most beautiful, natural looking color you'll ever have in your life- stop highlighting and frying it!!!!

-Wrinkles are a sign of aging. Yes, that is true.
Why are we trying to fight aging? It's beautiful, it's natural, it's the way things are meant to be. The same goes for graying hair. Don't work to cover it up- make a show of it! 87% of women believe they are too young to be old. Let's keep raising that number.

-Freckles are sunkisses. Who doesn't want freckles? If you have them- don't cake makeup over them. Everyone is jealous.


...I am by no means calling you "fake" if you were makeup. (I do!) I simply want to see a change in the REASON you wear it. Don't let it be because you're covering up something you don't like about yourself.

1. Beauty is in the eyes of the beholder.

2. Be comfortable, be you!</description>
  <mission>urge you to create your own definition of beauty.</mission>
  <name>Natural is Beautiful</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2884</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3331</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/f4/ht/8x/iY/TX/w4/nTzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
