<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In memory of the Holocaust and every international tragedy in the history of humanity, we must not forget that it happened. We must not force the horror from our minds. We must not let it happen again.



Let's allow Elie Wiesel to guide us as he says:

"If we forget, we are guilty, we are accomplices.

Neutrality helps the oppressor, never the victim. Silence encourages the tormentor, never the tormented. Sometimes we must interfere. When human lives are endangered, when human dignity is in jeopardy, national borders and sensitivities become irrelevant. Wherever men and women are persecuted because of their race, religion, or political views, that place must - at that moment - become the center of the universe. 

There is so much injustice and suffering crying out for our attention: victims of hunger, of racism and political persecution - in Chile, for instance, or in Ethiopia - writers and poets, prisoners in so many lands governed by the Left and by the Right.

Human rights are being violated on every continent. More people are oppressed than free. How can one not be sensitive to their plight? Human suffering anywhere concerns men and women everywhere. 
As long as one dissident is in prison, our freedom will not be true. As long as one child is hungry, our life will be filled with anguish and shame. What all these victims need above all is to know that they are not alone; that we are not forgetting them, that when their voices are stifled we shall lend them ours, that while their freedom depends on ours, the quality of our freedom depends on theirs.

Our lives no longer belong to us alone; they belong to all those who need us desperately."

1. Never forget.

2. Raise awareness.</description>
  <mission>prevent history from repeating itself.</mission>
  <name>Never Forget.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2890</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DX/JL/v8/YE/xo/2k/OwFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
