<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Every year, three million girls and women are targeted for genital cutting. An estimated 130 million girls and women have undergone the procedure, and as a result, have suffered serious life-threatening injuries. The scale of practice is extremely large. Female Genital Mutilation occurs in over 28 countries in Africa, parts of the Middle East and Asia, and recently, in the United States and Europe. In the past two decades, FGM has attracted much attention in the international and national policy areas. We as a global society that does not tolerate the procedure of FGM need to fight alongside these brave young girls. We need to inform, enforce, and demand that these girls be saved and can only do that through the support of the international community.

The child, completely naked, is made to sit on a low stool. Several women take hold of her and open her legs wide. After separating her outer and inner lips, the operator, usually a woman experienced in this procedure, sits down facing the child. With her kitchen knife the operator first pierces and slices open the hood of the clitoris. Then she begins to cut it out. While another woman wipes off the blood with a rag, the operator digs with her sharp fingernail a hole the length of the clitoris to detach and pull out the organ. The little girl, held down by the women helpers, screams in extreme pain; but no one pays the slightest attention.The operator finishes this job by entirely pulling out the clitoris, cutting it to the bone with her knife. Her helpers again wipe off the spurting blood with a rag. The operator then removes the remaining flesh, digging with her finger to remove any remnant of the clitoris among the flowing blood. The neighbor women are then invited to plunge their fingers into the bloody hole to verify that every piece of the clitoris is removed."


1. FGM is against international human rights.

2. FGM must be recognized as a serious international concern.

3. FGM should be outlawed in all countries, including all states in the US.</description>
  <mission>help support the cause to end FGM, a global concern, that has affected more than 130 million women worldwide. </mission>
  <name>Female Genital Mutilation: Support the Cause to End Violence Against Women</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2891</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">90884</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3255.9</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Cl/O2/no/Th/dw/22/bEBS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
