<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The first amendment sates: &#8220;Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the exercise thereof.&#8221; 

&#8220;If people are saying that most Americans are Christians, they might have a point; but those who argue that America is a Christian nation usually mean something more.&#8221;

In a U.S. treaty with Tripoli, we are quoted with the words, &#8220;the government of the United States is not, in any sense, founded on the Christian religion&#8230;&#8221; 

The Founding Fathers of this country did not create a secular government because they disliked religion. The separation of church and state does not deny or even oppose religion; it merely aims to separate it from politics.

Thomas Paine makes it even clearer when he wrote: &#8220;I do not believe in the creed professed by the Jewish Church, but the Roman Church, by the Greek Church, by the Turkish Church, by the Protestant Church, nor by any church that I know of. My own mind is my own church.&#8221; 
Through even that simple statement, we must learn that everyone&#8217;s sentiments are alike in regards to religion. Every person believes their own religion to be right. It may come as a surprise that the motto &#8220;In God We Trust&#8221; was not a currency requirement until 1957, nearly two centuries after the birth of our nation. Also, &#8220;under god&#8221; stated in the Pledge of Allegiance was added onto the original verse.

Although the more commonly interpreted meaning of the separation of church and state is freedom of religion, it also implies a freedom FROM religion.

1. restrict governmental interference with relgion

2. restrict relgious interference with government</description>
  <mission>abide by the First Amendment</mission>
  <name>Separate means separate.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2892</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">62</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Sw/ZJ/Af/LB/Nv/LR/CGjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
