<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Foundation is the not-for-profit corporation dedicated to building, programming and operating the Memorial and Museum at the World Trade Center site.  It has been over five years since we witnessed the extremes of human nature: unspeakable hatred reflected in the attacks of September 11th, 2001 and inspiring compassion as this country and the world came together in support of each other.  While each individual has a different 9/11 experience, collectively these experiences require us to think back and move forward. This message is at the heart of our fundraising campaign to build the permanent World Trade Center Memorial.

We need your help to make the Memorial and Museum a reality.  We hope that everyone will share in our efforts because September 11th was an event which impacted us all and forever changed our world. It is our goal to create a mass public campaign with our supporters measured in the tens of thousands. By contributing to this campaign, you can help honor the lives lost, pay tribute to those who risked their lives, and stand in solidarity with those who demonstrated compassion at a time of grievous loss.   Please join us today by making a contribution to help build the Memorial.

Joseph Daniels
President &amp; CEO
World Trade Center Memorial Foundation

1. Remember and honor the thousands of innocent men, women, and children murdered by terrorists in the horrific attacks of February 26, 1993 and September 11, 2001.

2. Respect this place made sacred through tragic loss.

3. Recognize the endurance of those who survived, the courage of those who risked their lives to save others, and the compassion of all who supported us in our darkest hours.

4. May the lives remembered, the deeds recognized, and the spirit reawakened be eternal beacons, which reaffirm respect for life, strengthen our resolve to preserve freedom, and inspire an end to hatred, ignorance and intolerance.</description>
  <mission>Facilitate the building, programming and operating of the Memorial and Museum at the World Trade Center site.</mission>
  <name>World Trade Center Memorial Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2895</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">425</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tJ/7H/ue/BA/Ah/vY/KTMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
