<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Essentially, the OLPC would like to provide children around the world with a specially designed XO laptop which only costs $200 to manufacture (but will hopefully decrease to $100 in the future). The laptops will bring help to the education systems for countries in poverty.

The following is an exerpt from the foundation's website:

"Any nation's most precious natural resource is its children. We believe the emerging world must leverage this resource by tapping into the children's innate capacities to learn, share, and create on their own. Our answer to that challenge is the XO laptop, a children's machine designed for &#8220;learning learning.&#8221;

XO embodies the theories of constructionism first developed by MIT Media Lab Professor Seymour Papert in the 1960s, and later elaborated upon by Alan Kay, complemented by the principles articulated by Nicholas Negroponte in his book, Being Digital.

Extensively field-tested and validated among some of the poorest and most remote populations on earth, constructionism emphasizes what Papert calls &#8220;learning learning&#8221; as the fundamental educational experience. A computer uniquely fosters learning learning by allowing children to &#8220;think about thinking&#8221;, in ways that are otherwise impossible. Using the XO as both their window on the world, as well as a highly programmable tool for exploring it, children in emerging nations will be opened to both illimitable knowledge and to their own creative and problem-solving potential.

OLPC is not, at heart, a technology program, nor is the XO a product in any conventional sense of the word. OLPC is a non-profit organization providing a means to an end&#8212;an end that sees children in even the most remote regions of the globe being given the opportunity to tap into their own potential, to be exposed to a whole world of ideas, and to contribute to a more productive and saner world community."


visit the website for more information:
http://www.laptop.org

1. Every child has the right to an education.

2. Education should not come at an unattainable price.</description>
  <mission>to provide children around the world with new opportunities to explore, experiment and express themselves.</mission>
  <name>One Laptop per Child (OLPC)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2899</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">45897</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">13908.04</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vv/0f/8C/nE/zG/mu/37rS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
