<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Independent filmaking has become increasingly popular over the past 100 years.
The roots of independent film can be traced back to when the early pioneer filmmakers in the 1900s who resisted the control of the a company called the Motion Picture Patents Company and the Edison trusts.
Independent films open our eyes to many causes.
Documentaries, horror films, etc. have a stronger effect if they are not created by billion dollar industries whose only interest is making more money.
They give a wider range of unique films.
Right now the most common way to see independent films is film festivals, which can cost up to $3000 per ticket. Most movie theatres and cinemas don't feel that the independent film industry has anything to offer.
Until the advent of digital alternatives, the cost of professional film equipment and stock was a major obstacle to independent filmmakers who wanted to make their own films. The cost of 35mm film is outpacing inflation: in 2002 alone, film negative costs were up 23%, according to Variety. Studio-quality filming typically required expensive lighting and post-production facilities. But the advent of consumer camcorders in 1985, and more importantly, the arrival of high-resolution digital video in the early 1990s, have since lowered the technology barrier to movie production considerably.
This group was also created to open the door to many other film festivals and movies that are NOT shown at the Sundance film festival, which is NOT the only independent film showcase.
In 2005, about 15% of the U.S. domestic box office revenue was from independent studios. Help keep that number growing by joining this cause and inviting everyone to join.

DONATIONS GO TO: Seattle International Film Festival (SIFF) Group and Independent Feature Project/Seattle (IFP/Seattle)

1. Increase awareness of independent films.

2. More funding is needed to keep the independent film industry alive.

3. Support the unique style of independent films.</description>
  <mission>To support the making and awareness of independent films.</mission>
  <name>Support Independent Films</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2924</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11556</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">60.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/v2/Xl/eH/L2/Xy/i1/xv0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
