<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In June of 2004, Victory Junction Gang Camp proudly opened its doors! The Camp was founded by Kyle and Pattie Petty, in honor of their son Adam. In 1999, after participating in a motorcycle ride to Camp Boggy Creek in Florida, the Petty family felt inspired to build a camp in North Carolina.  

Surrounded by beautiful hardwood forests, Victory Junction Gang Camp is located in the Piedmont Triad of North Carolina. The Camp was built on 72 acres that were generously donated by Richard and Lynda Petty. Victory Junction Gang Camp has a racing theme with the sights, sounds, look and feel of a race track! The Camp is comprised of 44 buildings, including the Goody's Body Shop medical center, the Hendrick Motorsports Fuel Stop dining hall, the Silver Theater, the Kyle Petty Charity Ride Across America water park, Adam's Race Shop, the Michael Waltrip Operation Marathon Sportscenter, Jessie's Horse Power Garage and much more!  

Victory Junction Gang Camp operates solely on the donations of wonderful corporations, organizations and individuals. Children that attend Victory Junction would not otherwise be able to attend a camp because of their medical needs.  

Victory Junction is a year-round camp that serves children, ages 7 to 15, with a variety of health issues. During the summer we offer week long disease specific sessions with up to 125 kids per session. During the Fall, Winter and Spring we offer family weekends with up to 32 families per weekend. 

The children we serve may have any of the following health issues: 
arthritis, asthma, cancer, epilepsy, hemophilia, immunology deficiencies/HIV, sickle cell disease, spina bifida, gastrointestinal disease, heart disease, kidney disease, liver disease, 
neurological disease, skin disease, burn survivors, cystic fibrosis, diabetes, autism, craniofacial anomalies, physical disabilities, kids on vents, transverse myelitis 

1. To enrich the lives of children with chronic medical conditions or serious illnesses. </description>
  <mission>Enrich the lives of children with chronic medical conditions or serious illnesses by providing life-changing camping experiences that are exciting, fun, and empowering, in a safe environment.</mission>
  <name>Victory Junction</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2927</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15575</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3760.84</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Sj/VL/fY/WX/Y4/JK/ZN/iIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
