<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>DO NOT DONATE MONEY!

Okay so people are all wearing shirts and arm bands and screaming and yelling "SAVE DARFUR OMG LOL!!!!!11!!!" And I'm kinda sick and tired of it honestly...I mean if they cared as much as they claim, then they would buy a rifle, buy a plane ticket, go to Darfur and protect the people there. Oh but they won't risk their lives, I guess they don't believe it that much do they? I mean it is horrible what is happening over there, I'm not a heartless prick. Tell me how many people would support a US intervention, or claim they would support sending the military over. Or how many people could tell me about the Armenian genocide? Why don't we get on the Turkish government for denying it happened? Its a fad to wear the Save Darfur apparel. Don't tell me about raising awareness either. If you wanted to raise awareness, why not print out a bunch of fliers and hand them out?

And another thing about Darfur...I would really love to know where all that money is going that people donate. To food? What the hell are they going to do with it? Try to eat it right before those people that are trying to kill them take it and eat. What on earth? I understand these people need things but I mean right now money can do precisely dick as long as they are being hunted down.

Then there are the global warming freaks. Who get in their cars, drive to some event or other about how global warming is destroying the earth. Then proceed to get back in their cars drive home and use an entire can of hairspray for that perfect hippie hair. Don't forget they use heat and air conditioning in their homes. That is the inconvenient truth. 

1. Canada's seal hunt must continue.

2. There must be a military intervention in Darfur.

3. Joining a cause shouldn't be trendy.</description>
  <mission>Make people shut the hell up.</mission>
  <name>The Anti-Cause Cause</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2928</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">82</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/y5/kc/5k/3l/bF/V6/1NoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
