<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The University of Iowa Dance Marathon is a student organization that provides year-round support to youth cancer victims and their families. &#8220;The Event&#8221; is a 24-hour Dance Marathon where students assemble to celebrate the children survivors and remember the children who have passed away throughout the year. Students plan and participate in Family Events, Mini-Dance Marathons, Miracle Games, car washes, silent auctions, and dinners. Additionally, they participate in other University of Iowa sponsored and affiliated activities and events, the majority of which are all philanthropic. 

     The primary goal of these activities is to raise additional money for children with cancer and to educate the community about the struggles and triumphs of these little warriors.

     The UI Dance Marathon is in association with Children's Miracle Network to help raise additional money for children with cancer. Children's Miracle Network is a non-profit organization dedicated to saving and improving the lives of children by raising funds for children's hospitals across North America.

  The University of Iowa Dance Marathon Main Event is a 24-hour dance marathon. All Dancers that have raised the required amount of money are invited to participate in &#8220;The Event.&#8221; All the Families sponsored by Dance Marathon participate in the event and many for the full 24 hours. 

     The Event requires that Dancers remain standing for the full 24 hours and no caffeine or watches are allowed. To pass the time, live entertainment is provided throughout the event; in addition to, a lively DJ. Live entertainment includes performances by local bands, University Bands, University Dance and Theatre Groups, Dance Marathon Family Speakers, and many more exciting acts. 

     In 2009, Dance Marathon raised an all-time high of $1,030,428.15!!! To date Dance Marathon has raised over 7.5 million dollars. Next year's big dance will take place on February 6, 2010. 


1. FTK! (For The Kids!)

2. When cancer is stopped we will dance for joy, until then we will DANCE4LIFE! 

3. Dance Marathon is 365 days that create hope, 24 hours to celebrate the fight, and one power hour that creates a miracle. </description>
  <mission>To create special projects to provide emotional and financial support to families treated by the University of Iowa Children's Hospital, with an emphasis on the Division of Oncology.</mission>
  <name>University of Iowa Dance Marathon</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2929</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1381</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">181.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fk/M3/RM/LP/2a/jn/E5/JpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
