<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The National Rifle Association, chartered in 1871, is not only the oldest sportsmen's organization in America, but also an educational, recreational and public service organization dedicated to the right of an individual citizen to own and use firearms for recreation and defense. 

Although the NRA has been traditionally an organization of marksmanship and education, it has become increasingly concerned about anti-gun legislation since the passage of the Sullivan Act in New York in 1911. Since this time, legislation placing restrictions on law-abiding citizens has become more and more prevalent in federal, state and local governments. Some of the major legislation that has passed since the Sullivan Act includes; the Firearms Act of 1934, the Gun Control Act of 1968 and more recently the Brady Bill and Crime Bill [which included a so-called Assault Weapon's Ban]. The firearms act of 1934 prompted the establishment of the Legislation Division. This division was created to combat anti-gun legislation and speak on behalf of law-abiding gun owners. The NRA Legislation division evolved into NRA's Institute for Legislative Action. Established in 1975, it has since been the fighting force, with the support of our 4 million members, for American firearm owners. 

Today, the NRA is striving to uphold the principles on which we were founded. The NRA has many programs and training courses directed towards firearm safety and education as well as competition and recreational shooting. The next few pages will outline the NRA's Purposes and Objectives and will overview the different aspects of the Association. 

The Purposes and Objectives of the National Rifle Association of America 

To protect and defend the Constitution of the United States, especially with reference to the inalienable right of the individual American citizen guaranteed such Constitution to acquire, possess, transport, carry, transfer ownership of and enjoy the right to use arms, in order that the people may always be in a position to exercise their legitimate individual rights of self-preservation and defense of family, person and property, as well as to serve effectively in the appropriate militia for the common defense of the Republic and the individual liberty of its citizens; 

To promote public safety, law and order and the national defense; 

To train members of law enforcement agencies, the armed forces, the militia and people of good repute in marksmanship and in the safe handling and efficient use of small arms; 

To foster and promote the shooting sports, including the advancement of amateur competitions in marksmanship at the local, state, regional, national and international levels; 

To promote hunter safety and to promote and defend hunting as a shooting sport and as a viable and necessary method of fostering the propagation, growth, conservation and wise use of our renewable wildlife resources. 


1. Ensuring the aforementioned right is not infringed upon </description>
  <mission>Defend and foster the Second Amendment Right to bear arms by all law-abiding citizens of these United States  </mission>
  <name>National Rifle Association</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/294</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">55647</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">956.33</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Nw/6C/NP/w8/45/JB/KP/4YS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
