<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Freedom Alliance Scholarship Fund honors the bravery and dedication exhibited by Americans in our Armed Forces who have sacrificed life or limb defending our country by providing educational scholarships to their children. In the last 20 years, over 15,000 service members have given their lives defending our country. More than 3,400 soldiers, sailors, airmen, Marines and Guardsmen have been killed in the war in Iraq, leaving behind approximately 2,000 children. 

Thousands more members of our Armed Forces have been permanently disabled, leaving their families in difficult financial situations. Their children &#8211; the sons and daughters of America&#8217;s military heroes &#8211; (many of whom are now young) will be eligible for a Freedom Alliance Scholarship in the years to come. 

Freedom Alliance has established a permanent Scholarship Trust Fund to aid the children of these brave Americans. In February 2007, Colorado Technical University pledged $1 million in full tuition scholarships for Freedom Alliance Scholarship recipients who wished to attend their university. 

Through the generosity of so many patriotic Americans, the Freedom Alliance Scholarship Fund will provide scholarships for thousands of young Americans, reminding them that their parents&#8217; sacrifice will never be forgotten by a grateful nation.
 

***NOTE***
The above has been reprinted from the Feedom Alliance Scholarship Fund website.
http://www.freedomalliance.org/fa/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=blogsection&amp;id=7&amp;Itemid=15
***End Note ***

1. Support of our US Military's Families.

2. Support of our US Military's Children.

3. Education for our US Military's Children.</description>
  <mission>Honors the bravery and dedication exhibited by Americans in our Armed Forces who have sacrificed life or limb defending our country by providing educational scholarships to their children.</mission>
  <name>The Freedom Alliance Scholarship Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2940</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">74</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">85.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xQ/NI/oN/C6/VS/jt/dsLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
