<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is not my child! This is about Kaleb Schwade, son of Kristy and Josh Schwade in Florida. This story moved me so I decided to make this cause on Facebook. 

***UPDATE from her blog ***
July 10th
He's having some troubles 

Well It is 6 days until the "planned" date for him to come home. 

Kaleb had a few problems in the last few days. They got him up to full feeds on the J tube and took him off of Reglin (this is a acid reflux med) and then he started to throw up again. So they did a gastric study and pored contrast into his G tube to watch exactly where it went in his digestive tract. The study showed that he immediately started to reflux pretty bad so they have determined that he will have to be on Reglin. They took him off of feeds yesterday and are slowly building it back up to full feeds. He is almost completely wheened off of the phenobarb. He has been moving more since they have been lowering the doses. They are still shooting for monday as far as him coming home, but because of the recent problems it may be pushed back to tues. or wed. He still isn't blinking at all. We think he can see something but we are unsure of what exactly. He is getting so long and so skinny. Before all of this happened he was a chunky boy.
____________________________________

Kristy Reynolds and her husband are parents to a baby boy named Kaleb. Kristy picked Kaleb up from home care and noticed something was wrong. She immediately took him to the hospital where he was diagnosed with Shaken Baby Syndrome. He now has meningitis in response the the surgeries on his brain, He is also blind. His sitter shook him so hard that he is in a coma, had to have spinal fluid drained from his brain.
Her myspace is: 
www.myspace.com/kristyreynolds  

For everyone that doesn't have a myspace or cafemom account and would like to check on his progress please go here...

www.babyhomepages.net/schwade 



1. Shaken Baby Syndrome Results

2. Help support this family!</description>
  <mission>Awareness about Shaken Baby Syndrome. Can you imagine a loved one at 6 months of age, blind and trying to survive because of the hands of a caregiver? Please support his little guy... he needs you.</mission>
  <name>Help Kaleb</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2953</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">19531</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">675.15</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bY/TZ/3Z/oK/WE/3f/NfAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
