<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>YWAM is an international movement of Christians from many denominations dedicated to presenting Jesus personally to this generation, to mobilizing as many as possible to help in this task, and to the training and equipping of believers for their part in fulfilling the Great Commission. As citizens of God's kingdom, we are called to love, worship, and obey our Lord, to love and serve His Body, the Church, and to present the whole gospel for the whole person throughout the whole world.

Those who work with YWAM, believe that the Bible is God's inspired and authoritative word, revealing that Jesus Christ is God's son; that people are created in God's image; that He created us to have eternal life through Jesus Christ; that although all people have sinned and come short of God's glory, God has made salvation possible through the death on the cross and resurrection of Jesus Christ; that repentance, faith, love and obedience are fitting responses to God's initiative of grace towards us; that God desires all people to be saved and to come to the knowledge of the truth; and that the Holy Spirit's power is demonstrated in and through us for the accomplishment of Christ's last commandment, "...Go ye into all the world and preach the gospel to every creature" (Mark 16:15).


1. Know God

2. Make God Known

3. Hear God's Voice

4. Practice Worship and Intercessory Prayer

5. Be Visionary

6. Champion Young People

7. Be Broad-Structured and Decentralized

8. Be International and Interdenominational

9. Have a Biblical Worldview

10. Function in Teams

11. Exhibit Servant Leadership

12. Do First, Then Teach

13. Be Relationship-Oriented

14. Value the Individual

15. Value Families

16. Rely on Relationship-Based Support

17. Practice Hospitality</description>
  <mission>Know God and Make Him known.</mission>
  <name>Youth With A Mission / Jeuenesse En Mission</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2957</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">105</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Vv/wT/gM/MF/Sj/MD/REpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
