<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is gastroparesis?
Gastroparesis means paralysis of the muscles of the stomach. Gastroparesis results in delayed emptying of food from the stomach into the small intestine.
The stomach is a hollow organ composed primarily of muscle that serves as a storage container for food. Food in the stomach is ground into tiny pieces by the constant churning that is generated by the contractions of the stomach&#8217;s muscles. Once the food has been adequately ground, it slowly is emptied from the stomach into the intestine in a metered fashion. Only food ground into small particles can be emptied from the stomach in a normal fashion, and smaller particles are digested better in the intestine. Moreover, the metering process allows the emptied food to be well-mixed with the digestive juices of the intestine, pancreas, and liver (bile) and to be absorbed well from the intestine.
What causes gastroparesis?
Gastroparesis can be caused either by diseases of the stomach&#8217;s muscles or the nerves that control the muscles, though often no specific cause is identified. GastroParesis is diagnosed through a gastric emptying study where you lie on a table for 2 hours after eating something with dye in it and the monitor how it goes through your stomach. The average person digests their food 100% in 2 hours but gastroparesis can cause the emptying to be anywhere from 95% (less severe) to 0%(extremley severe). The disease can manifest itself through diabetics, people who have had stomach viruses, and simply people who have always had a "weak stomach"

Gastroparesis At A Glance
Gastroparesis is a disease of the muscles of the stomach or the nerves controlling the muscles that causes the muscles to stop working.



1. There is currently no cure for Gastroparesis

2. The medicines that are out there only control the symptoms not the disease itself

3. Gastroparesis can lead to other problems such as appendicidis, tumors, and chronic pain</description>
  <mission>raise money and awarness</mission>
  <name>Support GastroParesis Research</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2972</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">478</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">210.11</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uR/JX/Hb/dU/VE/yY/1pDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
