<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Give2TheTroops (G2TT) is a 501 (c) 3 tax exempt non profit organization that sends care packages and letters to our deployed and wounded military troops in combat zones, and at home. 

Our FAN PAGE on FACEBOOK is: http://www.facebook.com/#!/pages/Give2TheTroops-Inc/163413816426

We are a NONPARTISAN, NON-POLITICAL, PATRIOTIC organization aimed at supporting U.S. deployed and wounded troops in harm's way. We are managed by patriotic citizens who ensure that deployed U.S. military members in all branches of service are supported with letters and care packages.

G2TT was founded in December 2002 by the wife of a deployed U.S. Marine, and now includes branches in several states. Since 2002, G2TT has sent more than 86,000 boxes, averaging 65 pounds in weight, to approximately one million deployed American troops in Iraq, Afghanistan, Kosovo, and other combat zones.

G2TT has been recognized by the Department of Defense, The White House Mayors, Governors, Representatives, Senators, and many other Congressional people as well as famous actors, singers and writers. G2TT has also been featured on national television and in national newspapers such as The NY Times, USAToday, The Washington Post, etc. 
	
G2TT supports wounded troops in Washington, DC area hospitals and at Camp LeJeune and at Fort Bragg&#8217;s Wounded Warriors Clinics by bringing them gifts &amp; cards of encouragement.  

We collect items such as food, toiletries, games, music, movies, cards and letters, and even school supplies &amp; toys for local children, as well as canine items for our military working dogs. (K-9's)

The best way to help is to volunteer your time to pack boxes or donate any items that you think troops might enjoy (see our web site for a LONG list!). The web site gives a large list of items requested, but SNACKS and DVDs are the most needed at all our branches.

THANK YOU!!!!!  Please go to our web site and read the LETTERS FROM OUR TROOPS.  There are thousands of letters &amp; photos from the troops saying thanks to all of you who help!


1. Boost morale by sending letters of encouragment

2. Send VERY LARGE care packages to units

3. Support deployed and wounded troops in harm's way

4. Visit www.Give2thetroops.org</description>
  <mission>To support the physical, moral, and spiritual health of America's armed forces in combat zones around the world through the letters and packages prepared and shipped by caring volunteers.</mission>
  <name>Give2TheTroops, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/299</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9074</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2301.06</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Cf/2k/Hz/zQ/Nj/O2/fN/qwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
