<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>
The Euthanasia Research &amp; Guidance Organization (ERGO), a nonprofit educational corporation based in Oregon, USA, was founded in 1993 to improve the quality of background research of assisted dying for persons who are terminally or hopelessly ill and wish to end their suffering. ERGO holds that voluntary euthanasia, physician-assisted suicide, and self-deliverance, are all appropriate life endings depending on the individual medical and ethical circumstances.

As well as conducting opinion polls, ERGO also develops and publishes guidelines - ethical, psychological and legal - for patients and physicians to better prepare them to make life-ending decisions. The organization supplies literature to, and does research for, other right-to-die groups world wide, and also briefs journalists, authors, and graduate students who are coming fresh to the issue.

ERGO is willing to counsel dying patients provided that they are competent adults and are at the end-stage of a terminal illness. Family members who want assistance are also welcome to make contact. Contact must be made by telephone, fax or e-mail.

The president of ERGO is Derek Humphry, the founder in 1980 of the original Hemlock Society which he built into a national organization. He retired as executive director in 1992 to concentrate on writing and lecturing. Humphry authored five books on euthanasia between 1978 and 1993, the best-known of which is 'Final Exit', an international bestseller.

1. Fight for the right to be in command of one's death when life has become suffering.

2. To end one's life is a moral choice to be decided upon by that person, not regulated by government laws.

3.  Supporting euthanasia for incurable disease, intolerable suffering, or a possibly undignified death in a painless or minimally painful way, for the purpose of limiting suffering for both patient, family and close friends.</description>
  <mission>Dedicated to preserving the right to die.</mission>
  <name>Euthanasia Research &amp; Guidance Organization</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2990</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">428</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wh/l1/px/Jg/qF/XX/4SXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
