<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Louis August Jonas Foundation, Inc. has been committed to cultivating enlightened young leaders for a better world for over 75 years. We do this by operating three International Scholarship programs for boys and girls, ages 14-15, where the content of an individual&#8217;s character matters most, and their financial resources matter least.

We firmly believe that youth are our future and we are particularly interested in bright young people who do not have the benefit of financial advantages but demonstrate ambition and promise. We are committed to helping our scholarship recipients reach their potential for leadership, for intellectual growth, for appreciation of diversity, and for sensitivity to the needs of others.

Participants are selected from all over the world and represent a very diverse population of young people with a common interest: to open their minds to international humanistic leadership in a supportive, &#8220;hands-on&#8221; environment emphasizing both leadership and a lifelong commitment to humanitarian service.

Today there is an active, global network of nearly 5,000 alumni from over 90 countries that includes many business, academic, political and humanitarian leaders who work together to create positive change around the world.

1. To foster an appreciation of both diversity and common humanity of the participants and encourage lasting friendships across boundaries of color, religion, gender, and nationality.

2. To expand the participant's intellectual horizons through serious discussion of personal and world issues and by encouraging introspection; to heighten artistic sensibilities through guided exploration.

3. To develop leadership abilities and self-reliance by encouraging each participant to take on significant projects and responsibilities for the program and to gain experience in motivating others.

4. To offer and demonstrate by action a strong working philosophy of living characterized by the belief that personal fulfillment flows from making lifelong commitments to serving society through the pursuit of humanitarian goals.</description>
  <mission>To develop in promising young people from diverse backgrounds a lifelong commitment to sensitive and responsible leadership for the betterment of their communities and the world.</mission>
  <name>Louis August Jonas Foundation, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2991</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">654</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">945.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ro/fL/k4/rS/mb/n3/6VTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
