<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Institute for Responsible Citizenship will shape the next generation of great American citizens. This cadre of young men will have the knowledge to make sound judgments, the character to flourish under the pressures of leadership, and the vision to bring new solutions to our nation's most pressing needs. They will influence and inspire future generations of men to value education, work hard, and achieve academic and career success.

Twenty-four carefully selected young men are brought to Washington, DC each summer to begin their two-summer experience with the Institute. During their time in Washington they engage in full-time internships, take academic courses at Georgetown, meet with high-level government and business leaders, and mentor young boys.

Our four-pronged approach of academics, internships, activities, and mentorship is uniquely designed to engage the hearts and minds of young African American men and to propel them into becoming community and national leaders. 

1. Too few students are inspired to pursue academic excellence or given proper guidance to pursue their dreams.

2. Not enough minority students are taking advantage of experiential learning opportunities.

3. Today&#8217;s educational system is failing to teach leadership and professional skills to students.

4. Black America is suffering from a lack of fathers and an abundance of children being raised in single-parent households.

5. Too few talented young people are inspired to place service to others ahead of their personal ambitions.

6. Too few underprivileged citizens and emerging minority scholars have a solid understanding of constitutional and economic principles.

7. Many people form opinions about the government without a clear understanding of government&#8217;s role and function.</description>
  <mission>Inspire promising young black men to become vigorous advocates of the American ideal, caring men dedicated to serving others, and dynamic role models for young boys losing hope.</mission>
  <name>Institute for Responsible Citizenship</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2993</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">22</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Up/lv/VA/2M/2x/m7/KnKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
