<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>When the power goes out many of Florida&#8217;s residents are left in the dark, some are left more in the dark than others.  As of now in the tri-county area there is no emergency response for the deaf and hard of hearing. 
When the television and the power stops,  hearing people simply turn on the battery powered radio and continue to stay current with the weather.  When you are deaf this does not happen.  Although pagers help during this time frame, it all comes to a close when the battery goes dead on the pager.  Now the deaf person is at the mercy of Mother Nature.  
During the eye of the hurricane Francis, Hugh &amp; Karen Curran (Treasure Coast Deaf Church) had several people stop by their home to check on them.  They had to tell the deaf to get back to their homes because the storm was only half way through.  The lull in the storm was what they thought was the end.  They did not have anyway of knowing when the storm was over.  
Therefore, Deaf and Hard of Hearing Services is trying to provide a way for the deaf to continue to receive weather information during the time when there is no television available

The primary goal of Deaf Emergency Response Project is to provide a viable emergency response to the local deaf and hard of hearing community for the tri-county area of central Florida through the following objectives: 
&#8226; Purchase and distribute (loan) pagers during the peak hurricane season
&#8226; Purchase and distribute (loan) electrical inverters to re-charge the pagers
&#8226; Obtain software programming to re-direct emergency notices from the NWS to an email to each pager
&#8226; Provide the same email service to other deaf who already have their own pagers
&#8226; Identify and notify those deaf and hard of hearing in the tri-county area of the service available
&#8226; Improve the process and number of pagers each year.
&#8226; Goal is to provide the communication means for all the deaf and hard of hearing with in the tri-county area.

WE NEED $20,000.00 TO MAKE THIS HAPPEN...


1. All deaf and hard of hearing should have emergency response notification

2. All deaf and hard of hearing are entitled to same emergency notification as hearing

3. It does not matter how big or small your donation is...YOU MAKE THE DIFFERENCE!!!

4. Awareness helps us prevail</description>
  <mission>The Deaf and Hard of Hearing Services (DHHS) is working to provide a form of communication for the deaf and hard of hearing during emergencies.  

</mission>
  <name>Deaf Emergency Response Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/2998</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">148</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xK/mR/5N/ti/iB/AG/3URS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
