<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>www.booksforthebarrios.com

IN THE PHILIPPINES

ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT THROUGH EDUCATION:
Like many countries, the Philippines faces problems such as mounting debt burden, the threat of economic decline, rapid population growth, war and civil strife, violent crime, and widespread environmental degradation. These problems become barriers to meeting basic learning needs. Many of the barrio schools to which BOOKS for the BARRIOS (BftB) offers assistance to have only a handful of books. In many cases, an entire class shares a single worn and tattered book. For many children, books delivered by BftB with color illustrations are the first such books they have seen.

ENVIRONMENTAL CONSERVATION:
The Philippines has more biological diversity per unit area than any other country, and has been described by Conservation International as the world's most urgent conservation priority. Because so much is at stake, BftB believes it is imperative to include environmental education as part of the standard curriculum in the Philippines.

IN THE U.S.

LANDFILL DIVERSION:
A variety of laws and ordinances require that California school districts renew their instructional materials and books every few years. BftB provides U.S. schools with an alternative to contributing to landfill.

ENVIRONMENTAL EDUCATION:
Because children in the U.S. are significant contributors to waste, therefore, U.S. children are the cornerstone of our U.S. Donor Children's Program. This program allows U.S. students to express their compassion for their classmates abroad while sharing educational materials in the U.S. The program instills values that will make for more environment-friendly lifestyles and more ecologically passionate individuals.

CHARACTER EDUCATION:
Elementary school students who participate in our U.S. Donor Children's Program develop an appreciation for the resourcefulness of people living with severely limited resources. Through this program, we foster awareness among U.S. children from an early age.


1. Filipino students are just like American students.

2. Filipino students are eager, yet book-deprived students.

3. Re-use is a powerful tool to educate both Filipino and American students about the environment.</description>
  <mission>We send books and educational materials to the eager, yet book-deprived students of the Philippines. Visit BftB website at www.booksforthebarrios.com for more info. These students are just like us!</mission>
  <name>Books for the Barrios</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3008</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4802</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">698.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Mk/qD/5b/mT/oT/Z1/xzJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
