<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>SweatFree Communities is a national network of grassroots anti-sweatshop organizations that works to build a global economy with justice and equality. We campaign for worker justice and a global trading system that reflects the values of working people and communities worldwide and gives just workplaces a chance to succeed. You can get active in the sweatfree movement by bringing the campaign to your community. Make sure your business, religious group, school, city council, or state government commits to buying products made in fair labor conditions and holds companies accountable to improve conditions in sweatshops currently in their supply chains.

Here are 5 ways you can take action:

1. Bring the sweatfree campaign to your community to ensure that your tax dollars do not support sweatshop conditions. Email organize@sweatfree.org to learn more.

2. Endorse the campaign. http://www.sweatfree.org/endorse

3. Next time you buy clothes, buy sweatfree. http://www.sweatfree.org/shoppingguide

4. If you have to wear uniforms for your job or for school, participate in our Me and My Uniform project. http://www.sweatfree.org/myuniform

5. Donate to the campaign! http://www.sweatfree.org/donate


1. Workers everywhere have a right to dignity and respect on the job, freedom of association, and living wages.

2. Sweatshop exploitation undermines local economies and the competitive ability of companies with fair labor practices.

3. Abuse of workers anywhere is bad for business and workers everywhere.</description>
  <mission>Ending sweatshop exploitation by inspiring responsible local purchasing and fostering solidarity between U.S. communities and workers worldwide.</mission>
  <name>SweatFree Communities</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3013</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">166</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">80.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ML/Qh/Qx/KN/yd/15/Qq/lKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
