<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Mental Illness is the second leading cause of disability and premature death in the United States. Depression, anxiety, and other mental health problems affect at least one in four people at any given time. That's more than 200,000 people in the Tulsa metropolitan area. Sadly, only a fraction ever seek treatment. Social stigma -- misunderstanding, embarrassment, and fear -- keep people from getting the help they need.

The good news is mental illness is treatable. Recovery is possible. The Mental Health Association in Tulsa offers a variety of programs and outreach efforts to get people connected with the information, resources and help they need.

As a member agency of the Tulsa Area United Way, and an affiliate of Mental Health America (the new name and face of the National Mental Health Association), the Mental Health Association in Tulsa is here for you. We work to overcome stigma through education, as well as provide advocacy, resources, support groups, outreach and safe housing.

For more information, please refer to www.mhat.org.

1. Through education, they build understanding, reduce stigma and improve the quality of life for those whose lives are impacted by mental illness.

2. The Association is working to eliminate and prevent homelessness of people with mental illnesses throughout Tulsa County.

3. Through TeenScreen and SafeTeam, the Association provides the means for early detection of emotional problems and offer hope for a brighter future for many of Tulsa's young people. </description>
  <mission>They are dedicated to promoting mental health, preventing mental disorders, and achieving victory over mental illness through advocacy, education, research, service and housing.</mission>
  <name>Mental Health Association in Tulsa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3017</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">154</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2p/Sq/CP/I7/YO/bc/RwNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
