<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Stop using palm oil, start saving the rainforest! Palm oil is found in 1 out of 10 products sold at your local supermarket. It's normally used to replace trans fat in common foods; however, it actually increases your chances of heart disease. Palm oil plantations are also the prime source for the destruction of the rainforest, the habitat of thousands of living species, a mass oxygen producer, and possible cures for cancer and other fatal diseases. With your help, WE CAN help save the rainforest and everything living in it.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
List of common products that may contain palm oil:&lt;br&gt;
Ice Cream&lt;br&gt; 
Chocolate&lt;br&gt;
Biscuits&lt;br&gt;
Cookies&lt;br&gt;
Crackers&lt;br&gt;
Bread&lt;br&gt;
Potato Chips&lt;br&gt;
Margarine&lt;br&gt;
Toothpaste&lt;br&gt;
Soap&lt;br&gt;
Detergents&lt;br&gt;
Cosmestics&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Species in the rainforest:&lt;br&gt;
Orang-utan&lt;br&gt;
Macaw&lt;br&gt;
Toucan&lt;br&gt;
Sloth&lt;br&gt;
Spider Monkey&lt;br&gt;
Rhinoceros Beetle&lt;br&gt;
Boa Constrictor&lt;br&gt;
Orchids&lt;br&gt;
Buttress Roots&lt;br&gt;
Strangler Fig&lt;br&gt;
Venus Fly Trap&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
What can you do to help? Many things! You can start with something as little as telling everyone you know about the dangers of the palm oil industry, or even checking your groceries for palm oil and replacing them with another product. If you like, you can even contribute financially to the cause, or write to your supermarket CEOs about protesting the palm oil industry. Any thing you can think of and do will help and benifit the cause. Thank you for your time and efforts! The orang-utan's appreciate it! 

1. We must stop giving our money to the palm oil industry and protest the usage of palm oil

2. We must tell everyone we know about the destruction of the rainforest

3. We must save the very place that has yet to be explored fully and is home to many living things</description>
  <mission>Promote awareness on the destruction of the rainforest, and fight for an end by any means necessary.</mission>
  <name>Stop using palm oil, start saving the rainforest! WE CAN!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3018</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">505</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/YU/j8/nu/S8/bZ/qw/XqTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
