<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>mission

Most of the nearly two&#8211;billion children in the developing world are inadequately educated, or receive no education at all. One in three does not complete the fifth grade.

The individual and societal consequences of this chronic global crisis are profound. Children are consigned to poverty and isolation&#8212;just like their parents&#8212;never knowing what the light of learning could mean in their lives. At the same time, their governments struggle to compete in a rapidly evolving, global information economy, hobbled by a vast and increasingly urban underclass that cannot support itself, much less contribute to the commonweal, because it lacks the tools to do so.

It is time to rethink this equation.

Given the resources that poor countries can reasonably allocate to education&#8212;sometimes less than $20 per year per pupil, compared to the approximately $7500 per pupil spent annually in the U.S.&#8212;even a doubled or redoubled national commitment to traditional education, augmented by external and private funding, would not get the job done. Moreover, experience strongly suggests that an incremental increase of &#8220;more of the same&#8221;&#8212;building schools, hiring teachers, buying books and equipment&#8212;is a laudable but insufficient response to the problem of bringing true learning possibilities to the vast numbers of children in the developing world.

Standing still is a reliable recipe for going backward.
Any nation's most precious natural resource is its children. We believe the emerging world must leverage this resource by tapping into the children's innate capacities to learn, share, and create on their own. Our answer to that challenge is the XO laptop, a children's machine designed for &#8220;learning learning.&#8221;


1. Every child deserves an opportunity through eduation no matter where they are born.</description>
  <mission>To provide children in africa with new opportunities to explore, experiment and express themselves.</mission>
  <name>Laptops for Africa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3028</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">17</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dw/P8/CL/sG/Rk/js/XBiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
