<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Sunlight Foundation was founded in January 2006 with the goal of using the revolutionary power of the Internet and new information technology to enable citizens to learn more about what Congress and their elected representatives are doing, and thus help reduce corruption, ensure greater transparency and accountability by government, and foster public trust in the vital institutions of democracy. We are unique in that technology and the power of the Internet are at the core of every one of our efforts.

Our initial projects &#8211; from the establishment of a Congresspedia, the making of &#8220;transparency grants&#8221; for the development and enhancement of databases and websites, and two separate efforts to engage the public in distributed journalism and offer online tutorials on the role of money in politics efforts &#8211; are based on the premise that the collective power of citizens to demand greater accountability is the clearest route to reform.

Sunlight&#8217;s work is committed to helping citizens, journalists and bloggers be their own best watchdogs, both by improving access to existing information and digitizing new information, and by creating new tools and websites to enable all of us to pool our intelligence in new, and yet to be imagined, ways. 

''Disclaimer: Andrew MacRae is not affiliated with the Sunlight Foundation in any official capacity. The information was taken directly from their webpage and may not entirely reflect their views.''

Learn more about joining our fan page- http://www.facebook.com/pages/Washington-DC/Sunlight-Foundation/6921874941 or by visiting our website! http://www.SunlightFoundation.com

1. Contemporaneous online filing.

2. Ending secret legislation.

3. Meaningful lobbyist disclosure. </description>
  <mission>Using the revolutionary power of the Internet and new information technology to enable citizens to learn more about what Congress and their elected representatives are doing. </mission>
  <name>Sunlight Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/303</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">618</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Pbb/0CDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
