<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The International Center for Limb Lengthening focuses on the care of pediatric and adult patients with limb deformities, limb length discrepancies, skeletal abnormalities etc. The ICLL is part of the Rubin Institute for Advanced Orthopedics, which is located on the Sinai Hospital of Baltimore campus. The ICLL is co-directed by Dror Paley, M.D. and John E. Herzenberg, M.D. Each year, the surgeons at the ICLL treat more than 2,000 patients who experience congenital, developmental, or post-traumatic limb deformities. Patients come from more than 50 countries around the world to receive treatment at the Center.

On September 2, 2007 the 2nd Annual Save-A-Limb Ride will take place at Oregon Park right outside of Baltimore, MD. I (Kristen) will be biking 30 miles for the cause. This ride is very important to me, as I am a patient of Dr. Paley's and went through three different limb lengthening surgeries nearly 9 years ago. Please help me raise money for the ride. Every dollar counts in helping to save people from facing amputation and treating those in need. Invite your friends to join and let's raise awareness together! 

If you are going to donate please go to the following website: http://www.active.com/donate/savealimb/kristensride

My goal is to raise $1000.00 by September 2, 2007. Again, please give your donation by visiting my website. Thank you for all of your help! You guys are awesome.

For more information please visit:
www.limblengthening.org
www.savealimbride.org
http://www.active.com/donate/savealimb/kristensride



1. To invest in and acquire, resources and technologies that directly benefit the advancement and quality of care to all patients.

2. To provide financial support to special needs patients who could not otherwise afford limb and joint saving care.

3. To provide educational and social therapeutic activities to children who suffer from limb deformities.

4. To financially support new research programs with the intention of helping save limbs and joints.</description>
  <mission>Raise money to change the life of someone struggling with a limb deformity.</mission>
  <name>Save-A-Limb</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3038</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">74</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">321.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ce/bb/iv/xf/I2/DW/cHAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
