<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It may seem superficial, it may seem unimportant, it may seem selfish and self-righteous, and some may even say that since it is mainly embedded in the culture of one kind of social structure in the world, "we did it to ourselves".

The truth is, though,  that body image problems are spreading like an epidemic and that they can be so severe so as to become a person's handicap; 

affecting their psyche, habits, studies, and even their relationships with people (from family, to friends, to sexual partners,etc). 

Severe body image problems can lead a person to becoming withdrawn, weak, vulnerable, at the mercy of others in relationships who compliment them, etc.   

This cause doesn't focus on blaming people/organizations/societal structures, but on encouraging everyone who has even the smallest doubts about their body to understand that we are all different, and each with our charms and peculiarities.  

Join it as a reminder that you're not alone and that others are working on the same thing or as an encouragement to those struggling with this.

It also encourages anyone who knows anyone else with a poor perception of their body to help them overcome these issues (not necessarily in an obvious matter).

The world is too beautiful, and it contains too many secrets that we need to unlock and appreciate, instead of spending time having a negative body image.

We are who are!



1. We will not let body image issues affect our life, psyche, relationships, etc.

2. We will work on accepting and loving our bodies, if we are not already doing it.

3. We will always be there to help others become comfortable in their own skin, if they are also struggling.</description>
  <mission>understand the charms possessed by our physical bodies and help others become comfortable in their own skin.</mission>
  <name>Love Your Body</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3048</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">97</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.14</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Et/sq/3T/I1/ZF/fE/qw/cbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
