<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Will you work for food?  Do you like to lift heavy stuff?  Have you ever wondered how far away Rockville is from D.C.?  Attending this moving party will make all of your wildest dreams come true!  And it will help Adrienne and Rachel a lot!  Really, we don't have that much stuff...  If you don't want to help us, just think about how you're also helping Daisy.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Here are the details:&lt;br&gt;
  
&lt;b&gt;What:&lt;/b&gt; Moving Party!!!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;When:&lt;/b&gt; Saturday, July 14 around 10 a.m.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Where:&lt;/b&gt; Starting in Glover Park and ending in Rockville
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;b&gt;Details:&lt;/b&gt; You will be assigned to the "A Team" or the "R Team." Once both trucks are unloaded at the final destination in Rockville, pizza and soda will be provided for everyone.  Rides to and from the Metro will also be available as both locations are only accessible by car or bus.  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;b&gt;RSVP:&lt;/b&gt; Please let us know if you can help ASAP!  Please show up if you sign up to help.  We are depending on you!  E-mail Rachel for more information.  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;b&gt;Why:&lt;/b&gt; Because it's for a good cause!  We can't afford a real moving service, and we definitely can't lift much...  We appreciate your help!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Who:&lt;/b&gt; Everyone's doing it...  All the cool kids will be there...  This is your chance to show your SOC spirit!  Or whatever type of spirit you have... 

1. Rachel and Adrienne are two awesome girls who need help moving.

2. Daisy would like you to help too. 

3. We reward our friends who help us move with free food.

4. Friends who help us move are moved up the list to be invited to subsequent parties.</description>
  <mission>Recruit enough friends to help us move our stuff.</mission>
  <name>Help Rachel and Adrienne Move!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3049</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/R3/vz/f7/5a/P5/I4/iy7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
