<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Why We Fight MS

Having multiple sclerosis (MS) means that you may suddenly have blurry vision. Or that your memory will fail you for no apparent reason. Or that you may not always be able to walk. The symptoms of MS are different, and often devastating, for everyone - the only certainty is that it will affect yet another person every hour of every day. 

Why I Ride

I've registered for the MS 150 Best Dam Bike Tour because I want to do something for the people who have been diagnosed - and because I want to do everything to prevent more people from learning what it means to live with this disease. Today, there is no cure for MS, and with diagnosis occurring most frequently between the ages of 20 and 50, many individuals face a lifetime filled with unpredictability

WHAT CAN YOU DO???
Donate to our team and help us to meet our goal...The National MS Society - Wisconsin Chapter will use funds collected from the MS 150 Best Dam Bike Tour to not only support research for a cure tomorrow, but also to provide programs and services which address the needs of people living with MS today. Because we can fight this disease by simply riding, because we have chosen to help thousands of people through a contribution to the MS 150 Best Dam Bike Tour, we are now getting closer to the hour when no one will have to hear the words, "You have MS."




IF YOU WISH TO DONATE...PLEASE HELP SUPPORT OUR TEAM'S FUNDRAISING GOALS...go directly to this site and donate with team HILL YEAH!!!  

http://www.nationalmssociety.org/site/TR?team_id=70891&amp;pg=team&amp;fr_id=5930


1. For a future free of MS, this is why we ride</description>
  <mission>make a future free of MS</mission>
  <name>multiple sclerosis (MS) 150 mile Best dam bike tour</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3061</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">377</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/St/nm/yx/HX/yT/fo/Hm7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
