<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For years now the media and said "professionals", have been claiming that violent games cause violence and make murderers and school shooters. Others say that gaming decreases intelligence. What evidence do they have that supports what they say? A few isolated cases? How about what they don't tell us, those cases they have also had mental issues. A common case is the Columbine High school shootings where the two instigators designed a Doom map from their school's blueprints. The game did not cause them to be violent, the disrespect and hate from others caused them to feel discouraged and depressed to the point that they wanted to hurt someone. If they didn't have Doom to design it on, they would have used paper or something else. Where is the proof then that violent games cause violence? Also, what about explicit music and Violent Movies which tend to be more violent than games?
We support gaming. Your views are appreciated and we would love to hear them.

1. Violent Games do not cause violence

2. Government should keep its hands out of the gaming industry

3. Government should dispel its position on M games, and allow ESRB to handle it

4. Gamers that play violent games should not be the first suspects for violent crime

5. Games should not be blamed for someone's violent or eccentric behaviour

6. Parents should take responsibility for what their children are and are not seeing. It's not the ESRB's job, it's not the government's job, it's not the manufacturers job. Responsibility for the children starts and ends with parents.</description>
  <mission>Support Gamers and show how games help people with their problems and how games help people relax as well as provide an avenue for group entertainment.</mission>
  <name>Violent Games Don't Cause Violence</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3064</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24144</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">68.12</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yU/p1/Us/LM/5u/L2/CUQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
