<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Nhimbe is a word from the Shona people of Zimbabwe referring to a community working together to help each other in daily life, for example, during harvest time. This traditional word reflects the deep commitment required both in North America and Zimbabwe to create this reality.

Location
    140 kilometers from Harare you will find the villages we have opportunity to serve. These seven villages are in the Mhondoro region. There are about 1,100 people who live there. Magaya village is located within walking distance to the other five villages and over many years has become a central point for exchange.

Background
    In 1998, Cosmas Magaya, a master mbira player, beloved teacher and highly respected businessman, was sponsored by Kutsinhira to come to the U.S. and stay with their community in Eugene, Oregon. It was during this time that he and Jaiaen Beck of Ancient Ways first talked of their communities' relationship.

    We have chosen to focus on 7 villages with over 250 families (1,100 people) in the Mhondoro area because of our history with teachers of traditional music who live there. Each year we have continued with surveys by interviewing village residents, primary and secondary school headmasters, as well as experiencing, exloring, and examaning the difficult aspects of rural life. 

Program Administration
    The Nhimbe for Progress program is being administered in Zimbabwe by Cosmas Magaya. Our goal here in the states is to work with him to facilitate funds and/or products reaching the villages as well as help with the administration in Zimbabwe. We are currently researching appropriate technology for cooking, as well as exploring all avenues for helping the people in the area modify difficult lifestyle situations and gain in prosperity, without losing all that is familiar. Personal empowerment is our focus.

1. improve sub-standard living conditions such as re-building collapsed huts that were destroyed by the floods, building wells, toilets and fuel efficient stoves, providing medical assistance

2. offer business opportunity to poor rural Zimbabweans

3. sponsor children who are unable to attend school because they cannot afford the necessary fees ($35/yr.), provide teaching materials to schools, establish a pre-school program

4. create a community fund to help with the special needs of the elderly, infants, and orphans.</description>
  <mission>To provide appropriate assistance to Zimbabwean people in an ecologically sound, self-sustaining, and culturally respectful way</mission>
  <name>Nhimbe For Progresss</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3071</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">35</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wC/RF/XK/PO/7q/Z1/X3sS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
