<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>LIBER OZ

"the law of
the strong:
this is our law
and the joy
of the world." AL. II. 2

"Do what thou wilt shall be the whole of the Law." --AL. I. 40

"thou hast no right but to do thy will. Do that, and no other shall say nay." --AL. I. 42-3

"Every man and every woman is a star." --AL. I. 3
There is no god but man.

1. Man has the right to live by his own law--
    to live in the way that he wills to do:
    to work as he will:
    to play as he will:
    to rest as he will:
    to die when and how he will. 
2. Man has the right to eat what he will:
    to drink what he will:
    to dwell where he will:
    to move as he will on the face of the earth. 
3. Man has the right to think what he will:
    to speak what he will:
    to write what he will:
    to draw, paint, carve, etch, mould, build as he will:
    to dress as he will. 
4. Man has the right to love as he will:--
    "take your fill and will of love as ye will,
    when, where, and with whom ye will." --AL. I. 51 
5. Man has the right to kill those who would thwart these rights.
    "the slaves shall serve." --AL. II. 58 

"Love is the law, love under will." --AL. I. 57 

1. Do What Thou Wilt shall be the Whole of the Law ("Will" is not "Want"- Will is the apotheosis of Freedom, and the strictest possible bond.  It is a responsibility, and it is a joy.  It is all the power that we have, and it is the limit of all our power.)

2. Love is the Law, Love Under Will  (Each event is the union of a star and a possibility, whether it is in violence of passion or violence of combat.  Each act of Love under Will requires respect, for the enemy and for the beloved.)

3. Every Man and Woman is a Star  (The essential nature of every human being must be encouraged, allowed to grow and flourish.  Whether others believe that it is "evil" or good" is irrelevent.  All socially installed inhibitions must be resolved and removed)

4. Let there be no property in the flesh!  Every man and every woman has the right to give himself or herself to the enjoyment of any other, as the Will speakth.  To repress the sex instinct or to deform its natural growth is the most grusome violation.

5. There is No God but Man.  Rather than placing his hopes in ideals and in faith, he must strive to be WORTHY of his divinity, and to create after his own kind.  Let us create without fear, for we can create nothing that is not God!

6. The word of Sin is restriction!  Let nothing deflect you from that austere and holy task. Liberty is absolute to do your will; but seek to do any other thing whatever, and instantly obstacles must arise.

7. Education should not be forced. This destroys the love of learning. The only compulsory education is how to cultivate and prepare food, how to make clothing, and how to make love.  Everything else is taught according to the student's Will to learn.

8. Protection and aid must be granted to all single mothers who are willing and able to raise their children according to their essential nature.

9. Existence is pure joy!  Sorrows are shadows that pass and are done.  Sorrow is an illusion created by existence, and the beginning of all evil is to mistake sorrow or suffering for truth.  

10. Humanitarian compassion is destroying the human race.  Leaders must make decisions based on reason and logic, not on uncritical emotional responses.

11. Science must be allowed to proceed without restraint, to fully map the human genome and to determine the limits of human potential.  To this end, private interests in scientific research must be severely restricted, so that science can be free.</description>
  <mission>promulgate the Law of Thelema as it has been described and detailed by Aleister Crowley</mission>
  <name>The Law of Thelema</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3077</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2008</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">427.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nO/6y/0b/QE/L0/ry/JXdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
