<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>May 27th, Britain's National Association of Teachers in Further and Higher Education (NATFHE) approved an academic boycott on Israeli higher education institutions that do not condemn Israel&#8217;s &#8220;apartheid policy.&#8221; NAFTHE,teachers' unions, voted 106 to 71, with 21 abstentions. which with a membership of 67,000 educators is one of the UK&#8217;s largest 

The boycott signifies a significant loss to academic progress. Israeli scientists have developed, on a per capita basis, more life-saving medical technologies than any nation in the world.
THIS BOYCOTT IS UNJUST. It holds the Jewish State to to a double standard of political scrutiny. NATFHE has not passed resolutions against Sudanese, Chinese Venezuelan academics, whose governments commit gross human rights violations. 
Only Israel, becuase it is the Jewish State, do they choose to single out for censure and isolation. This is anti-Semitism.
Israeli Education Minister Yuli Tamir on the boycott:
&#8220;The decision to boycott academic institutions is a move worthy of condemnation and revulsion. Those who are implementing this boycott are harming academia&#8217;s freedom and turning it into a tool for political forces.&#8221;
British Minister of Higher Education Bill Rammell , condemned the boycott.
"The UK government fully supports academic freedom and is firmly against any academic boycotts of Israel or Israeli academics...I am very dissapointed that the union has decided to pass [this] motio. I profoundly believe this does nothing to promote the Middle East peace process." (UKGaurdian)

Anti-Defamation League
http://www.adl.org/boycott/
http://www.adl.org/israel/letter_natfhe.asp
Sign the petition:
http://www.petitiononline.com/stopucu/petition.html
Scholars for Peace in the Middle East
http://www.spme.net/cgi-bin/display_petitions.cgi?ID=9
Alan M. Dershowitz 
http://www.alandershowitz.com/publications/docs/boycott.html
http://www.frontpagemag.com/Articles/ReadArticle.asp?ID=28660

1. Position #1</description>
  <mission>Expose the injustice of the British academia's boycott of Israeli academics</mission>
  <name>End the British Boycott of Israeli Academics</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3081</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">686</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/T5/VH/PI/ye/qi/g3/IR/0rS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
