<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>**** VISIT RIVER CENTRE CLINCS' WEBSITE****  
http://www.river-centre.org/  

**** ALL DONATIONS GO TO THE RIVER CENTRE CLINIC TO HELP OTHERS WITH THESE DISORDERS.  IT IS A COSTLY CURE SO ANY MONEY WILL HELP THE PATIENTS PAY FOR IT AND THE CLINIC TO HELP RAISE AWARENESS!****

***INVITE INVITE INVITE!!! HELP SPREAD THE WORD! HELP SOMEONE IN NEED! INVITE YOUR FRIENDS!!!***

The River Centre Clinic (RCC) Eating Disorders Programs provide a full range of treatment options for adolescents and adults with a primary diagnosis of an eating disorder. The levels of care provided at the RCC are designed to meet the needs of most patients with eating disorders, but it is important to note that treatment is individualized for each case.All aspects of the RCC programs are delivered by highly qualified professional staff. 


An eating disorder is a complex compulsion to eat in a way which disturbs physical, mental, and psychological health. The eating may be excessive (compulsive over-eating); to limited (restricting); may include normal eating punctuated with episodes of purging; may include cycles of binging and purging; or may encompass the ingesting of non-foods. The most heard about eating disorders are Anorexia nervosa and Bulimia nervosa. The most widely and rapidly spreading eating disorder is compulsive overeating or Binge eating disorder. These are also the three most common eating disorders. All three have severe consequences to a person's immediate and long-term health and can cause death. There are numerous theories as to the causes and mechanisms leading to eating disorders.

Anorexia nervosa is a psychiatric diagnosis that describes an eating disorder characterized by low body weight and body image distortion with an obsessive fear of gaining weight. Individuals with anorexia often control body weight by voluntary starvation, purging, vomiting, excessive exercise, or other weight control measures, such as diet pills or diuretic drugs. It primarily affects adolescent females in the Western world. Anorexia nervosa is a complex condition, involving psychological, neurobiological, and sociological components.

Bulimia nervosa, commonly known as bulimia, is an eating disorder. It is a psychological condition in which the subject engages in recurrent binge eating followed by intentional purging. This purging is done in order to compensate for the excessive intake of food, usually to prevent weight gain. Purging can take the form of vomiting; inappropriate use of laxatives, enemas, diuretics or other medication; or excessive physical exercise.

1. Raise awareness of this cause

2. Help someone you know

3. Invite people to join this cause 

4. Donate money to help others get help</description>
  <mission>Fighting Eating/Dieting Disorders</mission>
  <name>Help Fight Eating Disorders</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3093</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1289</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jb/ah/GZ/v2/Yh/bN/i7/1eS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
