<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Youth Villages is committed to helping troubled children and their families find success - together. Our cause began 20 years ago at a small residential treatment facility in Memphis, TN, and has grown to include an array of services dedicated to providing long-term solutions for children in the foster care system. 

Our cause is about changing the foster care system and the treatment of troubled youth. Youth Villages is one of the leading organizations in the U.S. for providing evidence-based treatments that keep children with their families or within a foster or adoptive family. Our programs focus on strengths of families and all the possible things in their environment that could cause certain behaviors to take place. The specific areas we focus on are individual challenges, home environment, school, peer interactions and the community.

Many children we serve have psychiatric, emotional and behavioral problems, may have been physically/sexually abused or neglected by parents or relatives, may be searching for an adoptive placement and, in many cases, are the toughest kids to work with. However, each one is special and each one has potential to be successful despite the daily difficult challenges they face.

Founded in Memphis, TN, Youth Villages now spans a seven-state region (AL, AR, MA, MS, NC, TN, TX) and the District of Columbia providing programs and services such as intensive home-based counseling, residential treatment, treatment foster care, adoption services, community-based services, 
transitional living services, specialized crisis services and intensive residential treatment. Nearly 1,300 employees and hundreds of volunteers and mentors serve over 11,000 young people each year.

Our programs use the principles of evidence-based treatment models, including Multisystemic Therapy (MST). To date, we have a 86% success rate of children successfully living at home with their families. 

Learn more at www.youthvillages.org.



1. Kids' needs come first...always. 

2. Children are raised best by their families. 

3. We provide a safe place for children in need. 

4. We strive to achieve positive, lasting results.

5. We are commited to staff.

6. We are each responsible for providing the highest level of service to our customers.

7. We constantly improve our performance to achieve excellence.

8. We create programs to meet the needs of children, families and the community.

9. We do what we say we do. </description>
  <mission>We help children &amp; families live successfully. </mission>
  <name>Youth Villages</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3094</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1320</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">80.08</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8Z/wJ/jY/Xr/ni/wJ/pXRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
