<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We are dedicated to continuing the legacy of Millard Fuller, our inspirational leader for 40 years and the Founder of The Fuller Center for Housing in 2005.  Millard Fuller also Founded and then led Habitat for Humanity from 1976-2005.

In just four years, we have Covenant Partners in 50 cities around the U.S. and 14 countries overseas.  Following his sudden passing on February 3, 2009, we have redoubled our efforts and re-committed ourselves to carrying forward the Fuller Center ministry he began.

Fuller Center projects are building and renovating homes across the country and around the world with those in need.  Millard always said that he had never seen an organization grow like the Fuller Center has.  We are an ecumenical Christian movement that welcomes anyone who wants to join with us to eliminate poverty housing.

There are countless opportunities for involvement, such as by organizing a Student Builders group or work team, involving your church or work place and working locally, traveling overseas with our Global Builders program, or even by riding a bicycle as part of our Fuller Center Bicycle Adventure!

But whether swinging a hammer, writing a check, or riding a bike, by all means get involved. And perhaps most of all, help us spread the word!

www.fullercenter.org

1. Everyone should have at least a simple, decent place to live

2. Everyone has something they can do to help

3. With God, all things are possible - including eliminating poverty housing

4. Grassroots efforts can enact incredible change</description>
  <mission>To eliminate poverty housing in the U.S. and throughout the world.  </mission>
  <name>The Fuller Center for Housing</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3100</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2050</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">11512.17</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/F6/AW/wX/UW/bb/Mv/PV/piS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
