<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Trafficking is the recruitment, harboring, transportation, provision, or obtaining of a person for labor or services, through the use of force, fraud or coercion for the purpose of subjection to involuntary servitude, peonage, debt bondage, or slavery.
 
Human trafficking is modern-day slavery and is now regarded as the third largest and fastest growing criminal industry in the world, involving a multi-billion dollar industry
 
In January 2005, the Campus Coalition Against Trafficking, a project of FAIR Fund and Polaris Project, was launched as a grassroots outreach initiative to build the anti-trafficking movement by training emerging leaders, fostering youth empowerment, raising awareness about human trafficking, and encouraging cross-sectoral linkages among social justice issues.
CCAT is open to both individual students and student groups who are interested in combating human trafficking.

The U.S. State Department estimates that 600,000 to 800,000 people are trafficked across international borders each year, with current estimates of 14,500 to 17,500 persons trafficked into the United States annually. Research suggests that over half of these individuals are youth, and 80 percent are women. Because most global estimates do not include estimates of internal trafficking that occurs within a country&#8217;s borders, it is widely agreed that trafficking across international borders only points toward a fraction of the global prevalence of this human rights abuse.

Commercial Sexual Exploitation(CSE) is a sad reality throughout the world, whether the country is developed, or developing. According to the U.S. Attorney's Office, the average age for entry into CSE for Washington, DC teens is 13 years old. 

Young people, particularly young women, should and must be involved in this fight against modern-day slavery.

For more information or involvement, please see:
www.ccatcoalition.org 
fairfund.org


1. Protecting the victims of trafficking.

2. Raising awareness in communities.

3. Empowering young women and men to protect themselves from CSE</description>
  <mission>To use grassroots community mobilization in engaging college campuses and other student and youth groups in anti-trafficking efforts in their communities and abroad.</mission>
  <name>Campus Coalition Against Trafficking</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3101</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">142</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yy/qj/cW/zB/D7/ph/qEuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
