<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The first official meeting of the North Carolina Beach Buggy Association was held in March of 1964 in Buxton; however, the idea of creating such an organization was born almost two years earlier in 1962. For those who don&#180;t know, in early March 1962, a fierce nor&#180;easter slammed the entire East Coast, causing devastating losses to the coastal communities from Florida to Maine. In fact, Buxton Inlet was formed between Avon and Buxton during the storm; however, it was artificially closed soon after the opening. The Outer Banks beaches took a tremendous pounding, and in the aftermath, the Government was considering closing the beaches to off road vehicles. Needless to say this did not happen, but the potential for such a closure raised concern among a few local citizens. There weren&#180;t 

 The current membership tops 4700, and license plate numbering over 12,000 have been issued



1. To enter and leave beaches only at approved and designated places determined by local, state, and federal ordinances. 

2. To eliminate speeding and reckless driving on the beaches. 

3. To respect local ordinances and the rights of property owners. 

4. To advise NCBBA members who are experiencing problems driving on the beaches. 

5. To respect persons bathing and picnicking by avoiding them whenever possible and by slowing down to minimum speed when passing such groups. 

6. To avoid littering the beach with trash by depositing it in trash containers wherever available or by bagging and removing it from the beach. 

7. To remove dead bait, carcasses, or other dead fish of any kind from the beach. 

8. To avoid over-crowding any one area and elbowing anglers from their chosen spots, particularly important where surf fishermen without vehicles are concentrated. 

9. To leave room for other vehicles to pass safely when parked.

10. To refill holes, and remove any boards or other aids after being stuck, leaving the beach passable for others. 

11. To observe common courtesy on the beach observing the rules of the road when meeting or passing other vehicles at constricted areas. 

12. To remember, at all times, that the unspoiled beaches of all seashore areas afford pleasure to everyone and it is incumbent upon each of us to preserve this natural heritage</description>
  <mission>preservation of and vehicular access to the natural beach </mission>
  <name>North Carolina Beach Buggy Association</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3107</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">33</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Xz/Tq/tM/b8/df/nB/2yuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
