<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In Defense of Animals promotes educational events, cruelty investigations, boycotts, grassroots activism, and hands-on rescue through sanctuaries in Mississippi and Cameroon, Africa.


Today, humans are inflicting great harm and suffering on the world's creatures and the enivornment through industries and attitudes that exploit animals and destroy wildlife. The response to this injustice is the development of a movement -the Animal Rights Movement: the vehicle for millions who seek justice and compassion for animals. 

Animal rights is an affirmation of all life, of humanity's ability and need to nurture and protect the sanctity of life in all species, human and non-human alike.

1. Urge students to object to dissection

2. Remove elephants from zoos

3. Ban Foie Gras

4. Enact stricter laws governing rodeo operations

5. End Cock Fighting

6. End Greyhound Racing

7. End Bull Fighting

8. Ban Animal Circuses

9. Encourage the Korean Government to enforce the Animal Protection Act

10. Stop companies from selling fur

11. Help all cities adopt the term "Guardian"

12. Save dolphins, whales, seas, sea lions, sea otters and other sea creatures

13. End marine mammal captivity

14. Boycott Petland

15. Support Buck's Bill, eliminating Class B Dealers

16. Stop Puppy Mills

17. Help Unwanted Animals

18. Promote Veganism

19. Implement humane alternatives to animal testing

20. Protect wildlife

21. End exotic bird trade</description>
  <mission>IDA is an international animal protection organization dedicated to ending the exploitation &amp; abuse of animals by defending their rights, welfare, &amp; habitat. </mission>
  <name>In Defense of Animals</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3114</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">29663</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2536.34</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Gr/Kp/f5/kp/ci/Ww/o3/tdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
