<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I just thought that this was an important thing for us to think about and remember. For the past five years I've always watched on T.V all the soldiers that were dying from Canada, even from Newfoundland and it always gave me heartache but nothing even as close to what I felt Easter Day, when I heard about the explosion involving six Canadian Soldiers, one our own Kevin Kennedy. I'd never felt to sick and guilty and just amazingly sad. These soldiers give up their normal lives with friends and families and jobs and even kids for many to do what they beleive is right? To risk everything so that we can be safe and continue with our lives that we take for granted everyday. I'll never really be able to repay or say anything that could even come close to what I feel about these men and women and how much they really matter. You arent just soldiers, or Peace keepers, your more than that. Your our sisters and mothers, daughters, brothers, sons, fathers, friends and family. Your more than amazing and brave and theres really no possible word that could express how truly honourable and amazing you all are. The only thing i could possibly say to really show how I feel and many others all over the world is "Thank you from the bottom of my heart". You'll never know how much you mean to me. And all Kevins Family members and friends, God is at your side and so am I. And all the soldiers that have done any time in Afghanistan, changed any little thing, helped any animal or child just i want you to know you are ture heros. And for your families I do feel for you. And God is with you. &#9829;Always know that and keep their memories alive. Rest in Peace Forever and Infinity. You are all so sadly missed but NEVER forgotten. &#9829;


1. Canadian Soldiers are Heros.

2. Forever they Should be remembered.

3. Should Canadians even go to war?</description>
  <mission>Commemerate and Appreciate our Soldiers for making a difference! :)&#9829;</mission>
  <name>A Tribute to Our Soldiors</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3123</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">730</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eo/wx/xM/wA/gD/M5/GIbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
