<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Kansas City Center for Urban Agriculture is a 501(c)3 tax-exempt corporation founded in 2004 by two Kansas City farmers dedicated to promoting urban agriculture in the Kansas City metropolitan area. Katherine Kelly (former owner of Full Circle Farm, Kansas City) and Daniel Dermitzel (former co-owner of Trailside Farm in Calhoun, Missouri) were inspired by a common vision of city farming that includes: 
 
-Small, community-based farms scattered throughout the metro, providing an abundance of fresh and healthy food to city residents, 

-New opportunities for people who would like to farm and generate an income doing so, 

-A new kind of urban design that turns unused, vacant and unsightly spaces to productive use and treats small-scale agriculture as an integral part of a beautiful, lively and healthy neighborhood. 

To realize this vision, the Center develops training and research programs for new and experienced farmers and for city planners and community members interested in city farming. Additionally, the Center operates the Kansas City Community Farm (KCCF), a working, certified organic vegetable farm where we develop and demonstrate production practices suitable for Midwestern urban agriculture. 

1. We see a place that will beautify and diversify the cityscape; a physical space where people gather to work, learn and exchange.

2. We envision a place abundant with life; life in the soil and in the field; a place of great diversity of plant and animal life; a home for creatures such as field mice, rabbits, birds, honeybees, and other insects; an example of nature and humans collabor

3. We see a place where diversity is valued as a source of strength in human culture much as it is in organic agriculture; a place rich in diversity of species as well as cultures, beliefs, practices and traditions. We see people from all sorts of paths, pla

4. We see a place where people learn about life cycles, trust, and cooperation, through close engagement with the natural processes of agriculture and food production.

5. We envision a place for on-farm research on topics from pest control and low-technology season extension to crop development; a place designed to encourage creativity and new thinking about how to make small-scale organic agriculture work; a place where f

6. We see a place that serves as a practical example of &#8220;farming in the city&#8221; for those who grew up on small farms in rural America or abroad and who wish to keep their agricultural heritage alive and to make agriculture a viable part of their lives in K

7. We envision a place where we connect with the world community through lectures, exhibits, and exchanges;  a place where we learn about the world's farmers, their challenges, triumphs, beliefs and hopes.

8. We envision a place where we learn not to say "it can't be done!" because we know that somewhere, in some corner of this world, somebody is probably doing it. </description>
  <mission>Promote community-based, small-scale, entrepreneurial farming in urban Kansas City.</mission>
  <name>Kansas City Center for Urban Agriculture</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3132</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">75</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">145.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vz/2p/yD/xB/qn/5V/XSqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
