<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It began long ago, but the shock really hit me at the death of Anna Nicole Smith. I turned on the news one afternoon to find that news reporters, young men and women who attended four to six years of college to deliver hard-hitting news, were reporting that there had finally been a lead as to who the real father of Ms. Smith's baby was.  
&lt;BR&gt; &lt;BR&gt;
I couldn't recall when CNN had become The E! Channel. I was distraught with the idea that this was not only being fed to me everywhere, but that I was being informed on the life of a drug-addicted slut.
&lt;BR&gt; &lt;BR&gt;
It all reigns even truer today as we wait to find out if Paris Hilton will stay in jail, or again be confined to the luxery of her own home for a DUI she was awarded for on VH1. This is what is wrong with us: these ladies should not be celebrated for their ignorance and slutty behavior, nor should they even be dignified with our attention. I was fortunate enough to witness one reporter respond to an Email that he will stop delivering news on Hilton when the public stops paying attention.
&lt;BR&gt; &lt;BR&gt;
It is people like them and reality shows such as Laguna Beach that are giving children and young adults false impressions of what life is all about: partying; hooking up; and spending your parents' money. These examples skew the mind of what a hero should be. How long can a divorced mother of three work two jobs to support her family, on top of going to school, when all her daughter cares about is Lindsay Lohan's new shoes?
&lt;BR&gt; &lt;BR&gt;
Don't get me wrong, shows like 'Made' and 'Beauty &amp; The Geek' are great and help the insecure become who they want to be.  Other shows do not, and serve no useful entertainment value.  While I understand that this is the mostly the fault of neglectful parents, I'd like you to ask yourself, next time you watch TV, "What is this doing for me?"

1. Do not donate to this group (though Childrens Hospital is pretty great). I don't want your money, just your awareness.

2. Be aware of what your pouring into your head.

3. Ignorance is not bliss.

4. Books are great.

5. So is Mythbusters.</description>
  <mission>to redefine the definition of "Entertainment."</mission>
  <name>Stop Global Ignorance</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3142</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jV/Sl/mY/Da/Jq/rl/SJNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
