<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>NSF programs include:

1. Far-reaching public education and awareness initiatives such as National Sleep Awareness Week&#174; and Drive Alert&#8230;Arrive Alive&#174;. NSF produces educational materials for the general public, such as our award-winning news magazine sleepmatters, brochures, videotapes and more. Media relations activities have garnered more than one billion media impressions each year.

2. Government relations and advocacy efforts to address legislative and regulatory issues related to sleep, alertness and safety, such as hours-of-service rules for commercial drivers. In addition, NSF advocates for federal funding of research and educational initiatives. Government relations staff works regularly with federal agencies as well as members and staff of key congressional committees.

3. Support of research through Pickwick Club fellowships. In addition, our highly respected annual public opinion surveys cover general information such as Americans' sleep habits, beliefs, and concerns, as well as specific topics, such as the impact of sleep problems on work productivity, women and sleep, and the effect of pain on sleep.

4. Outreach to healthcare providers to enhance primary care givers' understanding of sleep-related problems and treatments and to provide sleep medicine clinicians with tools to help them expand their reach and make positive changes within their communities. Publications targeted toward medical professionals include Sleep Medicine Alert newsletter and "white papers" on topics such as insomnia and melatonin.

The National Sleep Foundation (NSF) relies on grants, sponsorships, memberships and other contributions to help us provide comprehensive education and awareness programs. In addition, we actively collaborate with other concerned organizations - sleep centers, support groups for patients with sleep disorders, safety organizations, and many more - to help spread our important messages and improve public health.

1. Americans need to be aware that their sleep is an important component of their health and safety, and that they make obtaining sufficient sleep a priority.

2. Americans should recognize the signs and symptoms of sleep disorders and seek effective treatment for them.

3. Make new sleep-related discoveries that optimize public health and detection and treatment of sleep disorders.</description>
  <mission>To improve the quality of life for Americans who suffer from sleep problems and disorders.</mission>
  <name>National Sleep Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3144</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">149</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/XB/4t/IJ/1F/2P/cO/2siS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
