<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In the past few years, while the number of AIDS victims is steadily declining in the United States, in Europe, Asian, and Africa the number of AIDS cases is increasing by the thousands. The rate of AIDS growth in many of these countries is increasing faster than anywhere else in the world. The AIDS problem, however, is atleast two-fold as put by the WHO. Not only is money an obvious issue, as finding a cure comes with a mighty price tag, as does treatment, but the second issue of education  poses another massive roadblock. Until we can begin to educate everyone, not just the socio-economically privileged, there is no hope of stopping this epidemic anywhere in the world. The last anchor that the AIDS epidemic holds in Europe is the stronghold because of drug use. In many of the regions that have large amounts of drug use - there are also corresponding high numbers of AIDS victims. Again, until we can reach out to those who are not socio-economically privileged and help them - we cannot stop the epidemic.


A couple websites to check out:
1. http://www.unaids.org/
1a. http://data.unaids.org/pub/EpiReport/2006/20061121_EPI_FS_EECA_en.pdf
2. http://www.aidsactioneurope.org/
3. http://www.hrw.org
4. http://www.euro.who.int/healthtopics/HT2ndLvlPage?HTCode=hiv_infections

Post your own findings and educate those around you... this is not going away.

1. The spread of the AIDS epidemic must be stopped in Europe, Asia, and Africa through education, awareness, and a cure.</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness for the growing number of AIDS victims in European, Asian, and African Countries</mission>
  <name>Global AIDS Epidemic Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3151</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">42</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/HE/85/iI/TN/zD/OP/1BTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
