<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>MERGE is a newly formed non-profit organization that is geared towards raising the awareness of global issues through merging the talents of various artists (dancers, singers, actors, visual artists). We are striving to make our world a much nicer place to live and love. our main goals is to raise monies, through variety shows, and give to a charity of our choice. This year we are giving to the "Go Zero" Conservation Fund.

The Conservation Fund:

The Conservation Fund is the nation&#8217;s foremost environmental nonprofit dedicated to protecting America&#8217;s most important landscapes and waterways for future generations. The Conservation Fund pioneers a balanced, non-advocacy, non-membership approach to conservation, one that blends environmental and economic goals and objectives. Since its founding in 1985, the Fund has helped its partners safeguard wildlife habitat, working farms and forests, community greenspace, and historic sites totaling more than 5.5 million acres nationwide. 

GO ZERO:

Climate change has become the most pressing environmental issue of this century. But while most Americans agree that we must do something, the challenge seems too great, too complicated for any one of us to make a difference -- until now. 

The Conservation Fund has launched a new program that makes it easy and affordable for individuals, corporations, or even entire communities to Go ZeroSM by measuring and then offsetting their carbon dioxide emissions &#8211; simply by planting trees. 



The above information and more can be found by visiting : http://www.conservationfund.org/gozero




1. Offsetting the carbon dioxide emissions will better the health of our community.</description>
  <mission>help measure and then offset carbon dioxide emissions by planting trees.</mission>
  <name>MERGE goes Zero!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3154</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">52</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Em/vX/yr/qW/aN/1Z/CBDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
