<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>ONE is an effort by Americans to rally Americans &#8211; ONE by ONE &#8211; to fight the emergency of global AIDS and extreme poverty. ONE is students and ministers, punk rockers and NASCAR moms, Americans of all beliefs and every walk of life, united as ONE to help make poverty history. ONE believes that allocating an additional ONE percent of the U.S. budget toward providing basic needs like health, education, clean water and food would transform the futures and hopes of an entire generation in the world's poorest countries. ONE also calls for debt cancellation, trade reform and anti&#8211;corruption measures in a comprehensive package to help Africa and the poorest nations beat AIDS and extreme poverty.

ONE Declaration:
"WE BELIEVE that in the best American tradition of helping others help themselves, now is the time to join with other countries in a historic pact for compassion and justice to help the poorest people of the world overcome AIDS and extreme poverty. WE RECOGNIZE that a pact including such measures as fair trade, debt relief, fighting corruption and directing additional support for basic needs - education, health, clean water, food, and care for orphans - would transform the futures and hopes of an entire generation in the poorest countries, at a cost equal to just one percent more of the US budget. WE COMMIT ourselves - one person, one voice, one vote at a time - to make a better, safer world for all."

1. Reduce by half the number of people in the world who suffer from hunger, resulting in 300 million "fewer" hungry people each year.

2. Save 15,000 lives a day by fighting HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis and malaria, three of the world's most devastating diseases.

3. Improve the living conditions of vulnerable populations by, for example, providing access to clean water for 450 million people and basic sanitation to more than 700 million people.

4. Provide free access to primary education for 77 million out-of-school children with a special emphasis on girls.

5. Prevent 5.4 million young children from dying each year from poverty-related illnesses and 400,000 women from dying in childbirth each year</description>
  <mission>Making Poverty History</mission>
  <name>ONE!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3193</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">159</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/i0/QH/bO/Ri/Hq/1f/DOgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
