<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Historical Land Loss in Coastal Louisiana - Louisiana has lost 1,900 square miles of land since the 1930's. Currently Louisiana has 30% of the total coastal marsh and accounts for 90% of the coastal marsh loss in the lower 48 states.

Louisiana's Historic Land Loss in Perspective - During the 20th century, coastal Louisiana lost 1.2 million acres of land, and if nothing is done, could potentially lose another 435,000 acres in the next 50 years. The acreage lost and projected to be lost over this 100 plus year period is greater than the size of Delaware, and the Washington, DC-Baltimore, MD metropolitan area combined.

Population Living in the Coastal Parishes * Pre Katrina - Over 2 million residents, more than 50% of the state's population according to the U.S. Census estimates, lived in Louisiana's coastal parishes.

Louisiana Offshore Oil Port (LOOP) - Louisiana Offshore Oil Port (LOOP), located approximately 20 mile's off Louisiana's Gulf Coast, is the largest U.S. oil import terminal and handles about one million (1,000,000) barrels of crude oil a day.

Commercial Fishing - In 2002 Louisiana commercial landings exceeded 1 billion pounds with a dockside value of $343 million, that accounts for approximately 30% of the total catch by weight in the lower 48 states.

Recreational Fishing - Annual expenditures related to non-commercial fishing in Louisiana can amount to between $703 million and $1.2 billion.

Hunting - In 2001, expenditures in Louisiana amounted to $446 million.

Wildlife-watching - In 2001, expenditures related to wildlife-watching in Louisiana amounted to $168 million.

Fur Harvest - Trapping in Louisiana coastal wetlands generates approximately $2 million annually.

Alligator Harvest - The Louisiana alligator harvest is valued at approximately $30 million annually.

Waterfowl - Louisiana's coastal wetlands provide habitat for over 5 million migratory waterfowl.

1. Restore the vitality of the Louisiana Wetlands

2. Use oil revenue from the Louisiana Gulf Coast to fund the restoration caused mainly by the oil industry's use of the wetlands.</description>
  <mission>Rebuild the wetland along the Louisiana Gulf Coast</mission>
  <name>Louisiana Wetland</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3195</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">533</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/OM/qj/Fd/sD/3O/m8/itHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
