<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Colon Cancer Awareness Foundation (formerly the Charles A. Kraenzle Colon Cancer Foundation) is an all-volunteer organization dedicated to promoting awareness about colon cancer.  Raised funds help reduce the number of deaths from colon cancer through the promotion of early detection, additional research, and increased education and outreach efforts.  Net proceeds will be given to foundations dedicated to the fight against colon cancer, including the Lombardi Comprehensive Cancer Center at Georgetown Hosptial.  In its first foure years, the Charles A Kraenzle Colon Cancer Foundation has donated over $290,000 to awareness and research organizations.

The majority of proceeds are raised through an annual run/walk held in Washington, D.C.  The Fifth Annual Scope It Out 5K Run/Walk for Colon Cancer Awareness, a not-for-profit fundraising/awareness race, will be held at 9:00 a.m. on Sunday, March 29, 2009, at our new downtown Washington D.C. location begining at Freedon Plaza, during National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month.  The 5K has been reported as one of the fastest growing races in the region.  For more information, visit www.scopeitout5k.com.

1. Colorectal cancer is curable 90% of the time when detected early. 

2. Most of these deaths can be prevented by getting a colonoscopy at age 50, or earlier with a family history.   A colonoscopy is a screening test which 

3. Everyone should be screened at age 50, even when there is no family history, since 70 to 75% of colon cancer cases fall into this category.

4. The earlier colorectal cancer is detected, the more curable it is. </description>
  <mission>Increase awareness of, encourage early detection of, and support research efforts in fighting colon cancer</mission>
  <name>Scope It Out! -- Support Colon Cancer Research and Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3206</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1750</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">613.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Vw/Aj/PY/7o/DE/PR/QsSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
