<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>If you or anyone you know has been through an ordeal with Pseudotumor Cerebri or another neurological condition, please join this cause to offer your support.  If you have been suffering with some or any of these symptoms (see below), please contact your health care provider as soon as possible.  Catching it early is key!!!  


About PTC: &lt;br&gt;
Pseudotumor Cerebri (Intracranial Hypertension) is encountered most frequently in young women between the ages of 20 and 45. Headache is the most common presenting complaint, occurring in more than 90 percent of cases. Dizziness, nausea, and vomiting may also be encountered, but typically there are no alterations of consciousness or higher cognitive function. Tinnitus, or a "rushing" sound in the ears, is another frequent complaint. Visual symptoms are present in up to 70 percent of all patients with PTC, and include transient visual obscurations, general blurriness, and intermittent horizontal diplopia. These symptoms tend to worsen in association with Valsalva maneuvers and changes in posture. Reports of ocular pain, particularly with extreme eye movements, have also been noted.  Optic examinations of patients with suspected Pseudotumor Cerebri often reveal an eye condition called Papilledema, in which the optic disk is swollen, and permanent visual impairment may occur.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;

1. Young women and men need to know signs and symptoms of PTC to catch it early.

2. Young women and men who already have PTC need support to get through it.

3. Friends and family of PTC patients can show their support by joining this cause.

4. PTC survivors can lend support to current PTC patients by joining this cause.</description>
  <mission>To create awareness and support for a dangerous neurological and optical condition becoming more and more common among women (and sometimes men) in their 20's.  </mission>
  <name>Pseudotumor Cerebri (Intracranial Hypertension) Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3211</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1081</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jG/ef/X2/rQ/dk/0k/Hh4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
