<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Mission Lazarus is a quickly growing organization holistic ministry based out of Choluteca, Honduras. In the past few years with the help of many across the world, Mission Lazarus has raised millions of dollars for the building of wells, the construction of sturdy, long-lasting homes for the homeless, for the feeding of hundreds through the nutrition and family programs, for the healing of thousands through the lazarus clinic, for the education of hundreds of children through the Early Childhood Development Centers, for the training of farmers, preachers, teachers, carpenters, masons, blacksmiths, and sewers, and for the planting of churches throughout all of southern Honduras. 

100% of your donations will go DIRECTLY to the projects and ministries of Mission Lazarus, with 100% of the efforts seeking to meet the needs of those who are in the most desperate of need. The missionaries who work with Mission Lazarus raise their own support, which allows every penny that's given to go directly to Mission Lazarus. 

official website @: www.missionlazarus.org 
follow us: www.twitter.com/missionlazarus 
watch: www.youtube.com/user/missionlazarus

1. Everyone should be enriched holistically: Mind, Body &amp; Soul.

2. Everyone should have the opportunity to learn, and then to in turn, teach others.

3. Every child should have a home and a family to care for them.

4. Small donations from ordinary people can make a world of difference when used wisely.</description>
  <mission>A holistic ministry dedicated to primary education, skill development, health education and treatment, agricultural development, and preaching and teaching the word of God.</mission>
  <name>Mission Lazarus</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3214</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1119</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">794.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/D6/QQ/WI/G5/oO/OM/UE/irS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
