<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Goodwill is a network of 205 community-based, autonomous member organizations in the United States, Canada, and 22 other countries. Goodwill provides job training and career services to people with disabilities, welfare recipients, dislocated workers and other job seekers. The organization trains people for careers in fields such as financial services, computer programming and health care. Since its founding in 1902, more than 8 million people have benefited from Goodwill's employment programs, and in 2005 collectively over 846,000 individuals were served.

To pay for its programs, Goodwill collects and sells donated clothes, shoes, furniture and other items in its over 2,000 stores and on its Internet auction site shopgoodwill.com which is operated by the Orange County Goodwill. As of 2005, an average 62% of a Goodwill's operating revenue was derived from its resale stores. The organization also earns revenue and creates jobs by contracting with businesses and government to provide a wide range of commercial services, including janitorial work, packaging and assembly, food service preparation, and document management and destruction.  Goodwill also receives public and private support &#8211; it is a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization, though on average only 2% of its 2005 funding came from monetary donations.

To mark its centennial in 2002, Goodwill launched an international development project--the Goodwill Industries 21st Century Initiative--to help 20 million people enter the workforce and move up the career ladder by the year 2020. Last year, local Goodwills collectively provided employment and training services to more than 930,775 individuals.

http://www.goodwill.org/

http://www.goodwillindy.org/



1. We at Goodwill Industries will be satisfied only when every person in the global community has the opportunity to achieve his/her fullest potential as an individual and to participate and contribute fully in all aspects of a productive life.</description>
  <mission>Enhance the quality and dignity of life by eliminating barriers to opportunity for people with special needs and by facilitating empowerment, self-help and service through local organizations</mission>
  <name>Goodwill Industries - Help Your Community!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3219</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">92</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xS/25/xG/lH/Pu/MP/JM3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
