<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"For more than 55 years, United Cerebral Palsy (UCP) has been committed to change and progress for persons with disabilities. The national organization and its nationwide network of affiliates strive to ensure the inclusion of persons with disabilities in every facet of society&#8212;from the Web to the workplace, from the classroom to the community. As one of the largest health charities in America, the mission of United Cerebral Palsy is to advance the independence, productivity and full citizenship of people with disabilities through an affiliate network. 

We strive to build a better world for tomorrow&#8212;today. The backbone of United Cerebral Palsy is the services that are provided by our affiliates. UCP affiliates serve more than 170,000 children and adults with disabilities and their families every day. Our affiliates provide services such as housing, therapy, assistive technology training, early intervention programs, individual and family support, social and recreation programs, community living, state and local referrals, employment assistance and advocacy. Each affiliate offers a range of services tailored to its community's needs. 

The United Cerebral Palsy National Office, located in Washington, D.C., provides direct support to the affiliates via fundraising, marketing and communications, best practices, and programmatic support to name a few. We also serve people with disabilities and their families through the development of forward-thinking programs, information and referral service, legislative advocacy, technology initiatives and research."

-UCP.org


Cerebral Palsy is a common birth defect with many different atributes, running the gauntlet from a slight limp or paralysis, to severe cases involving little or no control of the body, and in some cases, developmental delays. C.P. is often caused due to a brain injury at or around birth, and is caused usually by lack of oxygen to the brain. In some rare cases, C.P. can happen to a child as late in development as 3 years of age as a result of an accident or child abuse.About two of every 1,000 babies born suffer from the defect, but continue to shine, overcoming their disabilities and  living an practicully  normal life. Several C.P. Celeberties include Josh Blue of "Last Comic Standing" fame, Christy Brown, who wrote the book "My Left Foot", and Stephen Hopkins, a signer of the US Declaration of Independence.

Many people see those with disabilities as helpless, but organizations such as UCP help change that perception and open a window of opprotunity to those with disabilities. UCP provides education and support for the public, in hopes that one day, all people with disabilities can flourish with no boundries.

1. To educate people on Disability awareness

2. To raise awareness of C.P.

3. To help those with C.P. and other disabilities become included and accepted in their community, as well as to live life to the fullest. </description>
  <mission>The mission of United Cerebral Palsy is to advance the independence, productivity and full citizenship of people with disabilities through an affiliate network. </mission>
  <name>United Cerebral Palsy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3226</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2249</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">234.35</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cT/43/L0/A2/AV/zM/3C/fBS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
