<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Lift Kids is a Minnesota-based nonprofit service enterprise taking action on the plight of impoverished children via a philanthropic franchise model centered around what we call the Lift Kids Village. We have assembled a volunteer corps of experts ready to go build villages and seed sustainable change..

Without concern for boundaries, borders, or divisions of any kind, we go to the places where children are starving and dying every day and build Lift Kids Villages that both alleviate immediate suffering by housing, feeding, and clothing kids, as well as empower them through education and entrepreneurial training.

1. Sustain. Lift Kids Villages are economically and socially self-sustaining. Rather than relying on donations and handouts to cover their operations, they provide opportunities for the children&#8212;even at young ages&#8212;to become part of a family environment t

2. Educate. Each Lift Kids Village will educate on both fundamental knowledge and specific vocational affairs, using curriculum provided by the local government and modified for a comprehensive range, from sex education to social and emotional skills to heal

3.  Replicate. We believe the philanthropic franchise model is the best approach to empowering kids. Because it&#8217;s our model that&#8217;s replicable&#8212;as opposed to our physical building plans&#8212;we replicate outcomes instead of surroundings. This means we can m

4. Volunteer. Voluntourism will serve as an opportunity for investors to observe their investments grow both interpersonally and financially by encouraging their hands-on participation.

5. Empower. Lift Kids Villages teach both in the classroom and through the experience of working with each other and the village management, like a family. Each villager will be given a position of empowerment in running the village&#8217;s sustainability busine</description>
  <mission>feed, shelter, and educate children by partnering with organizations on the ground to create small, sustainable villages according to a model that can be replicated around the world. </mission>
  <name>Lift Kids</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/323</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">804</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">150.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oo2/q0pS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
