<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is the Indianapolis Zen Center?

The Indianapolis Zen Center exists for you. We offer the practice of Zen Buddhism, in a traditional lineage, to central Indiana. Our programs include Introduction to Zen classes, retreats with authentic teachers, public dharma talks, cultural presentations and a weekly schedule of practice sessions. These activities are designed to support and inspire your effort to perceive your true nature.

The Indianapolis Zen Center is a member of the Kwan Um School of Zen, an international organization founded by Zen Master Seung Sahn, the first Korean Zen Master to live and teach in the West. Our center was founded in 1991 and affiliated with the Kwan Um School of Zen in 1996. We invite teachers from within our worldwide school to lead our local retreats, talks, ceremonies and other events.


How do I begin?

The Indianapolis Zen Center offers several ways for people to begin Zen practice. Every Wednesday evening at 6:30PM and every Sunday morning at 8:30AM, a dharma teacher provides a brief orientation for people who wish to attend practice at the center. There is no charge and no appointment is necessary. Please arrive a little early so that you can get settled. Another way to explore practice at the center is our monthly open house&#8212;the first Wednesday of every month at 6:00PM. The open house includes a brief orientation to practice forms. The open house is also free and you don't need to call ahead. In addition, every other month, the Zen Center presents an Introduction to Zen class that provides in-depth instruction in practice forms, history and philosophy. There is a fee for this 5-hour-long class, and advanced registration is required. Those with some practice experience are always welcome to join our regular schedule at the Indianapolis Zen Center without formal orientation and free of charge. 



website: www.indyzen.org


1. Realize Your True Self

2. Help All Beings

3. Participate in a Vibrant Community</description>
  <mission>Show your support for religious diversity within the Indianapolis community.</mission>
  <name>Support the Indianapolis Zen Center</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3237</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">51</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/lG/c0/B4/bn/00/Xu/1HVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
