<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>ACT embraces its responsibility to conserve, renew, and reinvent its relationship to the rich theatrical traditions and literatures that are our collective legacy, while exploring new artistic forms and new communities. A commitment to the highest standards informs every aspect of ACT's creative work.

Founded in 1965 by William Ball, ACT opened its first San Francisco season at the Geary Theater in 1967. In the 1970s, ACT solidified its national and international reputation, winning a Tony Award for outstanding theater performance and training in 1979. During the past three decades, more than 300 ACT productions have been performed to a combined audience of seven million people; today, ACT's performance, education, and outreach programs annually reach more than 250,000 people in the San Francisco Bay Area. 

Today ACT is nationally recognized for its groundbreaking productions of classical works and bold explorations of contemporary playwriting. 

The conservatory, led by Melissa Smith now serving 1,900 students every year, was the first training program in the United States not affiliated with a college or university accredited to award a master of fine arts degree. Danny Glover, Annette Bening, Denzel Washington, Benjamin Bratt and Winona Ryder are among the conservatory's distinguished former students. With its commitment to excellence in actor training and to the relationship between training, performance, and audience, the ACT Master of Fine Arts Program has moved to the forefront of America's actor training programs, while serving as the creative engine of the company at large.

American Conservatory Theater is an artistic community striving to provide leadership and inspiration to the American theater. We invite you to become part of our community by making a gift to A.C.T. Your gift will support not only our productions and actor training, but also programs created to introduce young people and new audiences to the magic of live theater.

1. Nurture the art of live theater.

2. Conserve, renew, and reinvent the rich theatrical traditions and literatures that are our collective legacy.

3. Explore new artistic forms and new communities through ongoing dialogue with our community.</description>
  <mission>ACT nurtures the art of live theater through dynamic productions, intensive actor training in its conservatory, and an ongoing dialogue with its community.</mission>
  <name>American Conservatory Theater</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3253</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">30</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mP/HE/Bv/K3/zk/gf/Zy4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
