<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We Need a Dept. of Peace&#8230; 

To reduce domestic and international violence 
To gather and coordinate information and recommendations from America&#8217;s peace community 
To teach violence prevention and mediation to America&#8217;s school children 
To effectively treat and dismantle gang psychology 
To rehabilitate the prison population 
To build peace-making efforts among conflicting cultures both here and abroad 
To support our military with complementary approaches to ending violence 
  
Proposed Federal Legislation to Establish a U.S. Department of Peace 

Bill was introduced into the U. S. House of Representatives during the 107th, 108th, 109th and now the 110th Congress.  Current bill number is (H.R. 808). Click here to see current co-sponsors.

Proposed legislation calls for the Department&#8217;s budget to be the equivalent of 2% of U.S. defense budget 
  
The Benefits: International 

The Department of Peace will: 

Advise the President, the Secretaries of Defense and State, and others on root causes of violence, plus practical ways to dismantle violence while still in a formative phase 
Support the military by: 
Providing cultural, ethnic and psychologically insightful information, education and technology 
Offering practical skills (conflict resolution techniques, and the like) for the amelioration of violence among adversarial factions 
Administer the training and support of civilian peacekeepers to participate in multinational nonviolent peace forces 
  



1. We must create a market place of ideas on a national level to find the best ways to prevent violence 

2. The United States needs to learn how to win the peace as well as the war.

3. A Dept. of Peace is fiscally responsible as it will effectively coordinate pre-existing efforts.</description>
  <mission>Foster a culture of peace by creating a cabinet level position to advise the President. </mission>
  <name>The US Dept. of Peace Initiative</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/326</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2141</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">120.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qnU/PoCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
