<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Chinese government allows for several million Bibles to be printed in country each year, and, while there are more bibles than ever now in China, it still cannot satisfy the hunger of 70 million Chinese Christians. Many Christians live in small rural villages, far from any stores where Bibles are sold. These people must resort to hand-copying Bibles in order to have something to read and study.

Right now you can help provide a copy of God&#8217;s Word for someone who is hungry for it. By making either a single gift or a monthly commitment, you will help brothers and sisters in China to connect with God through the comfort, power and guidance of His Word.

For only $4 we can send a bible to China to someone who really needs it. As Christians, can we ever even  imagine the frightening thought of not having our own Bibles in our hands. Many of us have several bibles lying around our homes, these people have none. How many times in our lives did we just need a boost and guidance from our Heavenly Father and the first place we search is through His Word in the bible. The Devil especially does not want God's word to be seen in China, lets all come together to Glory our Father through this ministry. Praise God for giving us more ways to extend the Kingdom of Christ.

Thank you for choosing to provide God's Word to the people of China. 

$4 will bring 1 bible to China.
$20 will bring 5 bibles to China.
$100 will send 25 bibles to China.

To donate specifically to Bibles for China, use the link below.

https://www.bible-league.org/blcorp/sbn/index.asp?typeinfo=1

If you'd like information about alternate
giving methods,
call 1-800-YES-WORD
(1-800-937-9673).

And even if the Lord is not calling you to donate at this specific time, you can also help out by sending this Cause to the Christian brothers and sisters you know out there so we are all aware of this shortage and that we may all come together to pray for the furthering of His kingdom in China.

1. There is but one living and true God 

2. The Bible is God`s written revelation to man</description>
  <mission>Share God's Word to the people of China</mission>
  <name>Bibles for China</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3268</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">750</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">355.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nT/VZ/y8/Hh/s2/4H/VaSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
