<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The V Foundation started with the dream of Jim Valvano, the passionate and committed former NC State basketball coach and award-winning broadcaster, as he battled cancer. Wanting to see the battle through to victory, Valvano recruited friends and family to lead The V Foundation in his quest to eradicate the disease that ultimately claimed his life. With a dire need for early developmental, critical-stage grant support, the Foundation was formed to assist the brilliant young researchers that will eventually find cures for cancer. 

As a young organization, The V Foundation has a strong presence in the scientific community that belies its youth. The Foundation&#8217;s Scientific Review Committee, comprised of some of the top physicians and research scientists from prominent universities and cancer centers nationwide, assures that only the cancer research projects with the most potential are funded. Thus, grant recipients funded by The V Foundation have excellent reputations within the scientific community. 

The V Foundation has an excellent track record for finding and funding elite young scientists. Between 1994 -- when the first V Scholar grants were awarded -- and 2003, The V Foundation awarded 109 V Scholar grants to promising young researchers nationwide to help them establish their laboratories. Of those V Scholars, 93 percent have received additional funding and are still working in independent labs. Five percent are currently working in related research. 

The V Foundation also takes great pride in its fiscal responsibility and is proud to announce that it gives 100 percent of all new direct cash donations to cancer research and related programs. Recognized for its prudent fiscal management, The V Foundation has earned a top four-star rating from Charity Navigator, America&#8217;s largest charity evaluator, for a fourth consecutive rating. Receiving a top rating from Charity Navigator indicates that The V Foundation has outperformed most of its peers.


1. The V Foundation is a charitable organization dedicated to saving lives by helping to find a cure for cancer. 

2. The Foundation seeks to make a difference by generating broad-based support for cancer research and by creating an urgent awareness among all Americans of the importance of the war against cancer.

3. The Foundation performs these dual roles through advocacy, education, fundraising, and philanthropy.</description>
  <mission>The V Foundation is a charitable organization and dedicated to saving lives by helping to find a cure for cancer.</mission>
  <name>The V Foundation (Delta Chi's International Philanthropy)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3271</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1778</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2017.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jw/4i/Ia/E6/Cm/0L/Uj7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
