<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>**************************************
http://sites.google.com/site/sulhapeaceproject/

**************************************

................................................................

SULHA is...

               Arabic for RECONCILIATION

                              Hebrew for FORGIVENESS

The Sulha Peace Project is a grassroots organisation that believes in equality, gives everyone a voice and redefines the idea of hope for tolerance in the world between all cultures and religions...this is "the way to Sulha."

A new peace language has been developing throughout the years, since Sulha's first gathering in 2001. 
Its grassroots methodology is expressed through listening circles, multicultural workshops, family &amp; teenage groups,
 interfaith rituals and celebration through the arts, all led by trained facilitators.
It is a concept that is breaking boundaries and creating circles of unity that are growing each day as the word is spread...

For more information visit http://www.sulha.com/

If you live in Israel, Palestine, United States or Australia log on to find out about your local meetings... If you live elsewhere, find out how to start your own!

Remember: 

"IF YOU WILL IT, IT IS NOT A DREAM."
  --Theodore Herzel

1. The way to peace is through rebuilding trust, restoring dignity and taking personal steps to ensure this - moving beyond the political agenda.

2. By people connecting as equal individuals, we can embrace our differences and learn to co-exist.

3. Coming together to share each other's culture is the path to Sulha... Through song, dance, learning and listening.</description>
  <mission>To build trust and restore dignity, from heart to heart and from village to village, moving beyond a specific political agenda, stereotypes, clich&#233;s, humiliation and despair.</mission>
  <name>Sulha Peace Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3280</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4522</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3774.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sr/Eh/Zs/jO/CW/E7/HxiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
