<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Phenylketonuria (PKU) is a genetic inborn error of metabolism that is detectable during the first few days of life by the appropriate blood testing eg. Newborn screen-test.

Persons born with PKU have an absence or deficiency of an enzyme called Phenylalanine Hydroxylase Enzyme. This Enzyme is responsible for processing the essential amino acid &#8220;Phenylalanine&#8221; When the enzyme is present or has normal enzymatic activity Phenylalanine is converted into another amino acid called &#8220;tyrosine&#8221;, which is then utilized by the body.

However when this enzyme is defective Phenylalanine abnormally accumulates in the blood and is toxic to the brain tissue. Without treatment this can cause serious or life threatening side effects like brain damage.

Other effects may include slow development, slow motor skills, behavioral and anger problems, as well as many other neurological symptoms.

To prevent Mental Retardation, treatment consists of a carefully controlled PHE-restricted diet begun in the first few days or weeks or life. This treatment /diet is strongly advised to be continued for life.

A carefully maintained diet can prevent toxic levels in the brain as well as all previously stated symptoms. It is proven that keeping Phenylalanine levels between 2-6 mg/dl is the safest, especially in infants, young children and women of childbearing ages. Frequent blood testing should be done to monitor the levels and to achieve this goal.

 In today&#8217;s world PKU is becoming more and more recognizable then it was 20 yrs ago, as PKU is an inherited automosomal recessive trait. Meaning two people who conceive a child must both be carriers .If both parents are carriers there is a 25% possibility of the child  being  born with PKU ,  50% chance of the child being a carrier them selves and 25% of the child  being neither.  If the same couple conceives more children there is a one in four or 25% chance of PKU in each pregnancy. Though not all siblings will be born with PKU the others will still be PKU carriers and have a chance themselves of having a PKU baby.n today&#8217;s world PKU is becoming more and more recognizable then it was 20 yrs ago, as PKU is an inherited automosomal recessive trait. Meaning two people who conceive a child must both be carriers .If both parents are carriers there is a 25% possibility of the child  being  born with PKU ,  50% chance of the child being a carrier them selves and 25% of the child  being neither.  If the same couple conceives more children there is a one in four or 25% chance of PKU in each pregnancy. Though not all siblings will be born with PKU the others will still be PKU carriers and have a chance themselves of having a PKU baby.

Even with today&#8217;s statistics there is not enough awareness or knowledge of PKU nor is there any coverage for PKU medical foods and supplies. 

*** This issue is extremely important to me as I was diagnosed with CPKU when I was one week old. I am now 23 years old and I value my health above all else.***** 

1. To have low protein foods and treatment covered by the goverments world wide

2. To have an instant home blood monitoring device made avalible to persons with PKU

3. To spread awarness internationally </description>
  <mission>To create and Spread Awarness for PKU , while trying to raise dontations for low pro food and research!</mission>
  <name>Phenylketonuria (PKU)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3301</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1767</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">205.13</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ES/je/ZD/dZ/iP/MV/Xh/RCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
