<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There are between 70 and 80 million landmines in the ground in one-third of the world's nations.  Landmines are indiscriminate weapons that maim or kill 15,000 to 20,000 civilians every year. They cost as little as $3 to produce, but as much as $1000 to remove.
The presence of landmines threatens people&#8217;s lives, and also prevents much-needed ecomonic growth and development. Long after wars are over, landmines  make land unusable for farming, schools or living, preventing people from rebuilding lives torn apart by conflict.

The Bad News
~ At the beginning of the 20th century, nearly 80 per cent of landmine victims were military personnel. Today,  90 per cent of landmine victims are civilians.
~There are 82 mine-affected countries around the world.  No mine clearance was recorded in 16 of the affected countries and no mine risk education activities were recorded in 25 countries.
~From 2002 through to June 2003, there were new landmine casualties reported in 65 countries.  Forty-one of these countries were not at war.
~UNICEF estimates that 30-40 % of all landmine victims are children under the age of 15.  Mines kill and mutilate 8,000 to 10,000 children each year.
 
The Better News
~As of 2004,  Costa Rica,  Djibouti, El Salvador, Kosovo and Moldovahave all been declared mine safe.
~The number of active mines in the world is decreasing.  As of February 2004, a total of 68 signators of the Mine Ban Treaty have destroyed nearly 30.5 million antipersonnel landmines. Fifty-five of these countries have completed stockpile destruction while 13 are in the process of destruction.

All imformation above came from www.landmines.org
You can also go to www.icbl.org or www.landminesblow.com or www.landmines.org.uk to find further information.

1. Support Adopt-A-Mindefield, the ICBL, The One Campaign, and other anti-landmine organizations

2. Get the United States to be a part of the Ban Mine Treaty

3. Rid the world of landmines and prevent the future use of them</description>
  <mission>To rid the world of landmines</mission>
  <name>No More Landmines</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3303</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6041</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">75.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/KF/MQ/hu/u6/HW/xk/HHaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
