<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>*What is autism?*
Autism, part of a group of disorders known as Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASD), is a complex neurobiological disorder that typically lasts throughout a person's lifetime. Developmental disorders that fall under the ASD are Asperger Syndrome, Rett Syndrome, Pervasive Developmental Disorder, and Childhood Disintegrative Disorder. 

*How can I tell if a person is autistic?*
No two people with autism are alike, but there are some signs that many share. People on the spectrum generally have difficulty relating to others; they may hardly speak, and if they do, they may not communicate in ways that other people can easily understand. They don't usually sustain eye contact, and have trouble reading social cues. They're also prone to repetitive behaviors, flapping their hands constantly or uttering the same phrase. They may also be more sensitive than typically developing children to sights, sounds and touch. 

Did you know&#8230;
-   1 in 150 children is diagnosed with autism
-   67 children are diagnosed per day; a new case is diagnosed almost every 20 minutes
-   More children will be diagnosed with autism this year than with AIDS, diabetes &amp; cancer combined
-   Autism is the fastest-growing serious developmental disability in the U.S.
-   Autism costs the nation over $90 billion per year, a figure expected to double in the next decade
-   Unfortunately, experts have been unable thus far to come up with a cure for autism, and there is no medical detection or cure for autism

The New Hampshire Walk in Nashua will be on September 9, 2007 and the Greater Boston Walk will be held on October 13, 2007. 

To Sponsor or Join my team, Toni's Tigers, please visit the following websites:
- New Hampshire walk in Nashua: 
http://www.autismwalk.org/site/TR?pg=personal&amp;fr_id=1534&amp;px=1131551 
- Greater Boston walk: 
http://www.autismwalk.org/site/TR?pg=personal&amp;JServSessionIdr010=23yl7lg0d1.app1a&amp;fr_id=1524&amp;px=1131551


1. Autism Speaks aims to bring the autism community together as one strong voice to urge the government and private sector to listen to our concerns and take action to address this urgent global health crisis. 

2. Autism Speaks is devoted to raising public awareness about autism and its effects on individuals, families, and society. 

3. Autism Speaks is working to bring hope to all who deal with the hardships of this disorder. 

4. Autism Speaks is committed to raising the funds necessary to support these goals. 

5. Autism Speaks is dedicated to funding global biomedical research into the causes, prevention, treatments, and cure for autism. 

6. It is our firm belief that, working together, we will find the missing pieces of the puzzle of Autism. 

7. It's absolutely necessary to have more trained professionals who can work with children with autism. 

8. We need to focus on three major areas in research: genetics, environmental triggers, and brain imaging technology. 

9. We must be committed to researching all potential causes of autism and we invite researchers to submit grant proposals covering a wide spectrum of ideas. 

10. We must find the causes of autism, develop effective biomedical treatments, and hasten the discovery of a cure. 

11. We must work together and complete the puzzle!</description>
  <mission>We will change the future for all who struggle with autism spectrum disorders.</mission>
  <name>Autism Speaks. It's time to Listen!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3310</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3533</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">480.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uj/2D/aL/Ji/st/Za/IPdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
