<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Crohn's and Colitis Foundations (CCFC &amp; CCFA) believes that a cure will be found for Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis. To realize this, the Foundations are committed, first and foremost, to raise increasing funds for medical research.

This year, CCFC research has confirmed what we have suspected for years that the highest rates of inflammatory bowel disease in the world are in Canada, and they are increasing. There is no known cause or cure for IBD.

Crohn's Disease can affect any part of the gastrointestinal tract, from the mouth to the anus. Patches of inflammation occur, with healthy tissue between the diseased areas. The inflammation can extend through every layer of affected bowel tissue. Crohn's disease can not be cured by drugs or surgery, although either or both can help relieve symptoms.

Ulcerative Colitis affects only the inner layer of the colon, or large bowel. It always starts in the rectum and may extend as a continuous inflammation from there into the rest of the colon. Usually ulcerative colitis can be controlled with medication. The disease can be completely eliminated by surgically removing the colon, but afterward, waste material may have to be stored and expelled through an external appliance.

www.ccfc.ca &amp; www.ccfa.org ~ Check It Out! ~

~ I was diagnosed with Crohn's Disease in late 2000. It has been a battle and quite frustrating at times. I have friends &amp; family who are also affected by IBD. We're here for the SUPPORT OF OTHERS and to HELP DO WHAT WE CAN IN THE FIGHT FOR THE CURE! Spread the word! Invite friends &amp; family! ~

Some support &amp; info
www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2218560915

</description>
  <mission>FIND A CURE! ~ Raising awareness, information, support of others and to help raise money. This disease has touched sooo many lives and is increasing rapidly! Let's nip it in the Butt! ~</mission>
  <name>Crohn's &amp; Ulcerative Colitis Foundations</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3312</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2132</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">845.58</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kl/Xp/li/Sc/Ri/M5/zbbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
