<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>To assist young men in their formation as leaders and as "men for others" through a program of rigorous college preparation in the tradition of the Society of Jesus.

Strake Jesuit is a private, Catholic, four-year college preparatory school for young men grades 9-12. The school was founded in 1960 by the New Orleans Province of the Society of Jesus, a religious order of priests and brothers also known as the Jesuits. The Jesuits bring over four and half centuries of tradition and commitment to academic excellence.

Located in southwest Houston, the school physically resembles a small college with its various buildings spread around its forty-four acre campus. This provides the school community with numerous outdoor grassy spaces and shaded areas for gathering and their personal enjoyment.

The current student population numbers approximately 840. Faculty, staff, and administration total over 80 yielding a student-to-teacher ratio of 12:1. In addition, fifty-seven percent of the faculty have advanced degrees in their areas. Ninety-one percent of the student body participates in extracurricular activities directed by numerous members of the school's faculty. The student body&#8211;with thirty percent minorities&#8211;and the staff reflect the diverse character of Houston itself. To ease the burden of tuition for their families, approximately ten percent of the student population receive financial aid totalling approximately $850,000.

Throughout its history, approximately ninety-nine percent of Jesuit's graduates have attended college. The average SAT score for Strake Jesuit students is 1296, over 250 points above the national average


1. We want to keep the Strake Jesuit experience available for all qualified applicants.</description>
  <mission>Educate young men to be "men for others"</mission>
  <name>Strake Jesuit College Preparatory</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3315</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45.04</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3u/NT/Ev/gG/02/Sd/4VzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
