<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Old Time music is the most underrated genre ever; it is a huge part of Appalachian culture that has spread across the United States and even to other parts of the world. It has existed since the roots of America were planted as a dance music, and remains the same today, although its roots have branched out to more creative outlets of old time music.  Technically classified as a North American folk music, old time music is so much more; in the past 300 years, it hasn't changed its core meaning due to its unbelieveable magical essence. Old time music is NOT bluegrass, but instead,  the founder of bluegrass.  We don't mind playing for audiences, but old time musicians would rather spend their days and evenings on the porch in the mountains playing tunes after tunes, holding a human connection that is difficult to find anywhere else.  We live the simple life. This isn't for Old Crow Medicine Show fans, and this isn't for O Brother Where Art Thou.  This cause is for all the dropthumbin', fiddlin, guitar-playin', bass-thumpin', flatfootin', music-understandin' people out there. Let's end the stereotypes and continue on like we always have...in peace, in happiness, and most of all, in harmony! The revitalization of old time music has never ended; you can be a part of the hillbilly revolution today! 

1. Old time music should be played all the time

2. We gotta pass this on to our children

3. Everyone should respect our innovative talent instead of labeling us with stereotypes

4. Music makes the world a better place

5. Live the simple life; understand one another. Play music!</description>
  <mission>For old time musicians &amp; friends of old time music.  </mission>
  <name>Preservin' Old Time Music!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3317</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">367</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zy/RJ/LM/wY/Ou/mt/ZUuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
