<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In the late 1970's, the Washington Park Zoo in Portland, Oregon (now called the Oregon Zoo) transformed an old concessions stand into what we now know as the Insect Zoo. Back then, it was deemed unsuitable for a food service environment, so with the help of an entomologist it became home to several representatives of the enormous population of arthropods (insects, spiders, crustaceans, etc.). Since the 1990s, it has been staffed by a passionate group of teen volunteers who would be active in teaching the zoo's visitors about these creatures. But in 2002, it was decided that the structure was no longer safe for volunteers, and has had its windows closed as an inactive station. However, the actions of just a few teenagers prompted the zoo to reopen the program despite the poor condition of the building. Until current projects at the zoo are completed, the budget committee cannot plan for a new insectarium; this could take 10-20 years.


But there is hope. A small number of ZooTeens have decided to take a stand. This group has decided to spearhead the task of raising at least $250,000 for a new structure. These high school and college teens agree that an insect program at the zoo is imperative; without one, it's cheating the animal kingdom of its most important representatives.



ATTENTION: DO NOT YET DONATE!! I need to iron out some kinks with the funding situation, so check back soon for an update.

1. Arthropods are the most diverse and important group of animals on the planet.

2. The Oregon Zoo needs an adequate place to represent these animals to educate and inspire the community to create a better future for them.

3. As teenagers, we have the drive to solve thisw issue.</description>
  <mission>Provide the publicity to get funds to build a new Insect Zoo at the Oregon Zoo</mission>
  <name>The Bug Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3323</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">35</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yD/aA/qT/cs/nT/DI/BVuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
