<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>FACTS ABOUT ANGELMAN SYNDROME
Introduction
In 1965, Dr. Harry Angelman, an English physician, first described three children with characteristics now known as the Angelman syndrome (AS). 1 He noted that all had a stiff, jerky gait, absent speech, excessive laughter and seizures. Other cases were eventually published but the condition was considered to be extremely rare at that time, and many physicians doubted its existence. The first reports from North America appeared in the early 1980s. Dr. Angelman relates the following regarding his discovery of this syndrome. 2 


AS has been reported throughout the world among divergent racial groups. In North America, the great majority of known cases seem to be of Caucasian origin. Although the exact incidence of AS is unknown, an estimate of 1 in 15,000 to 1 in 20,000 seems reasonable based a general assessment of the few surveys that have been conducted. 3-9 


Developmental and Physical Features
Angelman syndrome is usually not recognized at birth or in infancy since the developmental problems are nonspecific during this time. Parents may first suspect the diagnosis after reading about AS or meeting a child with the condition. The most common age of diagnosis is between three and seven years when the characteristic behaviors and features become most evident. A summary of the developmental and physical findings has been published for the purpose of establishing clinical criteria for the diagnosis and these are listed below. 10 All of the features do not need to be present for the diagnosis to be made and the diagnosis is often first suspected when the typical behaviors are recognized. 





1. Raise awareness of this rare genetic disorder

2. To raise funds for education, support, advocacy and research on behalf of persons with Angelman Syndrome

3. Further funding for Angels over the age of 21 yrs.</description>
  <mission>Bring awareness to this rare genetic disorder and help my daughter Madison Burleau with her journey through life with this syndrome. </mission>
  <name>Angelman Syndrome Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3325</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1387</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">95.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ln/H5/BB/vL/0Y/ok/Xa/hiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
