<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Casa Hogar Sion is an Orphanage in Tijuana Mexico. The original name of the orphanage was "El Faro" (the lighthouse) a group of volunteers started "Friends of El Faro" and kept the name.

In 1999 Mama Carmen and Papa Jorge Gonzales opened the doors of their home to a few abandoned children living on the streets. Word spread and in a very short amount of time children were being dropped off in the middle of the night by relatives who could not care for them, or were frightened because of a history of abuse. Through the efforts of affiliated churches and independent groups, private and corporate donors, there are now 7 buildings, and over 100 children. Now all the children are going to school, some of the older children are in private school and trade tech. There is a computer lab and classes running five days a week. Mama and Papa not only want to protect and take care of their children, they wants to provide them with opportunity and hope that only education can provide. 

This Cause is to raise awareness and money benefiting the children at Casa Hogar Sion. You can donate directly here through Causes (they change a small fee for their administration) or consider going to www.FriendsofElFaro.com and donating directly. 

Friends of El Faro is a 501(c)3 non-profit organization run by volunteers. 

Thank you so much for reading about Friends of El Faro and Casa Hogar Sion and our Cause. 

- Mason 
Friends of El Faro volunteer


1. Love, Shelter &amp; Help Educate the children

2. Help them build a new permanent home

3. Educate them to become self-sufficient</description>
  <mission>To improve the lives of the children of Casa Hogar Sion anyway we can. Longer term our goal is to help them build a new permanent home and become self-sufficient.</mission>
  <name>Friends of El Faro (Casa Hogar Sion orphanage)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3328</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1150</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5264.7</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/t0/kA/8Q/d8/EI/2n/ai/kRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
