<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Postpartum depression is caused by changes in hormones and can run in families. Women with severe premenstrual syndrome are more likely to suffer from postpartum depression. Mild or moderate depression, either postpartum or otherwise, can be treated with medication or with psychotherapy, or, particularly for women with severe cases, a combination of the two. Women who have postpartum depression love their children but may be convinced that they're not able to be good mothers.

About one in 10 new mothers experience some degree of postpartum depression. These complications usually occur within just days after the delivery, and can occur even a year later. These symptoms include:

    * Sluggishness
    * Fatigue
    * Exhaustion
    * Feelings of hopelessness or depression
    * Disturbances with appetite and sleep
    * Confusion
    * Uncontrollable crying
    * Lack of interest in the baby
    * Fear of harming the baby or oneself
    * Mood swings &#8211; highs and lows

Treatment for postpartum depression
Women need to be taken seriously when these symptoms occur. Generally a combination of psychotherapy and medication can reduce these symptoms. The ideal treatment plan includes:

    * Medical evaluation to rule out physiological problems
    * Psychiatric evaluation
    * Psychotherapy
    * Possible medication
    * Support group

It is imperative that women being treated for postpartum depression continue with treatment even after they feel better, because if they stop the treatment prematurely, symptoms can recur.

Postpartum mood episodes with psychotic features appear to occur in from 1 in 500 to 1 in 1,000 deliveries.



1. New mothers should not be embarrassed when faced with PPD.

2. There must be more acceptness and treatments readily available for women suffering from PPD or any type of depression.

3. It is never the mother's fault and she should never be blamed.</description>
  <mission>Educate people about Postpartum Depression</mission>
  <name>Postpartum Depression (PPD) Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3330</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1942</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">290.19</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Pj/Io/Vl/Fy/U1/vO/ty0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
