<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Children&#8217;s Miracle Network Dance Marathon program is a multi-hour event which blends dancing, music, games food and entertainment into one experience where students raise funds for kids treated at local Children&#8217;s Miracle Network hospitals. Students participate by staying awake and on their feet for a full 12 hours, all to raise money for Children&#8217;s Miracle Network. Volunteer dancers enthusiastically take part by dancing the day away while being entertained by various live bands, DJs, comedians, and various other forms of performances. Miracle Families from Central Florida come and share their stories of how Children&#8217;s Miracle Network has impacted their lives and in doing so inspire the dancers to stay energetic. This event challenges the dancers both mentally and physically, symbolizing the challenges faced everyday by the children treated at the local CMN affiliated hospitals: Shands Children&#8217;s Hospital at the University of Florida and Arnold Palmer Hospital for Children located in Orlando. 

Rollins College's First Annual Dance Marathon Event will be held on November 10, 2007.
If you are interested in registering, visit our website at 
http://www.rollins.edu/organizations/dancemarathon/

Also, check out our awesome video to see what we are all about!

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fBFzSwM2Ok4


If you are interested in helping out, contact Sara Patrick at SPatrick@rollins.edu or Kyndra Short at kshort@rollins.edu

1. Children are our future and each one deserves excellent medical care

2. Dance for life.</description>
  <mission>Raise money for Children's Miracle Network with the help of the Rollins campus and community.</mission>
  <name>Rollins College Dance Marathon -CMN</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3332</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">37</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sI/0V/Kb/ey/iC/PM/TibS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
