<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The goals of the National Prostate Cancer Coalition:

Awareness 
-------------------------------------------------------------

The National Prostate Cancer Coalition aims to educate every American about the risk of prostate cancer, the importance of early detection and the research funding needed to beat the disease. We have built a network of partners from Former New York City Mayor Rudy Giuliani to NASCAR, to create effective awareness campaigns like Do It For Dad, and Prostate Cancer Awareness Month.


Outreach 
-------------------------------------------------------------

The National Prostate Cancer Coalition manages the only national mobile prostate cancer screening clinic, the Drive Against Prostate Cancer, reaching out to at-risk and underserved communities by offering free, complete and confidential screenings. So far, the program has screened over 45,000 men.


Advocacy 
-------------------------------------------------------------

The National Prostate Cancer Coalition actively works with government officials to increase federal funding for prostate cancer research, by partnering with top-notch organizations representing high-risk groups such as African Americans and Veterans.

At our annual Spring Training, the personal stories and experiences of advocates from across the country bring the issue of prostate cancer research funding to life for elected officials, and have a critical impact on the outcome of funding decisions. Since NPCC was founded in 1996, annual federal funding has increased 5-fold.




1. Increase Awareness

2. Increase Outreach

3. Increase Advocacy</description>
  <mission>To raise awareness and funds to help fight prostate cancer.</mission>
  <name>Help Fight Prostate Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3338</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4492</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1247.68</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kn/PL/cL/Cx/Od/SX/7upS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
