<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Manchester College respects the infinite worth of every individual and graduates persons of ability and conviction who draw upon their education and faith to lead principled, productive, and compassionate lives that improve the human condition.

Values Statement
As a primarily undergraduate, residential, liberal arts community rooted in the tradition of the Church of the Brethren, Manchester College values:

&#8226;  Learning, because high academic expectations in an environment combining liberal arts and professional preparation equip graduates to live healthy, productive, and principled lives;

&#8226;  Faith, because our diverse faiths call us to make the world a kinder and better place, establish justice, build peace amid strife, and model lives of agape (selfless love), tikkun olam (repairing a broken world), and salam (peace);

&#8226;  Service, because committing self in service to others connects faith with action and abilities with convictions;

&#8226;  Integrity, because honesty and trust are the foundations of teaching and learning, enriching, enduring relationships, and strong communities;

&#8226;  Diversity, because understanding differences develops respect for ethnic, cultural, and religious pluralism; an international consciousness; and an appreciation for the infinite worth of every person; and

&#8226;  Community, because a positive community sharpens self-identity, promotes acceptance of the demands of responsible citizenship, and transforms conflict into mutual respect. 

1. Learning

2. Faith

3. Service

4. Integrity

5. Diversity

6. Community</description>
  <mission>Graduate persons of ability and conviction who draw upon their education and faith to lead principled, productive, and compassionate lives that improve the human condition.</mission>
  <name>Manchester College</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3340</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">282</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DT/TI/EY/Ke/up/Rk/I2/UaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
