<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I found a dream...This is a future project

Chapter One:
In about a year time I and some partners of me are moving to Zomba, a small region in central Malawi. The first target is to buy a big piece of land. When this land is found and purchased, there will be collected a crew: of local farmers, local chiefs, all civil society organisations with each one representative each, and together with voluntary architect&#8217;s, to draw a sketch of a community farm. 

When the Farm is constructed we will use all the raw material that exists in the local community , we will use the local traditional methods for constructing as long a it will not pose a health treats for the people which are doing the constructions, neither for the people living there after the buildings are constructed. 

All these past activities are estimated to endure for 6 months at maximum. 

Chapter two:
Hopefully in the end there will be at disposal for the project:
&#8226;	Own or rent big area of land (relative) 
&#8226;	At least two barns 
&#8226;	A house with learning facilities (classrooms)
&#8226;	Electricity 
&#8226;	A pump to collect water 
&#8226;	Several small houses for voluntary workers
&#8226;	A stable for horses and other animals
&#8226;	Toilets and bathrooms for large groups of people
&#8226;	Emergency diesel engine for production of electricity

  Chapter three:
It will suppose to have an income sum so it will not depend on donors. If you mix local knowledge with other knowledge you will get the best result, but the daily managers will be local. I hope that there will be built many bedrooms, for voluntaries they will receive housing and food.
Goals:
&#8226;	Farming school- in practice how to farm and be affective

&#8226;	Business school, learn about international trade and how to be an entrepreneur and a farmer at once. 

&#8226;	Animal holding and breeding

&#8226;	Children playground 

&#8226;	Farming and testing new methods 

&#8226;	Growing a big diversity of fruits and vegetables


1. Africa deserves better terms 

2. All humans are equal 

3. Many People suffers due to expliotation

4. Shelter, water and food and none corruptive states should ALL BE EQUAL HUMAN RIGHTS</description>
  <mission>To empower young people ,and to obtain a more stabile rural community in Malawi </mission>
  <name>Farming4life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3346</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">13</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/25/Vd/Gt/yr/7R/NX/Mz5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
