<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>***DONATE TO THIS LINK, NOT THE "DONATE" BUTTON***
http://heartwalk.kintera.org/sandiegoca/walkforjeff

Jeff, my one and only big brother, passed away in February due to heart failure. He leaves behind his new bride of only 9 months, my sister-in-law Christina, and their baby girl, Sienna, who is due in August.

I am helping the American Heart Association fight the nation's leading causes of death by participating in the Heart Walk. Step out against heart disease and stroke by supporting my efforts. I am doing this walk in Jeff's memory.

I have set a personal goal to raise funds for the American Heart Association and need your help to exceed my donation goal! We are raising critical dollars for heart disease and stroke research and education.

You can help me go far and beyond my goal by making a secure online credit card donation at the website below. This American Heart Association's online fundraising website has a minimum donation amount of $25.00. If you prefer to donate less, you can do so by sending the completed donation form and check directly to me. Please make a donation so I can raise more money than I would have ever planned!

Just because I have reached my goal doesn't mean we should stop supporting such a great cause! The more I raise, the better! Please help me in exceeding far and beyond my goal!

Your donation will help fight our nation&#8217;s No. 1 and No. 3 killers &#8212; heart disease and stroke. You are making a difference.

Any little bit that you can donate is very much appreciated. Thank you for your support! :]

***DONATE TO THIS LINK, NOT THE "DONATE" BUTTON***
http://heartwalk.kintera.org/sandiegoca/walkforjeff

1. We must help to fight our nation's #1 &amp; #3 killers - heart disease &amp; stroke.</description>
  <mission>Raise money to support the research of cardiovascular diseases and stroke.</mission>
  <name>Heart Walk 2007 - In Memory of My Brother, Jeff</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3350</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">13</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mz/eW/Sq/nt/0h/O6/nV8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
