<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Climate change is among the greatest threats to biodiversity today. As Earth's temperature rises, wildlife moves to more suitable habitat northward or perhaps to higher elevations. Some coral reef species cannot move, other species are not suited to new ecosystems, and some are simply running out of room to live. Meanwhile, glaciers are melting, ocean chemistry is changing, and entire populations of species are disappearing. If left unchecked, climate change could prompt the extinction of tens of thousands of species in as few as 50 years. 

It is well known that human activity, especially the burning of fossil fuels, causes global warming. However, few people realize that deforestation and land-use changes &#8211; such as slash-and-burn farming, soil degradation and loss, road building, and urban sprawl &#8211; account for as much as 20 percent of global greenhouse gas emissions.

Some 35.1 million acres of tropical forests are destroyed each year, releasing millions of tons of carbon dioxide (CO2) into the atmosphere. Not to mention the significant loss of biodiversity and habitat in each converted acre, or the cumulative loss of ecosystem services for local communities, including storm protection, non-timber forest products, ecotourism potential, and water purification.

Conservation International (CI) is working with partners in all sectors to better understand the impact of climate change on global biodiversity and to promote conservation as a strategy for mitigating global warming. By incorporating the science of climate change into conservation strategies, CI is demonstrating that CO2 emissions can be reduced not only by protecting and restoring forests that absorb the gas, but also by preventing release of the greenhouse gases when forests are cleared or burned.

Read more of this article &amp; find out more about Conservation International @:
www.conseravtion.org

1. To get people to WAKE UP about Climate change and realize that it doesn't just matter to us TREEHUGGERS. It matters to everyone and every species on this GOD-GREEN EARTH...

2. We must STOP damaging the EARTH we live IN with our everyday environmentally careless tactics.</description>
  <mission>To conserve the Earth's living natural heritage, our global biodiversity, and to demonstrate that human societies are able to live harmoniously with nature&#9829;</mission>
  <name>SAVE OUR Beautiful PLANET... Do something about CLIMATE CHANGE</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3355</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">45</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qN/Af/PI/0Z/w4/XJ/yJkS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
