<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Fragile X Syndrome is a genetic disorder caused by a mutation of the FMR1 gene on the X chromosome. It is responsible for instructing the cell to make a protein FMRP which is assumed to be essential for correct brain function. This can and does cause a variety of symptoms. 

Symptoms that MAY be present :

- INTELLECTUAL DISABILITY (for e.g. speech delays)
- AUTISM (www.nas.org.uk for further information)
- SOCIAL DEVELOPMENT DIFFICULTIES (e.g. shyness,limited eye contact etc)
- PHYSICAL FEATURES ( for e.g.elongated face,flat feet,hyperextensible joints etc)
-EMOTIONAL AND BEHAVIOURAL PROBLEMS (e.g. anxiety,unstable mood)
- SIMILAR/REPETITIVE MOVEMENTS 

(www.healthscout.com/ency/68/599/main.html gives more symptoms and definitions)


- Males tend to be MORE affected than females. 
- Females can be MILDLY affected to SEVERELY affected - one of the reasons why females tend to go UNDERDIAGNOSED. 
Problems emotion and behaviour wise are common in BOTH SEXES. 

Treatment - NO CURRENT CURE. 
ALTHOUGH:
-BEHAVIOURAL THERAPY 
-SPECIALISED EDUCATION (e.g. speech therapy)
-MEDICATION/TREATMENT of the physical abnormalities. 
Can help individuals with Fragile X Syndrome. 


As with many Genetic syndromes/diseases, Fragile X syndrome does not only affect the individual - it also has an impact on their families and the following generations. 


People's Experiences and knowledge may help to raise/answer questions which may be of benefit to those that are suffering. 
It may also help research in this area - after all there is only so much Scientific explanations can give!

Organisations 

The Fragile X Society
Rood End House, 6 Stortford Road, Great Dunmow, Essex CM6 1DA
Tel: 01371 875100
Website: www.fragilex.org.uk

Contact a Family
209-211 City Road, London EC1V 1JN
Tel: 0808 808 3555
Website: www.cafamily.org.uk

(www.bbc.co.uk/health/conditions/fragilex1.shtml)

Additional reading/info;
-As it is known Fragile X Syndrome is a triplet repeat disorder, that is it is associated with repeat nucleotide (components of DNA) expansion within the DNA sequence. 
-This repeat sequence in Fragile X more specifically can be CGG (cytosine,guanine,guanine) or GCC (guanine,cytosine,cystosine).
-In some cases though a compound array may be present - (GCCGTC)n(GCC)n where n = a threshold level of symptom causing, nucleotide repeats. It is important to note this case is rare but causes developmental delay. 
- These repeat sequences are what cause the "Fragile Sites" on the X Chromosome. 
- There are several different "Fragile Sites" but not all are present in each individual affected with the syndrome- it appears to be only one. 
- More specifically these "Fragile Sites" are called FRAXE (rare and milder symptoms), FRAXF (again rare but with developmental delay), and the most common is called FRAXA. 
- The FRAXA site has been mapped specifically to the site Xq27-q28. X indicates the X Chromosome, and q indicates the long arm of the Chromosome. 

Recent and existing developments in this area have found that:

- Carrier Females with greater than 100 CGG repeats (nucleotides of DNA) show significant levels of depression, deficits in interpersonal skills and withdrawal behaviour. 

- Around 20% of premutation Females show early menopause. 

- Some reports indicate that premutation males suffer from a tremor aged 50/60 which develops to ataxia. 

- Population studies show that in Israel and Italy 1 in 100 females (1 in 200 in Canada) have FMR1 repeat lengths of over 52 copies (of CGG)of the repeat sequence were present. 


1. Raise Awareness

2. Raise experiences/questions to help give a better explanation rather than just Scientific

3. Better communication between sufferers/families</description>
  <mission>Raise Awareness, and Help Further Research </mission>
  <name>Fragile X Syndrome</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/336</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3662</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">270.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3bq/RCiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
