<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Project Bread - The Walk for Hunger is a private, nonprofit organization whose mission is to alleviate, prevent, and ultimately end hunger in Massachusetts. Project Bread serves as Massachusetts' primary anti-hunger organization. The agency's goals are to make emergency food accessible to those who would otherwise go hungry; educate, mobilize, and empower people through the Walk for Hunger and other avenues of action; research and develop innovative solutions to end hunger; advocate, in partnership with others, freedom from hunger across the Commonwealth.

Since its inception in 1969, Project Bread - The Walk for Hunger has been the voice for hungry children and families in Massachusetts. Project Bread has established strong and effective community-based programs that ensure hungry families and individuals are not abandoned in their efforts to find healthy food.

Project Bread supports nearly 400 soup kitchens, food pantries, food banks, and food salvage programs in 129 communities in Massachusetts; operates the FoodSource Hotline, which responds to nearly 30,000 callers a year; delivers more than 6 million pounds of food each year to emergency food programs through its Food Drive for the Hungry program; works with concerned individuals and organizations to develop public policies that address hunger; provides technical assistance and management assistance to hundreds of emergency food programs to enable then to meet the needs of hungry people in their communities; develop and supports innovative efforts to feed children in schools, child care, and recreational settings, and at home through its statewide campaign, the Massachusetts Child Hunger Initiative (MCHI); works with elderly, children, and other at-risk populations to break down barriers to vital nutrition programs.

1. Hunger in Massachusetts must end.</description>
  <mission>The Walk for Hunger is a private, nonprofit organization whose mission is to alleviate, prevent, and ultimately end hunger in Massachusetts.</mission>
  <name>Project Bread - the Walk for Hunger, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3362</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">244</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">325.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jd/ZB/FU/dR/Gw/mt/Z7zS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
