<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Childhood strokes, though perceived to be relatively rare, have an incidence approximately equal to pediatric brain tumors. Epidemiological studies have revealed an annual incidence of 2.5-2.7 pediatric strokes per 100,000 children.1 This figure comprises ischemic and hemorrhagic events, and excludes strokes from trauma or birth-related complications.

When a blood vessel on or in the brain ruptures, blood flows into brain areas where it&#8217;s not supposed to go. It may pool in brain tissues, resulting in a blood clot. Also, because the vessel is ruptured, blood isn&#8217;t transported where it should go. As a result, the brain is deprived of oxygen, and this may lead to permanent brain injury. Hemorrhagic strokes are most often caused by rupturing or weakened or malformed arteries known as AVMs (arteriovenous malformations). The risk of hemorrhage is higher with certain illnesses such as hemophilia.

Will my child get better?

Recovery from stroke is different with each child. Prompt medical treatment and rehabilitation therapy can maximize recovery. In general, most younger people will recover more abilities than older people. Children often recover the use of their arms and legs and their ability to speak after a stroke.

What are the effects of stroke in children?
Hemiparesis (weakness on one side of the body), or hemiplegia (paralysis on one side of the body).
One-sided neglect (unilateral neglect), which causes the stroke survivor to ignore or forget their weaker side.
Aphasia (difficulty with speech and language), or dysphagia (trouble swallowing).
Decreased field of vision and trouble with visual perception.
Loss of emotional control and changes in mood.
Cognitive changes or problems with memory, judgment and problem-solving.
Behavior changes or personality changes, improper language or actions.



1. Awareness</description>
  <mission>Make people aware.</mission>
  <name>Childhood Stroke</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3365</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2828</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">599.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Sc/Zl/2Q/Nm/Ki/hg/5o5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
