<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>WHO WE ARE:

Firefly is a charitable organization that funds research in neurodegenerative diseases in pursuit of one day finding a cure.

We also believe that the earlier you adopt a healthy
brain routine, the better your chances are for having a healthy brain later in life.

For this reason, Firefly is dedicated to advancing brain health and inspiring all generations to take care of their brain every day.

OUR RESEARCH:

An important focus for Firefly funding is the pursuit of
cures. Through the Center for Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases at the University of Toronto, we fund early-phase, proof-of-concept research with a focus on Alzheimer&#8217;s and Lewy body disease.

We also source and share scientific discoveries that
connect a growing body of evidence which suggests
lifestyle and behaviour can help prevent or prolong
the onset of neurodegenerative disease later in life.

Both of these initiatives support a dedication to
investing in ahead-of-the-curve ideas with the
potential for truly breakthrough discoveries.


HELP BRAINS STAY BRIGHT:
Currently there are no cures and few treatments for
neurodegenerative diseases.

There are many ways for you to help fund important
research and advance the cause:

&#8226; Commemorating someone through our online In
Memoriam
&#8226; Participating in our annual Mental Marathon
&#8226; Donating your time or money to Firefly

Your brain - it&#8217;s a good cause.

For more information or tips on what you can do to help your brain last longer, visit our website.

FIREFLYFOUNDATION.ORG

1. Chances are your body will outlive your  brain, why not do the little things now that help you beat the odds?</description>
  <mission>Help you stay bright and create a culture of sustainable brains.  Your brain, it's a good cause.</mission>
  <name>Firefly Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3366</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/FP/Vn/vE/ed/uq/rS/PkyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
