<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>WAY-FM Media Group, Inc. has been in existence since 1987. The non-profit corporation began as a single FM radio station in Fort Myers, Florida.

In the early 1980&#8217;s, Bob and Felice Augsburg were were compelled by the burden to see a younger audience reached and Bob began producing a Saturday evening broadcast geared for youth. This program, which aired on WSOR, became the springboard for Christian Rock concerts in the area and the impetus for a 24/7 station with this type of format.

Through several years of prayer and discussion with other local parents and business people, a non-profit Florida corporation was formed and an application filed with the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) for an unused FM frequency. On December 24, 1986, an FCC permit appeared in the mail, allowing for the construction of a non-commercial FM station in Fort Myers. On October 9, 1987, WAY-FM (WAYJ) signed on the air.

By 1992, three WAY-FM radio stations were on the air&#8212;including Fort Myers (Florida), Nashville (Tennessee) and West Palm Beach (Florida). Over the years, WAY-FM radio stations have been selected four times as winners of the prestigious Dove Award for excellence in the operation of Christian Radio station.

At this time, WAY-FM owns and operates 14 full power FM radio stations including, newly added stations in Denver (Colorado), Wichita (Kansas) and Tallahassee (Florida). WAY-FM also owns more than 20 low-power repeater stations. The Christian Hit Radio Satellite Network (CHRSN) serves over 100 additional radio stations nationwide with satellite programming. Today more than 70 cities are impacted by WAY-FM.

Please donate to WAYFM in order to keep us on the air!!!

1. We believe in what is called &#8220;The Apostles&#8217; Creed.&#8221;

2. We believe there is one living and true God, eternally existing in three persons; the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit.

3. We believe in God, the Father, is involved in the affairs of men; that He hears and answers prayer; and that He saves from sin and death all who come to Him through Jesus Christ.

4. # We believe in Jesus Christ, God&#8217;s only Son, conceived by the Holy Spirit. We believe in His virgin birth, sinless life, miracles, and teachings; His atoning death; bodily resurrection; ascension into heaven; perpetual intercession for His people; and 

5. We believe in the Holy Spirit, who came forth from the Father and Son to convict the world of sin, righteousness, and judgment and to regenerate, sanctify, and empower in ministry all who believe in Christ. We believe the Holy Spirit indwells every believ

6. We believe that all the Scriptures of the Old and New Testaments are the Word of God, fully inspired and without error in the original manuscripts, and that they are infallible.

7. We believe all people are by nature separated from God and responsible for their own sin, but that salvation, redemption, and forgiveness are freely offered to all by the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ. When a person repents of sin and accepts Jesus Chris

8. We believe in the literal Second Coming of Christ as promised in the Bible in John 14.

9. We avoid any theological beliefs that go beyond the written Word and thereby divide the body of Christ.</description>
  <mission>encourage youth and young adults in their Christian lives and to introduce non-believers to Christ.</mission>
  <name>WAY-FM Media Group</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3369</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">38</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/h3/tJ/nB/ha/52/pp/BawS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
