<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For a couple of medicines available for women (Premarin and Prempro) approaching menopause, one of the ingredients is Pregnant Mare Urine (PMU). Mares (female horses) are made to be pregnant, stay in a dirty and tiny stall for their entire pregnancy, and have a machine attached to them to collect their urine, and give birth alone with no comfort or medical help. Then soon after birth, the foal (baby horse) is taken away from it's mother and shipped off in a crowded truck, often for days on end with no food or water, to the slaughterhouse. The mare is impregnated and the cycle starts again. This is extremely unfair to the animals and cruel in every kind of way. The horses are kept from doing natural things, expecially being able to move around and get excercise. As for the medicine, there are many other options, most of which are more natural and beneficial to the person. Please help stop the killing of PMU foals and the cruelty to the PMU mares by sending a message to both of these companies:

http://www.premarin.com/

and 

http://www.prempro.com/

and please also visit this website to help stop the company that creates these medicines:

www.StopWyeth.org.

Thank you!

**UPDATE**

I have created a website to promote this cause. Please go this website:

http://www.freewebs.com/pmuawareness/

Please read it thoroughly, and leaving a comment would be appreciated! Your ideas and suggestions mean a lot to me!

1. The cruelty to PMU mares must stop now.

2. PMU foals should be adopted out to good homes, NOT slaughtered.

3. Women can take healthier and more beneficial medicines not made with PMU.</description>
  <mission>Stop the killing of PMU foals and cruelty to PMU mares</mission>
  <name>PMU Foals and Mares</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3376</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7850</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">426.24</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6H/qS/RW/Aa/Mi/rW/Xy4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
