<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We began 25 years ago as a group dedicated to bringing black/white cultural issues within the church to the table.  We believe much of the difference and difficulty between our cultures is based in ignorance and supposition.

We meet with churches, non-profits, and other organization to assist them in navigating these tricky waters.  We believe God intended His Church to be involved in pulling down barriers rather than living homogeneously.

We promote active work in justice issues, and urge the church to stand strongly against injustice.  We work with leader, both established and upcoming, to show that "on earth...as it is in Heaven" is to be taken seriously, and that the Kingdom here on earth is represented by the church.

We encourage the church to not stop with "love the Lord, your God, with all your heart, soul, mind, and strength" but to also unpack and live out the second, which is important as the first one..."love your neighbor as yourself"

The Church is meant to be the agent of change in the world, fighting injustice, whether or not the battle seems winnable.  Our strength in fighting comes merely from the obedience of doing so, and God's action on our behalf.  Still, the number of people actively working for justice in this country is pitifully small.  A total of lest that 2% of an evangelical's income is given to charitable giving, and that's including tithing.  We cannot solely base involvement on that number, but there is truth in the words "where your treasure is, there will your heart be also."  The unfortunate truth is that the average evangelical's heart is not in it, as evidenced by where their treasure lies.

1. The Church is the primary tool God uses to bring about His will.

2. The Church must see more than abortion and the sanctity of marriage as cultural failures.

3. The "American Dream" and the call to a follower of Jesus are not meant to be intertwined.  One calls for gaining what can be gained...the other to give up what is gained for what cannot be lost.</description>
  <mission>draw Christians from different cultures into conversation</mission>
  <name>CURE (Chicago Urban Reconciliation Enterprise)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3380</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">41</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8f/MU/iN/Xi/h2/mf/6YzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
