<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>When you commit to the 30 Hour Famine, you commit to lasting change. You're making a difference in the daily lives of people who have very little nutritious food and access to safe water; some also suffer because of the prevalence of HIV and AIDS in their communities. The money that you raise will fund projects in not only Canada, but countries around the world, as well.

Read more about how your efforts will help children and communities in need.

Healthy food transforms lives
Healthy food is hard to come by in many parts of the world. Even though we produce enough food to feed all of the world's population, 850 million people still suffer from hunger every day. Read more.

Safe water for all
Water is the most abundant resource on Earth, yet there are one billion people without access to safe water each day. Where people don't have safe water, there is hardship and death. Read more.

Breaking the silence of HIV and AIDS
AIDS remains a silent killer of thousands of people every day. Stigma and fear surrounding HIV and AIDS make communicating about this disease and preventing its spread a special challenge in parts of Africa and Asia. Read more.

Protecting the children
Children are the most vulnerable members of our society and are often victims of war, poverty, and violence. Read more.
Hungry for change?
Read how World Vision works in countries like Niger, Mozambique, Senegal, Uganda, and Ghana.

For more information and to sign up go to:
www.famine.ca

1. No one should have to go hungery.

2. Everyone should be able to have clean, safe drinking water.</description>
  <mission>Raise money for world vision by signing up to the the 30 hour famine event or donating through this cause page to World Vision International.</mission>
  <name>30 Hour Famine</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3383</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2952</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">490.09</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gV/rO/qm/ZR/ud/65/Ej/UIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
