<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Global warming is a reality. With increased awareness of this phenomenon, more individuals will become motivated to make a change and thus save the environment from further destruction. We contribute significantly to this problem and it is time to put a stop to it. With increased education and public awareness of such environmental implications, this will ultimately foster the transition from awareness through concern and eventually to active participation both individually and/or collectively towards finding solutions for environmental problems and the prevention of future ones. It is therefore necessary to tackle these problems as soon as they arise. Industries need to be closely monitored and renewable energy sources need to be utilized. This can only be accomplished with the full cooperation of everyone. Education is the key to success, and therefore it is the main ingredient needed for permanent change to occur. Schools need to promote environmental education at an early age, for environmental education is indeed a lifelong process.

1. Promote global warming awareness

2. Creating a national framework - Environmental Defense Action Fund, the legislative policy arm of Environmental Defense, is working with Congressional leaders to slow global warming while boosting our global competitiveness.

3. Finding solutions in states and regions - We're advising local business, community and political leaders on global warming solutions that curb pollution and spur economic growth.

4. Partnering with businesses - Our corporate partnerships team works with business leaders to help them craft solutions good for both their bottom lines and the environment

5. Working internationally - Environmental Defense is helping developing countries benefit from sound environmental policies while helping America remain an industrial leader and stay competitive.

6. Advocating in the courts - Environmental Defense got its start 40 years ago by waging a science-based legal battle against harmful pesticides. Today, we prefer to work cooperatively, but still argue cases in the courts when necessary.

7. Innovating with farmers - We're cultivating the idea of growing fuel, as we look to launch a market for renewable energy grown on U.S. farms. These efforts will reduce global warming pollution while ensuring America's national security and restoring vital</description>
  <mission>To increase public awareness about the effects of Global Warming on the environment.</mission>
  <name>Help Save The Environment " Stop Global Warming"</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3385</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">429</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/rk/dl/lV/zZ/u7/Tq/00/BOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
