<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is an Assistance Dog?

An Assistance Dog is exactly that! A dog that assists someone who needs assistance. In our daily lives, we often take for granted the simple things, like being able to pick up a pen we've dropped or opening a door when we need to leave. An individual with a disability may have to wait for someone to do this for them or perhaps endanger themselves by trying to do it without help.

What things can an Assistance Dog do for a disabled person?

    * Pick up dropped objects
    * Pull a wheelchair up a small incline
    * Tug a door open
    * Turn a light switch on or off
    * Push an elevator button
    * Open the refrigerator
    * Help with transactions at store counters
    * Provide assistance with dressing
    * Provide companionship

          ...and so much more!!

How are the dogs trained?

All program dogs are trained using a method called positive reinforcement. This means we use the reward system for getting a dog to perform skills. Types of rewards used are: praise, treats, toys and anything else that lets the dog know how pleased we are with what they are doing.

Do the dogs like to work?

The dogs we train love to work! A happy dog is one with its tail wagging a mile a minute. Since we train in a stress-free manner, the dogs enjoy what they do. This makes a happy worker in the field once the dog is paired with its human partner.

Who can apply for an assistance dog?

Anyone with a disability that limits their independence! Every applicant is evaluated and those accepted are matched with a dog specially trained to allow them the freedom, companionship, and independence they so rightly deserve.

 

1. Place well trainind dogs only using positive training techniques. 

2. Keep open communication with each team throughout the life of the human-dog working team.

3. Advocate rights for a disabled service dog team.</description>
  <mission>Train unwanted dogs to assist those with vatious disabilities.</mission>
  <name>Train Rite</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3396</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">13</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/u0/iN/XS/nc/oH/0R/VgZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
