<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>WorldCamps is a U.S. based non-profit corporation whose goal is to provide a camp experience for children affected by HIV/AIDS in developing countries and to change prevailing attitudes and behaviors towards AIDS. This includes children who have family members that are HIV+ as well as children who are HIV+ themselves. At camp, we hope to impart HIV/AIDS awareness and prevention, as well as crucial life skills to the children. The camp provides a place for the children to play and relax, and to meet other children in similar situations. A typical schedule would include Sports, Drums and Dancing, Permaculture/Gardening, Arts&amp;Crafts, Adventure/Teamwork, Swimming (season-dependent), and Life Skills (proper nutrition/hygiene, HIV/AIDS awareness and prevention, healthy sexuality, gender stereotypes, etc.).

Currently, WorldCamps is located in South Africa, at a site outside of Johannesburg in the Magaliesburg Mountain area. Here, Camp Sizanani happens. "Sizanani" is a Zulu word for "help each other". 6 camps are held each year for a minimum of 10 days each. Boys' and girls' camps alternate, bringing together 110 children each time and 30-35 counselors. The children range from 10-15 years old and are largely from the Soweto area.

In September 2005, we hope to open a second camp in rural Limpopo Province, South Africa. Thereafter, we plan to have similar camps in other countries in Africa and the rest of the developing world. If you are an organization that is interested in partnering with WorldCamps and bringing us to your community, please contact Phil Lilienthal. 

(from: http://globalcampsafrica.org/about.htm)

1. AIDS awareness needs to be improved!</description>
  <mission>Raise AIDS awareness in the lives of people who have been affected by AIDS.</mission>
  <name>Global Camps Africa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3407</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">105</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ay/wn/bL/Jm/FA/Rl/oUlS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
