<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Mental health problems, ranging from mild depression to debilitating schizophrenia, affect 25% of US adults. 

Despite the huge number of people (including your own friends and family) who suffer because of these disorders, stigma is still a serious obstacle to receiving good treatment. Health insurance companies often refuse to cover mental health care. 

Organizations like Mental Health America (formerly National Mental Health Association) fight for all of us affected by mental health problems, and promote overall mental wellness. 

What can YOU do to help?
- TALK about mental health issues, with your friends, family, and community, to help break down the walls and end the stigma.
- Be supportive to those in your life who struggle with mental health problems;  being a good friend is often the best help you can offer.
- Contact local, state, and federal government officials and urge them to pass supportive legislation so mental health services are covered under health insurance. (visit mentalhealthamerica.net for information on mental  health-related policy)
- Take care of yourself! Find the things in life that make you feel good, and do them. Don't be afraid to ask for help when life gets overwhelming; you aren't alone in your struggles.


If you have any questions about where your donations will go, feel free to ask!
Check out our other facebook Causes site, under Mental Health America!



Please note: image courtesy of USA Today


1. Mental health affects everyone, so everyone should care.

2. We must fight the stigma surrounding mental illness.

3. We must promote mental healthcare for everyone.

4. Finding ways to take care of our mental health, before problems arise, should be a priority.</description>
  <mission>Fight Mental Health Stigma and Promote Mental Healthcare</mission>
  <name>Mind Your Health</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/341</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">732</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">102.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/beJ/SqhS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
