<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"The Dorough Lupus Foundation was established as the direct result of and in memoriam for the tragic loss of Caroline Dorough-Cochran to the devastating disease, Lupus. In response to public   interest generated upon the web-site of Howard Dorough (a.k.a. Howie D. of the Backstreet Boys) and at the urgings of prominent doctors within the field, Howard Dorough and family established the Dorough Lupus Foundation. The goal was to create a financial avenue for "donors" to send in charitable contributions to be allocated to organizations and individuals dedicated to the research, treatment and public education of the disease Lupus.

Angelia M. Herring took on the awesome responsibility of heading the foundation as the Executive Director and through a series of fundraising events and sponsorships, has been able to generate enough financial support to benefit the aforementioned organizations and individuals. The overwhelming lack of support, both financially and emotionally for those afflicted with this disease, has brought the Dorough family together to help give others what was unavailable for their beloved Caroline.

The Dorough Lupus Foundation has made tremendous strides in their primary years through their annual events, such as the Cruise and the celebrity filled Concert and auctions, all of which generate funds allocated by the foundation for the financial support of research, treatment and public education on Lupus. Additionally, the Dorough Lupus Foundation has established and implemented support groups for those affected by the disease and help sponsor financially stricken families to enable them to support and care for their loved ones while receiving medical treatments."

For more information, please visit:

http://www.doroughlupusfoundation.org

1. "It is the objective of the Foundation to make our organization the most prominent and compassionate Lupus Advocacy group around the globe, aiding and supporting those effected and/or affected by Lupus."</description>
  <mission>"The Dorough Lupus Foundation is an independent, non-profit organization. The Foundation's goals are to aide in research and educate the public about Lupus."</mission>
  <name>Dorough Lupus Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3416</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2147</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">23.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eh/kj/a1/ZO/Oo/Gu/fmVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
