<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Midori &amp; Friends provides high quality music education programs to underserved children in New York City's public school system. As a catalyst for change, Midori &amp; Friends can help underperforming schools become vibrant learning communities. Currently, we partner with approximately forty public elementary, middle, and high schools throughout New York City, providing musical opportunities for children, regardless of their ability, education, or economic background.

Midori, who serves as the organization's president, is a tireless advocate for arts education. She is involved in the development of programming and performs numerous concerts for children. Our Teaching Artists are graduates of the nation's top music schools and universities and have been carefully selected for their outstanding musicianship and exceptional ability to engage and inspire children.

Children in Midori &amp; Friends partner schools represent a broad range of ethnic and racial backgrounds, on average: 39% African-American; 36% Hispanic/Latino, 12% Asian American, and 12% Caucasian. The majority of children live in low-income communities, with 77% qualifying for the city's free lunch program. Approximately 20% have special needs, and many of our students live with foster families or in single parent households.

This year (2006&#8211;07) we are serving approximately 10,000 children citywide through in-school and after-school music instruction programs, family/community workshops at schools and community sites, an inter-school chorus comprised of children from across New York City, and our 2nd annual Children's Music Festival. In addition to services to children and their families, we offer Professional Development opportunities for Teaching Artists and classroom teachers.

1. All children deserve a high quality music education.</description>
  <mission>is to provide high quality music education programs to underserved children in New York City's public school system.</mission>
  <name>Midori &amp; Friends</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3422</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">134</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/A5/Sg/C3/S0/m0/CM/SHbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
