<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The country with the fastest growing refugee crisis in the world today is Iraq. Since the US conflict began in 2003, 2 million people have been internally displaced and 2.2 million Iraqis have fled their country with 3,000 more fleeing Iraq every day. Due to the unstable and precarious security situation in Iraq humanitarian operations have been drastically limited with most of the international humanitarian staff fleeting the country. In addition, the majority of the host countries, the biggest being Jordan and Syria, do not have systems in place allowing them to deal with such situations and are unequipped to handle large amounts of refugees. The majority of the refugees are left unacknowledged by their host governments, leaving thousands of people unaccounted for and unprotected from human rights and civil liberty violations, not to mention being denied access to basic human resources.
The US, until recently, has refused to publicly acknowledge the extent of the crisis and refuses to supply iraq and its surrounding countries aswell as the UN with the proper funds to help deal with the situation.
This Group's mission is to bring awareness and support to those in the shadows who are being directly effected by this  war.
The situation and statistics change everyday. This is only the tip of the iceberg.
For more info:

http://www.refugeesinternational.org/content/article/detail/9712

http://pulitzercenter.typepad.com/death_of_a_nation/

http://www.unhcr.org/cgi-bin/texis/vtx/iraq?page=home

1. Proper attention and action must be brought to this refugee crisis

2. This is NOT political</description>
  <mission>Bring awareness and support to Iraqi Refugees</mission>
  <name>Iraqi Refugee Crisis</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3426</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1864</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">350.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/G4/Ed/5K/eO/Eo/4N/VDMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
