<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dedicated to examining and informing people about the harmfull affects of F-Bombs




The Truth About F-bombs: Annylitcal Essay

One generaly fails to recognize the significantly harmfull and mammoth negative effects of an F-bomb. F-bombs today are habitually overlooked by society, and have even become generally accepted by a ludicrous few. One overlooks the truth about F-Bombs. 
It is through one's perception of the word morality that may help us to understand the F-bomb and it's position and place in life. Where does the F-bomb begin? Where does it end? In this essay, I shall hope to answer these questions and others. 
One may mistakingly believe that one does not think before he or she emits/ drops an F-bomb. It is quite to the contrary. The need to gain prestige and distinction from one's comrades is the prevailing reason for the increasing number of the dropping of F-bombs. One may essentialy feel that it is necessary to drop an F-bomb. I need to drop an F-bomb Nonetheless, F-bombs originate as a virtually harmless word inside the recesses of the speaker's mind. At this point, the dropper prepares to commence F-bomb deployment. 
This paper-tiger F-bomb phase, does not last long before the F-bomb is dropped. Once the foul word passes the speaker's sour lips, the F-bomb is no laughing matter. The F-bomb seizes control of the surrounding area, infultrating the ears and subconciouses of the listeners. It plagues the ears of the recipant, staining their soul with immorality, demoralization, atrocity, and spiraling depression. The speaker fails to recognize the filth and corruption they have inflicted on anyone within a 40' radius.
Help Global Warming,
Please, think before you drop an F-bomb.

1. F-bomb prevention

2. Maintain and deduce the spread of F-bombing

3. F-bomb recovery</description>
  <mission>Prevent the harmful spread and effects of f-bombs</mission>
  <name>F-Bomb Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3435</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ph/q4/Tz/el/nY/pZ/BHRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
