<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> UYA seeks to partner with other community and youth focused organizations to facilitate individual and community transformation. Our desire is to see youth succeed as positive and active community leaders. We anticipate that youth will demonstrate their confidence, commitments and skills in various public contexts, including education, business, politics, and church. To this end UYA will:

    * Engage youth in activities and mentor them in relationships that encourage them to excel and to express the drive to improve and change. When a young person realizes a capacity to excel, even if initially it is only for small goals, it is possible to apply that new confidence toward large goals.
    * Help youth determine a vision of the future for both themselves and their communities.
    * Empower youth to develop the required knowledge, skills and access to resources so they can achieve their goals.
    * Assist youth to accomplish life and community goals and to exhibit self-confidence through leadership and mentoring of others.
    * Help youth understand principles of self and community awareness and confidence, humility and compassion.


1. Inclusivity - Work with youth in all seasons and in every way for their well-being

2. Excellence - Work with all youth who come to us and who are willing to abide by our code of conduct

3. Relevance - Be culturally and socially relevant and welcoming to all youth, regardless of gender, race, or creed. Our primary focus will be youth whose opportunities are limited by poverty and social breakdown

4. Respect - Collaborate and partner with others; sharing our resources with other programs; developing and nurturing excellent relationships with other organizations for the promotion of whole and healthy communities

5. Christian Faith - Demonstrate God&#8217;s love through our actions, words and attitudes</description>
  <mission>To decrease youth poverty in the inner city area of Winnipeg.</mission>
  <name>Urban Youth Adventures</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3441</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mh/hy/Rc/OK/qW/Je/H3jS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
