<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For over 100 years, the Humane Society of New York has been a presence in New York City, caring for animals in need when illness, injury or homelessness strikes. In 1904 we were founded to protect the city's horses against abuse. Members fought for laws to punish negligent owners and place watering troughs in streets and parks. As funds allowed the Society expanded to include a free medical clinic and a small adoption center for cats and dogs. Today our hospital and our Vladimir Horowitz and Wanda Toscanini Horowitz Adoption Center help more than 30,000 dogs and cats annually, and their numbers continue to grow.

At the Society, the quality of each animal's life is paramount. Long before it was popular to think of animals as individuals - to consider their physical and emotional needs when taking responsibility for their care - we were doing just that. That means every day, every dog gets exercise time in the rooftop run, and the chance to walk outdoors with staff and volunteers. Cats enjoy daily play sessions outside their kennels. This very personal care is fully as important to a pet's well being as the inoculations, spay/neuter and other veterinary care provided during its stay in the adoption center. "This doesn't feel like a shelter" remark many visitors to the Society. "It feels like a home."



1. Seven days a week, dog and cat owners with limited means turn to the Society for quality veterinary care at affordable rates.</description>
  <mission>Humane Society of New York has been a presence in New York City, caring for animals in need when illness, injury or homelessness strikes</mission>
  <name>Humane Society of New York</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3442</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">272</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">85.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bf/eS/iF/zE/tA/rH/yWQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
