<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Keep a Child Alive is dedicated to providing life-saving anti-retroviral treatment, care and support to children and families with HIV/AIDS in Africa and India by directly engaging the global public in the fight against AIDS. 

There is a profound difference between living and life.

Living may extend time for another day.

But life is far more than sleeping and waking.

Life is more than merely existing.

And, although it would be easier, life cannot be bought in a pill.

That is why Keep a Child Alive buys more than just the pills needed to fight HIV/AIDS in Africa and India.

It buys the essential nutrition, shelter, support, and education to help ensure those pills are taken properly and effectively.

It buys the things we all take for granted, but that make all the difference. A bed. A roof. A ride. A book. A smile.

KCA offers children, their families and entire communities a shoulder to lean on and a heart that beats for them.

Because KCA believes we can do something bigger and better than buying the ability to live.

We can buy the dignity that is life. We can buy compassion.

Buy Love. Buy the cure. Buy Life.

Because the more you buy, the more you save.




We Focus on the Following Three Areas: 


TREATMENT Anti-retroviral (ARV) treatment has transformed the lives of people with AIDS in the West, returning them from sickness to health. But less than 5% of children with AIDS have access to these life-saving drugs. When the children are infected 50% die before the age of 2 and 80% die before the age of 5. When the public signs up to become a monthly, or "Life" donor, 100%* of their monthly donation goes directly to life-saving AIDS drugs and surrounding care. 

CARE Keep a Child Alive provides the medical services needed to make treatment possible. Doctors, nutrition, testing, transportation, and treatment for opportunistic infections are all necessary for anti-retroviral treatment to be successful. When necessary, KCA also provides nutrition for its patients believing that ARV&#8217;s are much more effective on a full stomach.

ORPHANS Currently 15.2 million children worldwide have lost one or both parents to AIDS, and by 2010 the number is expected to reach 25 million. 13 million of these children are in Sub Saharan Africa. These children will face enormous risks in their struggle to stay alive. They will often be forced into sexual exploitation or enrolled as child soldiers, this after the terrible trauma of losing your parents in front of you. Keep a Child Alive builds and sustains orphanages to keep the most vulnerable children out of harm's way. Orphanages are a last resort, but necessary when children have no extended family to turn to for support.


1. Providing AIDS treatment, care &amp; support to orphan care and clinical sites.</description>
  <mission>KEEP A CHILD ALIVE is an urgent response to the AIDS pandemic ravaging Africa and India.</mission>
  <name>Keep A Child Alive</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3449</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">17373</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">12509.31</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fK/QT/5P/yB/4m/hF/TX/LES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
