<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We are a group of high school students doing a project to help raise awareness about human rights violations in our world today. We researched the issues surrounding the Guantanamo Bay Detainment Camp.

Scope of the Problem

	How Bad Is It?
	This problem is extremely serious. Essentially, the U.S. has set bounty prices at around 10,000 dollars for citizens in other countries to turn in suspected terrorists. This bounty has tempted many to turn in people who have not been verified terrorists in return for the money promised. The falsely accused are not given a fair trial and placed in the Guantanamo Bay Detainment Camp. They are held indefinitely and are made to endure them most brutal conditions. This problem is affecting several hundred people (the exact number is not known) currently in the camp but that number is growing. 

Conditions in the Camp  
	FBI agents, Red Cross inspectors and numerous detainees have alleged to acts of torture including sleep deprivation, the use of so-called truth drugs, beatings, locking in confined and cold cells, and being forced to maintain uncomfortable postures. These acts of torture are what is seen on a daily basis in Guantanamo Bay

Four Main Reasons Why Guantanamo Should Be Closed
	First, Guantanamo is a symbol of being able to find loopholes in the law. The location was chosen because it was offshore and was thought to be out of the jurisdiction of any United States court. 
	Second, it has alienated Muslim communities by acting in a hostile manner toward the people of the Middle East.
	Third, the U.S. has compromised its moral authority in return for Guantanamo&#8217;s existence and the so-called fight against terror.
	Finally, the detainees have been arbitrarily captured, physically and mentally abused and tortured. Their human rights have been disregarded.  

Please help by donating to amnesty.org or aclu.org 


1. The US government should never, under any circumstances, be allowed to violate human rights

2. The use and operation of Guantanamo Bay should be shut down.</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness about the events occurring at Guantanamo Bay and help detainees obtain human rights.</mission>
  <name>Close Guantanamo Bay Detainment Camp!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3450</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">157</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Vn/WS/gd/Gk/V3/nO/324S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
