<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>New Friends, pride and self-esteem - these are the joyful gifts Happy Days is giving to kids diagnosed with cancer and their families.  Through our generous volunteers and donors we are providing  many specialized programs and events, year-round.  Our mission is to continue being a critical team member alongside medical professionals, giving these very brave and special families the support, strength and will to continue fighting.

ANNUAL EVENT SCHEDULE

CAMP HAPPY DAYS &#8211; CAMP 2009 - June 27-July 4th.  "A Most Excellent Adventure"

Camp Happy Days is our flagship event for kids with cancer and their siblings. Camp is an amazing week of fun, new friends and incredibl opportunity designed to provide the most unique experience possible for campers and counselors.
By day, access a waterfront teeming with fun - swimming, a waterslide, boating, tubing, fishing and the famous "blob".

Then walk over to woodworking, arts and crafts, painting, sewing, and ceramics.  Or test your skills at the giant climbing wall, one of the high ropes adventure courses or participate in team building games designed specifically for Camp Happy
Days. 

By night, experience stunning theme dances, professional entertainment and one-of-a-kind experiences unique to Camp Happy Days. 

Visit www.camphappydays.com for more information about our upcoming events.  Support us and make a difference in the lives of children fighting cancer.  



1. www.camphappydays.com</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to offer hope and encouragement to children diagnosed with cancer and their families by providing year-round programs special events and access to crisis resources. </mission>
  <name>Camp Happy Days (Kids Kickin' Cancer)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3452</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4857</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">580.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Oo/hL/WD/Wn/bQ/4I/KW/G5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
