<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>M&#233;decins Sans Fronti&#232;res, also known as Doctors without Borders, is a non-governmental international humanitarian aid organization established in 1971. The organization provides humanitarian assistance, medical training, and awareness during humanitarian crises in more than 70 countries around the world.

Working to rehabilitate hospitals, establish vaccinations programs and water sanitation projects, and train local medical personal in locations where infrastructure in insufficient or non-existing, MSF sets out to alleviate human suffering, to protect life and health, and to restore and ensure respect for human beings and their fundamental human rights.

Using funds from its Noble Peace Prize (1999) MSF has initiated the Campaign for Access to Essential Medicines strongly promoting the mandate for availability of affordable and adequate amounts of essential medicines for populations across the world.

View video:
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zxQYFfBeC3s

Visit:
http://www.msf.org/ (MSF International)
http://www.doctorswithoutborders.org/ (MSF USA)
http://www.msf.ca/en/index.html (MSF Canada)

http://www.accessmed-msf.org/campaign/ (Campaign for access to essential medicines)

Donations:

IF YOU ARE INTERESTED IN DONATING PLEASE VISIT  
http://www.msf.org/msfinternational/donations/
WHERE YOU CAN DONATE TO MSF DIRECTLY!

"Doctors Without Borders strives to operate efficiently and to minimize fundraising and administrative costs&#8230; 85.74 % of Doctors Without Borders' expenses went towards humanitarian aid to help patients and to raise awareness about populations in danger."

1. Provide emergency medical assistance to populations in danger

2. Establish and promote healthcare and sanitation programmes in regions with insufficient infrastructure

3. Campaign internationally for greater access to essential medicines

4. Bear witness and raise global awareness of crisis situations in the remotest corners of the world</description>
  <mission>Provide essential humanitarian aid and medical assistance to regions and populations during times of crisis irrespective of race, religion, creed or political convictions.</mission>
  <name>Support M&#233;decins Sans Fronti&#232;res/Doctors Without Borders</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3459</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">946</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/LC/Cp/PY/gk/Ke/yN/bZ6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
