<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I am incredibly excited about participating in the third annual Weekend to End Breast Cancer. After taking part in 2005, I would love to repeat that life changing experience. I have heard many stories about breast cancer, which have affected numerous people including my mother. I want my children to grow up in a world without Breast Cancer.

When I was 13, my Mom was diagnosed with Breast Cancer. On top of hearing about my Mom, my parents were going through a divorce. This was a huge battle for my Mother, my Sisters, and I; but we managed to overcome it with strength, courage, and resilience. 

My mom had undergone two major surgeries and radiation treatment. Seeing her in that state was difficult for me, but I knew she was strong and would pull herself through it. The support she had been given, along with her courage and determination made her succeed a fight against the disease most women fear.

My mother has been such an amazing role model through out my life. Her determination, courage, perseverance, and inspiration have reflected on me. Her battle against cancer was not a good experience, but it has improved our lives. I have learned to be grateful for life, and conquer the situations I am presented with. 

In the last 5 years, I have known many women who have been diagnosed with Breast Cancer. I am not only doing this walk for my mom and family, I am also doing it for all the women and families I know that have been touched with this terrible disease. The Weekend to End Breast Cancer is a two-day, 60-kilometre walk through the neighborhoods of Calgary. All the proceeds benefit the Alberta Cancer Foundation, funding important breast cancer research, education, services and care.

1. Breast Cancer effects 1 in 9 women.

2. All proceeds go to Tom Baker Cancer Center.</description>
  <mission>raise a minimum of $2000 to find a cure. Our Team Goal is $50,000!!!! DO NOT DONATE ON THIS PAGE, please go to http://www.endcancer.ca/site/TR?px=1735673&amp;pg=personal&amp;fr_id=1190 thanks!</mission>
  <name>Weekend To End Breast Cancer Calgary 2007</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3473</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">66</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gy/wb/I8/hd/ID/y1/dkPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
