<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>On December 9, 1981, at approximately 3:55 a.m., Officer Danny Faulkner, a five year veteran of the Philadelphia Police Department, made a traffic stop at Locust Street near Twelfth Street.  The car stopped by Officer Faulkner was being driven by William Cook. After making the stop, Danny called for assistance on his police radio and requested a police wagon to transport a prisoner. Unbeknownst to him, William Cook's brother, Wesley (aka Mumia Abu-Jamal) was across the street. As Danny attempted to handcuff William Cook, Mumia Abu-Jamal ran from across the street and shot the officer in the back. Danny turned and was able to fire one shot that struck Abu-Jamal in the chest; the wounded officer then fell to the pavement. Mumia Abu-Jamal stood over the downed officer and shot him four more times at close range, once directly in the face. Mumia Abu-Jamal was found still at the scene of the shooting by officers who arrived there within seconds. The murderer was slumped against the curb in front of his brother's car. In his possession was a .38 caliber revolver that records showed Mumia had purchased months earlier. The chamber of the gun had five spent cartridges. A cab driver, as well as other pedestrians, had witnessed the brutal slaying and identified Mumia Abu-Jamal as the killer both at the scene and during his trial. On July 2, 1982, after being tried before a jury of ten whites and two blacks, Mumia Abu-Jamal was convicted of murdering Officer Danny Faulkner. The next day, the jury sentenced him to death after deliberating for two hours. The Supreme Court of Pennsylvania heard the defendant's appeals and upheld the conviction on March 6, 1989.

26 years later, Mumia is "honored" by people across the world as a "political prisoner", with many supporters blindly supporting this cop-killer without any regard for the facts behind the case.  Mumia killed an innocent police officer out of cold blood; he must now suffer the consequences to the full extent that the American judicial system may serve.

Officer Danny Faulkner joined the ranks of those courageous officers who have given their lives to keep our nation's streets safe and free. Danny and Maureen Faulkner are the real victims; it is for them that we seek justice and the reason this site stands strong today.  

Visit http://www.danielfaulkner.com/ for the truth.  Notice how this is the only website to present all the court files and transcripts.  Read through them, and you will notice how fair the trial actually was.  Notice how the reporting on this website is presented factually and neutrally, as opposed to the highly opinionated and subjective material given by Mumia's support group that has no factual basis.

Read "Murdered By Mumia", the recently published book by Danny Faulkner's widow Maureen and Philadelphia journalist Michael Smerconish.  It will give you a clear understanding of the events that have transpired over the past 26 years.

Remember to spread the word.  Keep Danny's memory alive.  

1. Officer Faulkner acted bravely as one of Philadelphia's finest police officers.

2. Mumia Abu-Jamal is not a "political prisoner", but rather a cold-hearted murderer.  He deserves no support or respect.

3. Mumia has already received a fair trial and now must face the consequences of his immoral actions.

4. Regardless of your position towards the death penalty, Mumia is clearly guilty of his crime, and he deserves neither a new trial nor freedom.</description>
  <mission>Recognize the heroic actions of Officer Daniel Faulkner and the fact that Mumia Abu-Jamal murdered Officer Faulkner and received a fair trial.</mission>
  <name>Justice for Daniel Faulkner</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3496</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">18497</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">446.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/i1/eX/a2/yf/Fw/Z4/aKOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
