<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Worldwide Fistula Fund (an Illinois not-for-profit corporation), originally organized as The Worldwide Fund for Mothers Injured in Childbirth in 1995, is a public charity organized for the purpose of supporting international medical education and research on the problem of obstetrical trauma in the developing world. 

The most serious form of childbirth trauma in developing countries is obstructed labor, which in turn leads to the development of obstetric fistulas.  Obstructed labor occurs when the mother&#8217;s pelvis is too small to permit the fetus to pass through during childbirth.  This problem cannot be resolved without a surgical operation (Cesarean section), which is unavailable  in many parts of the world, especially in Africa.  Because most pregnant women in these countries cannot get emergency obstetric care, they may be in labor for days, only to a deliver a stillborn infant at the end of their travail.  

Prolonged obstructed labor results in severe damage to the soft tissues of the mother&#8217;s pelvis from the unrelenting pressure of the fetal head which has been impacted against them during labor.   This process cuts off the blood supply to large parts of the mother&#8217;s vagina, bladder and rectum and results in the death of these tissues.  This in turn creates large holes (fistulas) between these organs and leads to constant, uncontrollable loss of urine and stool through the vagina.  



1. Support for the repair of obstetric fistulas throughout Africa and other parts of the developing world are necessary.

2. Without this aide, many women will be shunned from their families and will lead a shameful and solitary existence.

3. Development of education programs to improve traditional midwifery practices and change the beliefs that have promoted the development of fistulas in the past as part of an on-going grass-roots movement to aid the empowerment of African women regarding ch</description>
  <mission>promote excellent, ethical whole-person care for women with obstetric fistulas.</mission>
  <name>Worldwide Fistula Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/350</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">488</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">387.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pK/pu/Jo/yO/Po/OD/Qi/4kS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
