<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>UC Davis undergraduates and medical students initiated the Vietnamese Cancer Awareness, Research and Education Society (VN CARES) in response to the National Cancer Institute&#8217;s Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) report that revealed Vietnamese American women had the highest incidence rate of cervical cancer &#8211; five times greater than Caucasian women.  To alleviate this alarming rate, VN CARES began working with the Vietnamese community of Sacramento in 2001 to implement their goals.

Payments for screenings and/or follow-up treatments are provided by the Cancer Detection Program (CDP).  Eligible women receive free screenings and follow-up treatments at various CDP-certified Sacramento clinics.  To seek out the target population, VN CARES holds monthly recruitments at local Vietnamese churches, temples and supermarkets in a grass-roots effort to rapidly enroll these women for screening.

VN CARES collaborates with Boat People S.O.S., a non-profit community-based organization that serves immigrants and refugees.  BPSOS schedules appointments for the enrolled women while members of the VN CARES clinical team are responsible for attending the clinic with the women to offer translational services and emotional support.  Through these efforts, we have been successful in alleviating the social barriers that may have had prevented these individuals from receiving their regular screening: language deficiency, cultural estrangement, high screening cost, and low accessibility.

Please visit http://vncares.ucdavis.edu for more information. All donations will benefit the Susan G. Komen Foundation to fund breast cancer research, patient services, and advocacy through its many grantees, including VN CARES.


1. Promote cancer awareness through outreaches and educational seminars in the Vietnamese community.

2. Recruit, enroll, and assist Vietnamese individuals into cancer preventative care and cancer treatment programs.

3. Conduct needs-assessments to improve the delivery of healthcare through literature review/research, and the gathering of qualitative and quantitative data.

4. Reduce the cancer-related disparities in the Vietnamese community.

5. Ensure that all Vietnamese individuals obtain skills and knowledge to maintain a cancer-reducing lifestyle.

6. Network with other organizations at local and national levels to achieve common objectives.

7. Inspire future health professionals to continue to share the visions of VN CARES.

8. Participate in the planning and implementation of research activities designed to identify the health care needs of the Vietnamese community.</description>
  <mission>To promote cancer awareness, knowledge, and preventative care in the Vietnamese Community, in addition to creating opportunities for students to gain experiences in the community.</mission>
  <name>VN CARES</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3523</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">80</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ng/pI/zB/xo/SD/GY/1vmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
