<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The brothers of Phi Kappa Theta - Alpha Rho Chapter - Of Belmont Abbey College, in North Carolina welcome the opportunity to brighten the lives and futures of children unfortunately afflicted with disease or disability

To nurture the belief in our commitment to Brotherhood beyond our immediate neighbors, at the 1997 convention in San Diego, the brothers of Phi Kappa Theta chose the Children's Miracle Network as our National Philanthropy. CMN is a non-profit organization dedicated to raising funds for children's hospitals. Currently there are over 165 hospitals in the network and annually 7 million children benefit from their care. Money raised goes toward patient services, research programs, new equipment, and capital facilities. One of the many great things about CMN is that donations go to each Chapters Local Children's Hospital - benefiting their community. 

Children's Miracle Network is the alliance of premier children's hospitals. Every year, Children's Miracle Network hospitals treat 17 million children for every disease and injury imaginable. Children's Miracle Network hospitals impact the lives of more children than any other children's organization in the world. Children's hospitals provide state-of-the-art care, life-saving research and preventative education for children 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. There is a Children's Miracle Network hospital dedicated to serving children in every community across the United States and Canada. These hospitals are committed to providing the best care for children when they need it.

Since all proceeds go to the hospital that is closest to each Chapter, all donations will be going to help...

 Levine Children's Hospital in Charlotte, North Carolina








1. TO HELP THE CHILDREN, BECAUSE IF WE DON'T, THEN WHO WILL?</description>
  <mission>Raise Money For Children's Miracle Network  Local Hospital (Levine Children's Hospital) in North Carolina </mission>
  <name>Children's Miracle Network - Phi Kappa Theta Fraternity - Alpha Rho Chapter - Belmont Abbey College</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3524</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">61</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8N/8P/EW/mW/OM/1A/lO2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
