<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dear Family &amp; Friends,
I am excited to tell you about a monumental endeavor I began in February.  I have been training to participate in my first triathlon!  That's right, on July 22 nd; I will swim, bike and run (.9 miles, 26 miles, and 6.2 miles) in the New York City Triathlon.
Completing a triathlon is a goal that I used to think was beyond my reach.  This kind of undertaking was for other people who were&#8230; in shape.  I am training to beat the voice that says, "You can't do it."  I am determined to defeat that voice. 
However, there is a far greater reason than my personal challenge of completing the race.  This is the reason I am writing to you today.  I selected to train with The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society.  I pledged to help raise money for research and patient services programs.  As you may or may not know, Leukemia is the #1 disease killer of children and young adults under the age of twenty.  Although the cause of blood cancers remains unknown, ongoing research and advancement in treatments brings us closer to a cure every day. 
Unfortunately, many of us know someone who has been affected by Leukemia, breast cancer or some other form of cancer.  Thankfully, we also know many people who have survived via the advancement in research and treatments available today. Without people like us who give to these organizations, those cures wouldn't be possible. 
Please support me in my effort of not only defeating that little voice that says, "you can't do it" but also to help raise money for research and patient services programs for the multitude of people that battle Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma.  
Much love,
Reuben Twersky
Fundraising link:  http://www.active.com/donate/tntnyc/tntnycRTwersk
Or you can send checks payable to: The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society. 
Mail them to:
Reuben Twersky
301 E. 79th St., Apt 5P
New York, NY 10021

1. Raise Money to find a cure to this horrible disease</description>
  <mission>Raise $2,500.00</mission>
  <name>Reuben Twersky's NYC Triathlon Fundraising The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3554</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Y4/44/py/mo/hD/3n/eluS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
