<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 1995 by award-winning playwright Karen Zacarias, Young Playwrights&#8217; Theater (YPT) teaches  students to express themselves clearly and creatively through the art of playwriting. Through interactive in-school and after-school programs, YPT activates student learning and inspires students to understand the power of language and realize their potential as both individuals and artists. By publicly presenting and discussing student-written work, YPT promotes community dialogue and respect for young artists. Throughout D.C. Public Schools (D.C.P.S.), YPT works with students who are ethnically diverse and chronically underserved, primarily in the Latino and African American communities of Columbia Heights, Mt. Pleasant and Adams Morgan neighborhoods in Washington, D.C. YPT strives to be a driving force in arts education nationally as well, leading the field with innovative arts-integrated and standards-based programs that engage students in an artistic process while truly enhancing their education.

Deeply engaged with local schools, YPT:

&#8226; Teaches hundreds of underserved students each year, enhancing their literacy and empowering them to engage the world around them.
&#8226; Fully integrates into existing curricula, using its innovative approach to learning to help classroom teachers teach the required standards.  
&#8226; Helps students learn the importance of writing, revision and grammar as a way to communicate what is important to them -- their ideas, dreams and beliefs -- to the world around them. 
&#8226; Employs accomplished teachers, who are also seasoned artists, to teach students the craft of theatre and playwriting.  
&#8226; Seeks to have long-term impact on student growth by working with a limited number of students each year and tracking their progress after their completion of the program.

As YPT seeks to nurture a new generation of writers, three core programs offer D.C. students the opportunity to share their words with the world: the In-School Playwriting Program, which enhances student literacy, creative expression and collaboration through the art of playwriting; the After-School Playwriting Program, aimed at strengthening students&#8217; community engagement, collaboration, and conflict resolution by exploring a theatrical process as an ensemble; and the Express Tour, a professional tour of plays written by young people that shares the work of young playwrights with their greater community in order to create a dialogue that can engage, entertain, and educate.

YPT has also recently expanded its programming beyond the classroom, presenting its new monthly play-reading series New Writers Now! to share student work with the community, expanding our studio space in Columbia Heights to host our new Young Playwrights&#8217; Workshop and collaborating with the Kennedy Center, the White House Historical Association and the Smithsonian Institution to create opportunities to showcase full-length plays by D.C. students for local and national audiences through our Special Projects series. 

Urban, low-income youth, who are especially at risk for social and educational disengagement from school, benefit greatly from arts integration programming. YPT programming actively engages all students, even those who are introverted or have special learning needs. We work to teach to multiple intelligences, employing visual, auditory and oral teaching and learning techniques to reach every student, including special education students and students who are Limited or Non-English Proficient. Participants in YPT programming develop cognitive, social and personal skills that not only provide them with the tools necessary to succeed in school, but help them to overcome the obstacles created by disadvantaged backgrounds to succeed in the postsecondary environment and in the workplace. 

To learn more about YPT, visit www.yptdc.org.</description>
  <mission>Young Playwrights&#8217; Theater (YPT) teaches students to express themselves clearly and creatively through the art of playwriting. </mission>
  <name>Young Playwrights' Theater</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3555</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">247</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">135.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fd/EN/Ds/mh/PH/Og/rT/uKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
