<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The comprehensive objective, to be achieved in progressive stages, is a democratic, non-military, federal world government, which can solve world problems peacefully and administer those affairs which transcend national boundaries for the benefit of humanity everywhere. 

The World Government will have a representative World Parliament to enact world legislation, with one chamber elected by the people; A World Executive responsible to the Parliament, with authority to implement world legislation directly; a World Judiciary with mandatory enforcement of decisions; and such other organs as are desirable and necessary for the adequate and effective solution of world problems and management of global affairs.

http://www.worldparliamentgov.net/

1. A World Government would serve to prevent war, secure disarmament, and resolve territorial and other disputes which endanger peace and human rights.

2. A World Government would serve to protect universal human rights, including life, liberty, security, democracy, and equal opportunities in life.

3. A World Government would serve to obtain for all people on earth the conditions required for equitable economic and social development and for diminishing social differences.

4. A World Government would serve to regulate world trade, communications, transportation, currency, standards, use of world resources, and other global and international processes.

5. A World Government would serve to protect the environment and the ecological fabric of life from all sources of damage, and to control technological innovations whose effects transcend national boundaries, for the purpose of keeping Earth a safe, healthy 

6. A World Government would serve to devise and implement solutions to all problems which are beyond the capacity of national governments, or which are now or may become of global or international concern or consequence.

7. Social change is needed globally, in order for the creation of a World Government to occur.

8. Efforts among individuals and organizations must work towards a common and holistic goal, as opposed to the dispersement of seperated,narrow causes.</description>
  <mission>Help to establish a directly elected,representative,democratic World Government.</mission>
  <name>World Citizens Movement</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3562</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">48</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PU/iy/Xo/bU/PY/V0/ux/RGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
