<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A few years back, I produced, directed, performed a fundraiser called "Literature &amp; Libations" for The Teresa Group (The Teresa Group is Canada&#8217;s oldest community-based chari&#173;table organization specifically serving children affected by HIV and AIDS and their families.)

With the help of talented friends and artists, those who also donated their time and those who came out to support, over $500 was raised in a one night only event. 

So here I am, now with the help of the web to spread the word even further... Please join me and do the same by going to their website, directly 

http://www.teresagroup.org

Why? because FB is still primarily a U.S functionality and if you click on the donate button .. the monies will go to the organization I chose in Los Angeles. .

Either way, It's all good.. :)) Keep the Light strong &amp; bright

Y.T. Dawna

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Now a little  bit about The Teresa Group:

"Working in association with the HIV and AIDS Comprehensive Care Team at the Toronto Hospital for Sick Children and other community agencies, The Teresa Group provides leadership through example, information, education and innovation."

"Hearing the voices of children and families affected by HIV and AIDS, The Teresa Group provides practical assistance and emotional support through professional staff and trained volunteers."

Please visit website for more information:

http://www.teresagroup.org

1. Hearing the Voices of Children</description>
  <mission>To raise funds, awareness,compassion &amp; love.. and to always remember</mission>
  <name>Children &amp; Families Living with HIV &amp; AIDS</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3578</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">262</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hK/QU/dp/g2/E8/Cc/1ZbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
