<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The mission is to ensure that completely reliable transport is available for the complete delivery of health services throughout Africa by 2015


   Vision

Riders for Health is an humanitarian organisation. For us, this means working towards a world in which no-one is subject to the miseries of poverty and avoidable ill-health.

   Mission

Riders for Health ensures vehicles used for the delivery of health care and associated development in Africa are available for the maximum time at the minimum cost.

Across Africa Riders is steadily solving the problem described by our Patron, HRH The Princess Royal, as 'the tyranny of distance'.

   Shared objectives

Working with our partners we aim to ensure that completely reliable transport is available for the complete delivery of health services throughout Africa by 2015.

Transport management is not a headline-making or an eye-catching initiative, but it is the long-term, essential answer to Africa's problems. Africa's people can be free of the oppression of disease; Africa can have a chance to move forward.
-----
-----------
For more detailed information about Riders' programmes please visit:

http://www.riders.org
-----------
-----

1. The work of saving and enhancing lives in Africa must principally be carried out by Africans.

2. The work must be systematic, replicable and sustainable.

3. It will involve changing attitude and outlooks as well as technical behaviour.

4. In every aspect of transport development, the needs of both genders must be considered and their needs promoted.

5. The work must be vigorous but culturally sensitive.

6. Riders for Health's work will enable people, from colleagues to beneficiaries, to fulfil their true potential.</description>
  <mission>Using motorcycles and 4-wheelers to deliver medicine in Africa!</mission>
  <name>Riders for Health</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3582</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4994</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2350.18</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wI/Ot/if/sA/WJ/yw/vY/lxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
