<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Do you think you're making enough of a difference in the international world? Check out the following articles on Genocide + Human Rights: 

Falun Gong: 
http://falunhr.org/index.php?option=content&amp;task=view&amp;id=1495&amp;Itemid=

PM, public servants at odds over policy
http://www.thestar.com/article/229056 

U.N. Peacekeepers Vow to Continue in Lebanon After 6 Troops Killed
http://www.nytimes.com/2007/06/25/world/middleeast/25cnd-lebanon.html?ref=world 

New York Times: 
Sudan Bowed to Pressure on Darfur Force: Opposition
http://www.nytimes.com/reuters/world/international-sudan-darfur-opposition.html

World Briefing | Africa: Rwanda: Genocide Trial Finishes After 5 Years
http://query.nytimes.com/gst/fullpage.html?res=9C01E6DE1030F931A35755C0A9619C8B63

The Toronto Star: 
Atrocities of a war without end
Congo is officially at peace, but the horrors go on for thousands of women and children who suffer sexual abuse in violence fuelled by guns and greed
http://www.thestar.com/article/223057 

The Horn of Africa's hidden war
Ogaden desert villagers accuse U.S.-backed Ethiopian soldiers of abuses in bid to crush separatist movement
http://www.thestar.com/article/226831 


KEEP CHECKING EVERY WEEK FOR NEW UPDATES!!! 

The Genocide &amp; Human Rights University Program is a two-week course at the beginning of August which takes a comparative approach to the study of genocide using a number of case studies such as the Armenian Genocide, the Jewish Holocaust, the Cambodian Genocide, the Rwandan Genocide and Darfur.  It will allow you to express yourself more effectively on issues of genocide and human rights and at the same time, you will meet like-minded youth from all over the world and make new connections!  

www.genocidestudies.org
www.zoryaninstitute.org 

ALSO, if you are interested in the GHRUP and would like to participate: 
Search for Genocide and Human Rights University Program as a Facebook Group and JOIN NOW! 


1. Genocide is a universal human experience and that, as such, it must be the concern of all individuals and institutions.</description>
  <mission>The mission of the IIGHRS is to help develop a new generation of scholars to engage in research and publication in the field of genocide and human rights studies.</mission>
  <name>International Institute for Genocide &amp; Human Rights Studies</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3590</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">190</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.03</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sH/u7/Sm/qd/li/dF/c6/TWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
