<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Operation Gratitude welcomes the participation of all people, of all ages, of all backgrounds and of all political persuasions

Visit the website: http://www.OperationGratitude.com/

Visit the YouTube Channel:
http://www.youtube.com/OpGrat 

Follow us on Twitter:
http://twitter.com/OpGratitude

Like us on Facebook:
http://www.facebook.com/OperationGratitude

MISSION STATEMENT:

Hundreds of thousands of American troops are deployed in hostile and remote regions of the world, including the Middle East, Afghanistan, and on ships throughout international waters. The physical conditions they must endure are difficult and they may be separated from loved ones for long periods of time. OPERATION GRATITUDE seeks to lift troops' morale, and bring a smile to their faces by sending care packages to service members deployed in harm's way. OPERATION GRATITUDE care packages contain food, toiletries, entertainment items and personal letters of appreciation, all wrapped with good wishes of love and support.

Through Collection Drives, Letter Writing Campaigns and Donations of requested items or funds, OPERATION GRATITUDE provides civilians anywhere in America a way to express their respect and appreciation to the men and women of the U.S. military in an active, hands-on manner.

OPERATION GRATITUDE is a 501(c)(3) non-profit, volunteer-based corporation, funded entirely by private donations. For safety and security, the assembling of all packages occurs at the Army National Guard Armory in Van Nuys, California. 

*Photo courtesy of Operation Gratitude*

To read past Newsletters:
http://archive.constantcontact.com/fs070/1100969980026/archive/1102679300225.html 

For more Photos: 
http://www.opgratitude.com/gallery.php

1. Send care packages to our troops through Operation Gratitude

2. Say thank you to our men and women in uniform

3. Write letters, collect items, raise funds

4. Become a "Fan" of Operation Gratitude: 

5. http://www.facebook.com/OperationGratitude</description>
  <mission>Put a smile on a Service Member's face and express our appreciation by sending care packages to those in harm's way</mission>
  <name>Send Care Packages to Our Heroes</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3596</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5764</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3458.16</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/WQ/0c/5E/cO/r4/EZ/ee/DWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
