<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hendricks Civic Theatre is a community theatre organization that has been around for about 30 years.  Based out of Danville, Indiana, we strive to provide opportunities for the public to be involved in theatre, with a special emphasis on presenting first-timers, both-young and old, with their first experience.

Several years ago, the old movie theatre we used to call "home" changed ownership, and was no longer available for our use, thus our wandering began.  Since that time, we have had to acquire a venue for each show we perform.  This is always one of the most difficult and stressful issues we deal with every production, not to mention one of the most costly.

Back in 1998 HCT had a little church building gifted to us.  Unfortunately after much research, conversion of that building to a theatre will be nearly impossible.
(for more on this see http://www.hendrickscivic.com/hct_theatre_files/theater.htm)

Hendricks Civic Theatre would like your support so we may continue to provide the theatre experience to the members of the community.  Having a permanent location will help us tremendously.  It would be a place we could tailor to our needs and we wouldn't have to work around other people's schedules to use it.  The benefits are too numerous to list them all.

There are many ways to support us.  You can donate money, participate in the shows, volunteer, or just simply come to watch one of our shows.

For more information on our theatre group, check our website at www.hendrickscivic.com

Thanks from all of us at HCT!

1. The performing arts are an important part of our community.

2. Theatre is a positive experience that should be shared with everyone.

3. Providing family-friendly shows and opportunities for first-timers are priorities.</description>
  <mission>Raise money for and promote awarness of Hendricks Civic Theatre (HCT) so we may get a permanent location to perform.</mission>
  <name>Help our Theatre Group get a Home!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3604</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">21</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/O0/d0/6C/Sv/C4/3U/ZOPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
