<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Bubel/Aiken Foundation was founded in July 2003 by singing sensation Clay Aiken from the hit TV show, American Idol. His interest in autism issues led him, along with Diane Bubel (whose son Michael is autistic and was tutored by Aiken), to found the Bubel/Aiken Foundation, which supports the integration of children with disabilities into the life environment of their non-disabled peers. Initially, Aiken developed the concept of the foundation as a project to complete credit hours needed for graduation from the University of North Carolina at Charlotte (UNC). Aiken worked on the organization and set up of the Foundation during the time that he was competing on American Idol and touring over the summer. After receiving over $50,000 in donations to the as-yet non-existent organization, Aiken decided to follow through and make the organization a reality. On July 28, 2003, just 2 months after the end of the competition, Clay officially announced the creation of The Bubel/Aiken Foundation.

The BAF runs summer camps which reflect this mission by providing camp experiences to children with and without disabilities in an integrated environment. Some of these camps are run in partnership with the YMCA. BAF also presents Able to Serve awards to support the volunteer efforts of children with physical and mental disabilities. These awards are granted to fund service projects by children with disabilities to encourage them to provide service to others.[1]

The BAF was presented with a $500,000 grant from the US government to develop a curriculum for inclusion to be used in schools across the country. In addition State Farm has granted $1.5 million dollars to The Bubel/Aiken Foundation to help develop a primary education curriculum focused on teaching social and life skills through service to children of all levels of ability.[2]

In addition the BAF sponsors "Wrapping For Inclusion" fund raisers during the holidays.

http://www.bubelaiken.org/

1. Creating an environment for children where inclusion is embraced</description>
  <mission>to bridge the gap that exists between young people with special needs and the world around them</mission>
  <name>Bubel/Aiken Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3606</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">102</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/N3/ub/kq/2a/Th/Kv/R0TS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
