<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>El Ranchito de Los Ni&#241;os is a safe, loving home where children grow in a supportive, family farm setting. Our goals are to give children a stable home in which they may grow to adulthood and to allow sibling groups to remain together. All ages of children, 0 to 18, are considered for admission to our home. Our preference is for an entire sibling group to be placed in El Ranchito de Los Ni&#241;os. All children have to go through a screening process in order to determine if our home is the correct placement for them.

El Ranchito de Los Ni&#241;os offers family-style living in a 7000 square foot home with Catholic Sisters serving as full-time house parents. Each child assumes responsibility for various tasks required to keep the home running smoothly (i.e. vacuuming, cleaning, dishwashing, table setting, etc.). Each child is expected to keep his/her room clean and tidy daily. Additional responsibilities at our home include animal care, landscaping, gardening, general maintenance, helping with meal preparation, laundry, etc.  Education, personal responsibility and growth as well as charitable giving to others are the guideline and basis for how the children are raised.

1. Children need a permanent stable home where they are loved unconditionally.

2. Allowing sibling groups to remain together signifies our commitment to family.

3. Education, personal responsibility and charity to others guide us as we strive to provide a successful alternative to temporary foster care. </description>
  <mission>provide a nurturing and long-term environment, in a rural setting, for children (focusing on sibling groups) who need a place to grow, love and learn.</mission>
  <name>El Ranchito de los Ni&#241;os, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3629</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1i/JT/nT/4D/t4/4q/rm5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
