<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Get Kids Going! helps disabled children take part in sport by providing specialist sports wheelchairs, sports grants and year round support. They can then compete in marathons, triathlons, tennis, athletics, skiing, rugby, basketball etc. With your help, many could become Paralympic champions and world record holders. Charity Registration No 1063471

We (Me, Graham Clark and Neal Curry) are planning on doing 3 challenges in order to raise money for Get Kids Going!

We decided on the 3 craziest challenges that we could come up with. You can see the links at the bottom.
The first 2 challenges consist of us trying to travel over 6000 miles in a car worth less than &#163;100. 
In the last challenge we are going to try and travel 26 miles in trainers that are also worth less than &#163;100.

I wonder which will be hardest? And whats more likely to breakdown, us or the car??

Please sponsor us at www.justgiving.com/three_events

PLEASE USE ABOVE LINK AND DO NOT USE FACEBOOK LINK AS IT TAKES YOU TO THEIR U.S. NOMINATED NON-PROFIT CHARITY.
                                                                           
For more details on any on these events goto:
                                                                              
1. http://www.calais2casablanca.com
                                                                                
2. http://www.home2rome.com
                                                                               
3. www.ingnycmarathon.org/results/index.php



1. Wherever possible everybody should have the same opportunities in life.

2. Everyone should have access to equipment that will maximise there potential irrespective of any disability.</description>
  <mission>Supply sporting equipment to disabled children</mission>
  <name>Get Kids Going! (NYC Marathon)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3641</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PL/Er/Cu/ZT/qx/XP/1BlS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
