<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A refugee is a person who "owing to a well-founded fear of being persecuted for reasons of race, religion, nationality, membership of a particular social group, or political opinion, is outside the country of his nationality, and is unable to or, owing to such fear, is unwilling to avail himself of the protection of that country..."

Refugees should receive at least the same rights and basic help as any other foreigner who is a legal resident, including freedom of thought, of movement and freedom from torture and degrading treatment. Economic and social rights are equally applicable. Refugees should have access to medical care, schooling and the right to work. 

it has been officially recognized that genital mutilation represents a form of persecution and that this can be a basis for refugee status. In at least one case, a woman who feared persecution in her country because of her refusal to inflict genital mutilation on her infant daughter was recognized as a refugee. 

It doesn't take much. There are numerous ways you can get involved to help raise funds for and awareness of refugee issues and the work of the UN Refugee Agency. 

- Make a donation today that directly translates into more refugee children attending school, new shelters for refugees and vital protection assistance. 
- Help us raise awareness about the plight of refugees. 
- Interested in working or interning with UNHCR? Find out how. 

You still have questions? Contact us. http://www.unhcr.org/cgi-bin/texis/vtx/contact?hq=y

Your support will make a difference.

Thank you! 


1. the agency has helped an estimated 50 million people 

2. Today, a staff of around 6,689 people in 116 countries continues to help 20.8 million persons.</description>
  <mission>Aid refugees emergencies </mission>
  <name>Refugees - UNHCR</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3644</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">428</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jM/u0/qO/bl/yi/Hu/e3SS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
