<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Without the Chinese government's oil contracts with Khartoum, Darfur would not be the bloodbath that it is today. Since 2003, at least 200,000 innocent Darfurians have lost their lives at the hands of the Arab, janjaweed militias. Since the genocide erupted, the international community has had little success in quelling the violence. If we are to make ANY progress, drastic action is in order immediately. 

The Communist Party bigwhigs in Beijing answer to no one. Without election cycles, the current regime is in power for as long as it wants to be. Pressuring the government from within the country is impossible. 

Diplomacy has yielded minimal success.  With a permenant seat on the security council, China is in a powerful position to curtail any and all efforts to end their fatal relationship with Sudan's oil industry. 

The only leverage left to pursue is a boycott of the  2008 Olympics in Beijing. China fought like hell to host the games and even just a unilateral American boycott would hurt the games.  Unlike China, we are a Democratic society in which pols are held accountable for immoral judgment. With enough voices demanding a boycott of 2008, our elected officals will listen. It's an uphill battle, butamidst diplomacy's continual failures, its the only battle worth pursuing. 

1. In the same way that President Carter boycotted the Moscow games in 1080 following the Soviet invasion of Afganistan, President Bush shall ban United States participation in the 2008 Summer olympic Games

2. We will accomplish this goal through lobbying our federal legislators who will consequently pressure Bush into calling for a boycott.</description>
  <mission>Pressure the Chinese government into ending their economic relationship with Sudan</mission>
  <name>Save Darfur: Boycott the 2008 Olympic Games</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3654</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">88</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Bi/Ld/lm/Iw/kL/7n/z4mS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
