<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"I ask you young people... to become prophets of life." - Pope John Paul II

FOCUS works with college students to help them make the heroic decision to give their lives to Jesus Christ. By doing so, they gain true Vision for Life: for leadership in college, and for making an impact after graduation. FOCUS helps college students to allow Jesus Christ to be the Lord of their lives - including their studies, social life, dating relationships, and major life decisions.

- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -

Founded in 1998 by Curtis Martin, FOCUS, The Fellowship of Catholic University Students, is a national outreach to college campuses, to secular and Catholic schools. Through small group Bible studies, large group leadership training, and one-on-one discipleship, FOCUS brings the fullness of life and truth in the Catholic Church to college students and gives the tools to help them share this good news with their friends. FOCUS is working to play a vital role in the new evangelization called for by Pope John Paul II. 

FOCUS teaches recent college graduates, trains them in the teachings of the Church, Scripture and practical aspects of ministry, and sends them out typically in teams of four to serve on college campuses. FOCUS staff members make an initial two-year commitment to this full-time work. FOCUS works with the blessing of the local bishop and the support of the pastor and existing ministry(ies).

1. According to Crisis Magazine (September 2001), half of Catholic undergraduates have stopped practicing their faith by the end of their freshman year alone.

2. Approximately 1,370,000 abortions occur annually in the United States according to the Alan Guttmacher Institute. One of every five abortions is performed on a college woman. - National Right to Life Committee

3. Each year, approximately 15 percent of the nation's 15 million college students suffer from a depression that renders them incapable of functioning normally. They skip classes, they isolate themselves form their friends, and they turn inwards in a downwar

4. 44% of United States college students engage in binge drinking. College presidents agree binge drinking is one of the most serious problems on college campuses. - Advocacy for the Prevention of Alcohol Problems</description>
  <mission>To know Christ Jesus, and to fulfill His Great Commission, by first living and then communicating the fullness of life within the Family of God, the Church. </mission>
  <name>Fellowship of Catholic University Students (FOCUS)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3661</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">421</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jX/18/Ov/QX/Fk/KX/6j/e8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
