<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Thinking that you know pretty well about TB? Thinking that TB is not a big deal?
Well, THINK AGAIN!

About one third of the world population are infected by the bacteria. New TB strains, the Multi-Drug Resistant (MDR) TB and the Extensively-Drug Resistant (XDR) TB are more difficult to cure than you would ever think. For regular TB, the treatment involves at least three drugs for SIX to NINE months every day. For MDRs, the regiment can go to TWO years. For XDRs, there is no effective cure yet.

Look at the cure rate: 
For all cancers in combination: ~ 66%. 
For SARS, the virus that we all panicked about: ~90%. 
For XDR TB under optimal health system: ALMOST 30%. 
For HIV patients, opportunistic TB infection is the leading killer. HIV kills 6000 people/day. TB kills 5000 people/day.

TB usually associates with poverty. TB hits mostly the youths and middle ages in their prime, so here goes the vicious cycle: you are poor and malnourished -&gt; you are more prone to TB -&gt; you cannot work and have no money for treatment / you spend all your money for treatment -&gt;  you get poorer. The cycle goes on. 

START NOW! STOP TB!

ACTION I:
We are sponsoring a 20-year-old college sophomore, a TB / Hep B patient in China, who cannot afford his cost of treatment. We decided to pay for his TB drugs (cost $500 in 12 months). We are also contacting hospitals in Vietnam and Zimbabwe to learn about their TB treatment policies and then can help needy patients there. We want to extend our project and reach as many patients as possible. Please help us to achieve this goal by donating generously!  

ACTION II:
Learn more about TB! Find out how TB affects your region and the world. Raise awareness about the threat and the socioeconomic subtext of TB. Stop TB from killing!

ACTION III:
Negotiate with major drug companies to produce cheaper and more effective drugs for regular and drug-resistant TB. 

PLEASE SUPPORT OUR CAUSE!


1. TB is a seriously resuming disease that needs to be recognized and eradicated

2. Health care is a universal right</description>
  <mission>raise public awareness about TB and give monetary support to needy individuals for their TB treatment </mission>
  <name>International Tuberculosis Relief Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3680</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">200</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qk/al/cA/nb/p7/6J/k0oS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
