<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>America is in desperate need of change. After eight years of Bush and neoconservatism, this country is crying out for a real leader, not a flashy politician hiding behind slogans and catchphrases. Ron Paul is our best hope to return America to the shining beacon of freedom it used to be.

Facts:

Ron has never voted to raise taxes.
Ron has never voted for an unbalanced budget.
Ron has never voted for the Iraq War.
Ron has never voted for a federal restriction on gun ownership.
Ron has never voted to increase the power of the executive branch.
Ron has never voted to raise congressional pay.
Ron has never taken a government-paid junket.

Ron voted against the Patriot Act.
Ron votes against regulating the Internet.
Ron voted against NAFTA and CAFTA.
Ron votes against the United Nations.
Ron votes against the welfare state.
Ron votes against reinstating a military draft.

Ron votes to preserve the constitution.
Ron votes to cut government spending.
Ron votes to lower healthcare costs.
Ron votes to end the war on drugs.
Ron votes to protect civil liberties.
Ron votes to secure our borders with real immigration reform.
Ron votes to eliminate tax funded abortions and to overturn Roe v Wade.
Ron votes to protect religious freedom.

A great interview at YouTube headquarters:
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yGGOiv7sA4w

IMPORTANT: If you are looking to donate to the Ron Paul campaign, DO NOT donate to this cause. At this point in time, Facebook Causes does not have the option of donating directly to political campaigns. Donations should instead be sent to: https://www.ronpaul2008.com/forms/contribute.cfm

1. The neoconservative foreign policy is trashing our image abroad, and is the #1 instigator of anti-American terrorism.

2. Our country lacks a sound fiscal policy. No nation cna survive on a diet of taxes, debt, and inflation!

3. Almost all major candidates for the Presidency are actively seeking to rip our Constitution to shreds.

4. Ron Paul is the only candidate from the major parties who can reverse our government's downward spiral.</description>
  <mission>elect Ron Paul President in 2008.</mission>
  <name>Ron Paul '08</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/371</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2492</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1160.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cE/pN/U5/TK/dq/bo/okqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
