<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>BRCA2 is a gene with many different functions.  It is found on the thirteenth chromosome and is officially called the &#8220;breast cancer 2, early onset&#8221; gene.  BRCA2 is a tumor-suppressing gene, which means that it acts to stop cells from growing and dividing in a manner that is too quick or erratic.  When chromosomes trade genetic material in preparation for cell division, BRCA2 supplies the instructions to construct a BRCA2 protein that helps repair any breaks in or damage to DNA.  This occurs in normal cells (in the nucleus) as a way to preserve the stability of a cell&#8217;s hereditary information.

However, when a mutation occurs in the BRCA2 gene, detrimental effects can occur; over four hundred and fifty mutations have been identified at this point in time and many of these mutations increase the risk of breast cancer.  The mutations occurring are additions or removals of nitrogenous bases in the BRCA2 gene, which cause the disturbance of protein assembly and thereby create a BRCA2 protein that does not function properly; when this protein is found in cells, it does not have the ability to help repair DNA that needs mending.  Not only can mutations in the BRCA2 gene cause an increased risk of breast cancer, but it also can cause certain types of anemia, leukemia, ovarian, prostate, and pancreatic cancers.

When a mutation occurs in the BRCA2 gene, it changes the function and ability of the BRCA2 protein, which can lead to an increased risk of breast cancer.


1. Awareness must be raised so that stem-cell and other types of research can be funded.</description>
  <mission>raise awareness about genetic breast cancer</mission>
  <name>BRCA2</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3711</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">705</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SZ/hL/Fl/x4/4n/2A/W1FS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
