<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Every week, you and I and the rest of the United States attend happy hours: to catch up with friends, shoot the breeze, and take the load off with an ice-cold lager. 

Across the globe in Sudan and the Horn of Africa, women and children yearn for the luxuries of friendship and laughter.  Caught in the crossfire of genocide and civil war, Sudanese families struggle daily to survive.  In fact, as the youth of America toast to the future, a typical woman in West Darfur is looking for the safest place to collect firewood or put her children through school.  And for orphaned Sudanese children, whose numbers are growing, the prospect of safe living and good fortune remains even more elusive.

I propose that we turn the tradition of the happy hour binge on its head.  Yes, you can still pad your beer gut after a long day&#8217;s work.  But let&#8217;s dedicate the second and third drinks to a child&#8217;s education in Sudan.  

For $25, you can pay for a Sudanese teacher&#8217;s salary for one month.  In beer speak, that&#8217;s about 4.5 beers.  ONE MONTH&#8217;S SALARY for a SUDANESE TEACHER or 4.5 beers.  The choice is yours.  

This initiative is a win-win for everyone &#8211; you drink less, improve your health, and help orphans receive an education in Sudan.  You&#8217;ll also have much cooler stories to tell than your friends. 

To get the ball rolling, I am chipping in $10 per week for the next 16 weeks to support &#8220;Schooling for Sudan Orphan Refugees&#8221; &#8211; www.globalgiving.com/1718.  

How you can help: 

1)  Host your own weekly happy hour to  raise awareness and support the cause. 
 
2) Tell all of your friends to come. 

3) Donate the cost of two beers &#8211; $10 &#8211; to support education for Sudanese orphans.

I am also launching three official &#8220;Summer Happy Hours of Hope&#8221; here in Washington, DC.  The venue will most likely be Bus Boys &amp; Poets on 14th Street and V in Northwest DC.  Stay tuned for further details.

1. We believe that if you can afford to drink two beers per week, you can afford to support a good cause while improving your own health

2. Orphans in Sudan have hopes and dreams just like you and me

3. YOU have the power to provide hope to the people of Sudan TODAY</description>
  <mission>Transform happy hours into a positive force for social change</mission>
  <name>Happy Hours of Hope - Spend Your Beer Money on Education for Sudanese Orphans</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3714</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">27</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6M/2q/po/gp/5c/Dj/Ty2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
