<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>PRISON RAPE Affects a large numbers of men, women, and youth; causes serious physical and psychological harm; targets the vulnerable; violates international, U.S., and state laws; but has been allowed to continue...

A recent study of prisons in four Midwestern states found that approximately one in five male inmates reported a pressured or forced sex incident while incarcerated

Following an incident of rape, victims may experience vaginal or rectal bleeding, soreness and bruising (and much worse in the case of violent attacks), insomnia, nausea, shock, disbelief, withdrawal, anger, shame, guilt, and humiliation. Long term consequences may include post traumatic stress disorder, rape trauma syndrome, ongoing fear, nightmares, flashbacks, self-hatred, substance abuse, anxiety, depression, and suicide.

Rates of HIV are five to ten times as high inside of prison as outside, making forced sex - where prevention methods are virtually nonexistent - a deadly proposition. 

Ultimately, 95 percent of all inmates are eventually released.  Upon release, male prisoner rape survivors may bring with them emotional scars and learned violent behavior that continue the cycle of harm. 

Prisoner rape is a violation of international human rights law that meets the definition of torture

The U.S. Supreme Court has held that prisoner rape is a violation of the prohibition of cruel and unusual punishment in the Eighth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution

Prisoner rape also costs taxpayers dearly in the form of higher rates of recidivism and re-incarceration, increased violence, higher rates of substance abuse, lawsuits brought by victims, mental health services, and medical care, including treatment for HIV and other sexually transmitted infections. Yet these high costs have failed to inspire most facilities to implement even the most basic measures to address the problem

(Stop Prison Rape) (www.spr.org)

1. fight to support safety

2. human dignity

3. human rights for all</description>
  <mission>seeks to end sexual violence committed against men, women, and youth in all forms of detention.</mission>
  <name>Stop Prison Rape</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3715</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">240</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">60.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Vp/cE/UD/ue/li/Un/wJsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
