<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Lojban (its name is a contraction for "Logical Language" in Lojban) is the most professional and thought-provoking of the modern logical languages, with a fascinating methodology for deriving its root words from Arabic, Chinese, English, Hindi, Russian and Spanish, the six most popular languages spoken by most of the world. Its creation and history includes a desire for unambiguous grammar based on predicate logic and exploring the Sapir-Whorf hypothesis that states that one's language affects how one thinks. Also,Lojban has a whole array of emotional indicators, with optional intensity indicators as well, expressing about 80 significant emotions. These can also be subdivided as physical, social, emotional, intellectual, sexual, or spiritual varieties. If everyone spoke not only a native language but Lojban as well, we could all communicate with one another more easily and more effectively.

http://www.lojban.org/

1. Lojban is designed to be used by people in communication with each other, and possibly in the future with computers.

2. Lojban is designed to be culturally neutral.

3. Lojban grammar is based on the principles of logic.

4. Lojban has an unambiguous grammar.

5. Lojban has phonetic spelling, and unambiguous resolution of sounds into words.

6. Lojban is simple compared to natural languages; it is easy to learn.

7. Lojban's 1300 root words can be easily combined to form a vocabulary of millions of words.

8. Lojban is regular; the rules of the language are without exception.

9. Lojban attempts to remove restrictions on creative and clear thought and communication.

10. Lojban has a variety of uses, ranging from the creative to the scientific, from the theoretical to the practical.</description>
  <mission>Spread the use of the Lojban language</mission>
  <name>Spread Lojban</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3718</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">45</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5K/wH/8w/Kd/m5/oN/2aAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
