<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It is the supreme goal of this cause to promote and to preserve the Baptistic principles of old.  To ensure that the sacrifice of Baptist martyrs is not forgotten and that  the principles established during the personal ministry of Jesus Christ are carried on well into the future.


1. We believe that there is one God, the source, support, and end of all things, eternally existent in three persons: Father, Son and Holy Spirit.

2. We believe in the deity of our Lord Jesus Christ; in His Virgin Birth; in His sinless life; in His miracles; in His vicarious and atoning death; in His shed blood; in His bodily resurrection; in His ascension to the Father's right hand; and in His persona

3. We believe that man is totally depraved, a sinner (lost) by nature and by divine decree, therefore in need of the convicting and regenerating ministry of the Holy Spirit.

4. We believe in the personality of Satan; in his power and kingdom; in His wiles; and in his judgment at the cross and his eternal destruction in Hell.

5. We believe in the present ministry of the Holy Spirit; that He convicts the sinner; regenerates the one who believes; indwells, seals, instructs, reproves and guides the believer; that He fills and controls every life that is wholly yielded to Him. 

6. We believe that salvation is the gift of God offered to man by His grace and received by personal faith in the Lord Jesus Christ.

7. We believe in the bodily resurrection of the saved unto "life" and the unsaved unto "judgment" and everlasting damnation.

8. We believe in the special creation of the existing space-time universe and all its basic systems and kinds of organisms in the six literal days of the creation week and in the full historicity and perspicuity of the Biblical record of primeval history. Th

9. We believe the Bible to be the inspired, the only infallible, authoritative Word of God and that He has preserved it for the English-speaking world in the Authorized King James Version.

10. We believe that a scriptural church is a visible assembly of baptized believers covenanted together under New Testament law for the purpose of carrying out the Great Commission with an unbroken history from the personal ministry of Jesus on earth to this </description>
  <mission>further the Gospel of Jesus Christ</mission>
  <name>Independent Baptists</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3733</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">57</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ua/SD/AC/uW/uj/Bl/7jrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
