<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>These evangelical groups, often referred to generically as &#8220;Jews for Jesus&#8221; or &#8220;Messianic Jews&#8221;, present Christianity in the guise of Judaism to attract potential Jewish converts. In direct response to this growing problem, JEWS FOR JUDAISM offers an extensive variety of preventive educational programs, innovative educational materials and specialized counseling services that help to keep Jews Jewish and bring them &#8220;back home&#8221; to Judaism.

JEWS FOR JUDAISM&#8217;s goals are to strengthen Jewish pride and identity &amp; to win back Jews who have been influenced by missionaries &amp; cults. Over 300,000 Jews worldwide have participated in our highly acclaimed programs &amp; activities, that are free of charge. They include lectures, speakers bureau, crisis/exit &amp; family counseling, campus programs, Russian outreach, website, Shabbat hospitality, audiotapes, ad campaigns, TV &amp; radio programs, counter-leafleting, library &amp; archives &amp; more. JEWS FOR JUDAISM unites the Jewish community in a common cause and is endorsed by a wide spectrum of Jewish agencies, rabbis &amp; educators. We're supported almost entirely by contributions from people like you. Your support allows JEWS FOR JUDAISM to continue to reach out to Jews involved with missionaries &amp; cults, share with them the joy &amp; beauty of Judaism and offer them a chance to "come home". Your gift allows us to continue to provide the resources &amp; programming that help to keep Jews Jewish. THANK YOU!



1. Jews for Judaism offers exit and family crisis counseling, individual sessions with people who are affected by cults or missionary groups.

2. Before a Jew goes looking for spirituality in other religions, he or she needs to take time to explore that found in Judaism. We have over three millenia of learning out, expressing and experiencing God's presence in our world. 

3. offer a number of preventive education programs. One of the most successful programs, designed for reaching an entire community is Jews for Judaism's Community Prevention and Response(CPR) Program. </description>
  <mission>is an international outreach and counseling organization dedicated to countering the multi-million dollar efforts of numerous missionary and cult groups that deceptively target Jews for conversion. </mission>
  <name>Jews For Judaism</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3735</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">967</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">165.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sQ/QR/ix/aP/rF/sF/cUFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
