<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Through making small changes in your own life and home, you can live a greener and healthier life, benefiting your local community directly and the nation and world indirectly. 

Here are 23 small things I just thought of that you can do to help improve the world.

1. Dry laundry on a clothesline instead of in a dryer. 
2. Plant a small vegetable garden. 
3. Buy organic and local.
4. Plant a tree. 
5. Buy American (or buy products made in the country in which you live if you live outside of the US). 
6. Buy Fair Trade. 
7. Think about what you're buying before you buy it. 
8. Ride a bike. 
9. Watch that thermostat! 
10. Stay informed. 
11. Be aware. 
12. Tell others. 
13. Don't use chlorine bleach. 
14. Use more recycled products. 
15. Use treeless paper. 
16. Recycle what you use instead of throwing away. 
17. BYOB - Bring your own bags when shopping.
18. Start a compost heap.
19. Volunteer. Anywhere. Anytime. 
20. Teach children to love and respect the natural world.
21. Use corn-based plastic products whenever you can.
22. Use biodegradable detergents or soap in your kitchen, bathroom and laundry. 
23. Write to your elected officials. 

Heifer International, Inc. is our charity because they take the idea that small changes can make a big impact for the better in the lives of individuals, families and communities all over the world. By donating location appropriate livestock to poverty-stricken individuals, the organization makes it possible for people to become self-sustaining and eventually have a surplus which they put back into their community for the benefit of their neighbors. Please consider making a donation today. It is not necessary to go through this page. You may visit http://www.heifer.org/ and choose an animal or a share of an animal to be given to a needy family in your name. The important thing is that people receive the help they need to make a difference.

1. It is possible for an individual to change the world for the better.

2. That the best way to start toward a solution to the world's problems is by acting locally.

3. That anyone can make a difference and everyone makes an impact, whether for good or ill, so we should try to make it good.</description>
  <mission>bring about a better world for everyone and everything by making small changes which add up to big changes over time.</mission>
  <name>Bettering the World Through Positive Action in Your Local Community, Home and Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3748</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">43</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8M/RK/0G/0Y/FN/AN/Xv4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
