<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.trich.org

Founded in 1991, TLC provides education, outreach, and support of research into the cause and treatment of BFRB disorders.  In choosing how to allocate our limited resources, we seek projects that will have large ripple effects, both at the personal and public level, and that will enable larger scale work to be done.  We are committed to a culture of humanity, consensus, and personal connection, while achieving the growth necessary to achieve our mission. 

Founded by Christina Pearson in 1991, TLC is a grassroots organization largely run and supported by people with TTM. It is funded through memberships, publication sales, and donations. TLC has convened a Scientific Advisory Board composed of leading researchers and clinicians in trichotillomania in the United States and beyond, which meets regularly to share Information and propose research strategies. The quarterly newsletter In Touch, a membership benefit, is the organization&#8217;s main communication vehicle and covers a wide variety of topics, ranging from self-help options, to the experiences those with trichotillomania and skin picking, to the latest scientific research.

1. We envision a world where Body-focused Repetitive Behaviors (BFRBs) are diagnosed quickly. 

2. and BFRBs are not a source of shame. 

3. Knowledgeable treatment is available to all people with these disorders. 

4. Treatments are more effective and eventually cures are found. 

5. Information and emotional support are available to people of all ages and their families. </description>
  <mission>To end the suffering caused by hair pulling disorder, skin picking disorder, and related body-focused repetitive behaviors</mission>
  <name>Trichotillomania Learning Center</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3750</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2465</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2244.39</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3V/Bm/Vi/3u/EJ/B5/Zk/4IS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
