<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Day by day the world&#8217;s problems grow more desperate. Humanity as we know it, trotters on the brink of disaster and lives in unprecedented chaos. We face problems of global warming, violence in the streets or in our homes, deforestation, extreme poverty, world hunger and the exploitation of human rights by government, racism, rape and unethical corporations. Even while governments mention &#8216;brotherhood of man&#8217;, and &#8216;peace on earth&#8217;, the world is raged with war. Our horrid past such as the killing fields of Cambodia, and the holocausts of Germany, the mass rape in Rwanda and the troubles in Yugoslavia just to name a few, and now the fierce and brutal oppression in Iraq and Palestine are mere examples of the horrible savagery modern man is still capable of in today&#8217;s world. In the 1990s alone, 100 million children died from starvation, its even worse knowing that the price of 5 stealth bombers could have fed these children.  BY THE TIME YOU ARE DONE READING THIS at least 100 people would have died from starvation. Western nations burn millions of tons of food a year just so as to keep artificial prices high. These children around the globe are starving because of mans inhumanity to man, not because of natural causes. War, embargoes, government corruption, and economic oppression such as the insurmountable debt many developing nations owe to international creditors who entice them to take out huge loans, are now holding them in economic slavery. We all take for granted the problems existing in the world today unless it affects us directly. The only thing that guarantees happiness in everyone&#8217;s life is the love of man towards man and the world. If peace can exist on all corners of the globe and in every household or in every individual then we are on the way to bringing heaven on earth. Please share your opinions, create ideas and spread the love baby. All the world needs is your love nothing more and nothing less. 

1. Create world peace with the help of everyone

2. people need to change their current way of life

3. more love and care is needed in our world</description>
  <mission>spread the awareness and passionate desire for creating peace in every person and the entire planet, so the world can be free of all its miseries. </mission>
  <name>PEP ( Peace on Earth Project )</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3755</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">98</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/UW/Ye/r0/Yc/eU/IO/CtqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
