<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hi everyone.

Everyone knows someone who has been affected by heart disease or stroke.  I lost my best friend in 5th grade to a heart attack that was caused from a heart problem. She was amazing to say the least, and can never be replaced. Her parents came up with an idea to walk in the Heart Walk, to remember Sara and also raise money to help other children and people who are affected by heart disease.

Annually I&#8217;ll be helping the American Heart Association fight the Nation&#8217;s number 1 and number 3 causes of death, heart disease and stroke at the Heart Walk. Funds raised through the Heart Walk support research, community service and public and professional education programs.

My personal goal each year is to raise $1,000. Your support will help.  Your donation will help me take a stand against the #1 killer of Americans, including women. Not only will you help me achieve my goal, you&#8217;ll also help the American Heart Association make important advances against heart disease and stroke.

Through Brenner&#8217;s Children&#8217;s Hospital, where Sara was treated, her parents have set up what is called &#8220;A Walk For Sara&#8221;. Please help me by supporting this cause, and joining our team or donating.

I will be posting updates about the yearly heart walk here and on a website that will be going up in June 2008!

Thank you for your support! Together we will make a difference!

1. Raise as much as possible.

2. Cardiovascular disease is our nation&#8217;s number 1 killer.

3. Seventy percent of Americans don&#8217;t get enough exercise, blaming lack of time and lack of motivation.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to raise awareness of heart disease and stroke and creating opportunities for people to improve their health by walking and raising funds to help fight against heart disease and stroke.</mission>
  <name>American Heart Association (A Walk For Sara)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3772</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nJ/oH/fm/GB/tc/40/RczS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
