<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our mission is singular: to end the devastating effects of MS. We meet our mission by providing critical "quality of life" local services to thousands of Ohioans living with MS and supporting the largest investment in MS research in the world (second only to the National Institutes of Health). Since 1946, the National MS Society has been and remains the only voluntary health organization dedicated to the prevention, treatment, alleviation and cure of multiple sclerosis. The National MS Society is the only voluntary MS organization that meets the standards of all major agencies that rate nonprofit groups. There is only one National MS Society.
 
The National MS Society's Ohio Buckeye Chapter is just one important part of a nationwide network that advances the Society&#8217;s mission&#8212;to end the devastating effects of MS. Founded September 24, 1953, the National MS Society's Ohio Buckeye Chapter provides services and programs to thousands living with the devastating effects of MS and their families within the Chapter&#8217;s 36-county territory. The National MS Society's Ohio Buckeye Chapter funds research, furthers education, advocates for people with disabilities, and provides referrals to healthcare providers and other resources within the community. The National MS Society's Ohio Buckeye Chapter has two offices to serve your needs:

National Multiple Sclerosis Society
Northeast Ohio Office
6155 Rockside Rd, Suite 202
Independence, OH 44131
(800) 667-7131 
	

National Multiple Sclerosis Society
Central &amp; Southeastern Ohio Office
651G Lakeview Plaza Blvd.
Worthington, OH 43085
(800) 667-7131



1. Commitment. We are passionate in our commitment to people affected by MS.  We strive to improve quality of life while searching for the cure.

2. Leadership. We are leaders in the fight against MS. Through creativity and hard work, we accelerate the pace of scientific discovery, promote quality health care, stimulate community resources and services, advocate for favorable government policies and a

3. Integrity. We are honest and straightforward in all that we do. We treat everyone with dignity and respect. We act responsibly with resources  entrusted to us. We are accountable and act in accordance with these values.  

4. Excellence. We set high standards of performance and service delivery and work towards excellence in our mission to end the devastating effects of multiple sclerosis. 

5. Teamwork. We advance the interests of people affected by MS through individual and team achievements. We recognize our  volunteers as our most valued resources. We encourage collaboration across organizational boundaries.  </description>
  <mission>end the devasting effects of Multiple Sclerosis</mission>
  <name>National MS Society- Ohio Buckeye Chapter</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3779</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">681</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">26.3</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tr/dK/Sl/fi/3S/Tu/zqFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
