<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We believe that the best way to ensure global development is by investing in the children. Not only must we feed them, but they  must be educated, and grounded in tried and true spiritual values as well.

We support organizations whose goal it is to to achieve this. 

By helping this generation of children get the education and resources they need, we will help the long term futures of poverty-stricken lands throughout the world, by providing the basics through which both they and their communities need in order not only to survive, but flourish.

It is our belief that we must provide the means for these children to live and work in their own lands, and to become the future leaders who will pave the way for the generations that follow, that they they too might live in peace,freedom, security, not constantly under the threat of starvation and disease.

1. We believe that we are our brother's keeper, and that we have a responsibility give them a hand up in life by voluntary sharing of our wealth.

2. We believe that by educating children to equip them for life in a global society is best done against a backdrop of tried and true Judeo-Christian values and ethics, 

3. We believe that sending a cheque is not enough, and that we must develop personal relationships with the children we sponsor.

4. We believe that the goal should be to raise these children to become leaders in all fields in their lands, in order to bring about social justice and healing.</description>
  <mission>Help eliminate poverty, disease and war by providing opportunities and basic sustenance for children in developing lands.</mission>
  <name>Sponsor a Child</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3784</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/M0/rN/aO/tQ/1S/2K/6CvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
