<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Polls and declining voter turnout suggest that Americans are growing more frustrated with their government&#8217;s ability to address the areas of society that need the most attention. Perhaps worse is that they feel that they are powerless to bring about positive change, and lack the necessary resources to take back control of their own communities.

The Institute for Domestic and International Affairs, Inc. (IDIA) is a 501(c)3 not-for-profit corporation dedicated to providing innovative educational opportunities to students of all ages so they may better understand their role in global and domestic civil society.  In order for the voting age population to be active participants in government and community, it is important that younger populations have an in-depth and compelling understanding of their responsibilities both to their government and to their fellow citizens.

Founded in 1992, IDIA has grown from a small non-profit organization serving local regions to a multifaceted organization impacting people around the world. While our first programs attracted just over one hundred people, IDIA programming now attracts more than 2,000 students each year from across the United States and around the world.  Since its founding, IDIA has positively impacted more than 20,000 participating students, developing educated voters, active community leaders, and future scholars.

IDIA provides the most rewarding educational experiences possible by moving students from benign classroom settings to more conducive learning environments.  Our issues for debate are timely and well-researched, and our conferences focus on important areas of global and domestic concern, ranging from such concepts as representative democracy to minority voice; from the interrelation of international interests to the implications of partisan politics in the United States.



1. One person, if equipped with the right tools, can make bring about positive social change

2. Knowing about the world is the only way to become a citizen of the world

3. Education is universal</description>
  <mission>Teach the next generation of leaders</mission>
  <name>IDIA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3786</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">133</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hb/HY/jo/BN/f0/k4/TCzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
