<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Vision: HOPE worldwide has a vision to bring hope and change lives.

Mission: HOPE worldwide is an international charity that changes lives by harnessing the compassion and commitment of dedicated staff and volunteers to deliver sustainable, high-impact, community-based services to the poor and needy.

History: The International Churches of Christ founded HOPE worldwide in response to the Scriptures that call us to have the heart of Jesus by serving the poor and needy throughout the world.  God has truly blessed our efforts and today the organization operates on every inhabited continent and reaches more than 1,000,000 people each year.

Reputation: HOPE worldwide is audited annually by an outside accounting firm (currently PricewaterhouseCoopers) and files Form 990 information returns with the IRS.  Charity Navigator, who evaluates U.S. charities on the basis of their financial soundness and efficiency, has given HOPE worldwide its highest rating of Four Stars.  In addition, the organization has status with the United Nations as an advisor to its Economic &amp; Social Council.  HOPE worldwide is also an approved charity with USAID.

Service: HOPE worldwide's Global Partners, as well as a number of other organizations and individuals, have contributed greatly to the success of the organization.  Through the teamwork of these partners HOPE worldwide continues to be recognized for implementing Best Practices in 17 countries.  These programs have been cited for their high-quality of care that produces consistent, positive and sustainable outcomes.


1. Helping poor and needy through disaster relief, health reform and serivce, education,  and vocational training.

2. Establishing long-term, community-based programs to provide continuing assistance to disadvantaged areas.

3. Creating volunteer opportunities to serve needs</description>
  <mission>HOPE worldwide is an international charity that changes lives by harnessing the compassion and commitment of dedicated individuals.</mission>
  <name>HOPE worldwide</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3788</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">16425</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">4051.29</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/66/zs/z0/VV/nG/0p/a7/NgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
