<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The PeaceCamp Initiative (http://www.peacecampinitiative.org) seeks to bring deserving Israeli and Palestinian kids, chosen in part for their leadership potential, to one of America's oldest summer camps (Camp Susquehannock, about 3 hours west of NYC in the Endless Mountains of NE Pennsylvania), where they would (perhaps for the first time) get a chance to be regular kids - on a soccer field, on a tennis court, at the table, in the cabin, etc. - and learn to respect each other as teammates, cabin mates, and friends. Returning home, these kids would then spread, like ripples from a pebble cast into a pond, the possibility of respect and tolerance amongst their peers. We started small - brought three kids in 2008, and then six kids (three boys, three girls) in 2009. We hope to bring a dozen kids in 2010. Eventually we might take on 20 kids (10 Israeli and 10 Palestinian) at a time.

Why Kids? 
because the old men are too bitter, the conflict too deep in their bones, and they've given up hope of ever trusting anyone on the other side of the Israeli/Palestinian divide.

Why Camp? 
 If you grew up going to summer camp, you already know the answer - because the friendships you make there are forever, because trust is forged on the playing field and in the cabin in ways you can never recreate in a conference room, and because there is laughter and joy at camp - and only with laughter and joy can there ever be hope.

In addition - camp takes kids out of their homes, to a place of new possibility, and surrounds them with counselors - adults who don't expect them to be one way or another (as parents sometimes tend to do), but fundamentally support them becoming who they really are.


1. Peace in the Middle East starts with Peace between Israel and Palestine

2. Leaders on both sides are too bitter, too entrenched, and too cynical

3. Creating leaders amongst today's youth is the only way to have peace tomorrow

4. Summer Camp is the best environment to forge trust and make friends</description>
  <mission>Create tomorrow's generation of Israeli and Palestinian peacemakers - by forging friendships and trust between Israeli and Palestinian kids today.</mission>
  <name>PeaceCamp Initiative - Forging Leaders for Tomorrow</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/379</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">141</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1295.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nGp/CTCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
