<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>So, you ask, what exactly is a feral cat??? 
Feral cats are the 'wild' offspring of domestic cats and are primarily the result of pet owners' abandonment or failure to spay and neuter their animals, allowing them to breed uncontrolled. Feral cat 'colonies' can be found behind shopping areas or businesses, in alleys, parks, abandoned buildings, and rural areas. They are elusive and do not trust humans. 
Many people assume their animals will survive when they move away and leave them behind. Contrary to popular belief, domestic animals do not automatically return to their "natural" instincts and cannot fend for themselves! Many "throwaways" die mercilessly outdoors from starvation, disease, abuse or as food to a predator. 
A pair of breeding cats, which can have two or more litters per year, can exponentially produce 420,000 offspring over a seven-year period, And the overpopulation problem carries a hefty price tag.

What can we do?....
Support the Hamilton\Burlington Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals. The SPCA is not a government organization, it is a registered charity not-for-profit organization devoted to the prevention of cruelty to animals. 
Animal Protection Services investigates public complaints of animals abuse, cruelty and any concerns regarding the care of any animal within the City of Hamilton and the City of Burlington. 
The Society relies strongly on public and corporate donations, legacies, and fundraising campaigns to fund its operations.
The generosity of the community we serve helps us support the animals in our care and allows us to give something back to our community by offering a wide range of programs and services.

&#61558;	Animal Adoption Humane Education
&#61558;	Animal Protection Services 
&#61558;	Pet Visitation / Pet Therapy
&#61558;	First Strike Animal Cruelty Program
And many more&#8230;..

Hamilton/Burlington SPCA http://www.hamiltonspca.com/index.php


1. To raise awareness in our community about the feral cat population

2. wonderful opprotunity to help those "who cannot help themselves!"

3. Help us make our planet a compassionate and caring world for the vulnerable</description>
  <mission>I have to pick a US charity for my charity but my goal charity is the Hamilton/Burlington SPCA http://www.hamiltonspca.com/index.php</mission>
  <name>Save the feral cat's of Hamilton!!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3792</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">19</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Al/aN/MP/xs/U3/D7/6cMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
