<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Ovarian Cancer National Alliance champions a three-pronged programmatic approach through awareness, education and
advocacy.
The Ovarian Cancer National Alliance is the national public policy arm of the ovarian cancer movement and works with members of Congress and the medical and scientific communities to improve outcomes for women with ovarian cancer and their families. The organization helps increase funding for critical ovarian cancer research and educates women and their physicians about the symptoms and guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of the disease.  In addition to its advocacy work, the Ovarian Cancer National Alliance educates survivors, family members and caregivers to be proactive on behalf of their loved ones and take appropriate action to get the care they need. 
Until an early detection test is developed, the best way to save lives is to educate women and their health care providers about the warning signs of ovarian cancer. We work nationally to communicate our message through local and national campaigns, events and programs. The Ovarian Cancer National Alliance&#8217;s Survivors Teaching StudentsSM Program helps tomorrow's clinicians understand how to identify the symptoms and risk factors associated with ovarian cancer. More than half of the accredited medical schools in the United States now offer this program to their third year students. Over 20,000 medical professionals have participated in this program since its inception and it is being expanded to include nursing schools and nurse practitioners. In cooperation with our scientific and medical advisory committee, practice guidance was produced to educate women and their physicians on next steps to consider when symptoms appear.  

1. Advocacy. Education. Awareness. </description>
  <mission>To advance the interests of women with ovarian cancer. </mission>
  <name>Ovarian Cancer National Alliance</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3795</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10499</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2590.4</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Af/lu/N8/O8/lC/rr/g1/E4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
