<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Arm &amp; Hammer 

Bic Corporation 

Boyle-Midway 

Braun 

Chesebrough-Ponds 

Church &amp; Dwight (Aim, Arm &amp; Hammer, Arrid, Brillo, Close-up, Lady&#8217;s Choice, Mentadent, Nair, Orange Glo International, Pearl Drops) 

Clairol 

Clorox 

Colgate-Palmolive Co. (Hills Pet Nutrition, Mennen, Palmolive, SoftSoap, Speed Stick)

Coty (Adidas, Calvin Klein, Davidoff, Glow, The Healing Garden, JOOP!, Jovan, Kenneth Cole, Lancaster, Marc Jacob, Rimmel, Stetson)

Cover Girl (Procter &amp; Gamble) 

Del Laboratories (CornSilk, LaCross, Naturistics, New York Color, Sally Hansen)

Dial Corporation (Dry Idea, Purex, Renuzit, Right Guard, Soft &amp; Dri) 

Gillette Co. (Braun, Duracell, Procter &amp; Gamble)

Helene Curtis Industries (Salon Selectives, Thermasilk, Unilever) 

Johnson &amp; Johnson 

Lever Bros. 

L&#8217;Or&#953;al U.S.A. (Biotherm, Cacharel, Garnier, Giorgio Armani, Helena Rubinstein, Lanc&#964;me, Matrix Essentials, Maybelline, Ralph Lauren Fragrances, Redken, Soft Sheen, Vichy) 

Max Factor (Procter &amp; Gamble)

Mead

Melaleuca

Mennen Co. (Colgate-Palmolive)

Neoteric Cosmetics

New Dana Perfumes

Noxell (Procter &amp; Gamble)

Olay Co./Oil of Olay 

Oral-B (Gillette Company) 

Pantene (Procter &amp; Gamble) 

Pfizer (BenGay, Desitin, Listerine, Lubriderm, Plax, Visine) 

Physique (Procter &amp; Gamble)

Playtex Products (Banana Boat)

Procter &amp; Gamble Co. (Clairol, Cover Girl, Crest, Gillette, Giorgio, Iams, Max Factor, Physique, Tide) 

Reckitt Benckiser (Easy Off, Lysol, Mop &amp; Glo, Old English, Resolve, Spray &#8217;N Wash, Veet, Woolite) 

Richardson-Vicks (Procter &amp; Gamble) 

Sally Hansen 

Schering-Plough (Bain de Soleil, Coppertone, Dr. Scholl&#8217;s)

S.C. Johnson (Drano, Edge, Fantastik, Glade, OFF!, Oust, Pledge, Scrubbing Bubbles, Shout, Skintimate, Windex, Ziploc) 

SoftSoap Enterprises

Suave (Unilever) 

Unilever (Axe, Dove, Helene Curtis, Lever Bros., Suave)

1. we have to cut down or stop using the products from companies that test on animals 

2. We must make people aware of companies that test on animals .</description>
  <mission>To make people aware of companies that test on animals</mission>
  <name>Animals testing</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3806</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">198</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ff/OC/YN/57/51/aD/M6DS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
