<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>   &lt;b&gt;IMPORTANT!!!&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;b&gt;We are NOT a crisis center!&lt;/b&gt; If you or a friend is in immediate danger, please call the Suicide Prevention Lifeline at &lt;b&gt;1-800-273-TALK(8255)&lt;/b&gt; to speak with a trained professional. Do not call or send us a message.
     

DID YOU KNOW THAT&#8230;

&#8226;There were 32,439 suicides in the United States? This is an annual rate of 11.1 deaths per 100,000 individuals.
&#8226;There are twice as many deaths by suicide as by HIV/AIDS in the U.S?
&#8226;For every 2 homicides in the U.S., there are 3 suicides?
&#8226;Worldwide, 1 million lives are lost to suicide each year?
&#8226;Suicide is preventable?

WARNING SIGNS OF SUICIDAL BEHAVIOR:

&#8226;Threatening to hurt or kill him/herself, or talking of wanting to hurt or kill him/herself
and/or
&#8226; Looking for ways to kill him/herself by seeking access to firearms, available pills, or other means
and/or
&#8226;Talking or writing about death, dying or suicide, when these actions are out of the ordinary.

These might be remembered as expressed or commmunicated IDEATION.

ADDITIONAL WARNING SIGNS 

Increased SUBSTANCE (alcohol or drug) use.
No reason for living; no sense of PURPOSE in life.
ANXIETY, agitation, unable to sleep, or sleeping all 
the time.
Feeling TRAPPED - like there's no way out.
HOPELESSNESS
WITHDRAWAL from friends, family and society
Rage, uncontrolled ANGER, seeking revenge.
Acting RECKLESS or engaging in risky activities, 
seemingly without thinking.
Dramatic MOOD changes.

HELP

If you or someone you know exhibits any of these warning signs, seek help as soon as possible by contacting a mental health professional or by calling the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline at:
1-800-273-TALK (8255)


&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.msplinks.com/MDFodHRwOi8vcGhvdG9idWNrZXQuY29t" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i193.photobucket.com/albums/z99/aastara/suicide_prev.jpg" border="0" alt="Photo Sharing and Video Hosting at Photobucket"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

 

1. Dedicated to understanding and preventing suicide as a means of bettering human lives.

2. For more information, check out www.suicidology.org

3. Want to get involved?? Check out the "A Million Voices Campaign" on Facebook Causes or at our website!</description>
  <mission>The American Association of Suicidology: 40 years dedicated to understanding and preventing suicide as a means of bettering human lives.

</mission>
  <name>Suicide is Preventable</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3810</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">248</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eg/sS/Rg/64/03/4L/kxaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
