<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Operation Snowball is an alcohol, tobacco and other drug use prevention program focusing on leadership development to empower youth to lead healthy drug-free lives. The program provides opportunities for youth and adults to work together in a spirit of cooperation to plan, implement and evaluate a community-based prevention program.

Operation Snowball acts as a prevention (not therapy) program for youth (and the not-so-youth!) to offer a variety of resources on healthy lifestyles, leadership and communication skills, and an opportunity to meet other people in their communities who share the ideals of a drug-free life. Snowballs, as they are commonly referred to, usually happen over an entire weekend in the form of a lock-in. Snowballs also can happen in one day and in other styles. 

Typically there are speakers and presentations for people to listen to and interact with as well as discussion groups to process the information. And of course there are plenty of fun activities in which everyone can get involved. Snowballs are not just an overnight event, meetings and drug free fun are continued throughout the year. 

Snowball chapters act as change agents in their communities. They work on community campaigns such as Red Ribbon Week, Drunk and Drugged Drinking Month, Alcohol Awareness Month and others. Chapters go beyond &#8220;just say no&#8221; to embrace a more complete and effective strategy to prevent harmful behavior and promote healthy communities. When individuals decide to say yes or no to drugs, they are influenced by their environment, including things like social norms, media messages, accessibility, and laws, rules, and policies. When young people become involved in efforts such as these, they not only help their communities; they help themselves grow into competent, confident, responsible, connected, productive members of society. 

Since its birth over three decades ago, Snowball has partnered itself with the Illinois Alcoholism and Drug Dependence Association (IADDA) and has formed its own board of directors. Snowball has branched out to many chapters in Illinois, California, Indiana, New York, North Carolina, Wisconsin, Lithuania, and Poland.

Snowballs are aimed at high school students. Operation Snowball has continued to spread its message by creating Snowflakes for junior high students, Segues for college students, Snowflurries for elementary students, Blizzards for families and Snocap for Senior Citizens. All ages can benefit from the idea of prevention. 

Learn more about Operation Snowball by visiting www.os-iti.org.



1. HUGS NOT DRUGS!!!</description>
  <mission>To provide awareness and prevention of alcohol, tobacco, and other drug use, while encouraging healthy decision-making in an active community of caring.</mission>
  <name>Operation Snowball</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3827</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1183</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">126.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Gc/4b/ZM/U6/RT/8C/VA4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
