<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> Carbon dioxide during the last 400,000 years and (inset above) the rapid rise since the Industrial Revolution; changes in the Earth's orbit around the Sun, known as Milankovitch cycles, are believed to be the pacemaker of the 100,000 year ice age cycle. Attribution of recent climate change and scientific opinion on climate change
The climate system varies through natural, internal processes and in response to variations in external forcing factors including solar activity, volcanic emissions, variations in the earth's orbit (orbital forcing) and greenhouse gases. The detailed causes of the recent warming remain an active field of research, but the scientific consensus  identifies increased levels of greenhouse gases due to human activity as the main influence. This attribution is clearest for the most recent 50 years, for which the most detailed data are available. Contrasting with the scientific consensus, other hypotheses have been proposed to explain most of the observed increase in global temperatures. One such hypothesis is that the warming is caused by natural fluctuations in the climate or that warming is mainly a result of variations in solar radiation. 

None of the effects of forcing are instantaneous. Due to the thermal inertia of the Earth's oceans and slow responses of other indirect effects, the Earth's current climate is not in equilibrium with the forcing imposed. Climate commitment studies indicate that even if greenhouse gases were stabilized at present day levels, a further warming of about 0.5 &#176;C (0.9 &#176;F) would still occur. 




1. Greatly Reduce The Effects Of Global Warming.

2. Filter Our CO2 Emmisons.

3. Create An Alternitive Fuel Source.</description>
  <mission>Stop global warming and create a secure future for generations to come.</mission>
  <name>Turn Down The Heat.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3829</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yg/ND/H2/Fc/WO/ip/7BfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
