<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is a group intended to educate anyone who is interested to know the truth about Islam and how can there be so many peaceful, productive, compassionate and moralized Muslim people and yet the image about Islam is that it&#8217;s a terrorist religion because of a few extremists.
How could the Prophet Mohamed (PBUH) to be considered the most influential single figure in human history! When he supposedly came with a message of terrorism?? It does not add up.
How can Muslim people reach the count of over 1.3 billion so far? Could it be that all of these people are attracted to terrorism? I am sure not. I am also sure that all of us can find someone in our neighbourhood who joined Islam and we can assess if they are of a terrorist mind or not.

So from this group and for this cause I would like to peacefully share information that can be validated 100% for people to know about the Islam faith. Away from what the media feeds the minds of the west.
This group will not be involved in any aspects of the politics behind the Islamic hijacking; it will simply explain what needs to be explained. Its sole purpose is to educate best knowledge about Islam and not try to convince anyone to join Islam.

Finally, for all non-Muslims who join this cause and would like any question to be answered about Islam please just message me with you question and i will do all i can to come back to you with the best answers from the heart of the Quran and the prophet&#8217;s teachings with proves and facts.

1. STOP Islam Hijacking

2. Clarify to the world what the faith Islam is all about, from the Quran and the Prophet's teachings</description>
  <mission>Clarify to the world what the faith Islam is all about, from the Quran and the Prophet's teachings</mission>
  <name>STOP Islam Hijacking</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/383</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1867</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/IMk/fbSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
