<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Behcet's disease is now recognized as a chronic condition that causes canker sores or 
ulcers in the mouth and on the genitals, arthritis(swollen, painful, stiff joints), skin 
problems and inflammation of the digestive tract, brain and spinal cord.

The exact cause of Behcet's disease is unknown.  Most symptoms of the disease are 
caused by inflammation of the blood vessels.  Inflammations is a characteristic reaction 
of the body to injury or disease and is marked by four signs;
  swelling
 
  redness
 
  heat
 
  pain
Doctors think that an autoimmune reaction may cause the blood vessels to become inflamed, but they do not know what triggers this reaction.  Under normal conditions, the 
immune system protects the body from diseases and infections by killing harmful 
"foreign" substances, such as germs, that enter the body.  In an autoimmune reaction, 
the immune system mistakenly attacks and harms the body's own tissues.

Behcet's is NOT contagious; it is not spread from on person to another.  Researchers 
think that two factors are important for a person to get Behcet's disease.  First, it is 
believed that abnormalities of the immune system make some people susceptible to the 
disease.  Scientists think that this susceptibility may be inherited; that is, it may be due 
to one or more specific genes.  Second, something in the environment, possibly a 
bacterium or virus, might trigger or activate the disease in susceptible people.

When a doctor suspect that a person has Behcet's disease, they may perform a 
pathergy test, in which they prick the skin with a small needle; 1 to 2 days after the test 
people with behcet's disease may develop a red bump where the doctor pricked the 
skin.  


 


1. Awareness Is The Key To Finding A Cure

2. http://www.geocities.com/behcetsdiseasecanada/homepage.html</description>
  <mission>To Raise Awareness</mission>
  <name>Behcet's Disease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3841</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">501</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">220.19</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4s/WK/KW/aS/nd/yq/hT/xxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
