<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The United States Senate Youth Alumni Association has formed in tribute to its "Mom," the beloved Mrs. George R. Hearst, Sr.

For almost thirty years until she passed away in 1999, Mrs. Hearst adopted as a surrogate mother 3,848 high school seniors who were delegates to the United States Senate Youth Program, sponsored by the William Randolph Hearst Foundation. Every year for the Week in Washington, Mrs. Hearst became the delegates' Mom. 

Like mothers everywhere, Mrs. Hearst did not lose touch with her brood when it left Washington. She made sure that every student knew how to reach her. Every single year she wrote to every former delegate she could keep track of. She and her devoted assistant Gladys Hundley, working for years with index cards, not computers, kept up with all of changes, moves, degrees, promotions, and even disappointments in the young lives of the former delegates. From time to time, she supported former delegates financially when there was a particularly acute educational need. Year after year, she remained a mother to them all.

As Mrs. Hearst's health began to fail, she asked several former delegates, some of whom were no longer young themselves, to think about continuing her work with former delegates. The United States Senate Youth Alumni Association ("USSYAA") grew from this request. Fortunately, the Association began to organize before Mrs. Hearst's passing, so that she could see that her wish for the future would be accomplished.

The USSYAA is now a reality. In 1999, Mrs. Hearst's last year at the Week in Washington, the Association paid tribute to her on her birthday at its first annual dinner. In the year that followed, the Association's Mission Statement was adopted, and its bylaws were completed.

1. Building and maintaining avenues of communication among program alumni 

2. Providing financial assistance for professional educational needs of program alumni

3. Supporting the William Randolph Hearst Foundation's United States Senate Youth Program when called upon to do so by program officials.</description>
  <mission>To continue the legacy of Mrs. George R.  "Mom" Hearst, Sr., through serving USSYP alumna.</mission>
  <name>United States Senate Youth Alumni Association</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3847</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">27</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Dw/5K/xh/Vo/Bi/15/FIUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
