<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The short of it:&lt;br&gt;
Mentally disabled American citizen Pedro Guzman was deported by the department of Homeland security after being arrested for trespassing (a misdemeanor).  Obviously this was a mistake (he is an American citizen!)  His family believes he is in Tijuana but cannot be sure, they have been searching for him for the last month and have filed suit against the dept of Homeland security and the L.A. County Sherriff's department.  Pedro lacks the cognitive ability to find his way back to the United States or to provide for himself.  Despite the fact that it is the government's fault, they refuse to help in locating him, aside from giving out a few fliers to the border officials in the hopes that Pedro stumbles into their offices (unlikely... he's mentally retarded!)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Full News Story:&lt;br&gt;
http://ktla.trb.com/news/ktla-deportedguy,0,5123083.story?coll=ktla-news-2
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Contact:&lt;br&gt;
President George Bush&lt;br&gt;
Gov. Arnold Scwarzenegger&lt;br&gt;
Senator Barbara Boxer&lt;br&gt;
Senator Dianne Feinstein&lt;br&gt;
U.S. Department of Homeland Security&lt;br&gt;
etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

General Note:&lt;br&gt;
ACLU of Southern California was chosen to receive funds because they are the largest organization helping the family.  The Salvation Army has also provided assistance if you want to donate to them as well (if you choose to donate to the Salvation Army, be sure to specify you want the money to help Pedro's family).

1. American citizens should not be deported

2. Families of individuals who are to be deported should be contacted first (especially if that person is incapable of speaking for himself!)

3. The Government has a responsibility in this issue because (1) he is an American citizen lost and in danger in a foreign country (2) it is their fault in the first place.

4. Government needs to provide some financial assistance to the family as they search for him without paychecks

5. Government needs to work in good faith with the Mexican Govt. in locating Pedro.</description>
  <mission>Find American citizen Pedro Guzman who was mistakenly deported</mission>
  <name>Bring Pedro Home!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3848</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/JS/rQ/EL/Cw/st/M4/pKlS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
