<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>   As most of you know or don't know, there is a crisis going on in Darfur, and many people are being killed daily. Sudan, where Darfur is located, has business ties with China, and for this reason, China has been non existent in helping the situation in Darfur. The reason why China is at fault here is becasue the UN has the ability to create a world wide effort to help stop the genocide in Darfur, but China has threatened to use their Veto power to stop any movement to help.
  The Olympics are being held in China next summer and this means lots of money for the country. We need to stop this cash flow so China will be forced to help out with the sitaution in Darfur. 
  So I propose a boycott on the sponsers that are helping fund the Olympics in China next summer. I know changing our lifestyle's may be ruff, but ask yourself, are some these materials worth someones life? 

List of Major Sponsers: 

Coca-Cola         
Mcdonalds         
Kodak
Omega
Samsung
Panasonic
Lenovo
Johnson and Johnson
GE
Visa

Heres a Link to all the sponsers of Olympics: 
http://en.beijing2008.cn/bocog/sponsors/sponsors/

If you don't know a lot about what's going on in Darfur please educate yourself, and make a difference. 

Here are some links pertaining to what is going on in Darfur:

http://www.darfurgenocide.org/

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darfur_conflict

http://www.savedarfur.org/content

http://www.rsf.org/rubrique.php3?id_rubrique=174

The Darfur people are being killed by mass amounts and we as people need to make a differnece. Write a letter to these major companies and explain to them why you are not going to purchase their merchandice. Help Spread the word and help this cause. Don't Talk About It Be About It!



1. Help out the situation in Darfur

2. Stop cash flow to China

3. Never Again should we let another Holocaust happen!</description>
  <mission>Stop Money Flow to China</mission>
  <name>The Olympic Sponser Boycott</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3855</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">16</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ls/yM/dN/in/o1/M7/CWAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
