<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Since the program began in 1998:

    * Approximately 800 children and youth participate in the eight-week summer program. Of those, more than 90 percent qualify for either free or reduced-price meals in public schools.
    * Up to 200 children receive homework assistance, health and nutrition education, a hot meal and extracurricular activities in the after-school program each year.
    * 345 young adults have served as interns in the summer and after-school programs; 37 percent have come from outside Texas, representing 24 states and eight foreign countries.
    * 21 former interns have enrolled in seminary, eight currently serve as staff in United Methodist Churches.
    * Over 75 percent of the interns either work or volunteer in some form of ministry.
    * Over 138 United Methodist churches from the North Texas Conference, as well as churches from out of state, have offered in-kind, financial and/or volunteer support
    * More than 1,200 people volunteer their time during the summer &#8211; doing such activities as reading with children, providing special activities, and preparing and serving dinner to the interns. Over 3,000 hours are spent each year reading one-on-one with children

http://www.projecttransformation.org

1. Provides community-oriented, safe and caring summer and after-school programs for children and youth

2. Offers leadership training, career exposure, and ministry exploration opportunities for young adults through summer and year-round services internships.</description>
  <mission>To connect the energy of young adults, the strength of church-supported institutions, and the untapped resources of underserved neighborhoods to meet the evolving needs of children and youth.</mission>
  <name>Project Transformation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3858</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">333</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">152.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zY/6n/CR/jg/D8/yv/u2BS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
