<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>China Labor Watch plays an important role in the promotion of labor rights in China . Through press releases, frequent updates of labor news on its website, in-depth labor reports, and communications with the media and other labor and human rights organizations, CLW presents the international community with an accurate picture of the labor situation in China. It has produced over a hundred press releases and more than twenty in-depth reports on a wide range of topics, including conditions in shoe, electronics and garment factories; the dangers of the mining industry; child labor and work injuries; lay-offs and unemployment; the effects of SARS on China 's workers; and issues facing women employees. 

By maintaining close relationships with many of the companies that source from Chinese factories, CLW encourages the development of a business framework in China that brings workers' rights to the fore of international discourse. It also helps advance the emergence of a strong legal structure in China by promoting the enforcement of local and national labor law, encouraging labor organizations to strengthen their leadership skills, and highlighting the efforts of labor activists to protect their own rights through the legal system. This combination of contacts on the ground and respectful dialogue with both businesses and government officials has gained CLW a great deal of credibility. 

1. Social and economic justice is essential to universal, lasting peace

2. Freedom of expression and association are essential to sustainable progress

3. Poverty anywhere constitutes a threat to prosperity everywhere

4. All workers have a right to be represented by the organization of their choosing

5. Workers are entitled to dignity, respect and a living wage

6. Child labor is a violation of human rights and should not be tolerated

7. Female workers are entitled to the equal oporitunities as male workers</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to protect the human rights and labor rights of workers in China </mission>
  <name>China Labor Watch</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3867</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">155</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bg/23/JW/6B/kI/2p/XC/BiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
