<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Wetlands are essential habitat for many types of ducks, geese, swans, herons, shorebirds, frogs, turtles, snakes, mink, otter, beaver, muskrat and other animals. Wetlands also provide spawning and feeding areas for fish, and homes for rare plants and insects. Wetlands are the base of several major food webs. Wetlands include wet meadows and open marshes, as well as forested swamplands.

The coast is used for anything from food production and storm protection.

More than 40 percent of the natural gas that&#8217;s used in the United States comes through Louisiana through a pipeline somewhere across the Louisiana coast. 

Louisiana contains 40% of the nation's wetlands and experiences 80% of the nations wetland erosion.

Louisiana is losing 25 to 35 square miles of wetlands per year.

Louisiana loses the coastal equivalent to a football field every half an hour. 

At some point in their life cycle, most aquatic animals depend on estuaries (marshes where the marine water and freshwater are mixed).

As the wetlands disappear, fish and wild birds lose a critical part of their habitat. Most of these species are either endangered or threatened.

Also, as one of our members pointed out, this is not simply an economic issue. Many people that live near the coast could easily lose their homes to the sea if the erosion continues at this alarming rate.

So, what can you do to help save the wetlands?? 
-Plant coastal grasses.
-Donate to wetland protection groups.
-Vote for candidates that will help protect the wetland.
-Pollute less. Recycle more.
-Use less water.


1. More and more wetlands are lost each day.

2. The wetlands need to be protected.

3. People should help save the coastal wetlands because they affect everyone.</description>
  <mission>provide the knowledge that it takes to save Louisiana's wetlands, marshes, and coastal areas.</mission>
  <name>Save Louisiana's Coast</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3873</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10119</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">535.3</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5c/sR/Jt/nW/Pd/r8/TY0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
