<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Ever since Fidel Castro took power in 1959, a great deal of American people have been praising him as a revolutionary hero to the Cuban people. Hollywood in particular has fawned over him and the socialist Cuban government. Chevy Chase once claimed that "socialism works" and "Cuba might prove that." Now, filmmaker Michael Moore is comparing the American health care system unfavorably to Cuba's in his new film "Sicko." However, the truth about Cuba, from its health care system to its human rights, is hardly what it is made out to be. Cuban hospitals are falling apart. Medicine is often so scarce that doctors are forced to perform amputations. Nearly all children are forced to become part of a government-controlled organization subject to Castro's will in order to receive education. For the sake of tourism, Cuban citizens are forced to go to third-rate beaches, hotels, and supermarkets. Dissidents are brutally beaten by mobs organized by Castro's regime. Despite numerous claims of torture, arbitrary imprisonment, unfair trials, and extra-judicial executions, the Cuban government has denied human rights groups access into the country. Many claim that Cuba's poor conditions are due to the U.S. embargo on the country, when in fact there are numerous companies in Cuba that Castro simply will not allow actual Cuban citizens to purchase from. By only making the finer resorts, hotels, beaches, and stores available to foreigners, Fidel Castro and the Cuban government have painted a veneer over their country in an attempt to mislead other nations. The aim of this cause is to open the eyes of the United States and the world to the persecution wrought by Fidel Castro and his socialist regime. 

Resourceful websites:

www.therealcuba.com
www.fiu.edu/~fcf/
www.cubacenter.org
http://frontpagemagazine.com/Articles/ReadArticle.asp?ID=7370


1. Cuba's cruel despotism must be widely exposed.</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness of the oppression being suffered by the Cuban people.</mission>
  <name>Exposing the Real Cuba</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3884</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">894</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cd/0H/4C/At/ZY/uF/M1yS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
