<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>At help2read we believe that education is the cornerstone of every nation, and reading is the cornerstone of every education. 

We help children love books! 

How?

By taking reading out of the classroom, combining it with games, and giving children choice. 

By giving children the individual care and attention we all need to flourish, and often take for granted&#8230;not everyone has time for bedtime stories, not everyone can read. 

Trained help2read volunteers help the same child either once or twice a week twice, for one year or one term, while Intensive help2read volunteers help the same child every day for at least one week, so children get priceless one-on-one care and support. 

We give each volunteer a box full of every type of book, from African Tales to Fairy tales, sticker books to pop-up books, poetry, puzzles, jokes, and games, and children can choose to spend the half hour however they like. Children quickly find a book they love and learn to love reading!

We currently help disadvantaged children throughout the Cape Peninsula, and we are looking to expand well beyond this in the future.

The children we help:

We help children aged 5-12 who find reading difficult

Many South African children have parents who can&#8217;t read or write in their own language, let alone English, how can they read to their kids? Yet, without those stories and one-on-one attention children fall behind their peers, losing confidence and self esteem. With the loss of confidence comes the loss of pleasure: kids who don&#8217;t feel confident about their reading simply don&#8217;t like reading, or books. 

See more at www.help2read.org

1. Many South African learners face a major disadvantage due to coming from illiterate homes.

2. South Africa's schools are overburdened.

3. One on one attention is the best way to educate.</description>
  <mission>share the joy of books with as many children as possible, empowering them with vital literacy skills they can pass on to their peers and future generations. </mission>
  <name>Help2Read</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3893</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/QN/jV/BP/zX/cg/BT/zFkS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
