<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Over 500 Million people a year contract malaria
Every 30 seconds, an African child under 5 dies of malaria. This results in 3000 deaths a day, and over a million a year.
The most serious malaria is cerebral malaria, which causes a swelling of the brain, seizures, and coma, and eventually death
The easiest way to prevent the spread of malaria is through the use of mosquito nets drenched in pesticides, at the cost of a couple dollars.
DDT is the most effective pesticide in killing malaria carrying mosquitoes
Zambia is a case in point. In some provinces, the rate of malaria is 1353 children have malaria per every 1000 child, meaning that many have had it more than once.
The Bill and Melinda Gates foundation is essential in purchasing and distributing nets.
Kalene Mission Hospital, in northern Zambia, is the place to take sick children. During the rainy season, they arrive in droves, in different stages of the illness.
One company is solely dedicated to finding a vaccine against malaria: Sanaria
Urban malaria is prevalent in cities like Calcutta. The monsoons are ideal for the mosquito to lay eggs and multiply.
Malaria has been around for tens of thousands of years. 3 presidents have had it. At 4 popes died of it. 
Plasmodium Falciparum

1. Malaria is a worst epidemic than it was in the 1950's

2. It kills over a million people a year, 90% of them children under 5

3. The best alternative to a vaccine is nets, pesticides and drugs.</description>
  <mission>Eradicate Malaria through the development of a vaccine. But meanwhile, it is important to provide mosquito nets and drugs to prevent and treat.</mission>
  <name>Fight against Malaria: The world's worst epidemic</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3902</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Po/P7/fv/JM/rp/RJ/ThiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
