<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Being a current owner of a St. Bernard, and a past owner of 2 other St. Bernards, I fully understand the hardships that these people are going through trying to support and find homes for God's "gentle giants".


Their cause as copied from their site: "To act as a shepherd for Saint Bernard dogs and puppies that are without suitable caretakers and are in need of help; to shelter the homeless; to care for and find homes for the unwanted, abandoned, neglected and abused; to feed the hungry; to provide medical services to the sick, injured and lame; to assist in the rescue of those subjected to conditions hazardous to their well-being or to confinement in government or private shelter, who without intervention would be needlessly Euthanize; to provide for the humane disposition of those not sound in mind, body or temperament; to educate the public as to the characteristics of, and proper care for, the breed so as to promote compatible, loving, lasting home/family placements; to educate the public as to responsible pet ownership so as to prevent accidental litters and to prevent inhumane trafficking in puppies and dogs, and so as to promote the most humane manner of disposition of pets at journey's end; to encourage, promote and support research respecting the breed that explores or improves relations between the breed and owners or sheds light on the causes of abandonment, neglect or abuse, or promotes the public's understanding of the special characteristics and attributes of the breed or that is designed to improve the welfare of the breed in any manner. Though the Foundation is established to provide services primarily to the Saint Bernard, the foundation will not refuse services to any dog in need of immediate and caring attention."


Their website can be found at: http://www.saintrescue.org/ 
Donations, Information, Awards, etc. can be found at: http://www.saintrescue.org/news.htm

1. To help lost/abandoned St. Bernards to find homes

2. To make sure these St. Bernards get up-to-date medical treatment</description>
  <mission>To save, heal, and find a home for St. Bernards and St. Bernard mixes.</mission>
  <name>Saint Bernard Rescue Foundation, INC.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3906</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">89</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">55.52</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nF/gd/mH/Ia/N0/gV/gsUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
