<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>On March 1, 2007 Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe insisted, &#8220;There is no evidence to prove there was coercion, nothing to support it (the coercion of WWII military sex slaves).&#8221; LABAN! Fight for Comfort Women is an online revolution fighting for justice. We ask Prime Minister Abe to look at the evidence, to see the coercion, to apologize and give appropriate reparations. The women are waiting.

World War II Comfort Women are the 200,000 girls and women abducted by the Japanese Imperial Army during WWII forced to experience a life of systematic rape and enslavement. They are now mostly in their 80's and they are dying. They were taken from Korea, China, Indonesia, the Philippines and Taiwan. In the Philippines, historians say there were about 1000 girls abducted.

We are united to defend human rights and support the passage of House Resolution 121 that calls upon the government of Japan to apologize for its war crime enslaving over 200,000 girls and women during World War II as "comfort women." The victims were referred to as "comfort women," but they were mostly girls under eighteen, some as young as twelve. They were kept in military "comfort stations" and were subjected to inhuman and degrading forms of sexual violence.

Credit to Annabel Park

1. Dignity must be restored upon the comfort women.

2. Violence targeting girls and women during armed conflicts must be prevented.

3. Prime Minister Shinzo Abe must apologize to the comfort women, yet must be executed without anti-Japanese sentiment.</description>
  <mission>Fight and support comfort women and help pass H.R. 121</mission>
  <name>House Resolution 121</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3910</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">192</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/d2/7m/8X/kM/Lb/Th/r6RS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
