<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>     For the 3rd year in a row, U.S. Rep. Bart Stupak has introduced legislation to change the patent that governs the property at Whitefish Point that Congress gave to the Great Lakes Shipwreck Historical Society (GLSHS). HR 2121 would incorporate the Human Use / Natural Resource Management Plan for WP into the GLSHS's land patent. This is the plan brought about by the settlement of the Michigan Audubon Society (MAS) lawsuit several years back.
      HR 2121 is not "straightforward and non-controversial" as Stupak has stated, but is an inappropriate favor for a special interest with a long history of being "ethically challenged". Neither of the other property holders at WP (MAS and U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service) has endorsed HR 2121. At the last Joint Committee meeting between the 3 parties, GLSHS asked for support, but also announced that they were going to change their patent regardless of what the other parties thought. 
     Now, Michigan's delegation in the U.S. Congress, especially U.S. Senators Carl Levin and Debbie Stabenow need to hear from constituents who think that there is enough development at Whitefish Point already. Please contact our Senators, and tell them that you don't want to see more development at Whitefish Point. Even very short letters will help!
     Send an e-mail, fax a short letter, or make a phone call. If you have time to contact only one, Senator Levin is the one to contact.

Senator Carl Levin's U.P. office (aide Amy Berglund):
phone: (906) 789-0052
fax: (906) 789-0015
e-mail: go to www.levin.senate.gov and find the place to type in your message.

Senator Debbie Stabenow's U.P. office (aide Sheri Davie):
phone: (906) 228-8756
fax: (906) 228-9162
e-mail: go to www.stabenow.senate.gov and find the place to type in your message.

1. Publically oppose HR 2121

2. Actively voice opposition to appropriate representatives</description>
  <mission>Defeat U.S. Congress House Legislature HR 2121</mission>
  <name>Defeat HR 2121</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3916</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Bw/Vb/fY/BO/dr/wb/7G4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
