<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://ihugfoundation.org/

What is i.HUG?

The International HUG Foundation (i.HUG) is a 501c3 grassroots organization focused on helping disadvantaged children in a slum area in Kabalagala Uganda. Poverty, the AIDS epidemic and other diseases have struck Kabalagala especially hard, creating a large orphan population, which the community is struggling to provide for. No government-run or public schools exist in this area, so many of these children don&#8217;t go to school. Instead, some are put to work at a very young age, while others live on the fringe, with no one to look after them and no place to go each day. i.HUG aims to help the poorest and most vulnerable of those children.

What does i.HUG do?

i.HUG currently has two projects. The first is a sponsorship program. Sponsors donate $360 a year to sponsor a needy child who cannot afford to go to school. That pays for the child&#8217;s school fees, school uniform, books and basic healthcare. Sponsors are matched with a needy child, and they receive a photo and a profile of that child, as well as some correspondence throughout the year. While our sponsorship project provides immediate relief, our second, long-term project embodies our philosophy of Sustainable Education and Ethical Development&#8212;what we call &#8220;The SEEDs Project.&#8221; Through this project, we are raising funds to establish a primary school in Kabalagala. 


IF YOU WANT TO SPONSOR A CHILD PLEASE GO TO  http://ihugfoundation.org/ BECAUSE YOU CANNOT DO IT THROUGH THIS SITE.  

1. Raise sponsorships for needy children so they can go to school.

2. Establish a school of highest quality.

3. Institute a training program for teachers and volunteers.

4. Increase access to medical treatment.

5. Form income-generating projects that contribute to the sustainability of the program.</description>
  <mission>Reach out to disadvantaged and orphaned children in Uganda by providing them with an education, access to healthcare, and an environment that fosters their physical, social and emotional development.</mission>
  <name>The International HUG Foundation (i.HUG)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3922</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">72</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4P/wc/CU/UE/DX/xI/zK4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
