<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I need YOUR help! Help me help the working homeless in our town to live a little better life. Currently, I am working on collecting Christmas ornaments that I will send to Our House. I am asking you to PLEASE help me get as many as I can. 
If you will, please give many any old ornaments or Christmas decorations that you no longer use. As long as they are still in working condition I will take them.
Or, if you want to buy me some new ones this would be great too. I know that Wal-Mart sells the plain glass balls for fairly cheap and the dollar stores sell boxes too and have decorations. Or, you can go as extravagent as Halmark, but this is not necessary. My point in saying this, is you do not have to spend much in order to help me. Every little bit help.
There are also two other options to help me. I am making ornaments to donate and will need supplies or you could make some yourself. If you want to go with that option message me at carrie72120@comcast.net or on Facebook and I will tell you my main needs at the moment.
The final option is to just donate some money to me for me to go out and buy either supplies or decorations. 
I plan on sending the ornaments by the end of October. If you do decide to help me, either call me at (501)920-8952 or message me on facebook and I will arrange to either pick them up from you or give you directions to my house to come and drop them off there.
Now, you may want to know a little more about Our House. The following is the Mission of Our House that I copied off of their web site. Our House provides the working homeless - families and individuals - with safe, clean, comfortable housing; food; free child care; education; and job training in order that they may return to independence and lead productive lives.
If you will, repost this on your profile or elswhere. Tell your friends. Help me spread the word about this project.
Also, please do not send donations on this page.  Contact me.  These donations go directly to Our House

1. Everyone deserves a Christmas.</description>
  <mission>give those less fortunate a better Christmas</mission>
  <name>Project Merry Christmas</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3930</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Vd/A7/oP/fG/kn/Zs/ruTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
