<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Colin Leslie Walk for Celiac Disease and Vendor Fair: October 18, 2009 

Here's the Info: 

The Colin Leslie Walk for Celiac Disease and Vendor Fair

October 18, 2009
9:00 am to 2:00 pm
Rye High School
Rye, NY - in Westchester County

Registration for the Walk includes admittance to the vendor fair. Registrationis required to attend the vendor fair even if you will not be walking. Lunch and snacks will be available for cash purchase, supplied by Soul Dog, a participating restaurant in the Gluten-Free Restaurant Awareness Program.

WALK: Starts at 10:00 am 2 mile or 4 mile route through scenic parts of Rye,
NY VENDOR FAIR 9:00 am to 2:00 pm
REGISTRATION: Pre-registration is available online until October 15, at www.colinlesliewalkforceliacdisease.org 
$20 (adults) $15 (children 12 and under)
You can also register at the Walk: $25 (adults) $20 (children 12 and under)

***Be sure to register by October 1 to be guaranteed a free t-shirt***

PARKING: Parking is behind 411 Theodore Fremd Ave., in Rye, for no extracharge. Free shuttle buses will be running throughout the day fortransportation between Rye High School and the parking lot. There is no parking at the high school. All proceeds will be donated to the Celiac Disease Center at ColumbiaUniversity. The Colin Leslie Walk for Celiac Disease in Rye, NY is co-sponsoredby the Westchester Celiac Sprue Support Group. For more information: www.colinlesliewalkforceliacdisease.org We hope you will join us at this special event.

Colin Leslie and Carine Leslie2009 Co-organizers 

www.colinlesliewalkforceliacdisease.org

1. Celiac needs to have more awareness

2. People need to get tested</description>
  <mission>Celiac Disease awareness and research</mission>
  <name>The Colin Leslie Walk for Celiac Disease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3952</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">415</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">155.18</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ZN/Q6/Zd/FS/cp/sZ/FibS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
