<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Who:
Proyecto Huasteco, Inc. is a publicly-supported, non-profit corporation organized to provide continuity and adequate financial support to Proyecto Huasteco &#8220;Sonrisa Alegre&#8221;

What:
Proyecto Huasteco, &#8220;Sonrisa Alegre,&#8221; is a program whose ultimate purpose is to rehabilitate children and adults with cleft lip deformities.

Why:
Because it improves the quality of life for scores of people who might otherwise endure a lifetime of heartbreak and humiliation. Also offers an opportunity to advance international understanding and goodwill between the peoples of Mexico and the United States.

How:
The Program is the result of joint efforts of a great number of people from Mexico and the United States. Proyecto Huasteco, Inc. is responsible for the overall organization and planning of the pjases; it provides medical supplies, nurses, physicians, and the plastic surgeon. The Mexican counterparts locate the patients and take care of them before and after surgery. They provide the hospital facilities, nurses and physicians.

Where:
Limited initially to the Huasteca region on the east coast of Mexico, the project has expanded and now moves in Mexico wherever the services of the Medical Team are requested. Larger cities are preferred because hospital and medical facilities are available.

When:
The project has progressed to a point where currently two phases a year are possible, one in May and another in November. As many as 69 operations have been completed per phase.

http://proyectohuasteco.org/index.html

1. To rehabilitate children and adults with cleft lip deformities.</description>
  <mission>To rehabilitate children and adults with cleft lip deformities.</mission>
  <name>Help support the rehabilitation of children and adults with cleft lip deformaties!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3953</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uv/6Z/8i/l2/Rf/16/sOYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
