<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Official website www.saveassyrianscause.com

The Assyrians (not to be confused with Syrians)are the indigenous inhabitants of Iraq and are the modern day descendants of the Neo-Assyrian Empire, which was one of the greatest civilisations to have risen from Mesopotamia until its fall in 612 B.C. Owing to their conquests Assyrians can still be found in Iran, Turkey, Syria and Lebanon in regards to the Middle East. 

Following the invasion of Iraq and the subsequent collapse of the Baath Party Regime in 2003, its most ancient people have been persecuted by terrorists. Kidnap, beheadings and church bombings have become a common feature of the campaign to oust Assyrians contributing to what is recognised as the Assyrian Diaspora (the scattering of people from their original homeland). This diaspora (the most famous being the Jewish one) started early last century with the Assyrian genocide during the First World War by Ottoman (Turkish) and Kurdish forces between 1914 and 1920. It has continued up to the present day and accelerated with the current unrest. Assyrians can now be found in large numbers in Europe, America, New Zealand and Australia.

To put it simply, Assyrians are targeted because they are a Christian minority in Muslim country. They have been seen by, what is hoped to be a minority of people, as collaborators with the West (U.S and U.K).

To protect Assyrians and other Christians from acts of violence and terror it is essential a safe haven is created in the modern Iraqi state as soon as possible with the aid of the West who so far have seemed to have forgotten about the Assyrians and their plight hence the need to raise awareness.

The charity that this cause supports is the Assyrian Aid Society of America (AAS), which was started in 1991. To find out more information about them and what they do please visit:- 

www.assyrianaid.org 

or click on the link at the top of the page which gives a concise summary of the AAS.

If you would like to contact me please do so at gregmayne@hotmail.co.uk or send me a message via Facebook.

Two websites that are very useful for finding out the latest news that affects Assyrians are:- 

www.ankawa.com

www.aina.org (Assyrian International News Agency)

http://assyrianvoice.net/emagazine/




1. Protection for Assyrians in Iraq must be implemeted

2. The creation of a safe haven for Assyrians in the Nineveh Plains

3. The prevention of the extinction of Assyrian culture and language</description>
  <mission>To help prevent the genocide of Assyrians and publicise their cause</mission>
  <name>Save Assyrians!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3957</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3150</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1090.61</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5h/xu/8f/EQ/j0/E4/je/1IS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
