<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I know of a group of students that - after school - go to a place that keeps them out of serious danger. For a few hours, these teens stay safe from life-jeopardizing activities involving drugs, guns and random violence.  The place is The House DC, where they go to build better lives with access to opportunities vastly unavailable to them otherwise.

Since 1999, The House, in Washington, DC, has been transforming and empowering the lives of inner city youth and their families. 

The House is located in the Anacostia area of Southeast on a street formerly known as "Murder Row." 
  
This former crack house is now a catalyst for youth to develop healthy relationships and experience changes of heart. 

After school, kids are learning!  Dance.  Cooking.  Computers.  Weightlifting.  Respectful hip-hop and R&amp;B.

All aspects of a teenager's development are taken into consideration at this safe-haven, an "urban oasis" in the midst of an area where it is not an exaggeration to say that bullets fly.

In my own brief experiences at the House, I had heard House staff recounting the fresh news of a young man who had just been paralyzed by a stray bullet.

Will you help?  On Facebook, now, you can help support a constant source of strength and hope for DC youth by joining this cause, telling your friends, and donating.

Thank you for taking time to consider supporting youth in our own "backyard,"  our nation's capital.

1. Urban teens can greatly use your support in a place that encourages them to learn and keeps them off of the streets.

2. Your support of creating awareness on Facebook can go a long way.

3. If you grew up with a liquor store on every block, where would you be today?</description>
  <mission>All teens need to be supported.  Some teens, like these in Southeast DC, need more.</mission>
  <name>Supporting the House DC</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/3980</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">59</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">345.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/IE/Ew/Kh/Fj/Eo/Xm/rk/7xS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
