<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The purpose of the Project is to show the world and ourselves what a passion people of all ages- especially young adults- have for their Lord. It's so people can have a place to voice what's buried so deeply in their hearts- whether it's fear, joy, confusion, or a deep longing. Whatever it is that you say when you close your eyes and pray, when you lift your heart to Him, that's what we want to see. As well as serving as an opportunity to really consider our relationship with God; this compilation will be a voice and evidence of living proof that our generations will NOT be quieted. We have an opportunity to prove that we are real and our relationships with God (whatever state they may be in) are real. I hope this book will not only serve as an outlet for those inside, but also serve as an inspiration to others as they struggle with their own prayers and relationships. Maybe it will show them that they are not alone. Write and send a letter to the address or just email to projectloveletterstogod@gmail.com.  Letters may be of any length, may be written anonymously or you can put your name. If you'd like we think it would have a great impact for you to put your hometown (i.e. Atlanta, Georgia) and age at the bottom. You can also put a pseudonym down. Whatever is most comfortable for you. We just want your letter! You may write as many letters as you'd like. No age limits. I would really like to have a wide variety of ages to make the compilation more poignant. This is something you can get your entire family involved in. You may write about anything you want. Whether what you're feeling is joyous, or fearful, passionate, or confused, we want your letter. All that matters is that it's heartfelt. It doesn't have to be eloquent. Just honest. You don't have to be part of a certain religion or denomination. In fact, it doesn't matter if you have a "religion." If you have something to say to God, then you've got something to say to him. And we'd like for you to share it.

1. The purpose of the Project is to show the world and ourselves what a passion people of all ages-- especially young adults-- have for their Lord.

2. As well as serving as an opportunity to really consider our relationship with God, this compilation will be a voice and evidence of living proof that our generations will NOT be quieted.

3. We have an opportunity to prove that we are real and our relationships with God (whatever state they may be in) are real.

4. When we have enough letters together we want to send this to be published. Any profits we may make off of the book(s) will probably be given to charity.

5. Send letters to projectloveletterstogod@gmail.com or 1007 Elsberry Drive, Woodstock, GA 30189</description>
  <mission>The goal of Project: Love Letters to God is to compile as many letters as possible from people with one common thread: God.</mission>
  <name>Project: Love Letters To God</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4004</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">207</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PJ/rv/jQ/kQ/4F/uA/eCPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
