<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Childhood Apraxia of Speech is a motor speech disorder. For reasons not yet fully understood, children with apraxia of speech have great difficulty planning and producing the precise, highly refined and specific series of movements of the tongue, lips, jaw and palate that are necessary for intelligible speech. Apraxia of speech is sometimes called verbal apraxia, developmental apraxia of speech, or verbal dyspraxia. No matter what name is used, the most important concept is the root word "praxis." Praxis means planned movement. To some degree or another, a child with the diagnosis of apraxia of speech has difficulty programming and planning speech movements. Apraxia of speech is a specific speech disorder.

In typically developing speech, children make word attempts and get feedback from others and from their own internal systems regarding how &#8220;well&#8221; the words they produced matched the ones that they wanted to produce.  Children use this information the next time they attempt the words and essentially are able to &#8220;learn from experience.&#8221;  Usually once syllables and words are spoken repeatedly, the speech motor act becomes automatic.  Speech motor plans and programs are stored in the brain and can be accessed effortlessly when they are needed.  Children with apraxia of speech have difficulty in this aspect of speech.  It is believed that children with CAS may not be able to form or access speech motor plans and programs or that these plans and programs are faulty for some reason.

For more information please visit http://www.apraxia-kids.org/



1. Every Child Derserves A Voice

2. Please join and help create awareness.

3. Donations go to Childhood Apraxia Of Speech Association Of North America</description>
  <mission>To strengthen the support systems in the lives of children with apraxia, so that each child has their best opportunity to develop speech</mission>
  <name>Apraxia - Kids</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4008</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8515</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">920.6</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1Q/4G/Kf/f2/AI/pw/mvRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
