<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Donations will go directly to the The Breast Cancer Research Foundation, Inc. (http://www.bcrfcure.org/)

As I am limited to US charities with this facebook cause, it seemed the closest match to what I was looking for, personally I know more about the Canadian Breast Cancer Foundation, and would highly recommend you make donations to them as well.... 

http://www.cbcf.org/

... 
I would like to acknowledge that I know there is another Breast Cancer cause on facebook (and possibly many more to come), but multiple causes will hopefully only raise awareness, and the other cause that I have seen gives it's donations to the Brigham &amp; Womens Hospital Inc.. a noble charity obviously, though one that does not deal specifically with Breast Cancer Research.
... 
From the Breast Cancer Research Foundation website:

The Breast Cancer Research Foundation is an independent 501 (c) (3) not-for-profit organization whose mission is to achieve prevention and a cure for breast cancer in our lifetime by providing critical funding for innovative clinical and genetic research at leading medical centers worldwide, and increasing public awareness about good breast health.  A minimum of 85% of all funds raised goes to breast cancer research grants and awareness programs.

In 2007, in the U.S., ACS estimates that breast cancer incidence in women will decrease significantly to 178,480 (from 212,920 in 2006). This represents a decrease of slightly more than 19%. Projected mortalities in women will also decrease, but not nearly as markedly, to 40,460 (from 40,970 in 2006.)

In men, incidence is estimated at 2,030 this year (up from 1,720 in 2006), with projected deaths almost the same at 450 (from 460 in 2006.) 

The Foundation welcomes and depends on contributions from all those concerned with women's health. Working together, we know we can find a cure in our lifetime.


1. fund research into improving detection, prevetion and treament

2. ultimately find a cure

3. create awareness through education</description>
  <mission>fund vital research into improving the detection, prevention and treatment of breast cancer as well as to ultimately find a cure and create awareness through education</mission>
  <name>Battle Against Breast Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4015</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">191690</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">9110.06</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/g0/YX/Ym/AF/ol/l5/Jm2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
