<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>If you have a child who is dealing with a family member&#8217;s cancer diagnosis, Camp Newhope can be a valuable resource to you and your family. When someone in a family is diagnosed with cancer, it not only affects them, it affects the whole family. Launched in the summer of 2002, Camp Newhope is a coping camp for children of cancer patients. The objective of this camp program is to bring these children together to honor their feelings and support them through their time of difficulty. Camp Newhope is a free program offered to children and teens (ages 6-18) who have a loved one with cancer.

Group sharing, big group games, artistic expression, and art therapy exercises are used to bring children closer to understanding their fears and concerns about cancer and offer a supportive and nurturing camp environment. Activities developed and coordinated by trained counselors promote expression and open the way for discussion from a child&#8217;s perspective.

During the summer months, we may go swimming, canoeing, and paddle boating. During the winder we may go horseback riding and hiking on nature trails. We&#8217;ve even been known to play in the rain!You never know what fun adventures will be awaiting you at camp!

For more information about Camp Newhope, or to make a tax deductible donation, please call or write:

Jen Batson or Sissy Hobbs, Foundation Coordinators
P.O. Box 660833
Birmingham, AL 35266-0833
Phone: 205.877.2224 or 205.877.2225
Fax: 205.877.1821



1. Cancer affects more and more families each day!

2. Children need to know they are not alone.

3. There needs to be a place for children to go so that they can learn more about cancer  and the side effects of the treatments.</description>
  <mission>To offer support to children who are coping with cancer in a loved one.</mission>
  <name>Camp Newhope - A camp for children who have a loved one with cancer.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4024</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">82</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qa/oG/2L/x4/Qp/JO/B5gS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
