<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Multiple sclerosis is a complex disease

While it is most often diagnosed in young adults, aged 15 to 40, we know that it affects children, some as young as two years old. The impact is felt by family, friends and by the community. MS is unpredictable, affecting vision, hearing, memory, balance and mobility. Its effects are physical, emotional, financial, and last a lifetime. There is no cure.

The Multiple Sclerosis Society of Canada is here to help. No one need face MS alone. In communities across Canada, our volunteers and staff provide information, support, educational events and other resources for people with MS and their families. Researchers funded by the MS Society are working to develop new and better treatments. Their ultimate goal is the cure for MS.

Did you know ... 

Canadians have one of the highest rates of multiple sclerosis in the world. 

MS is the most common neurological disease affecting young adults in Canada. 

Every day, three more people in Canada are diagnosed with MS. 

Women are more than three times as likely to develop MS as men. 

MS can cause loss of balance, impaired speech, extreme fatigue, double vision and paralysis. 

MS was first identified and described by a French neurologist, Dr. Jean-Martin Charcot, in 1868. 

We don't know what causes MS but researchers are closer to finding the answer.

Toll free to reach the nearest regional office: 1 800 268-7582

www.mssociety.ca
www.endms.ca

1. Provide hope for the future through the support of MS research into the cause, treatment and cure of the disease.

2. Provide hope for today through our many services that assist people with MS and their families.</description>
  <mission>To be a leader in finding a cure for multiple sclerosis and enabling people affected by MS to enhance their quality of life.</mission>
  <name>Multiple Sclerosis Society of Canada</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4028</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26506</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">4653.43</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/B0/ya/KH/Ao/tZ/ZY/bN/rKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
