<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Bread for the World is a collective Christian voice urging our nation&#8217;s decision makers to end hunger at home and abroad. By changing policies, programs and conditions that allow hunger and poverty to persist, we provide help and opportunity far beyond the communities in which we live.   

God&#8217;s grace in Jesus Christ moves us to help our neighbors, whether they live in the next house, the next state or the next continent. Food is a basic need, and it is unjust that so many people do not have enough to eat.  

We can end hunger in our time. Everyone, including our government, must do their part. With the stroke of a pen, policies are made that redirect millions of dollars and affect millions of lives. By making our voices heard in Congress, we make our nation&#8217;s laws more fair and compassionate to people in need.

Bread for the World members write personal letters and emails to Congress. We also meet with our representatives in Congress. Working through our churches, campuses, and other organizations, we engage more people in advocacy. Each year, Bread for the World invites churches across the country to take up a nationwide Offering of Letters to Congress on an issue that is important to hungry people.         

Bread for the World has two affiliate organizations. Bread for the World Institute does analysis and education on hunger issues. The Alliance to End Hunger engages diverse institutions&#8212;Jewish and Muslim groups, charities, universities, corporations, and others&#8212;in building the political commitment needed to overcome hunger.

Bread for the World works in a bipartisan way. It enjoys the support of many different church bodies. Bread for the World collaborates with other organizations to build the political commitment needed to overcome hunger and poverty.</description>
  <mission>Bread for the World is a collective Christian voice urging our nation's decision makers to end hunger at home and abroad.</mission>
  <name>Bread for the World</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4035</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1998</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">360.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/th/Jt/nz/dc/lh/BS/vl/FwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
