<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>About 100,000 worms, each smaller than the width of a grain of salt, will be making their way back from space next week as part of a six-month experiment aboard the International Space Station. 

Simon Fraser University scientist Bob Johnsen can hardly wait to analyze what's happened to them since they've been gone. 

"I'm very excited," said Johnsen, who will be heading to Cape Canaveral in Florida to collect the worms that have returned on the Space Shuttle Discovery. 
Johnsen is studying the effects of space radiation on the tiny creatures for the benefit of astronauts venturing off on lengthy trips to the moon and Mars in the near future. 
The research associate in the university's department of molecular biology and biochemistry said Wednesday the worms (C. elegans) have about a two-week lifespan on Earth and will have produced about 28 generations in space. 
He wants to study the mutations in the worms - the damage to their DNA from space radiation - over those generations to try to get an understanding of how the information could be applied to humans. 
That's because the worms that are barely visible to the human eye have about 20,000 genes, the same number as people and about half of them perform similar functions. 
"When you're on the space station you can measure radiation with physical detectors but you really don't know what the biological effects are on people that are staying on the space station for long periods of time," Johnsen said. 
"We want to get some understanding of the types of damages that space radiation causes and hope that we'll be able to start working on some countermeasures to protect our astronauts when they're going on these longer missions." 

 


1.  space radiation effects on worms returning from space must be made public!

2. We must work together to ensure these worms are treated humanely</description>
  <mission>raise public awareness about the space radiation effects on worms </mission>
  <name>space radiation effects on worms...for the greater good</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4040</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ul/NN/7s/Cd/IE/Wm/IdYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
