<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>YouthServe is the largest youth service organization in Birmingham bringing youth, ages 13-18 from all walks of life and from all over Birmingham together to participate in community service and social change. YouthServe hosts monthly Saturday workdays, after school projects, four camps in the summer, teaches a service learning curriculum in area schools and facilitates a year long youth philanthropy project. Whew, that's a lot. And we have fun doing it. Plus, we have great t-shirts that we give out. 

YouthServe hosts Community Action Projects one Saturday a month. All young people, ages 13-18 are invited. At YouthServe we believe that change is a group project, which means everyone must be involved. 

We believe in picking up a hammer or shovel and working side by side with each other to get things done to make our corner of this world a better place. And we could use your help

Give Us A CALL!

Lauren Banks, Executive Director, lauren@youthservebham.org

LaTonya May, Program Coordinator, latonya@youthservebham.org

Sarah Davis, Community Action and Service Coordinator, sarah@youthservebham.org

Emily Peterson, Executive Assistant, emilyp@youthservebham.org 

Americorps VISTAS:
Emily Salinas
Tiffany Brown
Jeffrey Williams
Marquita Holbert 

Trent Ramsey, Founder

YouthServe Office
 2717 7th Avenue South, Suite 105, Birmingham, AL 35233, 
(205) 521-6651

Located in the Lakeview District of Birmingham (one block north of St. Vincent's Hospital)




1. Promote youth volunteerism and leadership

2. Host 3 Urban Service Camps

3. Implement Service Learning in area schools</description>
  <mission>Empowering Youth Leadership through Community Service</mission>
  <name>YouthServe</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4041</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">180</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">70.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0A/XB/4a/w3/L4/Cy/uu/jdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
