<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Every day in Iraq, Afghanistan, and other nations all over the world, US soldiers die. It is a very sad truth, and many deaths are preventible. Most soldiers, especially in Iraq, are hurt by IEDs or road-side bombs. Many experts say that heavier-armored Humvees and military transports can prevent deaths due to terrorist boobie traps. Yet, the government refuses to invest the required money to armor all of our transports.

But our vehicles aren't the only thing unprotected. The soldiers themselves are given government-issue Interceptor body armor, which is bulky and often times not very useful.

Before leaving office, Donald Rumsfeld passed down a decree to the military stating that soldiers are no longer allowed to accept body armor sent to them from their families. So that means that soldiers have to wear the medeocre GI armor (if they get any at all), and they are not allowed to buy or recieve any better armor. Essentially, the government is telling our soldiers to have the same level of protection, and we won't allow you to be any safer.

This group is designed to raise interest about the safety concerns of our soldiers, to ask our local politicians to do something about it, and to help promote new and better protection technology.

UPDATE:
Here's something from the TV show Future Weapons about this system known as Dragon Skin. It demonstrates how well new technologies in body armor can protect soldiers. It also shows how weak even a quarter inch of steel plate armor is against light arms like the AK-47-- weapon of choice for insurgents.
http://youtube.com/watch?v=KS0pSwdQfbY

1. Raise awareness of safety issues for soldiers

2. Promote the use of more/better armor on transports and on individual soldiers

3. Allow families and other organizations to provide protection for their loved ones

4. Prompt the government to act to provide better armor</description>
  <mission>To better protect our soldiers overseas</mission>
  <name>Better Protection and Armor for Our Soldiers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4042</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2142</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">150.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fu/eX/o4/Qn/zn/nG/qHUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
