<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>DOOR stands for "Discovering Opportunities for Outreach and Reflection" which tells you we connect volunteers to service experiences in our cities.  We value the reflection upon those experiences as well as seeking God's reflection in the work we do, the ministries we are a part of in the city and within us as we serve others.

Your donation goes to our local leadership initiatives.  We strive to lift the voices of the local youth and young adults, the efforts of our local ministries in leadership of the local community.

D.O.O.R. currently has six sites:
Atlanta (Georgia), Chicago (Illinois), Denver (Colorado), Hollywood (California), Miami (Florida), and San Antonio (Texas).  Our locally governed programs are multi-cultural, multi-denominational, and multi-lingual. 

The "Discover" program provides coordinated weekend and weeklong programs designed to challenge individuals and groups (junior high through adult) to see the face of God in the city.

"Discern" is a semester-long program for individuals. Participants take time to focus on mission, service, and learning on a particular topic or with a specific population.

The "Dwell" program allows individuals ages 18-30 to live together in Christian community, serve, study, reflect, and learn both individually and as a team for at least one year.

Visit www.DOORnetwork.org or call the National Office at 303-295-3667 to set up a group trip, apply for either Discern or Dwell openings, or make a general donation to the organization's mission.

You may either donate on this page by clicking the "Donate" button or you can mail checks directly to the National Office:

DOOR
430 W 9th Ave
Denver, CO 80204

We are partnered nationally with the Mennonite Mission Network and the Presbyterian Church (USA.)  We also partner with the United Methodist Youthworker Movement, the Christian Reformed Church, the United Church of Christ, and Mission Year.

Become a Fan of our Fan Page! DOOR (Discovering Opportunities for Outreach and Reflection.)

1. We consider service an essential, daily part of living out authentic Christian faith.

2. By giving and receiving God's love, stereotypes are broken down, people physically feel God's presence and we build the Kingdom of God.

3. We work in partnership with other Christian organizations that value the gifts and the needs of the city.</description>
  <mission>To invite others to come and See the Face of God in the City. We host groups &amp; individuals to see that God is alive and working in our cities and to become a part of that divine transformation.</mission>
  <name>Discovering Opportunities for Outreach and Reflection (D.O.O.R.)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4043</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">427</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">615.74</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/C2/M6/Jr/TC/qt/om/xx/Z3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
