<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>World Connect was founded in 2005 to improve the health and well-being of women and children underserved and under-resourced communities worldwide. From 2006-2009, the organization focused primarily on Maternal, Newborn and Child Health programs in the Dominican Republic, which garnered national recognition and included training and equipping four hospitals and operating two maternal and infant rural health clinics.

In 2009, World Connect expanded its activities into youth development with the incorporation of the Kids to Kids Program, committed to creating opportunities for kids everywhere to participate in arts, sports, education and environmental projects. World Connect is expanding its programs again in 2010 with a new grant making mechanism, World Connect Grants, designed to connect mothers to mothers worldwide to address social problems affecting women, children and communities through health, education and income generation projects.

In response to the devastating earthquake that shook Haiti on January 12, 2010, World Connect has created a special relief effort, Help Hispaniola 2010. With extensive experience working in the Dominican Republic and deep connections to Haiti, World Connect has been assisting the relief efforts by navigating the shipment of critical medical supplies and equipment and dedicating staff time to coordinate logistics and is dedicated to being a part of the long-term commitment to help Haiti rebuild and recover.

World Connect also continues to support several of its initial clinical partners through its maternal and child health grant program.


1. World Connect: One organization, many projects and places!</description>
  <mission>World Connect's mission is to improve the health and wellbeing of women and children in under-resourced communities by empowering local leaders to solve local challenges.e.</mission>
  <name>World Connect</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4048</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">307</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2128.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yD/Gn/44/jC/1A/IK/Ka/4dS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
