<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We are looking for sponsors for this event that will allow ACES to better serve the community on a consistent basis, as well as the date stated above.  ACES is a 501(c)3 non-profit organization.  We has a Health Initiative Focus; including Blood Pressure Screenings, Obesity Reduction &amp; HIV Prevention, not to mention being an Educational Enhancement Center.

MISSION STATEMENT: ACES Museum is dedicated to honoring Black and Minority Veterans and their Families.  It is based at the building that houses the restored Parker Hall, where veterans converged in the past.  The original stage, piano and hall have been restored.  ACES have been certified as historical by the Germantown Historical Society.

PURPOSE OF FUNDING: ACES proposes a community developmental program. 

A.V. Hankins, MD, FACP, will follow the same integrative, ego stimulating educational style that has merited a Medical Honors in Teaching Award at Michigan State College of Human Medicine and an Alpha Omega Alpha Medical Teaching Honors Award from Drexel University in 2004.

BENEFITS: ACES advertise on radio, via flyers, online via our website and by way of our developmental television program.  A program booklet will be distributed listing all participants and friends of ACES.

CREDITS: ACES has been part of the following events: Smithsonian WWII Celebration &#9824; WWII Washington DC Memorial Parade &#9824; Juneteenth (Celebration of the End of Slavery) &#9824; Iowa&#8217;s Women&#8217;s WWII Celebration &#9824; Eisenhower WWII Weekend &#9824; ACES Day of Remembrance.

$50,000 help us meet our starting goal to provide the Greater Delaware Valley Area with a quality service, by keeping our communities safer, helping our Youth to &#8220;Respect the Past, While Preparing for Their Future.&#8221;

1. ACES motto is: &#8220;Respect the Past &#8211; Nurture the Future.&#8221;

2. There is an increase in violence related mortality, educational deficits and incarceration for the targeted youth.

3. ACES seek to preserve the past while exciting high risks about the possibility of a positive future.</description>
  <mission>See the legacy of the WWII and the minority veterans of war, continue with the memorabilia and artifacts she has collected and is seeking donations and contributions to complete this endeavor</mission>
  <name>ACES MUSEUM Honoring Black &amp; Minority Veterans of World War II &amp; Their Families</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4053</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">126</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/MV/oP/FT/yQ/gW/WG/LMpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
