<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The fact that you found our page proves how valuable the Internet can be as a tool to learn about the world around us.  That said, we are amazed that with a population of over 6 billion, only 15% have or use this amazing technology. More astounding are statistics for places like Africa where they make up approximately 14% of the world population yet only 2.2% of the population has access to the Internet. Compare this statistic to the continent of North America which constitutes 5.1% of the world population yet 68% use the vast array of services and information the Internet provides.  We do not think that it is a coincidence, with statistics like these, that North America is one of the strongest economic leaders around the world.

Help the world, Help the world's mission is to break down educational and technological barriers in regards to the Internet and its uses. Mainly, the ability to provide educational programs, for youth and adults alike, regardless of their geographical location.

With cooperation and support from Kidzstep Vocational Preparatory Centre and Task Park, Help the world, Help the world's goal is to ensure people around the world can raise their standard of life by elevating their ability on the internet playing field.

It is our contention that a simple solution can eradicate the vast differences between countries in regards to societal, educational and economic growth.

1. Education for all regardless of geographic Location

2. resource sharing for Charities and Non Profit Organizations

3. Virtual comunication in rural/remote areas of the world</description>
  <mission>Create equality in education regardless of economic and social standing</mission>
  <name>Help the World, Help the World</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4057</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">701</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/VY/oA/lq/ED/tr/KZ/hbIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
