<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>On May 9th, 2007, Baby Kaleb was admitted to the hospital in Florida diagnosed with SBS also called Shaken Baby Syndrome. Kalebs parents Kristy and Josh Schwade had thought that they had found the perfect babysitter to care for their child and wanted the absolute best for him. Little did they know that the person they trusted most with Kalebs life would almost take it away! Kaleb only went to the babysitter 5 times and the day before Kaleb had seen the doctor and was givin a "clean bill of health". The babysitter was charged and let out on a $5,000 bail!, she denies this and says that Kaleb was sick when he was dropped off that morning. Kaleb is still in the hospital and everyday that goes by is a day that he becomes a little bit stronger. This "Little Spartan" (fighter) as his mommy calls him is living proof of miracles.  I want everyone to know and pass the word around about Little Kalebs story. If anyone would like to make a donation you can write a cheque payable to Kristy Schwade or if you want to send the family a card please send it to the following address below....

Kristy Schwade/Kaleb Schwade

P.O.Box 291494
Tampa, FL  33687 - 1494

100% of the donations would cover the cost of medical bills, lawyer fees and any other expenses during this time. So far over $18,000 has been raised.

Check out Kristy's myspace page at..

www.myspace.com/kristyreynolds
                    or
www.babyhomepages.net/schwade

Thank you everyone for helping Baby Keleb Schwade  &lt;3  

P.S. I choose this picture of Kaleb taken one month and one day after he was hospitalized, if you look close you can see that this Little Man is holding up his arm :D  Yay Kaleb! Kaleb can also hear because he turns his head to the sound of his little glow worm! We are not giving up hope that he will 1 day be able to see again, and he's not going to be in a vegetative state as thought by the doctors for the reat of his life!!  
WAY TO GO KALEB!! * KEEP SHINNING *

1. People need to know WHAT THIS DOES...NEVER SHAKE A BABY</description>
  <mission>Share Kalebs story and let people know THAT IT IS NOT OKAY TO SHAKE A BABY!</mission>
  <name>Help Baby Kaleb</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4061</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">461</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Wk/Ok/hb/GZ/LB/lY/DGaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
