<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Poor health and poverty go hand-in-hand.Often,lifesaving drugs are widely available,but priced out of reach of the people who need them most to fight the AIDS pandemic.

In the 90s,before pharmaceutical companies made major price reductions and generic antiretroviral,ARV,drugs,were accessible in developing countries,HIV meant a rapid decline in health and certain death.Indian-made generic alternatives sold at a fraction of the price have been key to making lifesaving AIDS treatment a reality for more than 2 million people.

International trade and patent rules provide developing countries the flexibility to balance patent protection with public health imperatives.The government of India has used this flexibility to define what is &#8220;patentable&#8221; in India:Innovative drugs are issued a patent,and those that reflect minor changes to an existing drug aren't.

After its patent application for Glivec,a cancer drug,was rejected for not meeting the standard of innovation required,Novartis filed a lawsuit challenging Section 3(d) of India&#8217;s Patents Act,which defines what is patentable.If Novartis wins this lawsuit,incremental changes to existing drugs would be patentable and thus fewer drugs could be generically produced.Ultimately,this could jeopardize access to vital medication for millions of people.

2/3 of generic drugs manufactured in India are exported to other developing countries.In the context of the global AIDS crisis,the Novartis lawsuit threatens to reverse impressive treatment gains at a critical time.More than 5 million people who urgently need ARVs still don't have access to them.We can't allow anything to impede the global effort to achieve universal access to treatment.

CARE urges Novartis to drop its Section 3(d) lawsuit in India.We call our supporters and friends to ask the same of Novartis

1. Novartis to drop the case so poor people in India can still afford to buy medication.

2. ALSO,TAKE THE EXTRA INITIATIVE, CLICK ON THE LINK AND SEND A LETTER OF APPEAL TO NOVARTIS URGING THEM TO DROP THE CASE.

3. https://my.care.org/campaign/novartis?rk=LdeLEns1aUzWE</description>
  <mission>Help keep lifesaving medicines affordable</mission>
  <name>CARE.org</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4072</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">368</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">199.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bp/zT/4B/Kh/E4/ir/o7bS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
