<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Has a strange ever approached you in the streets and asked for money? Did you refuse? 

I was searching causes on facebook for something about the homeless people, and all I could find was causes about people trying to STOP others from helping the homeless. They say that the governement and police are spending too much money on the homeless, and that the money can be more appreciated elsewhere. But, the fact of the matter is that they are not spending enough money on the homless. People are too busy spending millions of dollars on the war, trying to protect their people, when many of their people are dying from starvation, aids, hypothermia and more.  

One of the main reasons a person passing by doesn't give the homeless money is because they think the homeless will not use it wisely. There is evidance to prove this. Many homeless people blow your money on drugs, or cigarettes. But truthfully, many people who have homes of their own blow their money on drugs too. It's an addiction, and maybe if we payed more attention to the homeless, we could help them to overcome this, and get their life back on track.

But, not all homeless people spend your money on such things. Many spend your money on medication for an illness that is the reason they are not able to get a job and support themselves. An illness they picked up from lack of proper diet, or hygiene as a result of being on the streets. 

The homeless get used to the hundreds of people who ignore them each day. The hundreds of people who brush past them, without a care in the world about someone other than themself. Being on the streets, one can get used to feeling invisible. So, the next time a rugged old man who smells bad asks for a buck or two, do not hesitate. How is one dollar going to change your life? Probably not at all. But think how much it may change theirs. Just to be able to know that people do see them, and that kindness is part of this world. 

1. About 1.35 million children are homeless in the United States alone.

2. 8 percent of the world's youth population are homeless

3. Many cities do not have proper facilities to help homeless people overcome their addictions

4. Just think if it were you. </description>
  <mission>Help people who do not have a warm bed to sleep in at night. </mission>
  <name>Save the Homeless</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4076</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">381</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/To/14/UL/GI/XV/xY/5CIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
