<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Global Alliance for Africa has focused on developing partnerships with Africans to provide food, shelter, and education to children orphaned by HIV/AIDS. We work through community-based (extended family or foster care family) initiatives, which involve an integrated program design that enables community agricultural cooperatives, safe water programs, and livestock initiatives.

GAA strives to provide the following for the over 6,000 children our program now reaches: 3 meals a day, a safe home environment, education through secondary school, access to health care, protection of legal assets, and psycho-social support.

GAA aims to provide educational opportunities and vocational training to strengthen vulnerable adolescents to support themselves. We operate through the following institutions: Tumaini Vocational Training Center, the Nurses Scholarship Fund, and the Community and School Library Program.

GAA provides training to financially strengthen families, households, and communities via the following measures: small business grants and small business management training, livestock and animal husbandry programs, safe water taps and access to clean water programs, and agricultural cooperatives.

Imagine how far your donation could go. For example:
$20 buys a goat that provides orphaned children with milk
$50 pays for an orphan's lunch at school every day for a year
$150 supports one AIDS orphan for an entire year
$500 supports a women's cooperative whose members take care of orphans
$2,000 funds a well site to provide families and communities with safe water

To learn more visit us on the web at http://www.globalallianceafrica.org/

Or contact us:
Global Alliance for Africa
703 W. Monroe
Chicago, IL 60661 U.S.A.
Phone: (312)382-0607
Fax: (312)382-8850
E-mail: director@globalallianceafrica.org

1. Community and family capacities to provide education and care for children who have lost one or both of their parents to HIV/AIDS must be strengthened.

2. Women and youths should have access to educational and economic institutions which foster entrepreneurship, empowerment, and self-reliance within communities.

3. Long-term, self-sustaining programs should develop to meet the needs identified by Africans themselves.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to collaborate with African organizations and communities to develop long-term, self-sustaining programs that meet needs identified by African organizations and community groups.</mission>
  <name>Global Alliance for Africa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4079</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">459</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">175.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zN/Yx/U1/DK/iY/JS/zCnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
