<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is a real life tragedy about a family whose baby, at only 5 months old, was shaken and is in the hospital fighting for his life. Kaleb, the only son of Kristy and Josh has been in the ICU since May 9th. Please view the following link that questions the legitimacy of stories circulating on the internet.
http://www.snopes.com/inboxer/medical/kalebschwade.asp

Kaleb experienced Shaken Baby Syndrome by the hand of a babysitter. 

This page is set up to help Kaleb and his family. Kristy and Josh spend mostly all of their free time at the hospital aching for a moment to hold their now sixth month old son. Expenses are mounting. This page is set up so that YOU can play an active role in helping Kaleb and his family. 

You can donate funds to cover medical expenses, lawyer fees, and other expenses by donating to the Help Kaleb Fund. 100% of funds will be used to help Kaleb's family. Please make checks payable to "Kristy Schwade", and send to: 
PO Box 291494 
TAMPA, FL 33687-1494 


It is preferred that you send any financial assistance to the address listed above and not the Nonprofit listed.  Althought he non-profit listed is a grerat one to support, this "cause" is for Kaleb and his family.

Please take a moment to read about this important issue, and join me in signing the petition. It takes just 30 seconds, but can truly make a difference. We are trying to reach 2,000 signatures - please sign here: http://www.thepetitionsite.com/1/put-rabeccas-saunders-away-for-life

Thank you!!!


1. To link people to a petition to lock Rebecca Saunders away

2. To raise money and to help with medical bills and support for Kaleb and his mom and dad Kristy and Josh

3. To raise awareness on Shaken Baby Syndrome</description>
  <mission>Put Rebecca Saunders away for LIFE and raise money for Baby Kaleb's family</mission>
  <name>Baby Kaleb</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4084</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">615</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pP/1S/Wt/Au/up/RQ/7XMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
