<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Please donate by using the link is Positions.  Thanks.

This disease is very personal to me, for my father passed away from it in 2001. Please help me to raise money so that other families will be able to save their loved ones. The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society's Light The Night Walk is the nation's night to pay tribute and bring hope to thousands of patients battling blood cancers and to commemorate loved ones lost. 
The Society funds lifesaving cancer research that has contributed to major advances in the treatment of blood cancers and many other types of cancer treatments such as chemotherapy and stem cell transplants that have prolonged and enhanced the lives of patients. New targeted therapies that kill cancer cells without harming normal tissue have already begun to provide drugs and procedures that are improving quality of life. 

But more research is critically needed:


Every five minutes someone is diagnosed with blood cancer. Every ten minutes, someone dies. 
Leukemia causes more deaths among children than any other cancer 
More than 20,000 Americans died from lymphoma in 2006 
The survival rate for myeloma is just 33 per cent
Please make a donation to support my Light The Night Walk and help save lives. Be sure to check my Web site frequently to see my progress, and again, thanks for your support! 


1. This disease is very personal to me, for my father passed away from it in 2001.

2. The Society funds lifesaving cancer research that has contributed to major advances in the treatment of blood cancers and many other types of cancer treatments such as chemotherapy and stem cell transplants that have prolonged and enhanced the lives of pa

3. Every five minutes someone is diagnosed with blood cancer. Every ten minutes, someone dies. 

4. http://register.lightthenight.org/LTNRegistration/app?page=TeamView&amp;service=page&amp;urlKey=TeamGP</description>
  <mission>Help raise funds for this organization, the walk is on Sept. 29th
</mission>
  <name>Leukemia and Lymphoma Society, Team GP</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4086</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6s/Vy/xC/VC/Zg/i0/C8QS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
