<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;b&gt;IMPORTANT!!!&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;b&gt;We are NOT a crisis center!&lt;/b&gt; If you or a friend is in immediate danger, please call the Suicide Prevention Lifeline at &lt;b&gt;1-800-273-TALK(8255)&lt;/b&gt; to speak with a trained professional. Do not call or send us a message.

&lt;P&gt;&lt;b&gt;The A Million Voices Campaign 
For High Schools and Universities&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;b&gt; JOIN US!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;The American Association of Suicidology (AAS) began the A Million Voices Campaign as a way to raise awareness about suicide and to generate financial support for survivor services. Now, AAS is looking to expand the Campaign into America&#8217;s universities and high schools.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;The A Million Voices (AMV) Campaign has been piloted around the country, with volunteers circulating AMV cards in a half dozen states. The cards contain suicide facts and warning signs as well as information about where to seek help. Campaign volunteers ask for $1 for suicide prevention, then give the donor a card. AAS has pledged to use 85 percent of the contributions to fund suicide prevention efforts, such as new support groups and materials for survivors.

&lt;P&gt;Proceeds of the High School and University project will go toward supporting the suicide prevention efforts of the schools. &lt;b&gt;Young people may not have hundreds to give, but $1 at a time, everyone can contribute toward saving lives from suicide.&lt;/b&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;To start a campaign in your city, university, or high school, please contact us at amv@suicidology.org&lt;/P&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;Check us out at www.suicidology.org&lt;/p&gt;   

&lt;fwl code="slideshow"&gt;&lt;MARQUEE WIDTH="100%" BEHAVIOR="alternate" SCROLLAMOUNT="5" DIRECTION="left to right" BGColor=""&gt;&lt;MARQUEE WIDTH="100%"&gt;&lt;a href="http://freeweblayouts.net" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i193.photobucket.com/albums/z99/aastara/aaslogo2.jpg" border="0"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;         &lt;/MARQUEE&gt;&lt;/MARQUEE&gt;&lt;/fwl code="slideshow"&gt;



1. Suicide is preventable!</description>
  <mission>Raise $1 Million, $1 at a time for suicide prevention.</mission>
  <name>A Million Voices Campaign for Suicide Prevention</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4091</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3317</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">530.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fm/2Q/jl/G1/kF/RT/V2DS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
