<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Esperanza is a nonprofit community development organization focused on serving the most impoverished families in the Dominican Republic and Haiti. Esperanza was founded in 1995 by former Major League Baseball player, Dave Valle and his wife Victoria.

Programs:
1) Microfinance - Our core program enables families to start or expand their own businesses through small loans, insurance, savings and business training to generate income and economic security. 

2) Health Care - In partnership with local medical clinics, Esperanza families receive free preventative health care exams, dental cleanings and basic vaccinations for their children. We also offer special services such as physical therapy, pediatric care,  OBGYN, dentistry and general medicine.

3) Education - We provide business and vocational training for the working poor to start or develop their own business. We also give their families access to computer training courses and our literacy program to increase knowledge and expand their opportunities for the future.

4) Social Mobilization - Through a network of local schools, churches, computer labs and community meetings, Esperanza helps to coordinate community resources and services &#8211; leading to a future free from poverty and dependence. 

Please visit our website at www.esperanza.org for more information.

1. Address the root causes of poverty, especially those impacting children, and facilitate activities that lead to improved living conditions, reduced infant mortality, greater life expectancy, better nutrition, improved education, increased income, environm

2. Focus on families and communities as the agents, planners, implementers and evaluators of the development efforts, where the vision comes from the people, and the ownership is theirs;

3. Improve the capacity of people to learn from their experiences of development, to be empowered by that process and to lead more fulfilled lives with greater understanding of the world they live in;

4. Free people from the bondage and oppression of cultural, social, spiritual and economic forces that inhibit becoming all that is intended;

5. Build alliances and partnerships with other institutions with compatible goals, such as churches, non-governmental organizations and local community groups;

6. # Lead to more technically appropriate and sustainable activities and practices that contribute to self-sufficiency and self-reliance;

7. Improve the leadership, management and organizational skills within the families and communities of a project area.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to free children and their families from poverty through initiatives that provide income, health care and education - restoring dignity and self-worth to those who have lost hope.</mission>
  <name>Esperanza International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4093</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">729</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3330.25</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Tk/wu/Rf/rz/2f/oE/2NvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
