<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Based on this AMAZING Song:

Legacy
by Nichole Nordeman 
album: Woven and Spun (2002),  Live at the Door (2003)
I don't mind if you've got something nice to say about me And I enjoy an accolade like the rest And you can take my picture and hang it in a gallery Of all the "who's who's" and so-and-so's That used to be the best at such and such It wouldn't matter much I won't lie, it feels alright to see your name in lights We all need an "atta boy" or "atta girl" But in the end I'd like to hang my hat on more besides The temporary trappings of this world I want to leave a legacy How will they remember me? Did I choose to love? Did I point to You enough To make a mark on things I want to leave an offering A child of mercy and grace Who blessed Your name unapologetically And leave that kind of legacy I don't have to look too far or too long awhileTo make a lengthy list of all that I enjoy It's an accumulating trinket and a treasure pile Where moth and rust, thieves and such will soon enough destroy I want to leave a legacy How will they remember me? Did I choose to love? Did I point to You enough To make a mark on things I want to leave an offering A child of mercy and grace Who blessed Your name unapologetically And leave that kind of legacy Not well-traveled, not well-read Not well-to-do, or well-bred I just want to hear instead Well done, good and faithful one I want to leave a legacy How will they remember me? Did I choose to love? Did I point to You enough To make a mark on things? I want to leave an offering A child of mercy and grace Who blessed Your name unapologetically And leave that kind of legacy I don't mind if you've got something nice to say about me



Here is the music video:
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d0S0ep-QsNI



1. EVERYONE can leave a legacy if they just TRY</description>
  <mission>make a difference in this world that will last when we are gone</mission>
  <name>I Wanna Leave a Legacy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4109</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wy/iD/I0/5t/yy/eh/PZXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
