<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>      Inspired by the Grameen Bank, Nicholas Kristof (PDF), and Kiva.org, Social Entrepreneurs of Grinnell (SEG) is the Grinnell College student group working to collect money for the distribution of microfinance loans. The world of microfinance, a sustainable way to assist sustainable development, is expanding at a tremendous rate and SEG is one of the first college groups to begin creating a fund to make microfinance loans.
      Micro-finance is a development plan that provides small loans to individuals in Third World countries that would not otherwise be able to gain credit. They take this money loaned to them and expand their businesses, improve their houses, or invest in better technologies for their farms. By providing individuals with funds, micro-financing is able to give to people the opportunity to invest in their own lives. Using the money that the Social Entrepreneurs of Grinnell, as well as other micro-financers on Kiva.org, give out, they are able to create a better life for themselves and their families. This is not charity and the loan will eventually be paid back, usually within a year. After the loan is paid back to the Social Entrepreneurs of Grinnell, we will loan the funds out again to another individual.

1. Work to alleviate self-perpetuating social and economic problems of inequality.

2. Accomplish our goals by giving people the agency, not just charity, by which to help themselves.

3. Provide these means in the form of microfinance loans to those who would otherwise be ineligible for such assistance.</description>
  <mission>foster connections between the First and Third world by giving agency to individuals in order to sustainably address the self-perpetuating social and economic problems of inequality.</mission>
  <name>Social Entrepreneurs of Grinnell (SEG)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4117</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PG/1j/6M/3x/LW/Tr/tgPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
