<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Your support to American Friends of Magen David Adom&#8217;s is urgently and critically needed

In the past five years, AFMDA has raised over $90 million for Magen David Adom. 
In the last two years, American Friends of Magen David Adom have sent 209 ambulances, including 71 Mobile Intensive Care Units (MICU's) and 7 bloodmobiles.MDA has a fleet of 656 MDA ambulances which travel over 5.25 million miles a year, taking care of more than 300,000 patients annually. 
AFMDA built the MDA National Blood Services Center in Ramat Gan in 1987 at a cost of over $32 million. The Blood Center is comprised of the Joseph Handleman Blood Bank and the Erna and Dr. Henry Marx Blood Fractionation Institute. Both of the institution's ensure that Israel's health care providers have enough blood to save life. The MDA provides 100% of the blood requirements of the Israel Defense Forces (IDF) and 95% of the blood needs of the Israeli hospitals and the general population. AFMDA will be mounting a $30 million expansion to the MDA National Blood Services Center over the next 3-5 years. 
AFMDA furnishes MDA with the crucial life saving equipment and supplies to serve Israel as "first responders" to all disasters and medical emergencies. 
AFMDA support ensures that all of MDA's Emergency Medical Station personnel undergo training every year and that the MDA Emergency Medical Stations are fully computerized with up-to-date technology. 
MDA has 100 Emergency Medical Stations in communities throughout Israel, from huge cities to small towns and kibbutzim and 11 dispatch centers. These stations provide emergency care and ambulance services, 24 hours a day, seven days a week, and 365 days a year. 


1. Help Magen David Adom</description>
  <mission>support Israel's EMS, blood centers and MDA</mission>
  <name>Support MDA - Israel</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/412</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">341</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">46.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nwD/NrSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
