<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>To all our friends at Mustard Seed Associates 
* Our Lenten guide was more successful than we could imagine.  It was distributed by groups as diverse as the global 24/7 prayer network and the Uniting Church in Australia.  It was also shared throughout a variety of churches and to students and staff at seminaries and Christian universities in the US and Canada. * Our conversation with Rudi Carrasco The Colour of Love in the City, brought together 55 people from diverse backgrounds for a lively discussion on racial issues. * Our first Celtic workshop held at the Mustard Seed House a couple of weeks ago filled our living room with participants.  * We are busy planning for our upcoming events &#8211; The Emerging Writer&#8217;s Workshop on July 14th, our annual Celtic Retreat August 17-19th and our next conference February 28, 29th and March 1st, 2008 &#8211; The Conspiracy Lives! What in the World is God Doing?

As you know one of the major ways that we share resources and communicate about upcoming events with our global network is through our monthly email newsletter the Seed Sampler. Some of you may remember its early beginnings four years ago when it was nothing more than an update of local events.  Under the able guidance of volunteers it has become a substantial and sometimes provocative resource on such diverse topics as Human Trafficking and Spiritual Direction. We are delighted to be able to draw on the expertise of a growing nucleus of writers from around the world who join us in this endeavour.     
We have created a new half time staff position for a newsletter co-ordinator and ask that those of you who enjoy reading the Seed Sampler each month consider a financial contribution to help support this position.  We are trusting God for $15,000 in contributions and pledges over the next 2 months.  Will you join with us in prayer and ask God how you can help us meet this need?  Donate online or send a check to Mustard Seed Associates, PO Box 45867, Seattle WA 98145.


1. anticipate the future

2. decode the culture

3. convey the Kingdom of God

4. create new ways to be a difference and make a difference</description>
  <mission>Mustard Seed Associates (MSA) is a small non profit organization that seeks to raise awareness of challenges that Christians will face in their lives, churches &amp; communities in the future.</mission>
  <name>Mustard Seed Associates</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4120</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">91</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">115.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ot/o7/4b/AC/ug/HC/1DxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
