<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>WHAT IS ALS?

Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), sometimes called Lou Gehrig's disease, is a rapidly progressive, invariably fatal neurological disease that attacks the nerve cells (motor neurons) responsible for controlling voluntary muscles. Unable to function, the muscles gradually weaken, waste away, and twitch. Eventually, the ability of the brain to start and control voluntary movement is lost. Because ALS affects only motor neurons, the disease does not impair a person's mind, personality, intelligence, or memory. Nor does it affect a person's ability to see, smell, taste, hear, or recognize touch. 

When muscles in the diaphragm and chest wall fail, patients lose the ability to breathe without ventilatory support. Most people with ALS die from respiratory failure, usually within 3 to 5 years from the onset of symptoms. However, about 10 percent of ALS patients survive for 10 or more years.

Facts: 

~As many as 30,000 Americans have ALS, and an estimated 5,000 people in the United States are diagnosed with the disease each year. 
~ALS most commonly strikes people between 40 and 60 years of age, but younger and older people also can develop the disease. 
~Men are affected more often than women.
~In 90 to 95 percent of all ALS cases, the disease occurs apparently at random with no clearly associated risk factors. 
~ALS is not contagious.
~ALS is a quite variable disease; no two people will have the same journey or experiences.  
~THERE IS NO CURE  OR TREATMENT THAT HALTS OR REVERSES ALS.

Through Extra Hands for ALS, high school and college students volunteer to help people with ALS and their families by doing chores and errands or just providing company for the homebound. Students also organize and participate in ALS public awareness events designed to teach their peers and communities about the disease.  Furthermore, fundraising is a vital part of this cause in order to fund more research towards the disease.



1. Volunteer to help people with ALS

2. Raise Awareness about ALS

3. Fund Raise to help towards ALS Research</description>
  <mission>Is to instill the importance of community service in young adults by uniting them with people who have ALS and their families while raising awarenss and promoting research!</mission>
  <name>Extra Hands for ALS</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4141</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">722</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/JJ/ey/4C/UO/gY/1D/3CFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
