<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Q: What is Industrial Hemp?
     A: Industrial Hemp is a number of varieties of Cannabis sativa L. that are intended for agricultural and industrial purposes. They are grown for their seed and fiber content as well as the resulting byproducts such as oil, seed cake, hurds, etc. Industrial Hemp is characterized by being low in THC (delta-9 tetrahydrocannabinol) and high in CBD (cannabidiol). THC is less than 1% and in Canada and Europe the current legal level for cultivation is 0.3%. The ratio of CBD to THC is greater than one.

First of all the new market for it would create not only a ridiculous amount of jobs, but it would create a whole new industry with jobs from low to high level positions! Along the same lines, the demand for Hemp in an economy looking for cheap clothing, and alternative fuel sources, would be incredibly high. This need for Hemp would allow farms on the borderlines of shutting down to have a new market to grow for. Being from Vermont, I know as well as anyone, that our farmers are in tough times right now. Industrial Hemp would, without a doubt, fix this problem.

Hemp Seed Oil can be used to fuel cars. Biodiesel is becoming very popular lately, and Hemp is actually the best plant to use for biodiesel. It boasts the highest oilseed yield out of all other plants used for biodisel. This means that one plant of Hemp can produce more fuel then any other single plant.

Hemp doesnt only produce more fuel per plant, it can produce more paper as well! Hemp produces 3-4 times more usable fiber for paper per hectre (per year) then our own forests. Forests that we are constantly destroying (killing wildlife!) to fuel our insane paper-need. Why do this when there is a more efficient paper-producing plant available?

Hemp can be used for TONS of other things, please check out the Wikipedia entry for Industrial hemp or go to www.votehemp.org for plenty more information.


1. The United States must allow the unhindered growing of the Industrial Hemp Plant

2. Paper making corporations of the world must switch to Industrial Hemp as its main source for paper

3. Industrial Hemp must be separated from Marijuana</description>
  <mission>Bring about the legalization of Industrial Hemp</mission>
  <name>Industrial Hemp</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4145</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">957</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.15</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/u4/qQ/rq/KI/aC/f6/rpIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
