<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Bush wants to inject more troops into Iraq. There have been more than 3300 deaths of American soldiers in Iraq at last count.  This is a war that is not winnable, we need to withdrawl and save the lives of current soldiers.  If Bush had two son instead of two party crazy herion addicts for daughters, and his sons were in Iraq you can be damn sure that we would not be there.  As long as there are at least two types of people there will be those exteremists, terrorists, who want the demise of the other.  We are not fighting piracy in Indosia.  We arre fighting a war that is unwinnable but also driving UP gas prices.  Bush needs to leave office or get his head out of his ass and do something.  

Please tell people about this, we are trying to save lives of soldiers.  Those soldiers are dying to protect the honor of a dumbass we call our president.  Families are being torn apart at the senseless deaths of Americans, who put their life on the line to protect the all of our freedoms, two of which I am expressing right now, Freedom of speech and press.   I am appalled at the money we have spend on the war.  Education is a much more pressing need than keeping the honor of a country.  
Limit our losses to those of the current date.  Some countries work better under certain governments.  China has a communistic view, and Americans have a democratic and capitalistic view.  These are the two most prolific economys in the world.  
Even if Bush does not want to pull our troops out of Iraq, I will be damned if I dont support them.  To all Americans in the armed forces, air force, navy ect.  I would like to thank each and everyone for putting your life on the line in order to protect my rights and those of 300 million other Americans.  To all those who have lost a loved one, my regrets, they died for their country, the most honorable way to die, fighting in a cause not only for oneself, but the allegid benefit of others.


1. Not Elect Future Dumbasses into Polotical Office

2. PROTECT THE LIVES OF AMERICANS WHO DONT NEED TO DIE</description>
  <mission>Pull our troops out of Iraq</mission>
  <name>Stopping Bush From Killing Americans</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4147</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">67</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dX/xi/ME/Ou/Rg/lr/u3hS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
