<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This group has been made in honor of those who have faught or are continuing to fight the brave battle. I am hoping that we can raise enough money to donate to the National Ovarian Cancer Association based here in Canada. This money will go towards helping those who are currently dealing with the disease as well as their loved ones. With enough money raised, i am hoping that we can help bring awareness to women and their families about this silent killer. Ovarian cancer claims the lives of thousands of women each day and I am hoping that with a large donation, we can say that we helped put a stop to that. 

I am not just a random person who wants to make a difference. I have been touched by Ovarian Cancer  within my family. Ovarian Cancer claimed the lives of both of my grandmothers and I am hoping that this money will help prevent that from happening to anybody else. One of my grandmothers lost her battle 26 years ago and it remains a black cloud over the heads of the women in my family. My second grandmother lost her brave battle to Ovarian Cancer just 7 short months ago. I don't want anybody else to have to experience the pain that i have felt. Ovarian Cancer continues to remain a black could within our family as my mother's risk of developping it is now up 50% and my chance of developping it is now up 25%. Let's help beat the odds!

Let's pull together as a society and raise money for an amazing cause! WE CAN DO IT. It's a silent killer. But it doesn't have to be. Let's help make Ovarian Cancer *HISTORY*!

1. To help make Ovarian Cancer *HISTORY*

2. To aid families who have been touched by Ovarian Cancer

3. To bring awareness to a silent killer</description>
  <mission>Raise money in honor of those who have fought or are continuing to fight the brave battle</mission>
  <name>Ovarian Cancer Awareness. A silent Killer; but it doesn't have to be!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4148</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">67101</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1529.31</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4F/KW/uI/Uq/e0/IY/fOrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
