<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It is well established that people with a surname that starts late in the alphabet suffer significant disadvantages in terms of income, happiness and overall life success. See here for a timely and understandable review of the relevant literature http://www.richardwiseman.com/quirkology/surname.html 

Given the systematic nature of the discrimination, we no longer accept this blatant injustice. The cause involves three phases:
 
1. Document the systematic and comprehensive scope of the discrimination. (Some things that immediately come to mind are email mailing lists where those with "early" letters get important information significantly earlier than those with later letters, alphabetical authorship lists, listings of all kinds, e.g. class listings or faculty listings. This leads to a very uneven - and very undeserved - high exposure of those with early-lettered surnames. See here for paradigmatic examples: http://psychology.uchicago.edu/people/faculty.shtml http://psychology.uchicago.edu/people/students.shtml ) 

2. Raising awareness about the significance of the matter. 

3. Come up with creative solutions to the existing and ongoing discrimination. (For example, educators bear the special responsibility not to entrench these effects by relying on alphabetically ordered class lists. Maybe outlawing alphabetic ordering altogether might be a good idea. Order by merit. Or age. Or any other criteria. Even random would be better. Names don't really mean anything any more. So we already have a random ordering. But one that consistently and unfairly benefits one group). 
One policy solution is obvious. Everyone knows the alphabetic order, so the cognitive economy of that shouldn't be underestimated. However, there is no reason to always start with "A". As a matter of fact, it would be trivially easy to (at least on websites) show lists with a random starting character (and then continue alphabetic ordering) every time the page is refreshed or reloaded. 
 

1. Position #1</description>
  <mission>To end alphabetical discrimination NOW</mission>
  <name>People for alphabetical justice</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4161</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ks/K2/Wt/Iv/Ju/oR/oLNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
