<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>DESCRIPTION:

Buruli ulcer is a neglected tropical disease caused by a germ which affects mainly the skin, but can sometimes affect the bone. 
The causative organism is called Mycobacterium ulcerans which belongs to the same family of organisms that cause leprosy and tuberculosis.

NB:

At least 1 billion people &#8212; one sixth of the world&#8217;s population, or 1 person in 6 &#8212; suffer from one or more neglected tropical diseases (NTDs), such as Buruli ulcer, cholera, cysticercosis, dracunculiasis (guinea-worm disease), foodborne trematode infections (such as fascioliasis), hydatidosis, leishmaniasis, lymphatic filariasis, onchocerciasis, schistosomiasis, soil-transmitted helminthiasis, trachoma and trypanosomiasis, although there are other estimates that suggest the number could be much higher. Several of these diseases, and others such as dengue, are vector-borne. Often, those populations most affected are also the poorest and most vulnerable and are found mainly in tropical and subtropical areas of the world. Some diseases affect individuals throughout their lives, causing a high degree of morbidity and physical disability and, in certain cases, gross disfigurement. Others are acute infections, with transient, severe and sometimes fatal outcomes. Patients can face social stigmatization and abuse, which only adds to the already heavy health burden.


1. BURULI ULCER IS POSSIBLE TO CURE WITH BASIC CARE AS IS USING A SPECIAL CLAY TO HELP HEAL THE WOUNDS!!! 

2. WHEN THOUSANDS OF DOLLEARS ARE INVESTED ON WAR BY THE US, NONE IS INVESTED IN TROPICAL DISEASES AS BURULI ULCER</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness on the matter and raise funds to help the victims</mission>
  <name>BURULI ULCER</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4171</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">18</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Gp/gd/NK/sQ/as/DA/F7cS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
