<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Allentown Women's Center (AWC) is a progressive, highly respected women's health care clinic that has been providing high quality reproductive health and abortion services for over 26 years. The Allentown Women's Center is committed to maintaining the highest standards of the medical field while providing emotional support in a supportive, non-judgmental environment.
Women are the gatekeepers of life. AWC supports and respects the right of every woman to make her own decisions regarding her reproductive health care and sexuality. Through education, outreach, and counseling support, AWC aspires to help create an environment where women will not be judged or harassed for their choices, but praised for their strength and courage. All Women Count at AWC!"
- AWC Website (http://www.allentownwomenscenter.com)

&lt;big&gt;Far more than donations of money, AWC is interested in volunteer "escorts". That is, people to assist patients in getting from our private parking lot, through a crowd of loud, offensive, and intimidating anti-choice demonstrators, to the clinic entrance. For more information, please contact the cause creator, Kate Wilgruber.&lt;/big&gt;

1. Freedom of access to reproductive healthcare is a universal right as decided by Roe vs. Wade.

2. The federal FACE act should be enforced. Designed to protect both providers and receivers of reproductive health care services, it forbids the use of 

3. Although the first amendment should be staunchly upheld, pro-life demonstrators should have to operate within the same strict legal perameters as demo</description>
  <mission>Protecting the rights of women to have access to reproductive healthcare free from harassment, violence, surveillance and judgement.</mission>
  <name>Support the Allentown Women's Center</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4199</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">131</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">34.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8t/On/ZP/sD/3M/4u/Op/IIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
