<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Transparency International, the global civil society organisation leading the fight against corruption, brings people together in a powerful worldwide coalition to end the devastating impact of corruption on men, women and children around the world. 
TI&#8217;s mission is to create change towards a world free of corruption. 

Transparency International challenges the inevitability of corruption, and offers hope to its victims. TI plays a lead role in improving the lives of millions around the world, by building momentum for the anti-corruption movement, raising awareness and diminishing apathy and tolerance of corruption, as well as devising and implementing practical actions to address it. 

Transparency International is a global network including more than 90 locally established national chapters and chapters-in-formation. These bodies fight corruption in the national arena in a number of ways. They bring together relevant players from government, civil society, business and the media to promote transparency in elections, in public administration, in procurement and in business. TI&#8217;s global network of chapters and contacts also use advocacy campaigns to lobby governments to implement anti-corruption reforms. 

Politically non-partisan, TI does not undertake investigations of alleged corruption or expose individual cases, but at times will work in coalition with organisations that do. 

TI has the skills, tools, experience, expertise and broad participation to fight corruption on the ground, as well as through global and regional initiatives. 

Now in its second decade, Transparency International is maturing, intensifying and diversifying its fight against corruption. 


1. TI believes that keeping corruption in check is only feasible if representatives from government, business and civil society work together and agree on a set of standards and procedures they all support. 

2.  TI also believes that corruption cannot be rooted out in one big sweep. Rather, fighting it is a step-by-step, project-by-project process. 

3. Finally, TI believes in a non-confrontational approach to get all relevant parties to the table.</description>
  <mission>To expose government corruption around the world.</mission>
  <name>Transparency International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4240</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">781</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.14</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Hi/B2/tx/TV/Q6/RW/84uS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
