<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Planting Churches in Unreached Areas
In each aspect of Gospel for Asia&#8217;s ministry, the primary aim is to plant churches among the unreached &#8212; those who have never heard the Gospel. 

Sending Native Missionaries
Gospel for Asia trains and sends native missionaries because they have proven extremely effective. They are already familiar with the language and culture, and they live at the level of the people they serve, thus removing many social barriers. 

100 Percent Goes to the Field
Gospel for Asia sends 100 percent of the money you donate for work on the mission field to the field. Nothing is taken out for administrative expenses.
 

--==NOTICE==--
(Thanks to Devorah Allen for this suggestion).
For those of you who don't know, when you click the "Donate" button above, you are actually giving your donation to JustGive.org, who then passes your donation on to Gospel For Asia. Please do not send your donations through this organization. I have no doubt that they are a fine ministry with an honest purpose, but they do appropriate 4.5% of your donation for their own operating expenses. (This information can be found under their Terms of Use, at the bottom of the donations page.) Instead, let me urge you to go directly to GFA's website, www.gfa.org, and send your donations from there. Or you can call 1-800-WIN-ASIA to donate over the phone. You can be assured that when you donate directly to GFA, 100% of your gift will reach missionaries on the field.





1. That the Bible is the verbally inspired, inerrant Word of God. It is the complete revelation of His will for salvation and the only unfailing rule of faith and practice for the Christian life. 

2. In one God, Creator of all things, eternally existing in three persons: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, and that these three are co-eternal and of equal dignity and power. 

3. In the deity of Jesus Christ; His miraculous conception by the Holy Spirit; His virgin birth; His sinless life; His substitutionary death on a cross; His bodily resurrection; His ascension to the right hand of the Father; and His personal, imminent return

4. That man was created by and for God; that by man's disobeying God, every person incurred spiritual death, which is separation from God, and physical death as a consequence; and that all people are sinners by nature and practice.

5. The Lord Jesus Christ died for our sins and that all who believe in Him are declared righteous because of His sacrificial death and are, therefore, in right relationship with God. 

6. In the present ministry of the Holy Spirit indwelling all believers and thus enabling and empowering the life and ministry of the believer. 

7. In the bodily resurrection of everyone who has lived, the everlasting blessedness of those in right relationship with God, and the everlasting punishment of those who have rejected God's forgiveness in His Son. </description>
  <mission>To be devout followers of Christ and to fulfill the Great Commission among the unreached in Asia through training, sending out and assisting qualified laborers in partnership with the Body of Christ.</mission>
  <name>Gospel for Asia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/426</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6176</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2320.5</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/iyo/JUDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
