<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In September 2004, the non-profit Invisible Children, Inc. was created in an attempt give people a way to easily respond to the situation in Northern Uganda after viewing the film. Based out of San Diego, Invisible Children is changing the face of non-profit work by personally connecting two unlikely worlds &#8211; the youth of America with war-affected children around the globe. Using video, music, art, guerilla marketing, and an interactive web community such as &#8220;Schools for Schools,&#8221; Invisible Children is centered around raising public awareness in the U.S. in an attempt to spur youth into action and to change the current policies of governments around the world. Invisible Children, Inc. is the never before. Older generations&#8217; tactics are becoming irrelevant, and Invisible Children will continue pursuit of unconventional methods for reaching a generation that others are struggling to understand. 

Invisible Children Inc. is also responsible for raising significant sums of money, which go toward a number of programs they have developed in Uganda and America (see below) focusing largely on education and rehabilitation of war-effected areas. 

Invisible Children appeals to people who have a heart for children. The children in Northern Uganda are human beings, similar to those in the U.S. and everywhere else. But the world is large, child soldiers are being forced into combat right now around the globe, and many children still remain &#8220;invisible.&#8221; IC as a company, and the revolution it began, will continue to stand against such injustice. 


1. global awareness.

2. get involved

3. start a revolution</description>
  <mission>get the word out</mission>
  <name>give them freedom. (invisible children)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4269</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">940</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">125.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fq/pO/GL/tn/Sv/y5/KpsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
