<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We all hopefully know that there are many people out there who believe that by pretending to defy human nature and acting like they are trying to benefit others with their causes, and think that since the majority of Americans are dumb as shit (which is pretty damn accurate), they can get away with twisting other people's emotions with lies and overacting, but the small percentage of intelligent Americans need to defy these fat bastards and realize their true intent. These "feminists" and protesters for women's rights, they complain about how women are not taken as seriously as men, and are given lower wages than men, but somehow 99% of these women happen to be huge, repulsive lesbians with bowl cuts. People are given jobs based on a measure of their natural talent, and the truth is most women will get cushier and better paying jobs if they are prettier, or better at what they do. Women reading this at this point would probably start to get pissed because they are letting their emotions get the best of them, and i cant do anything about that, but what I can do is tell you that 99% of men would gladly have women open doors for them, pay for their dinners, and give them expensive gifts, and the guys that speak out defending these fat women and small amount of decent-looking women are very desperately trying to get laid, or are gender confused. The women who protest are either stubborn as fuck, ugly as hell, or dumb as shit, and THESE are the reasons they can't get good jobs or rich dates. There are many other causes just like this, but this was the main one that needs to be taken care of immediately. I would also like to add that people who join allot of good causes so they can look like good people and/or to feel like better people should just kill themselves and give all their money to people who aren't stupid fucks.

1. Everyone has equal oppertunity, just in diffrent ways

2. Liars must stop prospering

3. Money/time can be spent in much better ways

4. SMAK dEM HOES!</description>
  <mission>Stop the spread of stupid bitches and he-bitches in the United States</mission>
  <name>The Prevention of Global Whining</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4274</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">50</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hM/Q2/EY/3I/zY/rl/HZ4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
