<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Tony La Russa's Animal Rescue Foundation (ARF) was created in 1991 by Tony and his wife Elaine, to address the needs of companion animals. Their vision for ARF is an organization that can not only aid abandoned and homeless animals, but also promote the concept that people's lives can be enhanced by strengthening the bonds between humans and animals. With these intertwined goals as the guiding principles, and an intention to become a national as well as local leader, ARF has designed progressive programs for many populations including abused children, the elderly, victims of violence and others who can benefit from the healing contact of animals.

ARF is growing to meet the demands of the 21st century with the first private Adoption and Education Center in Contra Costa County. ARF will continue to respond to the immediate needs of animals who have been neglected, abused or deprived of love to ensure they find high quality homes. At the same time, ARF will embody the vision of a better future-one where animals are respected for the unique role they can and do play in making the world a better place for people to live and where there is a stable and loving home for every pet to complete its natural lifespan.

1. A pet is a lifetime commitment; companion animals need stable and loving homes.

2. As living dependent beings, companion animals should get our utmost consideration when we make decisions that impact their existence or quality of lif

3. Companion animals help strengthen families and make better people - thus forging better communities and making the world a better place to live.

4. All people, including those whose life circumstances make it difficult to have or take care of companion animals (elderly, ill, abused), benefit from </description>
  <mission>save dogs and cats who have run out of time at public shelters and bring people and animals together to enrich each others' lives.</mission>
  <name>ARF: Tony La Russa's Animal Rescue Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4290</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1193</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">290.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Wi/ZQ/8p/I3/t4/5B/Eg/c3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
