<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The definition of neglect from dictonaries.com 

1.	to pay no attention or too little attention to; disregard or slight: The public neglected his genius for many years.
2.	to be remiss in the care or treatment of: to neglect one's family; to neglect one's appearance.
3.	to omit, through indifference or carelessness: to neglect to reply to an invitation.
4.	to fail to carry out or perform (orders, duties, etc.): to neglect the household chores.
5.	to fail to take or use: to neglect no precaution.

from pet-abuse.com

The most common type of animal cruelty is neglect or abandonment - that is, people not providing adequate care for animals in their charge. These types of cases often involve situations where an animal is left without food, water or shelter, or when proper veterinary care was not obtained. In many of these cases, the underlying reason can sometimes be explained by the caretaker&#8217;s ignorance. This is why many animal control officers and humane law enforcement officers will first attempt to educate the neglectful caretaker, rather than immediately citing them or arresting them.

While ignorance can be blamed in some of these situations, an additional cause that seems to be a major contributor to neglect and abandonment cases is that the pet owner simply does not care. Even people with only the most basic knowledge of animal care can see that an animal has degenerated to the point where it is only skin and bones.

Many times, animals are purchased as pets, and simply forgotten about. Animals in this situation however do not merely gather dust. They are slowly starved or dehydrated to death, literally bled dry due to parasite infestations, or slowly garroted by their own collars.

1. To educate people about animal neglect</description>
  <mission>To end neglect to animals, no matter how small or insignificant it may seem</mission>
  <name>An End to Animal Neglect</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4292</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">88981</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1870.23</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/a5/1I/Le/Lc/i5/q1/2WwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
