<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Sea Shepherd Conservation Society was formally incorporated in the United States in 1981 in the state of Oregon. Previous to this, the idea of Sea Shepherd was formed when Captain Paul Watson founded the Earth Force Society in 1977 in Vancouver BC, Canada. The original mandate of both organizations was marine mammal protection and conservation with an immediate goal of shutting down illegal whaling and sealing operations, but Sea Shepherd later expanded its mission to include all marine wildlife.

With financial support from Cleveland Amory of the Fund for Animals, the society's first ship a North Atlantic sea trawler "the Westella" was purchased in Hull, England (UK) and renamed the Sea Shepherd.  It's first mission was to the ice floes of eastern Canada to interfere with the annual killing of baby harp seals known as whitecoats.

In the same year, 1979, the Sea Shepherd hunted down and rammed the notorious pirate whaler the Sierra in a Portugal harbor ending its infamous career as the scourge of the seas.

The success of the seal campaign and the ramming of the Sierra was the start of Sea Shepherd's historical 160 voyages over the next 2 decades, enforcing international laws where no law enforcement existed - on the high seas.

Sea Shepherd continues to accomplish its mission by upholding and enforcing international treaties, laws and conventions of world governments.

Sea Shepherd is committed to the eradication of pirate whaling, poaching, shark finning, unlawful habitat destruction, and violations of established laws in the World's oceans.

To that end, Sea Shepherd assists national and international bodies in the enforcement of international law under authority of the United Nations World Charter for Nature.



1. expose illegal tactics on the high seas

2. ensure survival for future generations</description>
  <mission>end the destruction of habitat and slaughter of wildlife in the world&#8217;s oceans in order to conserve and protect ecosystems and species. </mission>
  <name>Sea Shepherd Conservation Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4306</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6684</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">4312.81</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Be/hy/Ve/xW/tO/w5/IA/TsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
