<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Wounded veterans of the War on Terror must struggle every day to overcome life-changing sacrifices such as the loss of a limb, significant burns, and the reality of being in a wheelchair. The mission of The Coalition to Salute America's Heroes is to help the people who have given so much on our behalf overcome these obstacles and resume a productive and fulfilling life through programs targeted to their specific needs.

Join us in helping severly wounded and disabled War on Terror veterans rebuild their shattered lives.  They were there for you, now you need to be there for them. Visit our website &lt;a href="http://www.saluteheroes.org/"
target="_blank"&gt;Coalition to Salute America's Heroes&lt;/a&gt; to learn how you can help.

1. Emergency Financial Aid - Many wounded and disabled veterans face short-term financial problems and the Coalition helps pay for basic needs (i.e. rent, utility bills, car payments, etc.)

2. Career Network - Employment programs such as career counseling and job shadowing. An office at Walter Reed Army Medical Center offers full transition employment assistance for those service-members leaving Walter Reed.

3. Homes for Heroes - provide support for new disability-adapted home or home repair/modifications.

4. Road to Recovery Conferences - Events for wounded heroes and families that provide educational seminars, entertainment, relaxation and tribute.</description>
  <mission>A way for individuals, corporations and others to help our severely wounded and disabled Operation Enduring Freedom and Operation Iraqi Freedom veterans and their families rebuild their lives. </mission>
  <name>Coalition to Salute America's Heroes</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4314</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">600</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">195.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Sm/3W/Jq/Rw/PP/F4/7vVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
