<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The primaries for both parties for the 2008 presidential election are well underway.  Both parties are filled with charismatic, powerful, sharp candidates.  However, for many conservatives, there is no where to turn.  The Republican party is filled with individuals with very liberal backgrounds, or globalist policies.  

All of the current 'top-tier' candidates have supporter globalist policies including so called free trade agreements that are cheating us out of billions of dollars, such as NAFTA, CAFTA, and Most Favored Nation Trade status with Communist China.  Where are conservatives who believe in the strength and freedom of this country left to turn?

All of the current top tier candidates have taken moderate positions on abortion.  There is no top-tier candidate (including MIke Huckabee) who supports a constitutional ban on abortion, they all feel that it should be left up to individual states.  They believe that state's rights are more 
important than the rights of human beings. 



Duncan Hunter is a U.S. representative from Southern California and is a candidate for the 2008 election.  He has been vocally fighting against the president's amnesty plan, even using up campaign time, and working to protect our borders.  He worked to build a border fence in his district that cut illegal immigration by 90% and he promises to build a fence for this country with in 6 months in office if elected. 

Duncan Hunter has a consistent and strong conservative record unlike the other candidates (yes, even Fred Thompson).  He has free-market solutions to democrat problems (and would pull in many Reagan Democrats), he sees our country's problems with Iran, North Korea, and China, and will work towards a strong national defense.  

He has perfect ratings from every key conservative grassroot organization including the NRA, the Eagle Forum, Concerned Women for America, the National Right to Life, etc.  He has worked to pass a bill he wrote to define life at conception, which would force the 14th amendment to apply to saving unborn children.  

In a party full of wanna-be's and posers, Duncan Hunter is the real Reagan Candidate in a time that desperately needs one.   


www.ontheissues.org

www.gohunter08.com

www.dhgrassrevolt.wordpress.com

1. Duncan Hunter is the right man for the job. </description>
  <mission>Support the candidacy of Duncan Hunter</mission>
  <name>Liberty and Freedom 2008: Duncan Hunter for President</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4324</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">38</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mO/g8/jJ/JK/Vm/DK/pp6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
