<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Africa, a continent endowed with immense natural and human resources as well as great cultural, ecological and economic diversity, remains underdeveloped. Most African nations suffer from military dictatorships, corruption, civil unrest and war, underdevelopment and deep poverty. The majority of the countries classified by the UN as least developed are in Africa. Numerous development strategies have failed to yield the expected results. Although some believe that the continent is doomed to perpetual poverty and economic slavery, Africa has immense potential. 

HIV/AIDS and extreme poverty are the two most important issues of our lifetime, and if we lose this perspective then they will only continue to become worse. We must not allow the dialogue for eliminating HIV/AIDS and extreme poverty to burn out like a neglected fire. We must engage in the dialogue and retain our global perspective. 

The current HIV/AIDS epidemic has inflicted the most devastating medical impact of the past 600 years, and the disease of poverty continues to present the greatest barrier to good health.

Perhaps you&#8217;ve seen news reports about the humanitarian crisis in African countries. Maybe you saw a Red Cross ad on TV urgently asking for your help. However you&#8217;ve learned of the need, your help can&#8217;t wait in many African countries where some many organizations are working to save and improve lives. Please help, donate something. Impossible is nothing in Africa.

Together, we can give the African people the tools they need to beat extreme poverty and the chance for a hopeful future.

Save African Children
Your help is critical because the children of Africa - now more than ever! --- are in need of health care, education, food, shelter and care and support. The AIDS pandemic is an unprecedented challenge - but with your support, they can meet all basic needs, also you can bring hope, opportunity and save their lives! Help with your donation to this humanitarian organization.


1. Save African Children from HIV/AIDS 

2. Save African people from extreme poverty</description>
  <mission>Eliminating HIV/AIDS and extreme poverty in Africa</mission>
  <name>Save African Children from HIV/AIDS and Extreme Poverty</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4326</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">659</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">60.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Hs/eS/0M/wA/FG/FC/OYJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
