<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"My view is that the United States' special relationship with Israel obligates us to be helpful to them in the search for credible partners with whom they can make peace, while also supporting Israel in defending itself against enemies sworn to its destruction" President Obama

"American and Israel share a special bond. Our relationship is unique among all nations. Like America, Israel is a strong democracy, a symbol of freedom, and an oasis of liberty, a home to the oppressed and persecuted." President Bill Clinton 

"Israel was not created in order to disappear - Israel will endure and flourish. It is the child of hope and the home of the brave. It can neither be broken by adversity nor demoralized by success. It carries the shield of democracy and it honors the sword of freedom." President John F. Kennedy 

"I see Israel, and never mind saying it, as one of the great outposts of democracy in the world, and a marvelous example of what can be done, how desert land can be transformed into an oasis of brotherhood and democracy.  Peace for Israel means security and that security must be a reality."  Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.

"The government of Israel will do all that is required to assist in the struggle against terror, out of deep friendship, kinship and support for the American people." Prime Minister Ariel Sharon 

"The United States-Israeli relationship is based on the broadest conception of American national interest in which our two nations are bound forever together by common democratic values and traditions. This will never change." Colin Powell

</description>
  <mission>To support to the US-Israel Relationship </mission>
  <name>America Stands with Israel </name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/433</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">14558</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">483.59</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DuS/eXBS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
