<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Since the UN&#8217;s declaration in 1990 that universal basic education is a fundamental human right, the international community has asked an open-ended question &#8211; how can the private sector use market forces to improve international education, especially for women? This year, University of Arkansas students responded by developing and implementing a new and innovative microfinance for education investment model which provides female students and their families with loans to pay for tuition, books, uniforms and school supplies.

The need for a female specific education program is critical in the developing world and microfinance&#8217;s success at promoting small business development, particularly for female entrepreneurs, provides a model that can be adapted to promote female education and health knowledge. In Belize, only 43 percent of primary school students enter secondary school and more than half of these students drop out before completing their degree. A lack of adequate financial resources, such as the ability to borrow is a critical factor that explains why so many students are abandoning their education. Consequently, within every generation of Belizean students, nearly 75 percent are not obtaining their full level of basic human capital. A lack of education is especially damaging to women who are often undervalued and without job skills, health knowledge or a developed sense of self-confidence, which leaves women to fill passive social roles. Similar statistics prevail across the developing world and a successful microfinance for education project in Belize can become a prototype for future education initiatives in other areas of need. 

Although female students have benefited from economic growth and international education programs, many are caught in an education trap &#8211; their economic opportunities, health, and social voice in society are limited by low levels of human capital. Education traps affect both male and female students, but education opportunities are more limited for female students because of persisting inequality and a flawed belief that male education should be prioritized. 

A secondary education costs about $250 dollars each year, but a person with a high school diploma has a significantly higher earnings potential. Workers without a secondary education can expect to earn approximately $400 per month and job opportunities are limited. However, with a secondary degree, a person can expect to earn closer to $950 per month and have a higher job quality, stability and greater employment opportunities. This income difference significantly affects a family&#8217;s ability to sustainably escape poverty. 

Education&#8217;s impact becomes even greater when targeted towards female students and lending is more sustainable. Studies show that female students are better education credit candidates. They typically study harder and are more likely to stay in school. Further, by providing opportunities for women to attend school, microfinance investments can not only increase educational access and social equality, but female students positively impact the school&#8217;s learning environment. They raise the incentive for all students to learn by increasing inter-gender competition and cooperation in the classroom.  Similarly, education raises a nation&#8217;s quality of living not only through increased job skills, but by improving social and emotional capital such as efficient resource use, health knowledge and an awareness of property rights and democratic freedom &#8211; qualities which empower individuals and stabilize and improve a society&#8217;s infrastructure and quality of living. Women&#8217;s education is especially important because it ensures that knowledge of these concepts is passed to the next generation through maternal care. </description>
  <mission>Provide Financial Capital for Students' Education</mission>
  <name>Peacework Microfinance for Education Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4333</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">31</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oE/a8/hX/8n/Ym/kr/Mo/jZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
