<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Hoop Dreams Scholarship Fund (HDSF) was founded in 1996 by Susie Kay, who taught American Government at H.D. Woodson High School in Washington, DC for over a decade.  The organization began as a one-day event, a 3-on-3 charity basketball tournament staged to raise money for academic college scholarships for Kay's students.  Since then, still led by Susie Kay, a committed group of dedicated volunteers, supporters and a small staff has worked to grow the effort into a year-round not-for-profit organization committed to expanding the academic and career horizons of Washington, DC public school students.

Since our inception in 1996, The Hoop Dreams Scholarship Fund has helped send nearly 750 DC public high school students to college and move toward a more positive and enriched future with the combination of awarding of over 1,100 academic college scholarships and renewals, totaling approximately $2.5 million coupled with our year long college prep mentoring program, internship program and SAT prep partnership program with the Princeton Review. These programs and scholarships are combined with our community building efforts, which are all focused on empowering DC students and building bridges across diverse communities.   Hoop Dreams has brought together over 800 DC students and mentors from the local business community through our year long college prep mentoring program; facilitated hundreds of internships; engaged over 1,000 volunteers in community work; and helped coach nearly 400 students through our SAT prep program in partnership with The Princeton Review.  We are also very proud to note that many of our Hoop Dreams college graduates have returned to volunteer and mentor with the organization, completing the circle of community service. Over 125 of Hoop Dreams students have now graduated from college. Most of our students are the first in their family to go to college. Hoop Dreams remains deeply committed to uniting the community and building bridges while supporting our local students and their dreams.

HDSF works to create relationships, build networks and provide resources that:

Empower and support inner-city DC public high school students so they can find their best pathways to post-secondary education, career and an enriched life;
 
Build bridges of understanding and collaboration between diverse communities in the metropolitan Washington DC region; and
 
Promote an on-going commitment to community responsibility and a lasting spirit of service among students, volunteers supporters, and all involved.

Hoop Dreams aims to provide inner-city youth from Washington DC&#65533;s most disenfranchised neighborhoods with opportunities to develop skills, access resources and forge connections that will support their healthy development, academic achievement and life success. In the past year alone, Hoop Dreams has provided $250,000 in scholarships to 160 DC public high school graduates; we placed 33 high school seniors in paid internships; 85 inner city youth and nearly 100 adults participated in Hoop Dreams' intensive college prep mentoring program; and helped 65 high school seniors increase their SAT scores through The Princeton Review prep courses offered free of charge through Hoop Dreams.  

www.hoopdreams.org 

1. Mentoring

2. Scholarships

3. Career Preparation</description>
  <mission>Providing low-income children with a college education. </mission>
  <name>Hoop Dreams Scholarship Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4339</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">332</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">160.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mw/s0/M4/vu/4d/m0/3P/rGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
