<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Right to Dream is a charity registered in the UK, Ghana and the US with the objective of helping talented underprivileged African children play sport, obtain a first class education and develop key lifeskills to help them to achieve a better quality of life.

Right to Dream recognises the importance of sport and education in transforming young lives and our work uses this medium to empower young children who are drawn from a background of extreme poverty,  to achieve their true potential in life. 
  
Africa is full of many of the most passionate young athletes. For decades these young sportsmen and women have risen against colossal odds to win Olympic medals, become champions and play for some of the world&#8217;s greatest teams. They have also become a true source of inspiration and motivation to millions of Africans, proving that it is possible to rise in the face of extreme adversity and achieve one's true potential.  
 
However, despite the amazing achievements from the likes of George Weah, Abedi Pele, Haile Gebrselassie and Maria Matola, it has not become any easier for the next generation to realise their sporting potential. Poverty and disease crush the dreams of thousands of young athletes in Africa every year before they have the chance to prove themselves. Those who do go beyond these initial hurdles still have to face the major problems of bad facilities, poor coaching and very limited sponsorship - before they even enter the stadium.

Right to Dream overcomes these problems and offers Africa&#8217;s talented and passionate children the opportunity to fulfill their true potential in life through both sport and education.

1. Position #1</description>
  <mission>offer children from a background of extreme poverty the opportunity to fulfill their true potential in life through sport and education.</mission>
  <name>Right to Dream</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4344</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/b0/oF/AE/Nt/DU/eF/4LjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
