<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The National Alliance for Thrombosis and Thrombophilia (NATT) is a nationwide, community-based, volunteer health organization formed in August 2003. It is committed to preventing and treating the array of major health problems caused by blood clots, NATT's charter members were visionary patients attending a thrombosis and thrombophilia awareness meeting at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Today, NATT's membership and influence is growing. With the goal to ensure that people suffering from thrombosis and thrombophilia get early diagnosis, optimal treatment, and quality support; NATT members are committed to fostering research, education, support, and advocacy on behalf of those at risk of, or affected by, blood clots.

TO DONATE:

You can now donate ONLINE DONATIONS- THROUGH THE WEBSITE!!!

OR YOU CAN....

You can go to NATTINFO.org fill out the forms and mail them to:

The National Alliance for Thrombosis and Thrombophilia
Attn. Kathy Earley, Treasurer
P.O. Box 66018
Washington DC 20035-6018 

TO JOIN US!!

NATT is quickly being recognized as the premier community-based organization dedicated to prevention and treatment issues in thrombosis and thrombophilia in the United States .

Join us! We need your energy and your financial support to help our family, friends and neighbors fight the debilitating diseases caused by blood clots. Please get involved by contacting:

Tom Hogan, Secretary
(860) 376-3250
nattinfo@yahoo.com

However, the bad news is that only 50% of those with DVT have symptoms, making this &#8220;Silent Killer&#8221; extremely difficult to diagnose. This is compounded by the fact that 74% of Americans have no knowledge about DVT, its symptoms or risk factors. 

This is why raising awareness is critical. The National Alliance for Thrombosis and Thrombophilia (NATT) is working to prevent, diagnose and treat thrombosis and thrombophilia through education, research, support and advocacy.  




1. More than 900,000 people in the United States are estimated to develop venous thromboembolisms - or clots in the veins - every year.

2. Almost 300,000 people die each year in the U.S. due to blood clots in the veins

3.  This number is greater than the number of people who die each year of AIDS, breast cancer, or automobile accidents.

4. By raising money we can support the research and awareness needed to prevent these disorders.

5. I am a THROMBOPHILIC as well as others all over the world, help support me and the world!</description>
  <mission>Raise Money for the awareness and research of Blood Clots</mission>
  <name>National Alliance for Thrombosis and Thrombophilia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4347</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">650</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Md/Al/VC/Hn/ey/2r/CTWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
