<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>-Nearly 98% of all kidney transplants, 90% of liver transplants, and 85% of heart transplants are successful; 
-More than 1,800 organ transplants were performed in Canadian hospitals in 2000; 
-Donor families say they are comforted by the feeling that their loved one's death was not in vain. 

Did you know that?

-Anyone at any age can become an organ and tissue donor. The oldest organ donor on record was over 90 years of age and the oldest corneal donor was 102 years old. 

Retrieved from http://www.hc-sc.gc.ca/ahc-asc/media/nr-cp/2001/2001_36bk1_e.html

-Only patients who have suffered brain death in hospital can become organ donors because vital organs must be maintained artificially by a ventilator so they can be transplanted. However, only those whose hearts have stopped and cannot, therefore, be artificially supported by a ventilator (the heart and lungs have stopped working), can become tissue donors. 

-Most religions support organ donation as an act of kindness. 

-Organ donation does not preclude an open-casket funeral. When clothed, the body shows no outward sign of surgery. 

-Transplants can save health care costs: the cost of a kidney transplant averages $20,000 plus $6,000 per year thereafter ($50,000 over five years). Maintaining a kidney patient on dialysis costs $50,000 per year ($250,000 over five years). 


http://organdonations.ca/

1. Start by making your decision known, either by signing an organ and tissue donor card or by registering your consent through your provincial registry.

2. More than 3,700 Canadians are awaiting organ transplants for kidneys, hearts, lungs, or livers, and thousands of others are in need of replacements for tissues such as corneas, heart valves, bone grafts, and skin.</description>
  <mission>Create Awareness about organ donation</mission>
  <name>Organ Donation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4362</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">44675</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">776.48</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sA/Cp/Zd/w2/od/eo/phmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
