<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>*************************************
North America's Premier Cinemaquatic Event!
*************************************

SFOFF is the premier venue in North America for ocean films and media and celebrates its 6th anniversary in 2009. For the past five years, we have produced an acclaimed festival of ocean-themed films from all over the world that are largely unavailable to the general public. Themes range from marine science and industry to wildlife, environment, coastal cultures, sports and adventure. SFOFF's programs are intended not only to entertain the audience but, more importantly, to educate and encourage active participation in ocean conservation.

*********************************************
WAYS YOU CAN SUPPORT THE FESTIVAL:
*********************************************

~ Invite your friends to join this Cause! Use the 'Invite' link on the top right of this page.

~ Sign up for our newsletter at http://oceanfilmfest.org for the latest event updates.

~ Make a donation to our Cause through the link at the top of this page and support our vital oceanic mission.

~ Volunteer at the festival and help foster new ocean stewards: volunteer@oceanfilmfest.org

~ Join our social networks!
http://www.facebook.com/pages/San-Francisco-Ocean-Film-Festival/6590266164
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=17886709560 
http://www.myspace.com/oceanfilmfest 
http://www.youtube.com/oceanfilmfestival 
http://www.flickr.com/groups/oceanfilmfest08/ 
http://www.socializr.com/user/oceanfilmfest 
http://www.change.org/oceanfilmfest


More Info:
http://oceanfilmfest.org

Online Store:
http://zazzle.com/oceanfilmfest*


1. To preserve ocean biodiversity, and become better ocean stewards.

2. To support emerging and established filmmakers who celebrate the sea with inspirational films that increase our appreciation of the oceans that surrou

3. To provide free events where students can view inspirational and informative ocean films and interact with filmmakers and marine scientists.</description>
  <mission>To use film to improve public understanding of the environmental, social, and cultural importance of marine ecosystems and to increase active participation in ocean conservation.</mission>
  <name>San Francisco Ocean Film Festival</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4363</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">52</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nP/uQ/zD/oR/bA/JL/hz/wAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
