<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The U.S. Public Service Academy will be America&#8217;s first national civilian university, a flagship institution designed to build a &#8220;more perfect union&#8221; by developing leaders of character dedicated to service in the public sector.

Modeled on the military service academies, the Public Service Academy will provide a rigorous undergraduate education followed by five years of civilian service to the country. It will develop young leaders with the character, intellect, and experience necessary to meet the challenges of the twenty-first century.

The Academy is dedicated to creating a corps of passionate and patriotic civilian leaders willing to devote themselves to the pursuit of academic excellence, civic engagement, and leadership through public service. The Academy seeks to develop students who pursue the highest ideals of human character and the American values of freedom, democracy, and equal opportunity; strive for individual excellence yet feel a personal responsibility to achieve the common good; and appreciate their rights and uphold their responsibilities as citizens of the United States. As an academic institution, the Academy is committed to free and open inquiry, free expression of ideas, and the pursuit of truth. As a public institution, the Academy strives to connect the classroom and community through a consistent commitment not only to creating knowledge but also to sharing and applying that knowledge to serve the American public and world at large. As a national institution, the Academy endeavors to build a corps of civilian leaders willing and able to confront the challenges that face this country in the future.

1. The United States should offer a tuition-free civilian leadership academy, not just tuition-free military academies.

2. Recent events have inspired a younger generation and imbued many young people with a sense of civic engagement not seen in decades. Unfortunately, many of these students are priced out of public service careers because they rack up so much debt while in s

3. We face a critical and growing shortage of public servants &#8211; as baby boomers retire, we will need more teachers, more cops, more air traffic controllers, more everything.</description>
  <mission>build a corps of civilian leaders who have the moral character, academic training, and leadership experience necessary to serve the American people honorably and effectively.</mission>
  <name>US Public Service Academy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4365</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">559</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">300.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Dt/QJ/HS/2z/Rt/Ww/8ToS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
