<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Heirloom seeds : seed collected and passed down to the next generation within a family for several generations.
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heirloom_seed
Hybrid seeds: hybrid seed is seed produced by artificially cross-pollinated plants. 

On the merge of Y2K I was in the US and in researching survival ways I came to a plan of supporting my own food, this led me to seed saver&#8217;s exchange (SSE), and growing my own plants and harvesting their seeds to grow them again. 

Discoveries:
1-hybrid seed plants cannot be grown from seeds harvested from them
2-same for genetically modified (GM) seeds
3-Number of varieties of vegetable seeds available in most garden shops are very limited

SSE:
Established in 1975 &amp; considered the leader who led to the heirloom movement in the USA, adding more varieties of seeds to the seed market. In the year 2000 SSE was able to launch a website where non-members can purchase seeds from them
Danger of lack of variety and use of GM seeds:
1972 corn epidemic that hit the USA and destroyed 15% of the crop at total, in some areas it was a s high as 50% death http://www.theecologist.org/archive_detail.asp?content_id=231

Are hybrids and (GM) seeds really good for the farmer ( a good debate)??
-they are more resistant to certain diseases---they might kill wild life (bt-corn vs butterfly google it and see)
- they produce higher yeiled&#8212;yetthe farmer is forced to always depend on several houses or companies that produce GM seeds or Hybrids since he cannot grow them again from seeds like farmers used to do

I call for us humans to be sensible enough to support the keeping of all varieties we have by supporting a cause of keeping seed varieties alive by supporting and going this cause to support SSE, and if there are enough people who will only buy these varieties of food then the mass agriculture will notice and a trend like the one seed savers exchange started might just begin in the agricultural industry.

1. Support Seed Saver's Exchange

2. Make people understand the benifit of saving seeds

3. Shedding a light on Heirloom vs Hybrid vs genitically modified seeds

4. Shedding a light on the potential Danger of only having hybrid or genitically modified seeds in our lives</description>
  <mission>support the heirloom movement of seeds and the genetic diversity of Plants.</mission>
  <name>Keep seed varieties alive</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4378</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">644</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">18.14</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/A1/7l/7U/RD/4I/mq/2PhS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
