<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our mission is to stop the worst politician from becoming President.  Not only is he making millions from doing his job but he is only recognized because of 9/11 a spotlight he had been searching for his whole life and will still not relinquish.  But, we forget that because he could not get police and firefighters to talk he cause many of them to die.  He will be the reason why hundreds will be getting cancer from the improper clean-up he handled.  We saw him try to break his mayoral limits and powers and would only break so many executive office powers that Bush will look soft.  He was a horrible assistant attorney general, there is no way we can let U.S Attorneys serve to Giuliani's pleasure.  He micro-managed too many of his city agencies and tried to make his image look better by bludgeoning these agencies and even those not under his control, the MTA and board of education.  All to no avail as he was not productive and only blossomed his arrogant bravado.  He claimed to do great for transportation, housing and safety improvements, but most credit belongs wholly to predecessors&#8217; decisions and to economic good luck: As he left office the New York Times noted that on his first day as mayor in 1994, the Dow Jones had stood at 3754.09, while on his last day, Dec. 31, 2001, it opened at 10,136.99.  "What really drove many of his actions as mayor was a zealot&#8217;s graceless division of everyone into friend or foe and his snarling, sometimes histrionic, vilifications of the foes. Those are operatic emotions, beneath the civic dignity of a great city and its chief magistrate." -Jim Sleeper
Rudy Giuliani is not a strong leader and should not be a President.
http://www.thelibertypapers.org/2007/06/12/rudy-giulianis-meaningless-and-anti-liberty-12-commitments/

1. To prevent Giuliani from becoming President

2. To get the knowledge out there that makes Giuliani the wrong choice

3. Get a Democrat into the office!</description>
  <mission>To prevent Rudy Giuliani from being President</mission>
  <name>Stop Rudy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4393</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vf/6y/KU/jG/h7/wn/1LMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
