<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Many people think that battered women have black eyes and broken bones. However, domestic abuse encompasses a whole range of ways of controlling and hurting.Physical abuse includes pushing, shoving, slapping, hitting with fist, kicking, choking, grabbing, pinching, pulling hair, or threatening with weapons.  

Abused women: 
They reflect feelings of guilt, depression, isolation, embarrassment, humiliation and worthlessness. They convey helplessness, sadness and anger through different ways that trigger intense emotional distance resulting from the abuse.  Moreover, they try to prove that life is under control, yet face life with self esteem issues and feelings of being powerless and helpless. 
They dont know when to give up and walk away, and
take responsibility for anything and everything. They may sound strong-minded, but their wants, needs and reasons never carry the same weight for their as those of her partner.
They believe they're entitled to far less from life than other people. 

Male abusers: 
Most have been abused or neglected during their childhood, or have witnessed violence in their homes while growing up. 
At least 70% of the men who batter were either battered as children or saw violence occur regularly in their homes. They minimize and deny to themselves about the violence; they project blame onto the victim; it is painful if and when they fully realize what they've done.Batterers tend to be excessively dependent on the victim. They personalize often-they see everything (both good and bad) in their lives, as causing the events in their lives, i.e.; "if she didn't irritate him, he wouldn't have to hit her". Men who beat have a need to control; they define it as being in control of others--but are not in control of themselves. The control issue usually escalates in the relationship. They view themselves as emotionally isolated, They may have a history of abuse in their own family and may have been abusive in courtship

1. You dont have to be married or living together to suffer from domestic abuse

2. Taking the first step to face the abuse is healthier than avoiding it, so contact your local police and they will guide you 

3. Men and Women need to be aware of ways to treat the aftermath of the abuse or how to avoid it all together.

4. Domestic Assault and Battery is an issue that everybody should be aware of

5. Supporters of this group should try their best to educate the ignorant by injecting knowledge into their surrounding environment

6. There is no excuse for any violent behavior! No matter the situation .. EVER</description>
  <mission>to help people distinguish and become aware of the signs of abuse, and to assist the abused in overcoming this heinous and atrocious crime.</mission>
  <name>Awareness is Bliss! Fight against Domestic Assault and Battery</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4425</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">683</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fJ/gJ/BP/Yw/Rd/Bk/sEVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
