<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Most Congressmen are lawyers, and many others are businessmen. They know what &#8220;fiduciary responsibility&#8221; is. For members of Congress, it means reading each word of every bill before they vote.

But Congress has not met this duty for a long time. Instead

- They carelessly pass mammoth bills that none of them have read. Sometimes printed copies aren&#8217;t even available when they vote!

- Often no one knows what these bills contain, or what they really do, or what they will really cost.

- Additions and deletions are made at the last minute, in secrecy.

- They combine unpopular proposals with popular measures that few in Congress want to oppose. (This practice is called &#8220;log-rolling.&#8221;)

- And votes are held with little debate or public notice.

- Oh, and once these bills are passed, and one of these unpopular proposals comes to light, they pretend to be shocked. &#8220;How did that get in there?&#8221; they say.

There&#8217;s a basic principle at stake here. America was founded on the slogan, &#8220;No taxation without representation.&#8221; A similar slogan applies to this situation: &#8220;No LEGISLATION without representation.&#8221;

We hold this truth to be self-evident, that those in Congress who vote on legislation they have not read, have not represented their constituents. They have misrepresented them.

And since Congress has repeatedly committed &#8220;legislation without representation,&#8221; strong measures to prohibit these Congressional misrepresentations are both justified and required.

To this end we have created the &#8220;Read the Bills Act (RTBA).&#8221; The requirements of the RTBA are listed below in the Positions section of this cause.

To read the bill itself, please click here:
http://www.downsizedc.org/rtba_legislation.shtml

To contact your representatives in Congress and urge them to sponsor and vote for the RTBA, click here:
http://action.downsizedc.org/wyc.php?cid=27

For more information on this bill, click here:
http://www.downsizedc.org/read_the_laws.shtml

1. Each bill, and every amendment, must be read in its entirety before a quorum in both the House and Senate

2. Every member of the House and Senate must sign a sworn affidavit, under penalty of perjury, that he or she has attentively either personally read, or heard read, the complete bill to be voted on

3. Every old law coming up for renewal under the sunset provisions must also be read according to the same rules that apply to new bills

4. Every bill to be voted on must be published on the Internet at least 7 days before a vote, and Congress must give public notice of the date when a vote will be held on that bill

5. Passage of a bill that does not abide by these provisions will render the measure null and void, and establish grounds for the law to be challenged in court

6. Congress cannot waive these requirements</description>
  <mission>We believe the federal government has grown too large, too intrusive, and too expensive. We believe in constitutional limits, small government, civil liberties, federalism, and low taxes.</mission>
  <name>Read the Bills Act: Make Congress Read the Bills Before Voting for Them</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4429</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7389</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">68.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/TY/qy/jI/HL/q7/HA/t5XS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
