<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Rotary Foundation is working to achieve world peace and understanding through local, national, and international humanitarian, educational, and cultural programs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Rotary Foundation's Humanitarian Programs fund international Rotary club and district projects to improve the quality of life, providing health care, clean water, food, education, and other essential needs primarily in the developing world. One of the major Humanitarian Programs is PolioPlus, which seeks to eradicate the poliovirus worldwide.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 

Through its Educational Programs, the Foundation provides funding for some 1,200 students to study abroad each year. Grants are also awarded to university teachers to teach in developing countries and for exchanges of business and professional people. In addition, Rotary's Educational Programs include two specific to fostering peace:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 

- The Rotary Peace and Conflict Studies Program was established to provide professionals from around the world the opportunity to be trained in conflict resolution and mediation strategies and to become better equipped to help prevent and resolve conflict, as well as foster policies and create settings that ensure peace, worldwide. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

- The Rotary Centers for International Studies in peace and conflict resolution program train "Rotary World Peace Fellows". They will be a part of tomorrow&#8217;s solution in promoting greater tolerance and cooperation among people worldwide. Rotary World Peace Fellows, who are chosen from a wide variety of countries, can help future leaders advance knowledge and understanding.

1. While there is poverty in this world there will never be peace

2. Peace is possible!

3. Basic human rights should be available to all</description>
  <mission>advance world understanding, goodwill and peace through the improvement of health, the support of education and the alleviation of poverty.</mission>
  <name>The Rotary Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4435</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7423</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1886.7</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/r3/d7/kU/ZX/va/Vg/Rc6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
