<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Center originated in September 1987, after a Police Social Worker identified a need in the community.  It was recognized that there was an increasing number of sexual assault victims coming forward, and that they had to travel 30 miles to the nearest rape crisis center for services. Representatives from several social service groups held the organizational meeting to form an agency that would provide services to victims of sexual assault/abuse throughout Kankakee County.  In November 1987, the Center became an independent, non-profit organization and incorporated under the name Kankakee County Center Against Sexual Assault (KC-CASA), changing the name to better reflect the population served.  Services were then expanded to include counseling, advocacy, public education and professional training.  In 1988, KC-CASA became a member of the Illinois Coalition Against Sexual Assault and became one of 33 rape crisis centers in the State of Illinois to provide comprehensive services to sexual assault/abuse victims.  In 1991, KC-CASA initiated a Children&#8217;s Services Program to address the significant increase in sexual assault/abuse cases involving children.  In 1993, KC-CASA developed an organized program to provide public education to churches, schools, and community groups to increase public awareness and knowledge about sexual violence issues.  In 1994, the community education program expanded to a full time program, to include prevention education for children pre-school through college.  In 1995, the advocacy program was expanded, specifically focusing on victim sensitivity in the medical system.  In 2002, KC-CASA celebrated its 15th anniversary.  We re-established our identity as The Center Against Sexual Assault, and began using &#8220;The Center&#8221; as the shortened version.  New initiatives were implemented and new partnerships were established to expand awareness and provide services to more people.

1. Known victims and their families.

2. KC-CASA helps immensely and needs our support!</description>
  <mission>To improve the quality of services for survivors of sexual assault/abuse, to assist in their recovery and to work towards the elimination of sexual violence.</mission>
  <name>KC-CASA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4447</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">162</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0a/Ws/MJ/Wy/ky/CW/ZoFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
