<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Some Facts:

"The single most prevailing factor responsible for the endangerment of species today is habitat loss and degradation. In fact, about 60 percent of species that the Committee on the Status of Endangered Wildlife in Canada (COSEWIC) identified as being at risk are affected by habitat problems. If a species cannot find suitable conditions in which to live, it simply will not survive." (1)

"Today, many species are exposed to environmental contaminants, probably the second most important factor (after habitat loss and degradation) that causes species endangerment. DDT, Fenitrothion (once sprayed on forests to control spruce budworm) and carbofuran (used to control grasshoppers) are several chemicals that do a great deal of damage to wildlife. In addition, many chemicals are discharged by industry into the air or water, or leach off forested or agricultural lands into water bodies and can be detrimental to a variety of organisms. Acid rain has done its share of damage.

Chemicals discharged into the environment can have indirect effects. Recent studies indicate that depletion of the ozone layer, caused by chemicals that are released into the atmosphere may be having serious detrimental effects on wildlife. For example, it is believed to be responsible for reducing the survival of amphibian eggs before they hatch." (2)

Ressources:

1. http://www.speciesatrisk.gc.ca/Q3_e.cfm
2. http://www.speciesatrisk.gc.ca/Q3_e.cfm

1. We need to be more educated about wildlife to prevent the extinction of such species.

2. We should reduce their contributions to the greenhouse effect by using other methods of transportation. Such pollutants are also harmful to animals.

3. We should eliminate the use of pesticides. </description>
  <mission>Save our Animals </mission>
  <name>Wildlife</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4465</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0V/wd/lj/mO/F2/hG/vbTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
