<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Breast Cancer 3-Day Walk is a 60-mile walk over the course of three days. Net proceeds benefit the Susan G. Komen Breast Cancer Foundation and the National Philanthropic Trust, funding important breast cancer research, education, screening, and treatment. 

This is my third year doing the walk, and my goal is to raise a minimum of $2,200. At the end of 2005, my life was affected by breast cancer when my mom was diagnosed. I know too many other individuals and families have been affected by this disease as well. This is why I walk this 60 mile journey with my Girls Gone Walking team members, my sister and mother. 

This event isn&#8217;t easy, but I promise you, I wouldn&#8217;t be doing it if I didn&#8217;t believe 100% that it was worth every muscle ache, weary night, and months of training to do it! I'm not asking you to walk 60 miles, but I am asking you to provide any financial support to the cause in order to FIND A CURE!

PLEASE DONATE AT MY PAGE: 
THINK PINK, CLICK THE LINK!
http://08.the3day.org/goto/karenmoss

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://secure3.convio.net/npt/site/Donation2?df_id=1207&amp;FR_ID=1187&amp;PROXY_ID=1155690&amp;PROXY_TYPE=20&amp;outreachid=oLwNaJPBOBRrv903fvPzgO8c7y6FPU6V"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="I'm walking 60 miles in the San Diego Breast Cancer 3-Day! Will you help me reach my goal?" title="I'm walking 60 miles in the San Diego Breast Cancer 3-Day! Will you help me reach my goal?" src="http://08.the3day.org/site/DynImg/OlxYC-CVD1DQdEkRef6nDJdU4bA04UaH.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

**Please go to THIS link and donate, that way the money will directly go towards reaching my goal of $3,000 for the 3-Day. Again, do not donate through facebook, click the link!**

1. No one should have to deal with the physical, mental, financial, etc burden of cancer

2. A cure IS possible, but only with the support of people you recognize the need to come together and donate

3. Spread the word to your friends- the walk is a great way to raise awareness of breast cancer</description>
  <mission>To save lives and end breast cancer forever by empowering people,ensuring quality care for all and energizing science to find the cures</mission>
  <name>THE 2008 SAN DIEGO Breast Cancer 3-Day</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4471</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">25</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eH/BK/vu/1G/LU/1s/w8/LpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
