<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Fibromyalgia is a chronic pain illness which causes mainly widespread pain, fatigue, and sleep problems.  Other symptoms vary depending on the person but include headaches, dizziness, restless leg syndrome, coordination problems, impaired concentration and memory, vision problems, anxiety, depression, and rashes.  

An estimated 5-7% of the US population suffers from Fibromyalgia.  It is mainly found in middle aged women but men and children are also affected.  The juvenile form is known as Primary Juvenile Fibromyalgia Syndrome.  There is no known cure and few proven treatments and the disease is considered to be life long.  A lack of education for many health care professionals has led to a common 5 year search for a correct diagnosis.  

The NFA is a non profit organization founded in 1997.  They support local support groups, provide newly diagnosed patients and their families with information, help educate health care professionals about the illness, publish a magazine three times a year with new information and patient stories, run the annual Fibromyalgia Awareness day on May 12th of every year which they founded, participate in lobbying for research funding, awareness, and patient protection, support research towards a cure, and are active in the media. 

more info: www.fmaware.org 

1. Health care professionals must be knowledgeable about Fibromyalgia and how to diagnose it

2. Public awareness must be spread in order to provide support for patients

3. Research needs more attention and funding</description>
  <mission>To spread awareness about Fibromyalgia and fund research towards the cure</mission>
  <name>Open doors for Fibromyalgia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/448</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">36726</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">170.06</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Vjw/QgbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
