<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Right To Play uses specially-designed sport and play programmes to improve health, build life skills, and foster peace for children and communities affected by war, poverty, disease. Working in both the humanitarian and development contexts, Right To Play has projects in more than 20 countries in Africa, Asia and the Middle East.

Right To Play is a global-scale implementer of Sport for Development and Peace programmes and takes an active role in driving research and policy development in this area and in supporting children&#8217;s rights.

Working with our partners, funders and the local communities, Right To Play tailors every programme to meet identified needs. Each programme has specific goals, impacts and outputs. To build each programme we draw upon our specially-designed sport and play-based resources, as well as the expertise of our programme development, research, monitoring and evaluation, policy and country office teams.

The principles of the Convention on the Rights of the Child underpin everything we do. We ensure that our programmes benefit the most marginalized children including girls, street children, former child combatants, refugees and children affected by HIV and AIDS.

Currently Right To Play works in: Azerbaijan, Benin, Chad, China, Ethiopia, Ghana, Indonesia, Jordan, Lebanon, Liberia, Mali, Mozambique, Pakistan, Palestinian Territories, Rwanda, Sierra Leone, Sri Lanka, Sudan, Tanzania, Thailand, Uganda, United Arab Emirates, and Zambia.

Right To Play is headquartered in Toronto, Canada and has fundraising offices in China, Norway, Netherlands, Switzerland, the UK, the US, U.A.E. and Canada.

To learn more about Right to Play, please visit www.righttoplay.com.

1. Basic Education and Child Development: Foster the healthy physical, cognitive, social and emotional development of children, and are a child-friendly way to teach important values and life skills. 

2. Health Promotion and Disease Prevention: Educate and mobilize communities around national health/disease priorities, including HIV/AIDS, malaria and immunization by providing knowledge and attitudes that contribute to sustainable behaviour change.

3. Conflict Resolution and Peace Education: Create tools for teaching conflict resolution and peace building skills. Regular activities also encourage and facilitate the normalization, rehabilitation and reintegration of children affected by war.

4. Community Development and Participation: Build local capacity by training community volunteers. These individuals become positive role models for children and learn leadership and job skills that lay the foundation for successful community development.</description>
  <mission>To improve the lives of children in the most disadvantaged areas of the world by using the power of sport and play for development, health and peace.</mission>
  <name>Right to Play</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4487</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4160</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1669.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6c/pA/rD/NY/TU/Tm/hBgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
