<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Myriad opportunities exist to join Team FIMRC. Whether you decide to initiate a chapter at your school, get involved with the national office in Philadelphia, or actually go to the clinic itself your participation is  critical to the overall success of FIMRC and the children we aid.

We are continually expanding our horizons and we welcome your interest and talents. To learn more about how you can assist us in completing our mission, please e-mail info@fimrc.org.

-----------

Through determination and the belief that all children deserve health, FIMRC declares itself as a major force in the delivery of healthcare worldwide &#8211; one clinic and one child at a time.

-----------

FIMRC is supported by its chapters, the numerous fundraisers it organizes, and the contributions of people like you. We require no minimum contribution and we are appreciative of any donation that you are able to make. Generally, all funds support one of our on-going projects, and we invite you to choose a project that you would like your donation to support. 

Please view our current projects here:
http://fimrc.org/projects.php

1. Fundraising for the construction of pediatric clinics in areas currently lacking a reliable source for healthcare.

2. Directly influence the health of children by encouraging and supporting individuals and groups who desire to travel to medically underserved areas of the world.

3. Encourage future health leaders to become involved in our purpose by recognizing their achievements.</description>
  <mission>To provide access to medical care for the millions of underprivileged and medically underserved children around the world.</mission>
  <name>FIMRC: Foundation for International Medical Relief of Children</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4492</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">351</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1624.04</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/FT/Mz/F3/rF/Nr/7l/Y8HS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
