<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hopscotch Network chapters across the US hold fundraisers and networking events to support our Current Drive's nonprofit organizaiton, and to build and further unite our network - having a great time making an even greater impact.

JOIN THE BOSTON HOPSCOTCH GROUP- http://www.facebook.com/s.php?init=q&amp;q=BOSTON+HOPSCOTCH&amp;ref=ts&amp;sid=d4ce71e7a00ef21ba49e2fd457b40fd1#/group.php?gid=38265800291

JOIN THE NYC HOPSCOTCH GROUP- http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=34043526710&amp;ref=ts

JOIN THE SAN FRAN HOPSCOTCH GROUP- http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2221166392&amp;ref=ts#/group.php?gid=2622455963

JOIN THE TAMPA HOPSCOTCH GROUP- http://www.facebook.com/s.php?init=q&amp;q=tampa&amp;ref=ts&amp;sid=c599c8a64243d9e1f6b964571bc8a523#/group.php?gid=5237484755



CURRENT DRIVE
We're excited to announce that all money raised this year will benefit KnowledgeBeat. KnowledgeBeat is dedicated to furthering education in rural areas of Africa with an initial focus on Zambia. Through programs that bring children and communities enhanced educational resources and opportunities, they are improving quality of life and laying a foundation for Africa&#8217;s future. More information can be found at: www.knowledgebeat.org.

Website: www.hopscotchnetwork.org

ABOUT HOPSCOTCH NETWORK
Hopscotch Network is a growing network of young professionals and students who want a fun and unique way to make an impact in their local communities. With a focus on improving the lives of underprivileged children, Hopscotch organizes social and volunteer events to build a national community of philanthropic young people, and raise capital or needy organizations who share our vision. 

OUR MISSION
Help underprivileged children by raising funds and offering needed services for partner non-profits committed to the advancement of underprivileged children 
Mobilize a powerful group of young adults who have the shared desire to support children 
Provide this group of young adults with a social outlet and network to form meaningful and lasting relationships 

MEANS TO AN END
Our chapters host networking and fundraising events across the US. These events raise funds to create an immediate and meaningful impact on the nonprofit we are partnering with on our current drive. We also seek to provide members access to a powerful group of young adults who are not only social, but are socially aware. 



1. All children should be offered the opportunity to thrive in a global society.

2. Younger generations must become more socially active and socially responsible.

3. Young adults can and should make a material impact on the world through benevolent nonprofit work.</description>
  <mission>Aid underprivileged children while creating an outlet for young adults to give charitably, improve the community through service, and promote social activism.</mission>
  <name>Hopscotch Network</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4495</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">303</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mU/zi/Jf/au/jx/gF/DKAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
