<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>According to the United Nations, a child is a person under the age of 18. Despite the fact that the government of Iran has signed International Covenants that forbid them to execute anyone who has allegedly committed an offence before the age of 18, they continue to do so. Amnesty International has documented 21 executions of child offenders in Iran since 1990. In many cases, these minors have been imprisoned until the age of 18 and then executed. Currently, there are at least 32 minors on death row in Iran. 

Stop Child Executions Campaign is created to raise awareness about this issue, and more importantly to put an end to one of the most heinous manifestations of the death penalty -- its use against children. It is only through pressure on the government of the Islamic Republic of Iran, both internally in Iran and internationally that we can make a difference. Over the years we have witnessed child offenders being saved and even released from prison through international pressure as seen in the cases of Nazanin Fatehi and Afsaneh Norouzi. 

In order not to have to save one life at a time, please sign the petition and join our campaign to STOP CHILD EXECUTIONS once and for all. 

http://www.petitiononline.com/sce/

FOR DONATIONS VISIT:

http://www.stopchildexecutions.com/donations.aspx

Please join our group for the latest news:

http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2258845188

1. A person who has allegedly committed an offence before the age of 18, should not be executed.</description>
  <mission>Is to raise awareness about this issue, and more importantly to put an end to one of the most heinous manifestations of the death penalty -- its use against children.</mission>
  <name>Stop Child Executions</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/451</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15620</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1209.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0NN/zoeS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
