<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The American system of government is founded on two counterbalancing principles: that the majority of the people governs, through democratically elected representatives; and that the power even of a democratic majority must be limited, to ensure individual rights.

Majority power is limited by the Constitution's Bill of Rights, which consists of the original ten amendments ratified in 1791, plus the three post-Civil War amendments (the 13th, 14th and 15th) and the 19th Amendment (women's suffrage), adopted in 1920.

For the past four years, some of the most powerful politicians in America have made it their mission to accumulate unchecked government power, relentlessly undermining civil liberties. In unprecedented ways, they are invading our privacy, undermining our Constitution and squelching dissent. All too frequently, they are shamelessly using the &#8220;war on terror&#8221; as cover for their assault.

If the rights of society's most vulnerable members are denied, everybody's rights are imperiled.

ACT NOW TO SAVE YOUR FREEDOM!

1. Save your First Amendment rights-freedom of speech, association and assembly. Freedom of the press, and freedom of religion supported by the strict separation of church and state.

2. Save your right to equal protection under the law - equal treatment regardless of race, sex, religion or national origin.

3. Save your right to due process - fair treatment by the government whenever the loss of your liberty or property is at stake.

4. Save your right to privacy - freedom from unwarranted government intrusion into your personal and private affairs.</description>
  <mission>Preserve all of the protections and guarantees provided by the US Constitution and the Amendments to it</mission>
  <name>Save Your Freedom!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/453</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">89</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zoC/mGxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
