<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The organization is committed to ensuring the presence of dance as a vital and growing art form reflecting the rich cultural diversity of the community. Through its programs, SADU serves choreographers, dancers, dance companies, dance schools, and audience members. Representatives of all forms of dance are encouraged to participate in the programs of the Dance Umbrella.

Our programming includes:
Dance at Radius - free monthly dance performances held on Fridays at the Radius building featuring local dance companies.

Julia L. Cauthorn Scholarship - SADU provides tuition assistance to six aspiring young dancers annually.  The scholarship is a competitive award, based on technical merit and financial need.

Dance Around the World - a free family-friendly presentation of dance showcasing the many cultures that make San Antonio a diverse community.

Dance Enterprise Workshops - dedicated to developing the business and administrative skills vital to the arts community.

Toolkits - Administrative tools for the dance community - The Publicity Toolkit provides information on the major media outlets serving the SA area, while the Production Toolkit provides information on the facilities for dance performances in SA.

Fiscal Sponsorship - SADU adopts charitable dance projects, if the projects are consistent with SADU's mission.  This sponsorship allows the project to receive nonprofit benefits, including reduced rate theatre rentals, tax exemption on qualifiying purchases and the ability to apply for grant support.

WIP (Works-in-Progress/Wednesdays-in-Performance) -
An innovative choreaography development program created to support the development of new works by dance artists and to establish dialogue between the dancer, choreographer and audience.




1. Dance in San Antonio is vital to the SA community.</description>
  <mission>promote, support and educate dance in San Antonio.</mission>
  <name>San Antonio Dance Umbrella</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4541</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">30</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/XP/xu/ab/Qf/0Y/fx/EtBS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
