<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Jewish Alliance for Justice and Peace (Brit Tzedek v'Shalom) calls for an end to the Israeli occupation of Palestinian lands, evacuation of Israeli settlements in occupied territories, and the establishment of a viable Palestinian state alongside the state of Israel based on the 1967 borders. The organization's mission is to provide a voice within the American Jewish community for the many people who support these positions and to lobby Congress and the White House.

1. The evacuation of Israeli settlements in the Occupied Territories.

2. The termination of terrorism and state-initiated violence against all individuals with special care being taken to avoid harming civilians. We seek to build a future in which both peoples use non-violent means to resolve social and political inequities.

3. A complete end to the Israeli military occupation of the territories occupied since 1967 in the West Bank, the Gaza Strip and East Jerusalem with border adjustments agreeable to both parties.

4. The establishment of a viable Palestinian state based on the pre-1967 borders alongside Israel with both states guaranteed the ability to maintain secure and recognized boundaries free from threats or acts of force.

5. The establishment and recognition of Jerusalem as the capital of both states. Such recognition must also insure unfettered access to all religious sites.

6. A just resolution of the Palestinian refugee problem that takes into account the needs and aspirations of both peoples.

7. The recognition that as Jews and U.S. citizens, we have a special responsibility to urge our government to pursue policies consistent with the requirements of a just peace for Israel and the Palestinian people.</description>
  <mission>Educate and mobilize American Jews in support of a negotiated two-state resolution of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.</mission>
  <name>Brit Tzedek v'Shalom</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4547</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">381</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1626.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/UM/L2/RA/da/3G/rH/YivS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
