<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our goals are to protect and restore the native biological diversity and watersheds of the American Southwest; educate and enlist citizens to support protection of the forests, rivers, deserts and grasslands of this arid region; advocate for the principles of conservation biology in plans to restore degraded ecosystems and watersheds; enforce and strengthen environmental laws; support communities in efforts to protect their land and to practice and promote sustainable use of natural resources.

Our Activism

Forest Guardians is leading the fight to protect and restore the forests, rivers, grasslands, wildlife and wilderness of the Southwest, Southern Rockies and Southern Great Plains. We believe that the diversity of wildlife, plants and ecosystems, and our untrammeled wild spaces, hold the key to the rehabilitation of our impoverished region Our economic and cultural success are inextricably tied to a healthy land.

Forest Guardians celebrated 15 years of defending wildness on September 30th, 2004. We&#8217;re looking forward to many more years of successes and challenges at the vanguard of the environmental movement&#8212;redefining the public debate about wildlands conservation and preservation. Read about our success..

Our vision is strong. Our staff is the catalyzing agent&#8212; building the political mandate for environmental protection. Challenges to the environmental movement have never been greater. Forest Guardians is  ready to meet these challenges. If you care about wild forests, free-flowing rivers, untrammeled deserts, and the creatures that inhabit these beautiful places, support Forest Guardians. We are here to ensure protection and restoration of our last wild ecosystems.





1. fundamentally reform federal endangered species policy by steadily applying pressure on the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to list and provide critical habitat for imperiled species; watch-dogging federal land managers such as the Forest Service and Burea

2. reform livestock grazing on public lands by enforcing federal environmental laws, challenging wasteful and ecologically harmful ranching subsidies, and educating the public about the real ecological costs of livestock production in the arid Southwest

3.  transform a mainstream image of arid landscapes from wastelands to wildplaces

4. reform policy and use the courtroom to halt destructive logging projects by promoting on-the-ground forest and watershed restoration projects that also provide economic opportunities to forest-based communities

5. National Forest Protection and Restoration Act on July 26th, 2005 to ban commercial logging in National Forests and fund critical forest restoration work and community protection from fire

6. ensure that dams throughout the Rio Grande basin are managed significantly better such that water releases mimic natural flows, thereby restoring some of the natural dynamism of river ecosystems. In addition, we believe some dams should come down and, if </description>
  <mission>Forest Guardians seeks to protect and restore the native wildlands and wildlife of the American Southwest through fundamental reform of public policies and practices.</mission>
  <name>Help Restore the South West</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4552</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">32</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jd/Q2/QQ/as/CE/E2/EoqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
