<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>An inferno raced through a Charleston, South Carolina, furniture warehouse collapsing its roof and killing nine firefighters in a tragedy that the city's mayor described Tuesday as "difficult to fathom."

"They lost their lives fighting for the safety of our citizens," Charleston Mayor Joseph P. Riley Jr. said. 

"Nine brave, heroic, courageous firefighters of the city of Charleston have perished fighting a fire, and in a most courageous and fearless manner, carrying out their duties," Riley said. "This is a tragic event for our community, the magnitude of which is difficult to fathom or quantify."

"We lost over a hundred years of service to the city of Charleston Fire Department, over a hundred years of dedicated service," Riley said. "To the families who gave them to us, we protected them as much as we could. They did exactly what they were trained to do. I can't say enough of these nine guys. They were my friends. I lost nine of my best friends." 

The deaths are the single greatest loss of American firefighters in the line of duty since the September 11, 2001, attacks, according to statistics compiled by firehouse.com. The attack on New York's World Trade Center resulted in the deaths of 343 firefighters. 

It is the first time Charleston has lost a firefighter in the line of duty in at least 10 years, Charleston firefighter Lt. Chad Watson said.

The victims and their years of service are:

-- Capt. William "Billy" Hutchinson, 48 (30 years)

-- Capt. Mike Benke, 49 (29 years)

-- Capt. Louis Mulkey, 34 (11&#189; years)

-- Engineer Mark Kelsey, 40 (12&#189; years)

-- Engineer Bradford "Brad" Baity, 37 (9 years)

-- Assistant engineer Michael French, 27 (1&#189; years)

-- Firefighter James "Earl" Drayton, 56 (32 years)

-- Firefighter Brandon Thompson, 27 (4 years)
	
-- Firefighter Melven Champaign, 46 (2 years)


1. Position #1</description>
  <mission>show our support for the 9 fallen firefighters of the Charleston Fire Department</mission>
  <name>Charleston Firefighters</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4556</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1875</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wv/T3/s8/UW/Nx/g0/pIvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
