<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We have all be touched by numerous diseases over the years, cancer probably being one of the highest. It's time we all put our best foot forward to do something. There are numerous projects that have been created out there to put large masses of computers together to achieve one common goal, research.

By joining these projects more money can be put to research while our computer`s crunch the numbers, not only will it be a cheaper process but if you pass this information along it could grow to become the most power system to date. Stop waiting and watching the problems unfold, by downloading one of these applications it will use your computer's unused hardware to process information and help find a cure for a number of diseases. The folding@home project is currently working for a cure for the following diseases:

    * Alzheimer's Disease
    * Cancer
    * Huntington's Disease
    * Osteogenesis Imperfecta
    * Parkinson's Disease
    * Ribosome &amp; antibiotics 

More information on the project
http://folding.stanford.edu/
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Folding%40home

What results has come out of this program?
http://www.stanford.edu/group/pandegroup/folding/results.html

Download here
http://www.stanford.edu/group/pandegroup/folding/download.html

If you have any questions or concerns about the project please feel free to ask.


If you want to put your computers unused resources towards another project I encourage you to do so.

To fight AIDS click on the following link
http://fightaidsathome.scripps.edu/

Climate change prediction.
http://www.climateprediction.net/index.php


I`d explain more but there is a 2000 character limit, please pass this one to as many friends and family you possibly can.

Note: This was not created for donation purposes, rather to encourage more people to join the supercomputer, created entirely for the research of numerous diseases.




1. Use computer ressources to fight cancer.

2. We can all contribute to the solution of cancer.</description>
  <mission>Fighting diseases via protein folding</mission>
  <name>Protein Folding</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4581</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">190</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2J/pd/gr/6r/V3/gW/SZgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
