<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO DONATE, PLEASE DO NOT CLICK THE "DONATE" BUTTON ON HERE.  PLEASE GO TO To make a donation please visit: http://www.aidsmarathon.com/sponsor.asp?citycod...

My Number is: 5427

Or search by my name: Michelle Miskey

OR

You may make a payment by check payable to: National AIDS Marathon

Donations may be mailed to:
National AIDS Marathon Training Program
c/o AIDS Project LA
2550 9th Street #103
Berkeley, CA 94710-2551 
Runner# 5427

PLEASE MAKE SURE TO ADD #5427 IN THE COMMENT/ MEMO FIELD OF YOUR CHECK. THIS ENSURES THAT CREDIT WILL GO TOWARDS OUR GOAL OF $4,200.00


PLEASE DO NOT CLICK ON THE "DONATE" BUTTON TO DONATE.  THE DONATION THERE DOES NOT GO TOWARDS MY PERSONAL GOAL OF RAISING $4200.

THANK YOU THANK YOU THANK YOU


As you may or may not have heard I (Michelle Miskey) am training for the AIDS Marathon on November 25, 2007. Yes that is right 26.2 miles!

I will be logging nearly 500 miles in this six-month training program put on by the National AIDS Marathon. It's an exciting journey. And even though I'll be getting up at the crack of dawn while most of you are still sleeping and have my share of aches and pains and possibly toenails falling off, we know that the cause is worth it.


ALL Donations are Tax Deductible. Tax ID#: 52-1122-122 (National AIDS Marathon)

Thanks for your generous support.

Most sincerely,

Michelle Miskey 

Please feel free to get in touch with me should you have any questions or concerns at 

(213)700-2672 OR michellemiskey@yahoo.com 



THANK YOU SO VERY MUCH FOR TAKING THE TIME TO READ THIS. PLEASE FORWARD THIS TO ANYONE YOU KNOW! 

PLEASE HELP US, HELP OTHERS! 


1. Education = Prevention

2. Prevention = Health

3. Health = Life</description>
  <mission>Provide education, food banks, transporation, home health care and other vital services - to help keep people alive until there is a cure</mission>
  <name>AIDS National Marathon</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4587</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fw/nS/G4/12/fB/uA/Af4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
