<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The largest Jewish campus organization in the world, Hillel: The Foundation for Jewish Campus Life provides opportunities for Jewish students at more than 500 colleges and universities to explore and celebrate their Jewish identity through its global network of regional centers, campus Foundations and Hillel student organizations. Hillel is working to provoke a renaissance of Jewish life.

Hillel's mission is to enrich the lives of Jewish undergraduate and graduate students so that they may enrich the Jewish people and the world. Hillel student leaders, professionals and lay leaders are dedicated to creating a pluralistic, welcoming and inclusive environment for Jewish college students, where they are encouraged to grow intellectually, spiritually and socially. Hillel helps students find a balance in being distinctively Jewish and universally human by encouraging them to pursue tzedek (social justice), tikkun olam (repairing the world) and Jewish learning, and to support Israel and global Jewish peoplehood. Hillel is committed to excellence, innovation, accountability and results.


1. The college years offer the last opportunity to provide Jewish content to young people before they disperse to the working world.

2. Jewish students need a welcoming and inclusive environment where they are encouraged to grow intellectually, spiritually and socially.

3. Students need to find a balance in being distinctively Jewish and universally human. Hillel helps by encouraging them to pursue tzedek (social justice), tikkun olam (repairing the world) and Jewish learning, and to support Israel and global Jewish peo</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to enrich the lives of Jewish undergraduate and graduate students so that they may enrich the Jewish people and the world.</mission>
  <name>Hillel: The Foundation for Jewish Campus Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4598</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">471</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">193.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SV/sh/DC/oT/3b/Tb/sCvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
