<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Parkinson's disease is a movement disorder that is chronic and progressive, meaning that symptoms continue and worsen over time. As many as one million Americans suffer from Parkinson's disease. While approximately 15 percent of people with Parkinson's are diagnosed before the age of 50, incidence increases with age. The cause is unknown, and although there is presently no cure, there are many treatment options such as medication and surgery to manage the symptoms.

Parkinson's disease occurs when a group of cells in an area of the brain called the substantia nigra begin to malfunction and die. These cells in the substantia nigra produce a chemical called dopamine. Dopamine is a neurotransmitter, or chemical messenger, that sends information to the parts of the brain that control movement and coordination. When a person has Parkinson's disease, their dopamine-producing cells begin to die and the amount of dopamine produced in the brain decreases. Messages from the brain telling the body how and when to move are therefore delivered more slowly, leaving a person incapable of initiating and controlling movements in a normal way.

Parkinson's disease can also cause several different symptoms. The specific group of symptoms that an individual experiences varies from person to person. Some of the most common symptoms of Parkinson's disease are:

    * tremor of the hands, arms, legs, jaw and face
    * rigidity or stiffness of the limbs and trunk
    * bradykinesia or slowness of movement
    * postural instability or impaired balance and coordination
     


Information provided by: Parkinson's Disease Foundation   
For more information on this disease please visit  http://www.pdf.org/

1. That Parkinson's is a Terrible disease to have and watch someone have

2. People need to know more about the Disease

3. We need to find away to stop it!!</description>
  <mission>To make people aware of how horrible of a disease Parkinson's is!</mission>
  <name>Parkinson's Disease Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4603</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">635</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.18</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/u6/DG/3C/HZ/Tr/IM/Yr/dNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
