<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Symptoms
The primary symptoms of fibromyalgia include widespread musculoskeletal pain, severe fatigue, and disturbed sleep. Fibromyalgia means pain in the muscles, ligaments, and tendons &#8211; the soft fibrous tissues in the body. 

Most patients with fibromyalgia say that they ache all over. Their muscles may feel like they were pulled or overworked. Sometimes fibromyalgia symptoms include muscle twitches and burning sensations. More women than men are afflicted with fibromyalgia, and it shows up in people of all ages. A conservative estimate of its prevalence is 2% of the general population, but it may be as high as 3-5%.

To help your family and friends relate to your fibromyalgia symptoms, have them think back to the last time they had a bad flu. Every muscle in their body shouted out in pain. In addition, they felt devoid of energy as though someone had unplugged their power supply. While the severity of symptoms fluctuates from person to person, fibromyalgia may resemble a post-viral state. This similarity is the reason experts believe that fibromyalgia syndrome (FMS) and chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) may actually be the same condition. Gulf War syndrome also overlaps with FMS/CFS.

Common symptoms of fibromyalgia:
Pain, Fatigue, Sleep Disorder, IBS, Headaches, TMJD, Painful Periods, Chest Pain, Morning Stiffness, Cognitive or Memory Impairment,  Numbness, Muscle Twitching, Swollen Extremities, Skin Sensitiveness, Dry Eyes and Mouth, Dizziness and Impaired Cordination.

Aggrevating Factors:
Changes in Weather, Cold, Drafty Environments, Air Conditioning, Allergies, Hormonal Influctuations, Stress, Depression, Anxiety, and Over-Exertion

www.fmnetnews.com

1. Finding Health Care Professionals That Acknowledge, Understand and can Treat Patients Properly with FMS

2. Educating Family and Friends on How To Cope With a Loved One's Suffering

3. Helping Secure More Research and Studies into the Barely Known Syndrome</description>
  <mission>Educate our loved ones to what we suffer through daily, and how to help us make life a little easier on us one step at a time.</mission>
  <name>Fibromyalgia Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4610</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9791</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">617.85</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0V/0G/H4/Za/vv/Dj/N7bS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
