<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This movement began long before Show Hope. It began long before any of us were born. This movement is rooted in the heart of God (Ps 10:14) and began with God&#8217;s infinite love for orphans. This movement will continue long after we are gone, because God loves orphans. This movement consists of broken hearts longing to experience the redemption that is found when we turn our attention off ourselves and love these waiting children.

The forgotten children of the world are some of the most valuable hidden treasures that exist. We seek to serve these orphaned, foster, and waiting children in the name of Christ, regardless of their gender, religion, race, or ethnicity, and we will begin on our knees. Will you join us?

=============

Over 143 million children have lost one or both parents. 

At least 16.2 million children worldwide have lost both parents. 

Every 14 seconds a child loses a parent due to AIDS. 

Conflict has orphaned or separated 1 million children from their families in the 1990s. 

43.4 million orphans live in sub-Saharan Africa, 87.6 million orphans live in Asia, and 12.4 million orphans live in Latin America and the Caribbean. 

1.5 million children live in public care in Central and Eastern Europe alone. 

At any given point there are over 500,000 children in the U.S. Foster Care system. 

In some countries, children are abandoned at alarming rates, due to poverty, restrictive population control policies, disabilities or perceived disabilities, and cultural traditions that value boys more than girls. 

1. No child should be left orphaned forever.

2. Adoption is a marvelous picture of God's love for us.

3. There is One who infinitely loves each orphan and calls His people to join Him in caring for the fatherless. Each one of us can Show Hope to an orphan</description>
  <mission>to be AWARE of the need of orphans around the world, RESPOND to God's love for us and His call to care for orphans, SHOW HOPE to waiting children.</mission>
  <name>Shaohannah's Hope</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4611</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2149</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">398.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/JW/In/nY/Q5/n1/eg/76hS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
