<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Epilepsy Niagara provides support services, education and awareness to all persons living with epilepsy and their support network.

Values:
- Everyone has the right to a quality of life, regardless of disability
- Individuals with epilepsy should live a positive lifestyle with the focus on abilities and not disability
- Individuals with epilepsy should not be discriminated against
- All individuals should be treated with respect, compassion, and dignity.

Epilepsy affects approximately 1% of the population making it one of the most common neurological diseases

Goals
1. Epilepsy focused services will be provided to both the individual who has epilepsy and their support and/or community network. This includes family, friends, co-workers, organization associations, school, employers, group homes etc.
2. Educational awareness and support services should be made available for both the individual and their support network (family, community, school, work etc) in order to assist with the decreasing the stigmas and move towards positive coping mechanisms
3. To provide one-on-one emotional support to people living with epilepsy and their families
4. To make educational material available to members
5. To provide up to date research information about epilepsy
6. To provide educational presentations to the Niagara region to assist in advocating for members
7. To provide peer to peer support through support groups and telephone/email networks
8. Public awareness will be provided to decrease stigmas often associated with epilepsy
9. To develop a strong volunteer base for fundraising and program activities
10. The staff and directors will work towards identify the financial resources and programs needed to maintain efficiency and provide quality of services for those affected by epilepsy

Contact Info:
Email: info@epilepsyniagara.org 
Website: http://epilepsyniagara.org/ 
Street: 5017 Victoria Aveneue, Niagara Falls, ON, L23 4C9 




1. Everyone has the right to a quality of life, regardless of disability</description>
  <mission>Improving the quality of life of people who are affected by epilepsy</mission>
  <name>Epilepsy Niagara</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4614</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">165</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/05/BT/Ln/C7/8s/uG/EdZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
