<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is Pact?

Pact's name was chosen because of its meaning: a "pact" is a solemn agreement; to be of one mind; a covenant. At Pact, we believe that in making an adoption plan, birth parents and adoptive parents enter into an agreement to recognize and protect the best interests of the child. Essential to that agreement is a lifelong commitment to recognize, respect and address the dual heritages - both personal and cultural - that are the child's birth right. Our goal is for every child to feel wanted, honored and loved, a cherished member of a strong family with proud connection to his or her rich heritages.

Throughout the seven years since its inception, Pact's founders and small staff have dedicated themselves to the mission of providing the highest quality adoption-related services to children of color, their birth parents and their adoptive parents. Despite its limited budget, Pact has helped place over 450 children in permanent, loving families and has counseled thousands of adopted adults, birth parents, foster parents and adoptive parents. Pact also works with adoption professionals to facilitate adoptions and to initiate programs that better serve clients raising children of color. Importantly, Pact goes beyond traditional adoption services by offering extensive post-placement opportunities for all families raising children of color (same-race, transracial, international, transcultural, etc.), providing informative and essential education, connection and support.

1. Personal and cultural heritages are every child's birth right.

2. All children should feel wanted, honored and loved.

3. All children should have a strong family and proud connection to his or her rich heritages.</description>
  <mission>provide education and support to adopted children (and adults) of color and their families.</mission>
  <name>Pact, an Adoption Alliance</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4615</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">174</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">675.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Eq/Ym/Nb/bE/Dn/kb/g31S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
