<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A Rocha USA's mission is the Conservation of habitats and species world-wide through environmental education, conservation activities and scientific research. This mission can be accomplished in local neighborhoods, at a field study center, or in far-flung parts of the world. 

Equally important, A Rocha is concerned about people - building a sense of connection and Community. In this busy, mobile age, we tend to lose our roots and our relationships. A Rocha is in the business of reconciliation - between people and God; people and the natural world; and people with each other. Birding field trips, conservation activities, lectures and other events not only allow us to discover the wonders of our world and to make a practical difference, but also to work together and become part of a growing international community. 

In addition to Conservation and Community, A Rocha is rooted and motivated by biblical faith. This does not mean that A Rocha is an "exclusive" Christian organization. Rather it is a conservation organization that has grown out of the conviction that part of being human, made in God's image, is to appreciate, care for and be involved in God's created world. Many articles throughout A Rocha's website explore the connection between biblical faith, life, culture and conservation. 

An additional core value for A Rocha is Cross-Cultural. We work together with a wide variety of people and agencies towards a common purpose: the conservation of key habitats and species. 



1. Equipping and empowering members, wherever they are in the United States, to engage in practical conservation in their own communities. This demonstrates Jeremiah 29:7 - "to seek the welfare of the city where God has planted you." 

2. To establish field study centers in various key habitats across the United States. 

3. To provide resources (through prayer, finances, volunteers or technical expertise) to the other A Rocha projects. </description>
  <mission>Conservation of habitats and species world-wide </mission>
  <name>A Rocha</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4624</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">103</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Jv/8T/eA/3D/jD/mg/6bmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
