<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Iraq War started on March 20, 2003. This is an ongoing war which began with a United States-led 2003 invasion of Iraq. The main reason for the Iraq War offered by U.S. President George W. Bush and supporters in the Republican and Democratic parties, was that Iraq was developing WMD's. In George W. Bush's 2003 State of the Union Address, he claimed that the U.S. could not wait until the threat from Saddam Hussein became imminent.
The war began in March 2003, when a largely British and American force supported by small contingents from Australia, Denmark and Poland attacked Iraq. The invasion led to the overthrow of Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein. The U.S.-led coalition occupied Iraq and attempted to establish a new democratic government. The coalition, however, was unsuccessful in restoring order to Iraq. 
Since March 20, over 12000 troops have been sent to Iraq to proctect us. 
Now it is our time to help them. There are several ways to help bring home healthy troops. There are also many ways to help brighten the soilders day.

There are causes such as 
Soilder's Angels-www.SoldiersAngels.org

 
United Service Organizations- www.OperationUSOCarePackage.org


Operation Helmet-www.operation-helmet.org

and others. 

They need our help.




**Some information and the picture were taken from other sources**


http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ervaMPt4Ha0

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vt0eSaqnSdg

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qSeYlcOs9D0

1. Help bring our troops home safely

2. Assist the Iraqis with reconstruction and humanitarian assistance</description>
  <mission>support all of the troops that are overseas</mission>
  <name>Remember the Soldiers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4639</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2357</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/N5/rf/wV/1l/BL/U1/RHFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
