<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Why Are We doing this

Had enough of Joe Lieberman playing both sides of the aisle? Sucking up to Sean Hannity and Bill O'Reilly on FoxNews? Talking down to 
other Democrats as if he and his Republican buddies have some sort of monopoly on moral authority.
Lieberman supported Bush needless war and to this day, defends Bush's dishonest and flawed Iraq policies.
Joe goes out of his way to stifle debate about the Iraq war. Even during the 2004 Presidential election, Lieberman praised Bush, while chiding John Kerry.
And who can forget his comments about Abu Ghraib, made only worse by his endorsement of Mr. Torture Made Legal, Alberto Gonzales?
Then there is "The Kiss", when, after the annual State of the Union address, George Bush so quickly embraced his DINO friend, Joe, on national TV!
But of course these things happen naturally with a politician who has long since forgotten those that brought him to power.
Joe no longer works for us, but works for big Energy, Defense and Finance Corporations. The same Corporations that are making a killing
from Bush's and Joe's illicit war. Joe also sides with Bush and the GOP on School vouchers.
Joe is more popular among CT Republicans than he is among CT Democrats. The other side absolutely loves him! Is there anything more to be said? 
Now, He's even selling us out on social security!


CT deserves better. And across this great wide country, all those Democrats who have fought for the Party of the People, well, they deserve better, too!


Contact Joe and tell him how you feel!

Washington
706 Hart Office Building
Washington, DC 20510
(202) 224-4041 Voice
(202) 224-9750 Fax
For TTY Call 711

Connecticut
One Constitution Plaza
7th Floor
Hartford, CT 06103
(860) 549-8463 Voice
(800) 225-5605 In CT
(860) 549-8478 Fax
For TTY Call 711

http://groups.myspace.com/saynotojoe

www.askslim.org

1. We must stop the war with Iran before it starts.

2. We must not let John McCain become president!</description>
  <mission>Stand up to Joe Lieberman and his war mongering and his support for the Bush Admisisration!</mission>
  <name>Say No To Joe: The Anti-Joe Lieberman Cause</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4644</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">42</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/lK/12/NU/Vd/5j/XI/cnrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
