<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Mission Statement:
WELS Kingdom Workers exists for the purpose of assisting the Wisconsin Evangelical Lutheran Synod (WELS) mission divisions in their task of making disciples according to the Great Commission of our Lord Jesus Christ.

To Inform
We seek to carry out the Great Commission by making WELS member aware of how WELS Kingdom Workers (WKW) is helping meet needs in our mission fields. We accomplish this through presentations (.doc) to congregations, schools, and church-related organizations. Video, print, and other means of communication are also used.

To Encourage
Lay people get personally involved in WKW through prayer support, financial support, and service. Mission-minded WELS lay people are encouraged to establish chapters to more effectively involve people locally in mission work. A chapter can involve one or many congregations. The chapters mission focus is accomplished by adopting a WKW national project and establishing one or more local mission outreach projects.

To Facilitate
We recruit qualified WELS and ELS lay people of all ages to provide time and talents through the three divisions of WKW: Builders For Christ, Christian Volunteer Corps, and Faith In Action. These mission assistants serve WELS congregations and missions across the United States and around the world.
To Provide
We receive project requests, from the WELS Board for Home Missions and Board for World Missions, which are approved but not funded. Projects are then selected from these prioritized lists with attention to those with lay involvement.

The Schwan Foundation provides matching funds for contributions received in support of WKW projects. Contributions received along with matching funds go directly to our projects and are not used for administrative support.

Taken from http://www.wels.net/cgi-bin/site.pl?2617&amp;collectionID=1071&amp;contentID=10461&amp;shortcutID=13378

1. To inform WELS members of teh needs and opportunities that exist in home and world mission fields.

2. to encourage WELS members to become personally involved in mission work.

3. to provide and coordinate volunteers in mission fields.

4. to provide financial support for unfunded mission programs.</description>
  <mission>To assisst the Wisconsin Evangelical Lutheran Synod (WELS) mission divisions in their task of making disciples according to the Great Commission.</mission>
  <name>WELS Kingdom Workers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/465</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">124</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">70.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/OOg/YGAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
