<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>At Sentebale our priority is to reach the people who are not normally reached by existing aid organisations or government.

In particular we will support herd boys, who live in remote mountain country and do not attend school; victims of domestic violence and sexual abuse who cannot live at home; the deaf, blind and disabled; as well as both one and two parent orphans.

Sentebale will work by directing aid to the mostly voluntary, grass-roots community services that are attempting to fill the gaps which existing aid organisations and government have not filled. We will also consider more entrepreneurial projects which have the capacity to change the lives of communities trying to support orphans and vulnerable children.

The problems in Lesotho are now so acute that Sentebale is having to adopt innovative approaches in delivering support. We will work with organisations even if they do not have the management structures in place normally required by donors so long as they are delivering an effective service. Part of what we do will be to assist small community organisations to develop more sophisticated management skills, and to work alongside them as they acquire them.

By investing strategically - not just granting generously - we aim to help community based organisations increase their impact on the lives of the children they serve.

In addition Sentebale is committed to collaboration with all aid providers in Lesotho - whether major international grant-makers, smaller NGOs, local service providers or government.

What we want to do is build stronger, more effective organisations serving more children better.


*From http://www.sentebale.org/home/index.html

1. Sentebale targets particular support to the most vulnerable of vulnerable children - the abused, disabled, ill, abandoned and neglected.</description>
  <mission>Transform the lives of Lesotho's orphans and vulnerable children - the forgotten victims of poverty and of the HIV/Aids epidemic ravaging their country. </mission>
  <name>Sentebale</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4659</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">326</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">125.82</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ej/K3/TJ/Hu/8u/aI/5gJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
