<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The United World College-USA was founded in 1982 in Montezuma, NM and is part of an international movement that now includes eleven two-year pre-university residential schools worldwide offering the International Baccalaureate Diploma curriculum plus a three-year tertiary college of rural development and agriculture in Venezuela.

The UWC-USA enrolls just over 200 students. Of these, 150 places are offered to students from more than 90 countries outside the U.S. The remaining 50 places are offered to students from the U.S.

Atlantic College in Wales, the first United World College, opened in 1962 and was instrumental in the creation of the International Baccalaureate, the world's first and most widely recognized international curriculum. The strength of the UWC movement is evident in the volunteer leadership of Her Majesty Queen Noor of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan, the President of the United World Colleges and Nelson Mandela, former President of South Africa, the honorary President.
Nelson Mandela.

While the UWC schools share a mission statement and a common philosophy, individual characteristics shape each college into a distinct community. Volunteers organizing as National Committees in over 100 countries select their most promising students through national competitions and nominate them for places and scholarships to the colleges. In many other nations, government or other non-governmental agencies oversee the competition to nominate their best students. 

1. Education as a force for peace

2. Uniting people of different people, nations and cultures

3. Creating a sustainable environment</description>
  <mission>UWC makes education a force to unite people, nations, and cultures for peace and a sustainable future.</mission>
  <name>United World College - USA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4662</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">611</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1933.26</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Hc/u7/sg/XK/pZ/wj/J47S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
