<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There are thousands of organisations that seek to aid in the extinction of the refugee crisis, as well as helping refugees, each with a specific purpose or goal. And, every organisation helps out in some way, whether big or small. There are so many reasons why one should consider becoming part of an organisation in which he or she believes. However, there is only one reason why one should consider helping Project CAER:



Project CAER, through the generosity of so many wonderful donors, has seen actual results, firsthand, in the Lugufu refugee camp in Africa. Though other organisations do a world of good, Project CAER has helped to establish schools, libraries, medical centers, and jobs for refugees in progressive refugee camps in Lugufu, Tanzania, Africa. And, this is a known FACT. Each time a yearly donation is collected, it is HAND DELIVERED to the camp where refugees reap every benefit of every cent contributed. Instead of aiding in establishing stronger foundations in the organisation, Project CAER's money goes to books, school supplies, food, medical supplies, and manipulatives for those looking to find work in a progressive, thriving refugee camp.

VISIT: www.projectcaer.tripod.com

DONATE: Whatever you can

CHANGE: The world
	

1. The Refugee Crisis in Africa has Gone Unnoticed due to the Overwhelming State of Many of the World's Poorer Nations. It is time to change the way things are for Africa. Here are some ways Project CAER has been and is going to make a change:

2. Provide relief for a wide array of necessities, such as:

3. Medical, Education, and Sustainability

4. Establishing network ties in United States and United Kingdom, with African Refugees in the Lugufu Refugee Camp, among youth and adolescents, encouraging global connection for change. 

5. Informing individuals through a curriculum geared toward better understanding the refugee crisis, in hopes that ideas for change can be invented and put into action. </description>
  <mission>Provide Relief to Africa's Refugee Crisis</mission>
  <name>Project CAER--Compassion, Awareness, and Empathy for Refugees</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4664</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mu/3D/U7/1u/qb/Wp/hCTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
