<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Tiger Cubs BSA: A school-year program for first-grade (or 7-year old) boys and their adult partners that stresses shared leadership, learning about the community, and family understanding. Each boy-adult team meets for family activities, and twice a month all the teams meet for Tiger Cub den activities.

Cub Scouting: A family and home-centered program that develops ethical decision-making for boys in the second through fifth grades (or who are 8, 9, and 10 years old). Fourth and fifth-grade (or 10-year-old) boys are called Webelos Scouts (WE BE LOyal Scouts) and participate in more advanced activities that begin to prepare them to become Boy Scouts. Cub Scouting s emphasis is on quality program at the local level, where boys and families are involved.

Boy Scouting: A program for boys 11 through 17 designed to achieve the aims of Scouting through a vigorous outdoor program and peer group leadership with the counsel of an adult Scoutmaster. (Boys also may become Boy Scouts if they have earned the Arrow of Light Award or have completed the fifth grade.)

Varsity Scouting: An active, exciting program for young men 14 through 17 built around five program fields of emphasis: advancement, high adventure, personal development, service, and special programs and events.

Venturing: A program for young men and women who are 14 (and have completed the eighth grade) through 20 years of age to provide positive experiences through exciting and meaningful activities that help youth pursue their special interests, grow, develop leadership skills, and become good citizens.

1. Instilling timeless values...

2. duty to God and country,

3. duty to self and others.</description>
  <mission>The Mission of the Boy Scouts of America is to prepare young people to make ethical choices over their lifetime by instilling in them the values of the Scout Oath and Law.</mission>
  <name>Boy Scouts of America (Mecklenburg County Council)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4665</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">193</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bp/1H/ew/2s/Hd/fR/jc6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
