<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We wish to garner support for the council and bring about awareness and new membership.

 In 1927, William F. Livermore, a special Deputy Regional Scout Executive of the Boy Scouts of America, gathered a group of Bucks County community leaders together at the Elks Home in Bristol to organize Bucks County Council. Thomas B. Stockham was elected President and Livermore was scout Executive.

The Council was incorporated under the law of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania in the Courts of Bucks County on August 13, 1928 and the official name was Bucks County Council, Boy Scouts of America. Henry Palmer headed a committee to find a camp site. They decided on a site along the Raritan River, first renting and finally buying the site. The "Good Times Hall" was donated by Mr. Palmer, and the Doylestown Kiwanis Club donated a craft lodge. "BUCCOU" was picked as the name for the camp since the site was located out of the county. Although it was a very beautiful site, it was never popular with Bucks County Scouts.

Camp Ockanickon was purchased in 1940 and Buccou was sold. Camp Ockanickon has grown and is enjoyed by thousands of boys and young adults each year. It is open for weekend use by Cub Packs for picnics and Webelos Overnighters, Scout Troops and Explorer co-ed events.

During the period from 1965 to 1968, a service Center in Doylestown was completed and is in use today.

Bucks County Council, since its inception, has continued to assist Scouting through a representative executive board supporting volunteers who directly serve over 10,000 boys and young adults in more than 240 Cub Packs, Scout Troops, Varsity Teams and Explorer Posts.

http://www.buckscountybsa.org/


1. Encourage BSA volunteers and membership

2. The Scout Oath and Law should be lived in everyday life

3. Support one of the best organization for young boys to become well-rounded men</description>
  <mission>To meet the spiritual, developmental, and social needs of young people by instilling lifetime values, based on the Scout Oath and Law, that result in achieving full potential.</mission>
  <name>Boy Scouts of America, Bucks County Council, PA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4672</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/o7/Er/Lx/OA/8E/6D/OU7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
