<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Muringato Primary School is located in Nyeri District, Central Province, Kenya. Muringato is located in an area of profound poverty levels due to unstable, low-wage employment; landlessness; low education levels; and high HIV infection rates.

The children of Muringato school experience multiple effects of such poverty: malnutrition; lack of proper clothing; chronic illness; fatigue; improper physical development; anemia; and poor test scores. These children are, at times, recruited or forced into child labor in order to attain money and/or food for their families. Problems unique to the girl-children include: early marriage, teenage pregnancy, sex-for-survival, and the inability to attend school when menstruating because of a lack of sanitary supplies. Last year, only one female Muringato student and two male students proceeded to secondary school (grade 9).

Nutrition is a key challenge for Muringato as it is impossible for a child to learn effectively if they are starving. Muringato has been donated 5 acres of land from Kimathi Institute of Technology, with whom they share land. With this land, Muringato hopes to develop fields in which they can grow their own vegetables and maize&#8212;thus, supporting the children with healthy, well-balanced meals.

Muringato hopes to make the 5 acres of land mentioned above their new home. The staff would like to relocate the school to a location closer to a main road in order to facilitate safe commuting for student body. Relocating will bring Muringato closer to resources: a plot of land that can be developed to provide food for the children.Additionally, the new building will have windows (which are currently lacking) to keep out the cold air, and adequate walls, roof, and desks. 

1. Education 

2. Equality </description>
  <mission>to increase the education and health levels of the children at Muringato Primary School</mission>
  <name>Muringato Primary School</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4676</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0W/Qy/Gy/dM/nT/30/CXGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
