<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Team In Training (TNT) is The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society's most successful fundraising program nationwide. Since its inception in 1988, TNT has trained over 320,000 individuals and raised over $750 million. The Northern California Division has been an integral part of this success. In the coming year, we anticipate that nearly 4,000 people will sign up for one of our teams. These cyclists, cross country skiers, runners, walkers, and triathletes will reach both their fitness and fundraising goals while raising an estimated $15 million dollars to support the Society's work. Each member of the team participants in honor of a child or adult from the Bay Area community affected by leukemia or another blood cnacer. Completing an endurance event is a celebration of human spirit, physical ability, and mental endurance. For members of Team In Training, it is also a celebration of life.

On October 21, 2007 I will be running in the Women's Nike Marathon in San Francisco. I will join this amazing group of athletes as we cross the finish line. That means that we will be running 26.2 miles in honor of those who are fighting cancer and 26.2 miles in memory of those who have lost their courageous battle with a blood cancer. My goal is to raise $3,000 for The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society. I dream about crossing that finish line but I need your help and support to get there. I know that the majority of those reading this know someone they love who has fought, or is currently fighting, a cancer. Let them inspire you to give generously and know that whatever you are able to give will make a difference to patients and their families. 

1. Blood cancers (leukemia, non-Hodgkin&#8217;s lymphoma, multiple myeloma, and Hodgkin&#8217;s disease strike 105,000 Americans every year

2. Blood cancers account for 59,2000 deaths every year in America

3. Every week there are 1,900 new cases of leukemia, lymphoma, or multiple myeloma diagnosed in the U.S.

4. Every week, 1,100 Americans die from a blood cancer

5. Leukemia: 208,080 Americans have leukemia with 35,070 new cases diagnosed every year. Leukemia causes more deaths than any other cancer in children under the age of 20. 32% of cancers among 0-14 year olds is leukemia. Over the past 30 years, leukemia surv

6. Lymphoma: 519,473 Americans have lymphoma with 66,670 new cases diagnosed every year. Non-Hodgkin&#8217;s lymphoma is the 6th most common cancer in the U.S. From 1975 to 2003, the incidence rate of Non-Hodgkin&#8217;s lymphoma rose 76%.

7. Myeloma: 58,336 Americans have myeloma with 16,570 new cases diagnosed every year. The incidence rates of myeloma in men are 62% higher than in women. The median age of diagnoses is 70 years of age. Myeloma rarely occurs in people under 45.</description>
  <mission>The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society's mission is to cure leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin's disease, and myeloma, and improve the quality of life of patients and their families.</mission>
  <name>Gina Is Running A Marathon With Team In Training to Support The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4685</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mj/Hr/IG/AM/k5/ig/65mS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
