<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Cluster bombs scatter dozens to hundreds of explosive bomblets that spray deadly shrapnel fragments over wide areas of land, making it very difficult to avoid civilian casualties. The bomblets sometimes fail to detonate on impact, leaving behind large numbers of unexploded duds that are akin to landmines. 
In the last 15 years, the U.S. has dropped cluster bombs in civilian-populated areas of the former Yugoslavia, Afghanistan and Iraq. U.S.-made cluster bombs have also been dropped in many other countries. The United Nations has discovered U.S.-made cluster bombs dropped in front of hospitals, schools and other civilian areas. 

Since the last U.S. cluster bomb was dropped on Laos in 1973, approximately 12,000 Laotian civilians have been killed or injured by an unexploded bomblet. As many as 60% of casualties from unexploded cluster munitions in South East Asia are children.

The Cluster Munitions Civilian Protection Act of 2007 (S. 594) would ban the use of cluster bombs in or near civilian areas and ban the use, sale and transfer of almost the entire existing U.S. arsenal of close to one billion bomblets. 

Sign this petition now to tell your Senators to cosponsor 
the Cluster Munitions Civilian Protection Act. 

visit:

http://www.thepetitionsite.com/takeaction/352193122?z00m=9440233

Sign the petition at the bottom of the page and get people to join this cause!!

1. The use of Cluster bombs indescriminantly kills civilians!

2. If countries like America can stop, so can the rest of the world!

3. CHILDREN are often KILLED as a result of the small unexploded bombs resembling small toys. Innocent children are at risk!</description>
  <mission>Help pass the "Cluster Munitions Civilian Protection Act"</mission>
  <name>Ban the use of Cluster Bombs</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4689</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">234</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7H/qx/nJ/gz/pk/Pd/NqES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
