<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Cystic Fibrosis is an inherited, chronic disease that affects the lungs and digestive system of about 30,000 children and adults in the United States (70,000 worldwide). A defective gene and its protein product cause the body to produce unusually thick, sticky mucus that:  clogs the lungs and leads to life-threatening lung infections; and obstructs the pancreas and stops natural enzymes from helping the body break down and absorb food.

In the 1950s, few children with Cystic Fibrosis lived to attend elementary school. Today, advances in research and medical treatments have further enhanced and extended life for children and adults with CF. Many people with the disease can now expect to live into their 30s, 40s and beyond.

June 9:  1,100 members.
June 12:  2,000 members.
July 8:  5,796 members, $860.
Sept 17:  22,053 members, $1,643.
February 23, '08: 66,820 members, $5,003


HOW CAN YOU HELP?

RECRUIT:  credit card users, family, friends, your neighbor, anyone! (try 5 a day) 
REMEMBER: if we all recruited one person, the cause would double over night.
FUNDRAISE:  bake sales, can drives, bowl-a-thons, talk to your schools, jeans for genes days at work
DONATE:  please donate $5 minimum.
ASK FOR HELP:  the majority of people you ask will not turn you down; its up to you !
REMEMBER WE CAN NOT DO IT ALONE:
we need you.

Please consider supporting the cause:  all donations DIRECTLY benefit CYSTIC FIBROSIS RESEARCH for a cure **Even a small $5-$10 tax-deductible donation can drastically help toward finding a cure** Thank you for your support.

1. Cystic Fibrosis is affecting lives all over the world.

2. Any amount donated is worth saving a life.

3. Cystic Fibrosis is not promoted enough and needs all of the help it can get to be cured.</description>
  <mission>Raise Money and Awareness.</mission>
  <name>Cure Cystic Fibrosis</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/469</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">373508</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">80343.39</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kYi/mC2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
