<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>(Sorry if I've spammed you already with this, but I just thought I'd set up a cause to make donating easier and to keep the IRC on your radar.)

This year I'm going to be cycling in the Tour de Pierce to help benefit the International Rescue Committee (IRC) and I need your help! Founded in 1933, the IRC (not to be confused with the chat protocol with the same acronym) is a non-profit organization that provides relief and resettlement services for refugees displaced by wars, ethnic cleansing, and natural disasters. You can find out more about them at their website.

Team IRC will be riding in the Tour de Pierce on June 24 to help raise money for the IRC's programs that benefit documented refugees and local Katrina and Rita evacuees. This is where you come in. By making a tax-deductable donation to the IRC, you will help provide direct assistance for refugees in the form of basic necessities, job readiness workshops, transportation to interviews and meetings with case managers, and more to help them begin their new lives.

You can help support IRC Seattle this year in one of three ways. You can donate through this handy page, mail me a check made out to "IRC Seattle Resettlement Office", or send a check directly to the IRC (with my name and 'Team IRC' in the memo line). Just mail the check to:

International Rescue Committee c/o Megan Anderson
100 South King Street, #570
Seattle, WA 98104

If you're a cyclist and want to help out by riding for Team IRC and chilling on the road with me, send an email to Megan Anderson at Megan (dot) anderson (at) theirc (dot) org asking for a registration form. The $5 team registration fee gets you a spot on Team IRC for either the 12, 30, or 50 mile ride through Pierce County.

Thanks a lot for your support,

Derek

1. Refugees uprooted by global crises deserve aid and support to help them re-settle and adapt to their new lives.

2. The IRC is a quality organization with a proven track record of effectiveness and fiscal responsibility.

3. Bikes are neat.</description>
  <mission>Ride my bike in the Tour de Pierce to raise awareness for and benefit the International Rescue Committee</mission>
  <name>Tour de Pierce bike ride for the IRC</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4691</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/XK/fh/3L/AX/Ke/5v/jBRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
