<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hello, all. i started this group because it's what i believe and it appalled me that there was actually someone who started a group that supported imperialism. That said i want to state that i will use examples of past nations that are doing the same as us i won't name them until the end for dramatic effect of course. 
     There was a nation, an empire, that took over most of Europe, parts of the northern coast of Africa, and pieces of the Middle East. At their beginning they were great. They wanted to spread their greatness. What become of their efforts? Ruins. Ruins and a lesson to be learned. "Those who do not study history are doomed to repeat it." 
     There was once an empire that had so great a navy that no other nation could even start to rise. Though it did not take over Europe it ended all attempts at a reclamation of the sea. It took brave men (libertarians no less!) to stand up to this imperialistic nation, and fight for their rights.
     The first was Rome, the second was Britain. Although Britain is still in existence it is only because they have many intelligent logical people in their nation. These people realized that on their current path they would perish. 
     The third nation is US. THE US. It's too bad that there is a lack of logical people in this nation, or if there are logical people in this nation they do not reside in this state which is no fault of theirs. If we continue upon our path we will surely die. We will be yet another unheeded example of the obvious formula "you can control no one but yourself." 
     As a side note i would like to advise and encourage anyone who agrees with the main message behind this proof to join another libertarian cause or group, or if not join at least research.

1. Americans must fight for their rights.

2. These rights will not come from the Middle East.

3. If you attempt to control another's life they will resent it and you.</description>
  <mission>fight imperialism</mission>
  <name>Justice</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4696</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tL/tU/m2/mC/AU/T0/16IS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
