<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The statistics regarding domestic violence and sexual assault are staggering.  Unfortunately they are not just statistics, they are our mothers, daughters, sisters, and friends.  It seems hard to find someone who hasn't been affected, in some way, by this sickness in our society.

The Fraternity of Alpha Kappa Lambda, as leaders in our communities, cannot sit idly by while it continues.  AKL has established a national service project, These Hands Don't Hurt, in an effort to harness the vast resources of our Fraternity.  

These Hands Don't Hurt was established as a multi-faceted program for our chapters.  AKL recognizes that throwing money at a problem is not enough.  We must help educate the community and offer our hands-on support of such causes.  This program addresses each of those needs.
As a Fraternity we are capable of harnessing our manpower to assist others in a &#8220;hands-on&#8221; fashion.  Part of this program is offering to lend a collective hand to assist local organizations.  

These Hands Don&#8217;t Hurt seeks to use the skills, talents, and manpower of AKL members to support local shelters and organizations.  Like any not-for-profit organization these local groups have many projects and tasks that are left undone because of manpower.  Chapter members may help paint a shelter, organize a holiday party for battered kids, or a number of possibilities.  The actual tasks may vary from chapter to chapter but each is of equal value to these organizations.

   


1. Raise awareness and support for those who are victims of domestic violence.</description>
  <mission>Stop Domestic Violence</mission>
  <name>These Hands Don't Hurt</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4712</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1719</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">55.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ol/Uq/CZ/UI/xh/Io/jPTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
