<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Like any responsible parents, Kristy and Josh Schwade wanted what was best for their only child, Kaleb.  They did a background check on their day care worker, and even interviewed her in her home for two hours.  Kristy was even willing to drive 20 miles out of her way to provide, what they thought to have been, "optimum" care in a good neighborhood.  

On May 9th, 2007 their worst nighmare was brought to fruition.  After being in the care of this home day care worker only five times, Kaleb was picked up by his Grandmother and Aunt.  They noticed that he was lethargic and experiencing obvious breathing abnormalities.  The caregiver told them he was ill, but Kaleb had just visited the doctors the day before and was given a "clean bill of health".  When Kristy arrived at her mother's home to pick Kaleb up, she described him as "having no life in his body".  She tried repeatedly to wake him, but with no avail.  She and her father got in the car and rushed to the hospital.  While in the vehicle, Kristy lifted Kaleb's little eyelids.  She noticed that his pupils were different sizes.  Being the wife of an EMT, she knew immediately that this was the sign of a head injury- Kaleb needed IMMEDIATE care.  They stopped at the nearest firestation.  The ambulance took him to the nearest hospital, and he was classified as a "trauma alert".  He was then life-flighted to Tampa General Hospital, and was admitted to the Pediatric Intensive Care Unit (PICU).  He was diagnosed as having Shaken Baby Syndrome.  They also discovered that he had been SMOTHERED!  


1. Abuse by paid caregivers must end

2. prayer is the best thing that we can do for this family</description>
  <mission>The mission of my cause is to provide support for the parents as well as raise awareness torward the prevention of others finding themselves in the same situation</mission>
  <name>Prayer for the family of baby Kaleb</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4714</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10985</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fh/S3/mo/DX/3T/qh/I8/cSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
