<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In 2007, the Egyptian government has sent a group of 40 Brotherhood member to be trialed in a military court, although the civilian court has acquited them, and not just once, but 3 times.
These 40 Have been in jail since December 2006 and their money was seized for no reason other than they believe that Pleasing Allah is their Ultimate Goal, and Islam is the best Way of Life and if Islam was implemented freedom and prosperity will be for all. They are being sent to military court because they have a view for reform.
Whether you agree with them in their values or not we should all agree that freedom is the right of every human being.
We believe that it is the constitutional right for every civilians, no matter what are their beliefs, Religion, Race, Nationality or any other classification you can Imagine, to be trialed in front of an independent civilian court.
We also believe that it is not allowed for any person to be sent to any type of courts for his political thoughts or for his view for reform.
If you share these believes, join the cause, get more informed about it and tell others about it also, the more people are involved, the more alive our case will be, and one day we will be able to really FREE EGYPT

For More Details Visit:
www.ensaa.blogspot.com
www.khirat-elshater.blogspot.com
www.river-nile.blogspot.com
www.pouregypte.blogspot.com

P.S.
We do NOT- with an increased focus on NOT- need or take Donations, SO do NOT Donate, all we need is your support and your voice. JOIN, Know, and TELL OTHERS 

1. Cancelling the unjust verdicts set by an unconsititutional military court on 25 muslim Brotherhood members

2. The Immediate release of Eng. Khirat El-Shater and his group.

3. The removal of all articles in the constitutuin or the law that give any person the right to trial anyone infront of an exceptional court

4. Promoting the indepence of judges and of the judiciary system

5. Freedom for all those who are imprisoned for political reasons, especially in Egypt, and in the whole world</description>
  <mission>end sending civilians to military courts Depriving them of their constitutional rights</mission>
  <name>No to Military trials for Civilians</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4723</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1733</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DL/MF/Qz/TQ/BA/q0/7PmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
