<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hundreds of millions of research dollars have been spent over the past 15 years to determine if the radiation from mobile phones poses a health risk. In recent years research has also been conducted on other "Digital Wireless" devices including Wi-Fi, digital cordless phones (900mhz, 2.4ghz, 5.6ghz, etc...).

This controversial issue has recieved a great deal of attention in the media, and has evoked extreme responses from the public and the industry, some condeming any suggestion there may be a health risk, others adorning foil-lined clothing to protect themselves. http://www.bbc.co.uk/science/hottopics/mobilephones/safety.shtml

Some things we do know for certain:

1. The latest technology used in digital wireless is unlike any other wireless technology that has existed prior, such as radio or tv towers, in terms of the "pulsed microwave radiation" that is used

2. Prior to the invention of the mobile phone, humans have never had exposure to this type of radiation in such close proximity to their body

3. While the jury is still out on whether there is clear evidence of a health risk, scientists worldwide have more than demonstrated "reasonable doubt." http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/507112.stm

4. In the 2002 UK, the "Stewart Report" was published in the UK with reccomendations that children limit or avoid usage of mibile phones altogether until further research demonstrates it is safe. http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/4163003.stm

5. Much like tobacco, billions of people worldwide have become dependent on wireless devices, so even if we did have irrefutable proof that there was a health risk, it will be nearly impossible for the industry and the public to adapt. Much like tobacco, people will continue to use wireless devices in spite of potential health risks.

6. All around the world, concerned citizens are taking notice of this issue, and taking their message to the street: http://www.antennafreeunion.org/

1. Our mission is to start a discussion about developing standard warning labels for all "digital wireless devices", including mobile phones, Wi-Fi, and digital cordless phones, specifically warning against exposure to children.</description>
  <mission>Alert the public of the potential risks of using Mobile phones, Digital cordless phones, and Wi-Fi. Especially for Children,</mission>
  <name>Warning labels for Wireless</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4731</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">19</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Wm/AK/0F/oY/xP/Tw/N18S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
