<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Just recently, 24 students and leaders from FSM went to Ban Nam Khem, Thailand

We experienced the truth of the world around us. That the world around is is nothing but what we tell ourselves it is not. We can't deny the truth any more.  We can't do anything but act

We can't stand the fact that in Ban Nam Khem, 
idoletry
sexual perversion
domestic abuse
alchoholism
lack of a true "family"
reservations of Burmese children that aren't allowed in Thai society but can't survive in Burma*
false hope
That Buddhism has been there for 4,000 years, and Christianity for only about 170.
That 6,000+ people died in the recent tsunami, and 80% of the people lost atleast 1 loved one
That if we don't act, they will live in Hell for the rest of eternity. 

All of that takes place on the streets, hearts, and souls of these children of God. These creations from our father. These brothers and sisters that we don't loose sleep over.

It's time for a change


*The children and familes of Burma are getting slaughtered. Once they, if at all, make it past the Burmese border, they are found in miles of jungle and suffering, and they then must make it to the Thai border. Once crossed, they are in Thailand. Unfortunately, it seems that in Thailand, a modern CASTE system is revised. Thai people are above the rest, and the Burmese resemble the untouchable. Their mobilization is restricted to foot and bicycle. Their jobs are restricted to what Thai people don't want. Their hearts are restricted to what they see in Thai people.






"Ban Nam Khem, Thailand" is a nonprofit cause. All donations are sent to Craig Miller, who is head of ThirstNoMore Inc, who has stations in the USA, Belize, Peru, Brazil, England, Russia, Sudan, and Thailand.

1. Bring Ban Nam Khem out of the turmoil running through the Thai and Burmese lives

2. Cease the Burmese segregation from the Thai people

3. Share the love and word of God to every person in Ban Nam Khem, in Thailand, and in the whole world

4. To show we care about the souls of these brothers and sisters

5. To let God perform his will through us</description>
  <mission>relieve Ban Name Khem from the turmoil of the world</mission>
  <name>Ban Nam Khem, Thailand</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4737</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">79</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">85.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uL/IY/Tu/Tq/XF/zP/dHAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
