<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 1978, the Downtown Women&#8217;s Center (DWC) is a nationally recognized nonprofit organization that provides 40,000 meals, 71 permanent supportive housing apartments, and a wide array of health, education, and other supportive services to more than 2000 homeless and very low-income women each year. The Center meets our mission by offering a warm, friendly atmosphere that encourages homeless women to commit to their own betterment and healing process. Our supportive community and much-needed resources allow homeless women to reconnect with their sense of self, reclaim goals lost in the day-to-day struggle for survival on the streets, and move toward self-sufficiency. In the local Skid Row community, the Downtown Women&#8217;s Center is the only resource that is exclusively for and singularly dedicated to serving the unique needs of this population.  

For more information, visit the DWC website at www.DWCweb.org

1. DWC is a nationally recognized leader creating innovative solutions to end women&#8217;s homelessness and advocate for social justice.

2. DWC is the only organization exclusively serving women in poverty on downtown Los Angeles&#8217; Skid Row.

3. DWC is a safe haven and supportive community facilitating healing and empowering homeless women to reclaim their dignity.

4. Founded by volunteers, DWC is a place where community members can share their unique talents and resources to create a better LA and a better world.</description>
  <mission>To provide permanent supportive housing and a safe and healthy community fostering dignity, respect, and personal stability, and to advocate ending homelessness for women.</mission>
  <name>Downtown Women's Center</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4743</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">419</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">626.12</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/L1/2U/RG/wA/PX/qZ/aD/VHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
