<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>SAVE is a student driven organization. Students learn about alternatives to violence and practice what they learn through school and community service projects. As they participate in SAVE activities, students learn crime prevention and conflict management skills and the virtues of good citizenship, civility, and nonviolence. 

On a Friday night in 1989, a young man named Alex Orange lost his life while trying to break up a fight at a party. Alex could have been just another statistic of another young life lost to violence. But the following Monday morning, his grieving classmates gathered in West Charlotte Senior High School&#8217;s (NC) cafeteria and vowed to organize against violence in Alex&#8217;s memory. The group formed Students Against Violence Everywhere (SAVE) an organization with the vision that all students will be able to attend a school that is safe and secure, free of fear, and conducive to learning.  

SAVE was born out of sorrow, but has grown with hope. In just 18 years, SAVE has expanded from that first chapter in Charlotte, North Carolina, to nearly 200,000 members in over 1,600 SAVE chapters across the U.S. SAVE members view each day as an opportunity to take steps that will save young lives like that of Alex, and they challenge others to do the same.  

SAVE serves youth in elementary schools, middle schools, high schools, colleges, and community youth-serving organizations in 45 states. Our chapters are open to all students, regardless of their geographic location, socio-economic status, race, ethnicity, gender, sexual orientation, age, physical ability, and/or language. 


1. Every student deserves to attend a school that is safe and secure, free of fear, and conducive to learning

2. School  and youth violence has affected every student.

3. Youth CAN make a difference and show they are the solution.</description>
  <mission>Decrease youth violence in our schools and communities by promoting meaningful student involvement, education and service opportunities in efforts to provide safer environments for learning. </mission>
  <name>Students Against Violence Everywhere (SAVE)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4745</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">654</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xc/M4/bi/Js/TI/jp/IrmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
