<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hillel is a &#8220;home away from home&#8221; for IU&#8217;s Jewish students, serving as a home base for students and providing a center for Jewish community to students facing the many new experiences of campus life.  Students can stop by to hang out, grab some FREE food, hang out with other students make new friends, to participate in one of our many programs, or to take advantage of our FREE matzah ball soup hotline (if you don't know about it...then just call us up and we will bring the soup to your door!). 

Most of Hillel&#8217;s programs are student initiated by the Student Leadership Cabinet.  These students oversee our student groups that create, plan and implement all of our social, religious, cultural and educational activities and programs.  Suggestions are always welcome.

Whether it is to satisfy your hunger with Hillel&#8217;s open fridge policy, or relax in the family room while watching television on the big screen, Hillel can truly be a home away from home. Students can study in our library, check email, surf the web using Hillel&#8217;s free wireless internet or the computers in the student office, play pool in the student lounge, or work out in the full Cybex weight facility.

For more info on IU's Hillel Foundation, please visit our website:  www.iuhillel.org


1. To enhance student life on campus

2. To serve as a support system for students while they are away from home

3. Serves as a center for Jewish life on campus</description>
  <mission>serve as a Jewish home away from home for IU student, and to be a center for diversity education on campus</mission>
  <name>Helene G. Simon Hillel Center at Indiana University</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4746</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">156</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.5</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sb/S7/we/Ge/0c/fH/PBDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
