<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Americans for Peace Now (APN) was founded in 1981 to support the activities of Shalom Achshav (Peace Now in Israel). APN is the leading United States advocate for peace in the Middle East. APN's mission is to help Israel and the Shalom Achshav movement to achieve a comprehensive political settlement of the Arab-Israeli conflict consistent with Israel's long-term security needs and its Jewish and democratic values. APN's activities have grown over the years to include: 

&lt;p&gt;Action Network-APN's Action Network generates immediate and forceful grassroots responses to political developments through its national membership base.

&lt;p&gt;Government Relations-APN builds relationships with members of Congress, congressional staff, and Executive Branch officials in order to educate them about important developments in the Middle East and the implications of policy choices presented to decision-makers.

&lt;p&gt;American Jewish Community Outreach-Through its membership in the Conference of Presidents of Major American Jewish Organizations, APN works with other mainstream American Jewish groups to support peace for Israel.

&lt;p&gt;Media Outreach and Monitoring-APN promotes its goals through press releases, editorials, and personal contacts with reporters. It is a respected source of balanced information on the Middle East, providing insightful commentary and analysis to interested journalists.

&lt;p&gt;Public Outreach-APN publishes a weekly email/fax newsletter on Middle East events, along with a quarterly newsletter and other information sheets. In addition, it maintains an active web site with the latest information from the organization, and it sends speakers to communities around the country to promote the cause of peace.

&lt;p&gt;http://www.peacenow.org

1. The creation of a viable Palestinian state that accomodates Israel's security requirements.

2. The evacuation of settlements.

3. The establishment of a credible negotiating track and the concomitant renewal of effective security cooperation.</description>
  <mission>To help Israel and Israel's Peace Now achieve a comprehensive political settlement of the Arab-Israeli conflict consistent with Israel's long-term security needs and its Jewish and democratic values.</mission>
  <name>Americans for Peace Now</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4768</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">224</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Pu/pU/sq/HQ/UL/o4/UDjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
