<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Pachamama Alliance is a U.S. based not-for-profit organization that was born out of a relationship developed between a group of people from the modern world and the leaders of remote indigenous groups in the Amazon region of Ecuador. This relationship was actually initiated by the indigenous elders and shamans themselves who, out of their deep concern for the growing threat to their ancient way of life, and their recognition that the roots of this threat lay far beyond their rainforest home, actively sought the partnership of committed individuals living in the modern world.

A consistent message that has been delivered by the leaders of indigenous groups is that one of the most powerful actions that can be taken in support of the rainforest is to "change the dream of the North." Projects that halt deforestation are timely and critical but only deal with the symptom of a more fundamental imbalance. Ultimately, to assure the survival of our rainforests-indeed of nature's ecosystems and even ourselves-causes which are deeply rooted in our modern worldview need to be addressed. Historically, our record of dealing with issues of environmental degradation provides little basis for optimism in the face of this challenge. Yet, the historical record is the product of a different time. Technology now supplies instantaneous feedback on the consequences of our actions and forces us to come to grips with the reality of living in the closed, interconnected system we call life on Earth. The growing sense of wonder and appreciation we feel for the very same natural systems that we now see our actions destroy provides the basis for hope. There is a new possibility that the future will not be an extension of our past. We have an unprecedented opportunity to live from a new vision-one formed from the intersection of our technological prowess and a new respect for the Earth.

Join us in bringing forth an environmentally sustainable, spiritually fulfilling and socially just human presence on Planet Earth.


www.pachamama.org

Stay updated and connect with others--join us on these sites!

Facebook: http://www.facebook.com/pages/Pachamama-Alliance/48485058304
Twitter: www.twitter.com/PachamamaOrg
Myspace: www.myspace.com/ThePachamamaAlliance
YouTube: www.youtube.com/user/ThePachamamaAlliance
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/companies/the-pachamama-alliance

1. Environmental Sustainability

2. Spiritual Fulfillment

3. Social Justice</description>
  <mission>To preserve the Earth's tropical rainforests by empowering the indigenous people who are its natural custodians and to inspire individuals to bring forth a thriving, just and sustainable world.</mission>
  <name>The Pachamama Alliance</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4773</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6542</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">7545.23</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/UK/EY/rO/HB/Sr/1Q/JA/etS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
