<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>GiGi&#8217;s Playhouse is a not for profit Down syndrome awareness center. With multiple locations, we offer activities, resources, educational programs and support for individuals with Down syndrome, their families, and the community. At GiGi&#8217;s Playhouse we celebrate the lives and showcase the talents and potential of individuals with Down syndrome. GiGi&#8217;s Playhouse is something different for everyone whether it&#8217;s a hug, a party, or an educational experience but most importantly GiGi&#8217;s Playhouse is a place to belong. The minute you walk in the door you can&#8217;t help but smile and by touched by Down syndrome!

More specifically we:
-Provide encouragement, support and up-to-date resource information to new parents of babies with Down syndrome
-Help pregnant mothers with the diagnosis of DS
-Provide a &#8220;place&#8221; for support groups, meetings, activities, etc&#8230;
-Network with parents and professionals
-Provide free literacy classes &amp; create individualized reading materials
-Offer programming for children &amp; adults with DS
-Offer extended programming for siblings, family, and the community
-Share research, literature, books, information &amp; resources
-Raise awareness through community events
-Help educate schools, churches &amp; hospitals
-Present at national conferences
-Provide multicultural play groups
-Support all families touched by DS

www.gigisplayhouse.org


1. We celebrate the lives of individuals with Down syndrome.

2. We believe in the talents and potential of individuals with Down syndrome.

3. We support all families touched by Down syndrome.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to bring Down syndrome awareness to the community!</mission>
  <name>GiGi's Playhouse</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4778</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">931</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">40.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0Z/Lr/H6/j4/Nx/VB/BwUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
