<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Centrally located in vibrant downtown Ferndale, just a mile from the Detroit City border, Affirmations is the center for LGBT activities throughout the community.   In keeping with its vision, Affirmations is the hub of the community, celebrating wellness, personal growth and development, centered in a state-of-the-art, multi-use facility that is financially secure. Because of its ability to change and meet community needs, Affirmations, a 501 (c) (3) nonprofit organization, has become not only the largest LGBT organization in Michigan, but also one of the ten largest in the United States. 

Programs include a nationally renowned youth services program, health services program, discussion and support groups, and social and recreational activities.  Resources at the center include our toll-free Helpline, the Pittmann-Puckett Art Gallery, game room, Bayard Rustin Resource Center and Library, and our volunteer and leadership development program. 

1. Affirmations strives to create an atmosphere of safety and acceptance for all people. Our focus is on helping lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender individuals find and develop community where we value and respect ourselves and others. Affirmations philo

2. Empowerment is the experience of feeling our power to effect change and create the life we were meant to live. We recognize one's ability to make one's own decisions and to live a rewarding and fulfilling life in ways that do not harm others. Affirmations

3. Holistic approaches to programs and services at Affirmations help to counter the impact of heterosexism and homophobia. Lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender people still live in a world that does not always recognize and honor our identity. We believe t

4. Strength-based approaches recognize that as a community, lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender people have the ability to meet their human needs. We work to counter the homophobic and heterosexist messages that indicate LGBT people are somehow deficient.</description>
  <mission>Affirmations is an evolving community center where all who gather are embraced and are free to be their authentic selves.</mission>
  <name>Affirmations</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4780</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">135</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">530.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yu/iV/MI/m8/fK/MR/wYJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
