<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>IHRF was formed to sponsor the development of new research to determine why IH happens and how new therapies might better manage the disorder while seeking a cure. A five-member, volunteer Board of Directors administers the Foundation, while a volunteer Medical Advisory Team screens and selects the most promising medical research projects. The Foundation will also promote the involvement of new researchers and research laboratories by identifying specific problems that need to be solved. 

We believe that education is a significant part of the process, which is why IHRF seeks to educate researchers, clinicians, patients and their families, and the general public about IH through Foundation-sponsored conferences, scientific symposia, this Web site, Foundation newsletters, and related printed media. 

IHRF recognizes the needs of those afflicted with IH. We encourage and aid patients and their families. One of our goals is to develop a national network of support groups for IH patients. A directory of resources containing the latest information on IH research, related articles, treatment options, and links to other relevant Internet sites is being compiled. We also intend to initiate the first professionally organized IH patient registry. 
----------------------------------------------

Description of PTC/IH

Pseudotumor cerebri literally means "false brain tumor." It is likely due to high pressure caused by the buildup or poor absorption of cerebrospinal fluid in the subarachnoid space surrounding the brain. The disorder is most common in women between the ages of 20 and 50. Symptoms of pseudotumor cerebri, which include headache, nausea, vomiting, and pulsating intracranial noises, closely mimic symptoms of brain tumors. This is an extremely rare disorder.

Info on this  page from the IHRF

1. We have a right to better treatments

2. We have a right to a cure

3. More people need to be informed of this rare disorder</description>
  <mission>To find better treatments &amp; a cure for PTC/ICH</mission>
  <name>Pseudotumor Cerebri/Intracranial Hypertension/IHR Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4782</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5369</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1242.65</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Km/F7/rt/Yq/xT/U6/qWcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
