<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Tiger Cubs is a year-round family- and home-centered program that encourages the ethical decision-making skills for first-grade (or 7-year-old) boys. These boys participate in the program with their adult partners. The program emphasizes shared leadership, learning about the community, and family understanding.

Cub Scouts is a year-round family- and home-centered program that develops ethical decision-making skills for boys in the second through fifth grade (or who are 8, 9, and 10 years old). Activities emphasize character development, citizenship training, and personal fitness.

Webelos Scouts is a year-round family- and home-centered program that develops ethical decision-making skills for fourth- and fifth-grade (or 10-year-old) boys. Webelos Scouts participate in more advanced activities that begin to prepare them to become Boy Scouts.

Boy Scouting. A year-round program for boys 11 through 17 designed to achieve the aims of Scouting through a vigorous outdoor program and peer group leadership with the counsel of an adult Scoutmaster. (Boys also may become Boy Scouts if they have earned the Cub Scouting Arrow of Light Award and are at least 10 years old or have completed the fifth grade and are at least 10 years old.)

Varsity Scouting. An active, exciting, year-round program for young men 14 through 17 built around five program fields of emphasis: advancement, high adventure, personal development, service, and special programs and events.

Venturing. A year-round program for young men and women who are 14 (and have completed the eighth grade) through 20 years of age to provide positive experiences through exciting and meaningful youth-run activities that help them pursue their special interests, grow by teaching others, and develop leadership skills.

1. The Boy Scouts of America was incorporated to provide a program for community organizations that offers effective character, citizenship, and personal fitness training for youth.

2. The BSA endeavors to develop American citizens who are physically, mentally, and emotionally fit; have a high degree of self-reliance as evidenced in such qualities as initiative, courage, and resourcefulness; have personal values based on religious conce</description>
  <mission>prepare young people to make ethical choices over their lifetime by instilling in them the values of the Scout Oath and Law.</mission>
  <name>Boy Scouts of America Utah National Parks Council</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4786</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">104</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.81</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Su/My/gh/ew/Rw/Eo/qTRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
