<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>ALS (Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis), commonly known as Lou Gehrig's Disease, is a progressive neuromuscular disease.  It damages motor neurons, the nerve cells that control all voluntary movement.  People living with ALS gradually lose the ability to walk, talk, and even breath on their own.  The life expectancy after diagnosis is three to five years.  Drugs have been found that substantially slow the progression of the disease, but doctors are still searching for a cure.

The ALS Hope Foundation is a nonprofit organization based at Drexel University College of Medicine in Philadelphia.  It researches possible treatments, funds research for other organizations, and cares for ALS patients.  The MDA/ALS Center of Hope provides medical care and counseling for patients, as well as a strong support system for family and friends.


www.alshopefoundation.org


P.S. -- One way you can help is by using Goodsearch anytime you need to make an internet search! Goodsearch is run by Yahoo and donates $0.01 to any charity that you choose every time you search.  It's a very easy way to help the Hope Foundation or any charity.  

Goodsearch also runs Goodshop, where you can shop at Amazon, Apple, Best Buy, Banana Republic, Sephora, etc. and a percentage of your purchase will be donated to the Hope Foundation!

www.goodsearch.com

1. ALS patients deserve the care and the tools to live as normally as possible.

2. People living with ALS--patients, family, and friends--need a support system.  They need people to lean on for help, guidance, and strength.

3. Hope is on the horizon. We get closer to finding a cure every day.</description>
  <mission>provide care for ALS patients and search for a cure</mission>
  <name>ALS Hope Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4787</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">620</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5H/FI/y1/n2/hL/es/UpES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
