<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Cutting off a husky puppy's head with a chainsaw... sounds like a horror flick, right? Not this time... someone in South Africa did it recently to his own dog. Add your voice to the growing number of people locally and internationally who want this abhorrent act to be taken more seriously by the South African courts.

THE WHAT...
On 22 February 2007, Phillip Matthysen, a South African man reportedly killed his Husky puppy after it instinctively bit out at his parrot and killed it (News24.com, 19 June 2007). It was reported that along with an accomplice, he allegedly proceeded to hold the dog down and cut its head off with a chainsaw. Due to a lack of comprehensive animal rights and protection in South Africa's legal system,  people committing these hideous acts stand to walk free with little or no consequences - this site exists to help gather support to stop this from happening!

THE HOW...
I have spoken to Mr. G Schultz, the prosecutor on this case, and arranged to meet him on July 23rd. I plan to give him a minimum of 25 000 of our signatures. There is no guarantee that this action will have the desired effect however our hope is that at worst, the magistrate will know there are more people watching this case than just those sitting in the court room.

You can also go to http://www.ecosystem.co.za/huskyjustice/, for more information about what is happening and how you can get involved.

-JONO- &amp; Lara

1. People found guilty of committing these inhuman acts of violence against animals are prosecuted to the maximum extent of the South African Law

2. Promotion of animal rights in South Africa, and around the world.

3. The prevention of animal abuse.</description>
  <mission>promote justice for animal rights in South Africa.</mission>
  <name>Husky Justice</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4788</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9613</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/IS/FF/lE/CF/uG/OM/42NS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
