<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Human's rights begin with children's rights. 
The major rights a human deserves, specifically as a child, are as followed.


"All children have the RIGHT to have their basic needs met, not only for survival and protection but also to be able to develop to their full potential, to participate as members of society (according to their age and development), and to grow up to be caring and responsible citizens.

The expression of the human rights for children take into account children's needs - the needs that must be met for children to have a happy and fulfilled childhood, so that they are able to grow to up to be strong, independent, caring and responsible citizens.

Survival: children first and foremost have a right to life - to have their basic physical needs met for food, shelter, safety, and health care.
Protection: they also need to be protected from injury and harm, not only physical but also emotional.
Development: they need all the things that will help them to grow and develop. They need friends and family, love and laughter. They need fresh air and safe places to play. They need stories and music, schools and libraries and all that stimulates the mind. They need to practice their culture and religion and to develop a sense of awe and wonder.
Participation: they need to share in the life of their family, school, community and nation, to take responsibilities and to have a voice. "




1. Children must be recognized as a productive part of society.  They are the future of the US.

2. Children must have more say in where, with whom, and how they live.

3. Children living with disabilities, violence, and poverty, must have their needs met.

4. Children have the right to have all of their needs met.</description>
  <mission>protect and preserve the rights those of us under the age of 18 deserve.</mission>
  <name>Child rights USA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4789</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">35</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/rl/Fc/k6/rQ/AX/jK/byZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
