<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For more than 50 years, Project HOPE has been providing health care to developing countries across the globe. The tragic reality is that, despite the progress made over the past half-century in reducing childhood deaths, 29,000 children under the age of five still die everyday, most of them in the developing world, and most of these from preventable causes. This toll is equivalent to a tsunami every week of the year, and it demands the same commitment to action. 

Some of our programs include: 
&#8226;	Providing permanent community facilities where mothers and children can receive basic preventive health care.
&#8226;	Creating Village Health Banks, providing low-income women with the means to improve their economic status as well as the knowledge and resources to improve their health and the health of their families
&#8226;	Training community health workers in a variety of interventions key to lowering child and maternal mortality rates. 
&#8226;	Delivering vaccines, antibiotics and basic medical supplies requested by the Ministries of Health or other HOPE partner agency in country, to save lives and extend the benefits of good health.
	
For more information on what we do, go to www.projecthope.org


1. EVERYONE should have the tools to fight HIV/AIDS, Hepatitis B, avian flu, tuberculosis, and malaria in their community, and should be taught preventio

2. EVERYONE should be able to count on someone for the aid they actually need during times of disaster.  

3. EVERYONE should have access to health care professionals in all areas of the world, and all healthcare professionals should receive the best possible 

4. EVERYONE deserves to have quality and accessible health care to meet their medical needs.</description>
  <mission>Campaign to Improve Health Care Around the World</mission>
  <name>Project HOPE</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4792</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">380</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">570.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5M/R2/zb/mq/UW/e4/xv/fqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
