<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria was established in 2002, with the support of the world's leaders and UN Secretary General Kofi Annan, to dramatically increase resources to fight three of the world's most devastating diseases, and to direct those resources to areas of greatest need by supporting locally-driven strategies. To date, the Global Fund has committed US$7 billion to 460 programs in 136 countries. 

The Global Fund is an innovative partnership of governments, non-profit organizations, and the private sector, working together to rid the world of AIDS, tuberculosis (TB) and malaria. Its sole purpose is to raise funds and make grants to countries, organizations and communities that urgently need financial help to allow them to respond to these epidemics. The Global Fund continues to fund grants dependent upon proven results and targets achieved. 

MEASU(RED) RESULTS
Many thanks to you for purchasing (RED) products: In May, $1.25 million of the first (RED) money received by the Global Fund flowed to Rwanda. This has gone towards the Rwandan Ministry of Health's comprehensive HIV/AIDS programs, mainly to provide anti-retroviral treatment for children and adults in a third of the country. 

During the week of September 11, 2006, $4 million of (RED) money flowed to Swaziland. Derek von Wissell, director of National Emergency Response Council on HIV/AIDS, described where the money will go: "First, a large portion of the money will be directed to orphans - feeding them, keeping them in school, protecting them and offering them a future. Second, some of the money will help support the treatment of people on anti-retroviral therapy. (RED) is saving lives. (RED) is helping orphans survive and giving them a better future. (RED) will make a difference." 

1. (RED) is the color of emergency. 5,500 people dying every day

2. It&#8217;s an economic initiative designed to support the treatment of people on anti-retroviral therapy</description>
  <mission>To raise awareness and money for The Global Fund, a percentage of each (PRODUCT)RED product sold is given to The Global Fund. The money helps women and children affected by HIV/AIDS in Africa.</mission>
  <name>Join (RED)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4795</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">45198</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1795.38</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Eb/Uq/sh/GA/Wp/Li/o7VS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
