<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is all a part of the hope campaign 
A peoples campaign from the UK and truly global. It is person lead, we are about education, hope, speaking out and standing together strong.

Its about time we focus in all thats good about us, believing and never giving up no matter what. The faith that we have within, letting that flame of hope burn brighter than before,
we got to come together and stand up, stand up with defiance, belief and truth. With all that we have got to come together and be united in giving a voice for all those who are suffering at the hands of those who do this crime of forced marriages. For change can only happen with us combined with every hope.
We got to walk the streets, talk on the net, have talks

come on people

The university initiative against forced marriages 
A proposal of action that could be implemented into action
The proposal is that Universities across South Wales,  And the whole of the UK  have collaboration in an effort in the awareness of Forced Marriages and the information  for students in the respective Universities.
The student groups in The Universities will link up

These are the main points of emphasis 

To raise awareness of forced marriages and related incidents involving both men and women. The Vital Statistics and information are known about. To go deep than that.
to work within the community, with schools, Universities and public libraries, religious institutions and leaders to enforce the messages that &#8216;Forced marriages ruin lives&#8217; and are fundamentally wrong.  

It is a of breach human rights 

No one has the right to force an individual into a situation such as a Forced Marriage.

That there is specialist help available (organisations e.g. miss Dorthory) out there for them, not to suffer alone, and it is not their fault that this happening.

To make well known that there is help/support, special help lines, websites, people to talk to. And for these to be passed on (go to these and give out leaflets and posters. Link into the key Information

The further objective is for there then for Then to be a conference organized for once a year whereby all the Universities get together.All aspects of  forced marriages will be discussed

The Goals are for an up and running united collaborative effort with this working initiatve
The Universities to have an organization 
To have a conference once a year

workable and realistic initiative that will only be achieved through dedication and networking
This will further drive the effort in the awareness of Forced Marriages in the South Wales area and throughout the UK and a Student; led united university initiative will mark a step in the direction

Project &#8211; One Voice, Mission statement &#8211; To be combined to be one to speak with one voice. 

The plans &#8211; for networking site for Forced Marriages (Hope) Plans for change 
The path wont be easy, even when we fall we will get there every step of the way
It is dedicated to those who are suffering because of a social evil that be stopped in everyway. And we will be the ears that hear their voice and the voice that speaks for them, we will be one voice. And through the networking site we will achieve this, a combined reinforced unit.

The Objective to get a vast networking site up and running to follow in line with the campaign manifesto to further explore this and push even further than before. 

We must endeavour to adapt and further our attempts to get people involved in being apart of change in the attitudes to forced marriages. Working as a combined unit is the most practical sustainable option to follow.  A major networking site would be a major development and serve as a centre base for all plans and needs to do what we can. A talk arena is where people discuss ideas and share information
and the site is all our ground to come together and be one combined in one area, pool of resources.



</description>
  <mission>This Document is regarding a proposed University collaborated effort in the raising of the awareness of Forced Marriages</mission>
  <name>Hope Campaign - Forced Marriages Shouldnt happen anymore.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4804</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">194</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/r7/tg/NI/pJ/uV/Gc/1M8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
