<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dalit comprise a staggering 25% of the total population of India. These 250 million people are the &#8220;outcastes&#8221; of Indian society &#8211; the &#8220;untouchables&#8221; &#8211; those called the &#8220;unborn&#8221;, as it would have been better for them had they never been born.

The Dalit are among the poorest of the world&#8217;s poor; they are stripped of their basic humanity, are denied basic human rights, and are entrenched in a system that gives them no freedom. Dalit are denied access to public wells and public parks. Many restaurants use separate drinking glasses for Dalit.

Dalit women are sold into bonded prostitution. Even finding a place to bury their dead is a problem.

Seventy percent of Dalit live below the poverty line. Only two to three percent of rural Dalit women can read and write.

The Dalit Freedom Network (DFN) began in 2002 to respond to the cries of Dalits for help in their quest for freedom from caste slavery. DFN has wholly embraced the idea of village transformation. Our goal is to see 1,000 villages in India holistically transformed over the next decade. 

For more information on DFN, see http://dalitnetwork.org

For more information on Dalits, check out these HRW reports:

http://hrw.org/campaigns/caste/presskit.htm
http://www.hrw.org/reports/2007/india0207/
http://www.hrw.org/reports/1999/india/


1. EDUCATION begins the process of change

2. HEALTHCARE must complement transformation

3. Dalit parents need ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT to support their families

4. SOCIAL JUSTICE means legal protection and international awareness</description>
  <mission>To empower the Dalits in their quest for social freedom and human dignity by networking human, financial, and informational resources.</mission>
  <name>Free the Dalit</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4807</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2137</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">402.48</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rz/MG/fQ/CI/Ef/5v/Gn0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
