<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Young American's for Freedom was established in 1960 to promote conservative values across across America as embodied in The Sharon Statement - especially among young people.

Specifically, the purpose of this cause is to restore Young Americans for Freedom to its rightful place as a powerhouse of the conservative movement ready and willing to fight liberalism wherever it may be.

1. Foremost among the transcendent values is the individual's use of his God-given free will, whence derives his right to be free from the restrictions of arbitrary force.

2. Liberty is indivisible, and political freedom cannot long exist without economic freedom.

3. The purpose of government is to protect those freedoms through the preservation of internal order, the provision of national defense, and the administration of justice.

4. When government ventures beyond these rightful functions, it accumulates power, which tends to diminish order and liberty.

5. The Constitution of the United States is the best arrangement yet devised for empowering government to fulfill its proper role, while restraining it from the concentration and abuse of power.

6. The genius of the Constitution - the division of powers - is summed up in the clause that reserves primacy to the several states, or to the people in those spheres not specifically delegated to the Federal government.

7. The market economy, allocating resources by the free play of supply and demand, is the single economic system compatible with the requirements of personal freedom and constitutional government. 

8. When government interferes with the work of the market economy, it tends to reduce the moral and physical strength of the nation.  When it takes from one to bestow on another, it diminishes the incentive of the first and the integrity of the second.

9. We will be free only so long as the national sovereignty of the United States is secure; that history shows periods of freedom are rare, and can exist only when free citizens concertedly defend their rights against all enemies.

10. The forces of international Communism are, at present, the greatest single threat to these liberties.

11. The United States should stress victory over, rather than coexistence with this menace.

12. American foreign policy must be judged by this criterion: does it serve the just interests of the United States? </description>
  <mission>promote conservatives values.</mission>
  <name>Young Americans for Freedom</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4839</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">44</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wO/80/pr/8b/Gl/Mt/XtDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
