<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I want Tom Tancredo to be President, but I will probably vote for Mitt Romney since he has more electability. So why am I making a group about Ron Paul? Well, I think that Ron Paul is a much needed figure in the political spotlight who can open up some very interesting conversation in the Republican Party. I wouldn't want him to be President because of his very libertarian views on most issues, but I think he has the potential to change the current Republican Party for the better. He represents a return to traditional conservatism that the Republican Party seems to have strayed from. He describes himself not as a conservative, since "conservatism" has been hijacked by current Republicans, but rather he calls himself a "constitutionalist". We need our candidates to promote responsible fiscal policy that involves a stable currency, and we also need a return to our Constitution. Ron Paul also believes that inflation is the worst kind of tax imposed on Americans. He sees a need to get inflation under control. What distinguishes him most from fellow Republican candidates is the fact that while he supports the "just war" theory as happened in Afghanistan, he rejects pre-emptive war as happened in Iraq. He shows that liberals shouldn't have a monopoly on the antiwar movement. After all, Eisenhower was the Supreme Allied Commander during World War 2. When he became President after the war, he pursued peace in the world. Nixon sought an honorable peace in Vietnam. Both were Republicans. I see Ron Paul as a modern version of our founding fathers. While neoconservatives like Rudy Giuliani and Bill O'Reilly try to pigeonhole him, or misrepresent his ideas, the Republican Party would be wise to take Ron Paul's ideas into consideration.

1. Ron Paul is a much needed voice in today's Republican Party.

2. We need a return to the Constitution and stable monetary policies.

3. Conservatives can oppose a war too. It's not just a liberal thing.</description>
  <mission>Change the current Republican Party by incorporating some of Ron Paul's ideas into Republican thought.</mission>
  <name>Ron Paul Republican Reform</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4852</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">25</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fG/5W/x4/GB/0k/3C/r3OS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
