<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>AD[H]D, or Attention Deficit [Hyperactivity] Disorder, is famous, but not for anything good. People who have ADD are told they are just trying to make excuses to daydream in class and not turn in their homework.

Subject to jokes and insults, we go through life thinking that ADD is a curse; in fact, the very name Attention Deficit Disorder lends itself to the idea that ADD is a sickness, or something that's not quite right which maybe, someday, can be fixed by technology or good psychologists. 

This cause is to publicly state that these thoughts are wrong. ADD is not a curse, but a gift. We should not hide it. There are so many positives to having ADD, but because of the "disorder" tagged onto the end, people shy away from it, or take pills in the hopes that it will go away. 

In fact, there are scores of things that make having AD"D" better than not having it. Those of us with ADD are:

1. daydreamers-- allows us to think things through in different ways without rushing
2. oversensitive-- makes us compassionate and loving friends, good listeners, and generous spirits.
3. impulsive-- gives a literally &#8220;fresh&#8221; perspective on everything and doesn't let us be overly cautious when decisions have to be made.
4. easily bored-- stops us from being too clingy when we ought to let things go. 

... not to mention how focused we are when things do matter, our ability to cut to the chase, how bright we are, and what creative things we come up with after all that mind work. 

Let's face it. ADD isn't a disorder at all. In fact, it's a blessing. Yes, sometimes we get distracted, but when we snap back into focus, great things happen. 
Fellow ADDers, friends, family, supporters, join up.

[All donations will go straight to Unique Minds, a support and advocacy group for children and adults with ADD.]

1. ADD is not a disorder.

2. Having ADD is not a negative thing.</description>
  <mission>to help raise awareness about the positives of ADD.</mission>
  <name>Appreciate ADD/ADHD</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4858</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2238</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ur/bR/Yc/nN/Ts/dD/CXgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
