<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Vision
Raising children who transform nations

Mission
Partnering with nationals to provide holistic, Christ-centered care for orphaned and destitute children, enabling them to create positive and lasting change in their nations

Strategy
To mobilize a movement of people, making possible the mission

Philosophy
Movement vs. Organization: Children of the Nations sees itself as a &#8220;movement of people&#8221; gathered by God to provide quality care to children under His guidance. He has created a worldwide body of people with a common passion who deny themselves to care for children. Children of the Nations is not a &#8220;missionary sending&#8221; agency but utilizes individuals from around the globe, tapping into their talents in a professional manner, which strategically assists the overall mission in accomplishing its goals

History
Chris and Debbie Clark founded COTN in 1995. God was working in their lives many years before, however, preparing the couple for this ministry.

Chris is himself a fifth-generation missionary raised in Africa by missionary parents. Convinced that God called him to minister to children, he pursued a career with Youth for Christ (YFC), where he worked as Director for ten years. Debbie, a teacher for ten years, also had a heart attuned to children in special need of care.

Today, COTN is working in the USA, Dominican Republic, Sierra Leone, Malawi, and most recently in Uganda to provide relief for orphaned and destitute children. COTN operates homes, schools, farms, skill centers, clinics and village feeding centers in an effort to give quality care to our children. Each country is established with an individual nonprofit organization.

From the initial desire in 1995, to &#8220;rescue&#8221; children from their despair, to today&#8212;creating a family for each child, COTN has come so far. Today, hundreds of staff members and thousands of volunteers provide care to rescue and raise tens of thousands of children who then are learning to be leaders for tomorrow!

1. Orphaned and Destitute Children

2. Holistic Care

3. Positive and Lasting Change</description>
  <mission>Raising children who transform nations (in Sierra Leone, Malawi, Uganda, and the Dominican Republic )</mission>
  <name>Children of the Nations</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/486</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7946</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3485.41</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/RH/6o/ns/UZ/uA/nC/O2/P7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
