<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A 1997 World Bank study estimated the annual cost of Pakistan&#8217;s environmental problems at US$1.8 billion in health expenditures, reduced labor productivity, and other costs. The availability of natural resources is limited by the dry climate and mountainous terrain, substantial population growth is increasing pressure on the resource base, and resource management has suffered from the emphasis on rapid economic growth and often-unregulated forms of economic productivity. As a result, human transformation of the environment is manifest in several problems. Population growth and poor water infrastructure have reduced per capita water availability from 53,000 cubic meters to 1,200 cubic meters, and heavy reliance on firewood has contributed to the world&#8217;s second highest rate of deforestation. Poor agricultural practices have led to soil erosion, groundwater degradation, and other problems that have hindered crop output and contributed to health problems for rural communities. Solid waste burning, low-quality fuels, and the growing use of fuel-inefficient motor vehicles have contributed to air pollution that in some cities&#8212;such as Karachi, Islamabad, Lahore, Peshawar, Quetta, Faisalabad and Rawalpindi&#8212;has exceeded levels deemed safe by the World Health Organization.

1.   Sustainable environmental management and energy development to improve the livelihoods and security of the poor

2.  Regional and global instruments for environmentally sustainable development that benefit the poor</description>
  <mission>Environmental issues in Pakistan threaten the economy and the population&#8217;s health, and there is little indication of their abatement.</mission>
  <name>Environmental issues in Pakistan</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4871</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">29</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vN/3L/ba/Uc/Fe/Ku/VcPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
