<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The New Haven region has the 7th greatest income disparity in the nation when comparing the poverty in our central city (and increasingly in our inner ring communities of West Haven , East Haven and Hamden ) with the wealth of our outer ring suburbs.   While jobs are growing in low-wage sectors and shrinking in high-wage industries, the cost of housing is increasing. Today a worker needs to earn approximately $35,000 annually to afford a two-bedroom apartment. The average number of homeless in New Haven each night is 1,200. 

United Way is committed to helping close this economic gap by working with partners to create a region where everyone has the opportunity to secure, safe and affordable housing, the skills and training needed to succeed in decent paying jobs and the means to be self-sufficient. United Way investments in innovative supportive housing solutions, job training, youth employment, and community conversations about what it takes to be a competitive region not only improve the lives of individuals and families but also strengthen our entire region. 

1. Increase the number of people employed in jobs that provide a livable wage.

2. Increase the number of youth, adults, and special populations that have the skills and education, including literacy, numeracy, and English-language s

3. Increase the number of jobs for youth.

4. Increase the number of families and individuals living in safe, affordable and decent housing.

5. Increase access to affordable, supportive housing for families and individuals with special needs and disabilities.</description>
  <mission>Generate increased opportunities for financial stability  </mission>
  <name>Promoting Financial Stability and Independence in Greater New Haven</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4887</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">16</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wY/SE/nD/cB/iJ/AH/VE/6pS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
