<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>After the 2005 Hurricane Katrina, Beyonce&#180;, Mathew and Tina Knowles along with Kelly Rowland founded The Survivor Foundation, a non-profit 501c(3) organization in efforts to help assist those who are still in need and affected by the horrible devastation.

We were established exclusively to raise, receive and distribute funds to assist families and individuals displaced by disasters, those who are homeless, and ex-offenders seeking to rebuild their lives in the Houston metropolitan area. 

We will partner with various community organizations and churches to identify potential families and individuals who might benefit from its services. 


We will offer a &#8220;Survivor Starter Kit,&#8221; which will provide the necessary educational materials and financial tools to families and individuals for a maximum of six months. The Kit will provide supplement housing, assistance with job training and placement, as well as transportation assistance. 


We will partner with public and private entities as well as non-profit organizations to provide job training and placement.  Our partnership with automobile dealers and auto leasing companies will aid in the transportation assistance. 


We are committed to providing emotional as well as short term financial support. 


We are committed to assisting families and individuals in rebuilding their lives. 


We are implementing our plan to build the Knowles-Rowland Building which to honor our 501c(3) status will be a 48-unit Short Term to Long Term Transitional Housing Facility. 


1. People devastated by this horrible event deserve a boost financially

2. Many are homeless or living in shelters, we can provide housing 

3. Many children have received no education in the past two years, we feel they need some and we can help</description>
  <mission>To help transform the lives of survivors of social, economic and catastrophic hardships by providing assistance, education and support.</mission>
  <name>Survivor Foundation Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4890</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fW/jW/vT/7l/KC/Bb/CKoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
