<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There are so many riders out there that over work their horses so that they can reach a certian goal for themselves or possibly just because of pride and ignorance. This cause to get equestrains aware that their horses are not machines and cant work as long and hard as they want, when they want. Many lame horses become lame by human error.

According to internationally famous veterinarian, Dr. James Rooney, most lameness in horses is related to mechanical factors. These include the horse's conformation, the type of work asked to do, and the various incidental traumas experienced.


Lame means moving with pain or difficulty.

.


GROUPS CREATED BY HALLE D.G.:
http://hs.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2259107091
http://hs.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2258522120

.

My Horse May Be Lame:
http://acreageequines.com/HorseCare/horsecare5.htm
.
VOULENTEER:  www.horsenethorserescue.org

1. Human error is a sad reason for a horse to go lame.

2. To many talented horses are lost to lameness. 

3. People need to learn that just because we are the most dominate species, doesnt mean we shouldnt care for the ones below us. 

4. Not only can over working your horse be dangerous and risking their physical health, but their mental health. 

5. Over working your horse can cause them mental distress, because of the stress of working to vigorously.

6. IF YOUR HORSE DOES BECOME PERNAMENTLY LAME. DO NOT EVEN CONSIDER THE SLAUGHTER HOUSE. ABUSE IS TO COMMON. 

7. We are not here to point fingers at riders with lame horses. accident do happen. so dont feel afriad to join.</description>
  <mission> To educate people so that horses do not become lame by human error and ignorance.</mission>
  <name>BEING LAME IS LAME</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4908</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1114</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DE/3r/rV/vL/lm/ME/s7lS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
