<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is Panic Disorder?

Panic disorder is an anxiety disorder and is characterized by unexpected and repeated episodes of intense fear accompanied by physical symptoms that may include chest pain, heart palpitations, shortness of breath, dizziness, or abdominal distress.

People with panic disorder have feelings of terror that strike suddenly and repeatedly with no warning. They can't predict when an attack will occur, and many develop intense anxiety between episodes, worrying when and where the next one will strike.

When a panic attack strikes, most likely your heart pounds and you may feel sweaty, weak, faint, or dizzy. Your hands may tingle or feel numb, and you might feel flushed or chilled. You may have chest pain or smothering sensations, a sense of unreality, or fear of impending doom or loss of control.

***********************************
People who have full-blown, repeated panic attacks can become very disabled by their condition and should seek treatment before they start to avoid places or situations where panic attacks have occurred. For example, if a panic attack happened in an elevator, someone with panic disorder may develop a fear of elevators that could affect the choice of a job or an apartment, and restrict where that person can seek medical attention or enjoy entertainment.

*********************************


1. Panic disorders should be treated more seriously- we should be given other options then just medication

2. WE are not freaks..everyone gets anxiety at one point or time in their lifes.</description>
  <mission>-help people cope -share are stories and are ways of dealing so that we can help each other</mission>
  <name>Panic/Anxiety Disorders</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4925</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2195</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1.63</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/LL/uK/sO/GT/ed/bu/OGjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
