<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>On the morning of August 8th, 1970, a pod of killer whales were traveling peacefully off the coast of Washington but were soon disturbed. A capture team was waiting for them and in the hunt captured 7 Orcas, but 5 others died from the struggle. The 5 that were killed were sliced open to be weighted, had anchors tied to their tails, and then sank to the bottom of the sea. This caused national headlines and incited public outrage. 

As for the 7 Orcas who were captured, all of them were sold to aquariums around the world. One Orca was sold to the Miami Seaquarium in Florida. She was given the name &#8220;Lolita&#8221;. At the Miami Seaquarium, Lolita was reunited with another Orca by the name of Hugo, who was also captured from the same family. For 10 years, Lolita and Hugo performed at the Miami Seaquarium, but they were confined to one of the smallest whale tanks in North America. In fact, the tank is so small that it violates the minimum size of Orca tanks set by the Animal Welfare Act. 

In 1980, Hugo killed himself by ramming his head continuously against the side of the tank. Upon his death he was dumped in the Dade County dump and still lies there today. Today, Hugo does not even have a tribute or dedication plaque to him, and some trainers even deny his existence at the aquarium. As a result of Hugo&#8217;s suicide, Lolita was left alone at the tank for nearly 20 years. 

Aside from being isolated alone in her small tank, her owner refuses to build her a larger tank. He has consistently promised to build her a new tank, but has yet to fulfill his promise. He only wants Lolita for money and refuses to use the money earned by Lolita to build her a new tank. 

As of today, Lolita is the only remaining survivor of the 45 Orcas that were captured from Washington. It seems that Lolita is destined to die alone at the Miami Seaquarium unless something is done.

&#8230;R.I.P. Hugo

www.miamiseaprison.com

www.orcanetwork.org

1. Lolita's tank is too small for her let alone any other whale

2. Orcas are highly social but she has not spoken to another whale for more than 25 years

3. She misses her family</description>
  <mission>Give Lolita the killer whale a better life</mission>
  <name>Free Lolita</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4942</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2715</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">112.36</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ke/tP/Kl/P2/F7/fW/s4ES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
