<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 1983 by Nancy Alcorn, Mercy Ministries of America is an international, non-profit outreach to troubled young women between the ages of 13 and 28 who struggle with eating disorders, addictions, unplanned pregnancies, abuse, and other issues. Mercy provides a free loving environment where mercy triumphs over judgment and broken lives are lovingly put back together.

Why is Mercy Ministries unique?

Individual care plan
Each young woman who enters our program requires individual care and attention. We work with the young women to assess the individual issues they are facing and how best we can stage their recovery process.  The length of stay for a young woman varies from six to twelve months according to her individual issue and progress.  Graduation occurs when a young woman has worked through the stages of recovery and consistently demonstrates that she is equipped with the necessary life skills and strategies to integrate back into society and lead a productive and fulfilling life. 

Voluntary Program
Mercy Ministries is a voluntary program. Young women must be willing to work with the staff and be involved in all aspects of the program. Each young woman makes her own choice about how she will apply herself to, and participate in our program and commits to making the necessary changes the program requires.  

No Cost
Our program is provided at no cost to the young women. The purpose of this is to demonstrate that we value any young woman who is serious about changing her life, no matter who she is, what background she is from or what her financial circumstance. 

Websites:
http://www.mercyministries.org/ -Mercy's Official Website
&lt;p&gt;
http://www.mercyministries.org/shared/flash/Magazines/winter2008/ - The New Online Magazine
&lt;p&gt;
http://www.mercyministriesnews.com/ - Your up to date resource for Mercy Ministries and the founder
&lt;p&gt;
http://www.runformercy.org - Run For Mercy Website
&lt;p&gt;
http://www.doublemercy.com - Double Mercy
&lt;p&gt;
http://ucok.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2207578589 - Mercy M. Supporters and Friends
&lt;p&gt;
http://ucok.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2259509019 - Mercy Prayer Warriors!
&lt;p&gt;
http://www.facebook.com/pages/Mercy-Ministries/22919271064?ref=nfThe Mercy Fan page
&lt;p&gt;
http://groups.xanga.com/groups/group.aspx?id=1546185 - A Mercy M. Blog
&lt;p&gt;
http://www.myspace.com/mercyministriesglobalThe Myspace Page for Mercy Ministries
&lt;p&gt;
http://www.nancyalcorn.blogspot.com/ - Nancy's Blog

1. Mercy triumphs over judgment and broken lives are lovingly put back together

2. The Bible is the ultimate source of truth

3. Helping girls and young ladies win back their lives that God designed them to have.

4. "It is our belief that if we provide places free-of-charge where girls can come and receiv</description>
  <mission>To transform the lives of troubled girls by providing free residential care in an environment of unconditional love</mission>
  <name>Mercy Ministries</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4952</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">16824</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3508.49</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ve/h0/bc/bm/Kx/Xo/jNCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
