<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hinduism is the world's 3rd largest religion with around 900 million followers in India and many more around the world. It was not originally a religion but rather a set of philosophies which were contained in the Vedas and the Upanishads (written in 5000BC) and were followed by the people on the Indian subcontinent. 

The real name of Hinduism is "Santana Dharma" which means eternal knowledge. The word "Hindu" was used as a derogatory term by muslim and christian invaders and over time the people who follow the philosophy of the Vedas have come to be known as Hindus.  

Hinduism is a flexible philosophy with a broadly defined set of ideas. Each Hindu community follows its own version of it, yet they are all part of a common identity. The different versions of Hinduism and the differing practices lead to the misconception that Hinduism is polytheistic. In truth Hinduism believes in only one god - or one supreme consciousness. The gods such as Shiva, Brahma, Vishnu etc are only manifestations or representations of this one god, and others such as Ram and Krishna are only incarnations of this one god. So at its core Hinduism is monotheistic althought it may appear otherwise.

1. 1) Hinduism is not a religion but a philosophy. It teaches that there are many ways to reach god, and each man must find his own path. It is therefore one of the most tolerant religions, and the majority of world's religions find a home in India with it.

2. 2) Hinduism stresses on non-violence and has a history of pacifism. It does not support killing for any reason except to defend oneself. This treatment extends to other life forms as well, which is why most Hindus are vegetarian.

3. 3) Hinduism has no rigid set of rules. It does not claim to be the final word of god, or the one true religion. It puts forth the law of Karma which states that your actions are what matter. Good actions give good karma, and bad ones give bad karma.

4. Your karma is what you take with you at the end of your life. Good and bad itself cannot be strictly defined for you by any book and Hinduism only lays down guidelines. The final decision is left to the individual. 

5. 4) Hinduism is the oldest existing religion (pre 5000BC) yet it is the biggest supporter of science. Knowledge is given the highest importance, and books are practically worshipped. It will never oppose theories such as evolution or the big bang. 

6. Much of the world's mathematics was developed in India - from the base 10 decimal number system, to algebra and geometry. Credit for this can be attributed to the lack of hindrance from Hinduism which did not oppose any of these developments. 

7. 5) To summarize, Hinduism is a collection of philosophies, a set of knowledge handed down over the millenia. And as all philosophies can evolve, so will Hinduism.</description>
  <mission>To support Hinduism as a unified philosophy for the betterment of the world and to spread an understanding of it.</mission>
  <name>Support Hinduism</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/496</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">17214</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45.3</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mlj/ccsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
