<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>You should join this cause if you believe the following 2 things:

1. When we vote for the President of the United States, everyone&#8217;s vote should count equally, regardless of what state the vote was cast in.

2. When we vote, our votes should be the final word on who&#8217;s elected President, not the votes of a group of electors.

It seems like in a great Democracy like the United States, these are things that should obviously be true about how we elect our President, but currently they aren&#8217;t. Under the current system, a person&#8217;s vote counts for more if it&#8217;s cast in a swing state than if it&#8217;s cast in a solid Red or Blue state. It also counts for more if it&#8217;s cast in a state with a small population than if it&#8217;s cast in a state with a large population. Furthermore, our votes don&#8217;t actually elect the President. Instead, he or she is elected by a body of electors who are supposed to vote for who we voted for, but who don&#8217;t have to. I personally believe that all of these things are deep flaws in our system. If you agree, you should join this cause and make a donation.

As an added bonus, you should also note that your donation will be going towards a variety of other election reforms supported by Fairvote.org, including an instant run-off system, which would make it easier for third party candidates to get a fair shot in Presidential elections.

1. Everyone's vote should count equally in Presidential elections.

2. The President should be elected directly by the people, not by a group of electors.

3. The United States should adopt a run-off system for Presidential elections.</description>
  <mission>Abolish the Electoral College system in the United States, and replace it with a direct vote for the Presidency.</mission>
  <name>Abolish the Electoral College!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4962</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">386</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.02</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Bk/s6/HA/0Z/lo/zT/Cc7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
