<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>RCRC was founded in 1973 to safeguard the newly won constitutional right to abortion.  The Coalition founders were clergy and lay leaders from mainstream religions, many of whom had provided women with referrals to safe abortion services before the Supreme Court legalized abortion in Roe v. Wade.  The founders believed that there would be at most a ten-year struggle to secure the right to choose. In fact the struggle is far from over.  It has changed and intensified, and the stakes are growing. 

Today, the Religious Coalition comprises national organizations from major faiths and traditions, religiously affiliated and independent religious organizations, affiliates throughout the country, the national Clergy for Choice Network, Spiritual Youth for Reproductive Freedom chapters, The Black Church Initiative, and individuals who support reproductive choice and religious freedom.

While our member organizations are religiously and theologically diverse, they are unified in the commitment to preserve reproductive choice as a basic part of religious liberty. 

Our rational, healing perspective looks beyond the bitter abortion debate to seek solutions to pressing problems such as unintended pregnancy, the spread of HIV/AIDS, inadequate health care and health insurance, and the severe reduction in reproductive health care services.  We support access to sex education, family planning and contraception, affordable child care and health care, and adoption services as well as safe, legal, abortion services, regardless of income.  We work for public policies that ensure the medical, economic, and educational resources necessary for healthy families and communities that are equipped to nurture children in peace and love. 

For more information, please visit:
http://www.rcrc.org/index.cfm
http://www.syrf.org/

List of member organizations:
http://www.rcrc.org/about/members.cfm

Pro-choice prayers and sermons:
http://www.rcrc.org/perspectives/prayers_sermons.cfm

1. We believe women and men should be able to decide what is best for themselves and their families, including giving birth, choosing adoption, and deciding to have an abortion.

2. We recognize and affirm that all life is sacred and that part of being human is the responsibility to hold all life and creation in sacred trust.  Part and parcel of that trust is the call to be responsible moral decision-makers.

3. Religious Coalition supporters are pro-choice not in spite of our faith but because of it. </description>
  <mission>The Religious Coalition for Reproductive Choice brings the moral power of religious communities to ensure reproductive choice through education and advocacy. </mission>
  <name>Religious Coalition for Reproductive Choice</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4973</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">258</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">158.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fW/Db/KJ/wS/kQ/Q8/CkOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
