<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Farm Sanctuary was founded in 1986 to combat the abuses of industrialized farming and to encourage a new awareness and understanding about "farm animals." At Farm Sanctuary, these animals are our friends, not our food.

When Farm Sanctuary's investigative and advocacy campaigns uncover cruelty at factory farms, stockyards and slaughterhouses, our Emergency Rescue Team helps bring the animals to safety. At our 175-acre shelter in upstate New York and 300-acre shelter in northern California, Farm Sanctuary provides lifelong care and rehabilitation to farm animals rescued from cruelty and neglect.

By opening our barn doors to guests at our New York and California shelters, Farm Sanctuary provides visitors with the unique experience of seeing the world through the eyes of farm animals. A shelter tour enables individuals to understand the abysmal realities of today's factory farming conditions. After coming face to face with a rescued chicken, nuzzling up to a gentle cow and rubbing a grateful pig's belly, many Farm Sanctuary visitors are forever changed.

Farm animals are specifically excluded from most state anti-cruelty laws and from the federal Animal Welfare Act. But we are working to change that.

Since incorporating in 1986, Farm Sanctuary has campaigned relentlessly to prevent cruelty, and to encourage legal and policy reforms that promote respect and compassion for farm animals. We have initiated groundbreaking prosecutions and precedent-setting litigation, and we have passed the first U.S. laws to prohibit inhumane factory farming practices. Our field investigations have turned up shocking cruelties, which have riled citizens and led to reforms.

1. Provide lifelong care and rehabilitation to farm animals rescued from cruelty and neglect.

2. Encourage people to move towards a plant-based diet to promote good health, environmental stewardship and compassion toward animals.

3. Campaign relentlessly to prevent cruelty, and to encourage legal and policy reforms that promote respect and compassion for farm animals.</description>
  <mission>Rescue - Education - Advocacy</mission>
  <name>Farm Sanctuary</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4986</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15015</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">18784.45</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4G/nU/dM/4T/sV/Km/4F/adS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
