<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Foundation grants dogs, cash grants and/or K9 Bullet Proof Vests to any department that qualifies and is accepted for a particular grant in New Hampshire, Maine and North-Eastern Massachusetts. The Foundation also maintains and runs the New Hampshire Police K9 Academy at the National Guard Training Site on the Pease Tradeport grounds in Newington, NH.
The Foundation holds Patrol Dog and Detector Dog certifications and competitions under the auspices of the USPCA (United States Police Canine Association), yearly seminars in patrol, narcotics, detection and tracking and seminars with internationally recognized experts on training issues.
Canine first-aid seminars are held regularly for K9 handlers and at least once yearly for the general public. The Foundation K9 handlers do educational support at schools, public events and fairs in an ongoing community policing effort and have the "Adopt-A-K9" program that includes the NH Governor's Award winning "K9 Kasha- The True Story of a NH K9" as well as the new, online journal "Growing Up K9  The Journey and Journal of K9 Kai."

Since 1995 we have raised over $200,000 with every penny going to the training, purchase and support of the police dogs. We are a 100% non profit with NO PAID STAFF. We have the only nationally accredited police K9 training site in New England. Our trainers are nationally recognized.

Be part of the solution and join the Working Dog Foundation today!

http://www.workingdog.org/index.html

1. A properly trained and handled Police K-9 is one of the best non-lethal aids in the prevention and detection of crime.

2.  Police K-9's in New England account for thousands of arrests yearly.

3. Each year they seize millions of $$ in illegal drugs off our streets.

4. Are effective at searching buildings and areas for unauthorized persons.

5. Are masters at tracking criminals and searching for alzheimer patients, lost children, etc.

6. Can find evidence dropped by fleeing criminals .

7. Pursue and apprehend, with minimum force, criminals fleeing a serious crime. 

8. Can aid in protection of the Handler. </description>
  <mission>Police dogs keeping your family safe.</mission>
  <name>Working Dog Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4988</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">86</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Hq/CM/Ik/43/Le/RO/ucpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
