<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The damages in life and property of these "natural" disasters overwhelms almost anything mankind has ever done, and yet we spend money only on efforts to predict these disasters, not prevent them.  Consider:

* At least 20,000 earthquakes occur around the world every year, causing an average of 10,000 deaths and billions of dollars in property damage annually. The estimated deaths from worse earthquake in recent history -- in Tangshan, China in 1976 -- numbered over half a million people. 

* Volcanic eruptions can kill from dozens to thousands of people, either at once or slowly due to environmental damage. An 1815 eruption in Tambora, Indonesia killed 92,000 people by gradual starvation; another in 1985 in Ruiz, Colombia caused tremendous mudslides that wiped out entire villages and 25,000 lives along with them. 

* Either volcanoes or earthquakes can cause tsunamis which in turn destroy ships, cities, and sometimes entire islands. The 1883 eruption in Krakatoa, Indonesia triggered a tsunami that killed 36,000 people. 

* Enormous mountain ranges caused by plate tectonics, such as the Himalayas and the Rocky Mountains, waste thousands of acres of what would be otherwise habitable and farmable land, increasing the population density in other nearby areas. 

* Political and racial differences among the peoples of the world are enforced by geographic boundaries -- oceans, seas and mountains -- which might never have existed had Pangaea never broken up. 

1. The human cost of plate tectonics MUST be a topic of modern dialogue.

2. Governments and civil society should do their utmost to end this scourge on humanity.

3. With action, we can prevail!</description>
  <mission>To end continental drift, the random and pointless shifting of Earth's land masses against each other. </mission>
  <name>Stop Plate Tectonics</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4990</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">198</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Hh/Ko/qw/Ph/Tb/62/bu7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
