<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We, the Talons of UNT, walk in memory of one of our beloved alumni James Sweat, who died of lymphoma a few years ago.


The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society's Light The Night Walk is the nation's night to pay tribute and bring hope to thousands of patients battling blood cancers and to commemorate loved ones lost.

The Society funds lifesaving cancer research that has contributed to major advances in the treatment of blood cancers and many other types of cancer treatments such as chemotherapy and stem cell transplants that have prolonged and enhanced the lives of patients. New targeted therapies that kill cancer cells without harming normal tissue have already begun to provide drugs and procedures that are improving quality of life.

But more research is critically needed:

    * Every five minutes someone is diagnosed with 
blood cancer. Every ten minutes, someone dies.

    * Leukemia causes more deaths among children than any other cancer

    * More than 20,000 Americans died from lymphoma in 2006

    * The survival rate for myeloma is just 33%



IF YOU WISH TO DONATE: DO NOT click the "Donate" tab in the right corner of this page.  


PLEASE CLICK ON ONE OF THE LINKS BELOW.


For any questions send a message or visit any one of our many donation pages listed below:

http://www.active.com/donate/ltnDallas/2052_MeanGreenTalons

http://www.active.com/donate/ltnDallas/2052_meangreengurl04

http://www.active.com/donate/ltnDallas/2052_torridturtle

http://www.active.com/donate/ltnDallas/2052_LongC86

http://www.active.com/donate/ltnDallas/2052_melaine27



These pages are set up through the Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society by our individual Talons Team members. If you are uncomfortable donating in this mannor you may donate by going to the Light  the Night home page: 

http://www.lightthenight.org/



Thank you again! 

1. Spread the word: "We shall not go quietly in to that good night!" 

2. Collect as many donations as possible. 

3. Fight for those who can't and for those who have not yet begun! Cancer is an enemy to all.... </description>
  <mission>to raise funds for cures for all blood cancers! </mission>
  <name>Light the Night: Leukemia/ Lymphoma Society-&gt; TALONS/UNT TEAM</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/4996</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/md/OR/1v/ID/hL/sM/fcXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
