<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"That whenever any Form of Government becomes destructive of these ends, it is the Right of the People to alter or to abolish it, and to institute new Government, laying its foundation on such principles and organizing its powers in such form, as to them shall seem most likely to effect their Safety and Happiness."
-The unanimous Declaration of the thirteen united States of America

"The world you desired can be won, it exists, it is real, it is possible, it's yours. But to win it requires total dedication and a total break with the world of your past, with the doctrine that man is sacrificial animal who exists for the pleasure of others. Fight for the value of your person. Fight for the virtue of your pride. Fight for the essence, which is man, for his sovereign rational mind. Fight with the radiant certainty and the absolute rectitude of knowing that yours is the morality of life and yours is the battle for any achievement, any value, any grandeur, any goodness, any joy that has ever existed on this earth."
John Galt 






1. We believe that government is dangerous to man's rights. That it ought not hold a legal monopoly of physical force against its own legally disarmed citizenry.

2. Government help to business or individuals is always disasterous. The only way a government can be of sevice is to keep its hands off.

3. Altruism is detrimental to civilization.

4. The only power government ought have is to crack down on criminals. When there are not enough criminals the state seems to be making them. This must stop

5. The only role of government is to protect an individual from physical harm.</description>
  <mission>bring down the state, and restore individual liberties</mission>
  <name>New American Revolution </name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5008</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">36</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Dc/wm/5I/q1/8b/er/uSOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
