<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>HUMAN PAPILLOMAVIRUS (HPV)
HPV affects both women and men.
&#8226; 	Anyone who has any kind of sexual activity involving genital contact with an infected person can get HPV&#8212;-intercourse isn't necessary.
&#8226; 	Many people who may have HPV may not show any signs or symptoms, so they can pass the virus on without even knowing it.
HPV is easily transmitted. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) estimates that 20 million people in the United States already had HPV in 2005.
According to the CDC, the only way you can totally protect yourself against HPV is to avoid any sexual activity that involves genital contact. HPV Types 6, 11, 16, and 18 account for the majority of HPV-related clinical diseases.
OF THE APPROXIMATELY 6 MILLION NEW CASES OF GENITAL HPV IN THE UNITED STATES EVERY YEAR, IT IS ESTIMATED 74% OF THEM OCCUR IN 15-TO-24-YEAR-OLDS.
&#8224;Number represents more than 30 genital HPV types, not just HPV Types 6, 11, 16, and 18.
THERE'S GOOD NEWS
Being vaccinated with GARDASIL before coming into contact with a person who has HPV may help protect you against HPV Types 6, 11, 16, and 18.
IMPORTANT INFORMATION ABOUT GARDASIL
HPV Types 16 and 18 cause 70% of cervical cancer cases, and HPV Types 6 and 11 cause 90% of genital warts cases.
GARDASIL may not fully protect everyone and does not prevent all types of cervical cancer, so it is important to continue regular cervical cancer screenings.
Anyone who is allergic to the ingredients of GARDASIL should not receive the vaccine. GARDASIL is not for women who are pregnant.
GARDASIL will not treat cervical cancer and genital warts, and will not protect against diseases caused by other HPV types.
GARDASIL is given as 3 injections over 6 months and can cause pain, swelling, itching, and redness at the injection site, fever, nausea, and dizziness.
Only a doctor or healthcare professional can decide if GARDASIL is right for you or your daughter.

1. According to the CDC, the only way you can totally protect yourself against HPV is to avoid any sexual activity that involves genital contact. HPV Types 6, 11, 16, and 18 account for the majority of HPV-related clinical diseases.

2. OF THE APPROXIMATELY 6 MILLION NEW CASES OF GENITAL HPV IN THE UNITED STATES EVERY YEAR, IT IS ESTIMATED 74% OF THEM OCCUR IN 15-TO-24-YEAR-OLDS.

3. Being vaccinated with GARDASIL before coming into contact with a person who has HPV may help protect you against HPV Types 6, 11, 16, and 18.</description>
  <mission>Educate those unaware of HPV</mission>
  <name>HPV Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5031</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1863</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">60.01</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/s8/uE/dN/TY/47/xE/sRDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
