<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Music and the performing arts connect youth with their culture through a common language crossing generational, social, and racial barriers. The activities that a young person pursues influence the type of person he or she becomes. The experience that comes with participation in a performing arts organization builds discipline, character, pride, and self-confidence at a crucial age and forms the springboard to even greater achievements in adulthood

The Blue Devils Parents' Association performing arts programs permanently enrich the lives of young people through a commitment to youth development and performance excellence while providing enjoyment for our local community and audiences worldwide.

The Blue Devils offer a learning experience in the art of baton twirling, dance, percussion, and music
performance. The Blue Devil family offers seven programs for young people age four to twenty-one:

A Drum &amp; Bugle Corps
B Drum &amp; Bugle Corps 
C Drum &amp; Bugle Corps 
Two Winter Guard Programs 
World Class Twirling Program 
Diablo Wind Symphony

Over 500 young people ages seven to twenty-one are currently members of the Blue Devils performing units. Over 5,000 young people, in 1,500 families, have been served by the Blue Devils since 1957.

http://www.bluedevils.org/


1. Building discipline, character, pride, and self-confidence while permanently enriching the lives of young people through a commitment to youth development and performance excellence. </description>
  <mission>Building discipline, character, pride, and self-confidence while permanently enriching the lives of young people through a commitment to youth development and performance excellence. </mission>
  <name>Blue Devil Parent Association</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5037</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/XG/tQ/KP/v4/wu/Wv/VncS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
