<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Child labor is a serious problem in many parts of the world, especially in developing countries. Labor is defined as physical or mental work especially of the hard or fatiguing kind. Child labor usually means work that is done by children under the age of 15, which restricts or damages their physical, emotional, intellectual, social, or spiritual growth as children. The International Labor organization estimates that there are 250 million children worldwide, between the ages of 5 and 14, who are now working. "Africa and Asia together account for over 90 percent of total child employment" Child labor is especially common in the rural areas of these countries. Usually there are no age requirements for schooling or for work. There are many reasons that these children work; poverty, lack of education, lack of knowledge of one's rights and cultural tradition are all contributing factors. These children are often working in severe and hazardous conditions. These children are deprived and mistreated. They are often beat or severely punished for making even the slightest mistakes. 
Poor families often rely on the labours of their children for survival, and sometimes it is their only source of income. This type of work is often hidden away because it is not always in the industrial sector. Child labour is employed in subsistence agriculture and in the urban informal sector; child domestic work is also important. In order to benefit children, child labour prohibition has to address the dual challenge of providing them with both short-term income and long-term prospects. Some youth rights groups, however, feel that prohibiting work below a certain age violates human rights, reducing children's options and leaving them subject to the whims of those with money.
Child labour happens for 61% in Asia, 32% in Africa, and 7% in Latin America, 1% in US, Canada, Europe and other wealthy nations In Asia, 22% of the workforce is children. In Latin America, 17% of the workforce is children. The proportion of child laborers varies a lot among countries and even regions inside those countries.

1. Child labour must end immediately

2. Establish and vigorously enforce legislation to protect the rights of children 

3. Prompt and stringent action should be taken against the industries that are encouraging the use of child labour. 

4. Boycott products and commodities that are likely to be tainted by the sweat of child labourers </description>
  <mission>             STOP CHILD LABOUR </mission>
  <name>Stop Child Labour !!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5045</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24260</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45.11</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/n1/2o/O1/xg/AA/ga/XdRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
