<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Los Angeles has the largest population of homeless military veterans in the nation.  An estimated 20,000 veterans live on the streets of L.A. -- eleven percent (11%) of all homeless veterans nationwide.  Many of these men and women suffer from co-occuring disorders, including substance abuse, mental illness and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), as well as chronic medical problems.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For the past 15 years &lt;b&gt;New Directions, Inc.&lt;/b&gt; has provided comprehensive long-term substance abuse treatment to our nation's veterans.  More than 800 men and women seek outpatient services from the agency each year, and 225 veterans receive round-the-clock care at four different residential treatment centers.  Also, currently in development is a 150-unit supportive housing facility for disabled veterans.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;New Directions&lt;/b&gt; provides a wide variety of services for homeless veterans, including job training and placement, parenting and money management classes, legal and financial assistance, counseling, remedial education and resources for alumni.  Residents leave New Directions with a job, housing, a savings account, computer skills, renewed self confidence and the support of mentors and peers.  Such a transformation takes hard work, motivation and accountability, but the results are life-altering -- and for many veterans, life-saving. 
&lt;br&gt;

1. Every Dollar Counts

2. $25 provides 3 meals for one day to 4 veterans

3. $50 provides 2 pairs of work boots or shoes for 2 veterans

4. $100 provides a suit for a job interview

5. $250 provides 1 day of Culinary Arts training for 8 veterans

6.  $500 provides 25 hours of computer training for 10 veterans

7. They fought for our freedom.  Now they need a fighting chance.

8. War is hell.  Being a Veteran shouldn't be.

9. Some heroes are homeless.  Don't turn your back on them.</description>
  <mission>empower homeless veterans by providing them with the tools they need such as counseling, sobriety, job training and a new lease on life.</mission>
  <name>New Directions, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5051</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">97</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7t/RZ/xy/S2/GR/lV/HXTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
