<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;b&gt;What is Microcredit?&lt;/b&gt;
Microcredit is the extension of small loans to entrepreneurs too the poor to qualify for traditional bank loans. It has proven to be an effective and popular measure in the ongoing struggle against poverty, enabling those to better their quality of life. 


&lt;b&gt;About Grameen Bank-&lt;/b&gt;
Grameen Bank (GB) has reversed conventional banking practice by removing the need for collateral and created a banking system based on mutual trust, accountability, participation and creativity. 

At GB, credit is a cost effective weapon to fight poverty and it serves as a catalyst in the over all development of socio-economic conditions of the poor who have been kept outside the banking orbit on the ground that they are poor and hence not bankable. 


&lt;b&gt;Nobel Peace Prize Winner-&lt;/b&gt;
Professor Muhammad Yunus, the founder of "Grameen Bank" and Nobel Peace Prize Winner is also the Banks Managing Director. He reasoned that if financial resources can be made available to the poor people on terms and conditions that are appropriate and reasonable, "these millions of small people with their millions of small pursuits can add up to create the biggest development wonder." - Muhammad Yunus~


&lt;b&gt;Recent Progress-&lt;/b&gt;
As of May, 2007, it has 7.16 million borrowers, 97 percent of whom are women. With 2422 branches, GB provides services in 78,101 villages, covering more than 93 percent of the total villages in Bangladesh.

Grameen Bank's positive impact on its poor and formerly poor borrowers has been documented in many independent studies carried out by external agencies including the World Bank, the International Food Research Policy Institute (IFPRI) and the Bangladesh Institute of Development Studies (BIDS).


&lt;b&gt;Our Mission, What You Can Do-&lt;/b&gt;
If we can raise money to keep the cause going- we can help Grameen expand farther into other regions of the Rural "Global South" and help heal the injustice of Poverty. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

1. The idea of 'credit' to better ones life is a Basic Human Right

2. Everyone has the Right to decide how to improve their lives when giving the Capability to do so. </description>
  <mission>To be Bankers to the Poor - Providing Capabilities Where There Are None</mission>
  <name>Grameen Foundation -- Expanding Microcredit</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5057</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">330</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">150.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mf/ma/kn/Mk/yu/SM/JxjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
