<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded by St. Andrew the Apostle in 37 C.E., the Ecumenical Patriarchate of Constantinople exists as the first throne of the Eastern Orthodox Church charged with leading the 300 million Orthodox faithful worldwide. His All Holiness Bartholomew became 270th successor to this seat in his 1991 election and appointment.  However, because of discriminatory laws endorsed by the Turkish government, the Ecumenical Patriarchate now stands on the brink of extinction &#8211; a system of discrimination which provides evidence substantiating a case of institutional and cultural genocide.

1. The Turkish government does not recognize the title &#8220;Ecumenical&#8221; title of the Patriarchate nor his authority over the 300 million Orthodox faithful worldwide.

2.  The Turkish government does not give legal recognition to the Ecumenical Patriarchate as a legitimate, independent entity. 

3.  The Turkish government has placed restrictions on the election of the Ecumenical Patriarch, restrictions of which may prohibit the election of an appropriate successor to Bartholomew. 

4. The Turkish government deprives the Ecumenical Patriarchate from educating and training its own clergy. In 1972, the Turkish government closed the Theological School of Halki which exists as the sole seminary in which to train clergy for the Patriarchate.

5. The Turkish government denies the Ecumenical Patriarchate all aspects of basic property rights. To date, 75% of the Ecumenical Patriarchate&#8217;s 1,747 properties have been confiscated. 

The extinction of the Ecumenical Patriarchate would be a crime against humankind; robbing the world of a living witness to over 2,000 years of passionate history in one of the world&#8217;s most celebrated cities.

For more information about the situation and how you can help, please visit:
Order of St. Andrew the Apostle: www.archons.org
Ecumenical Patriarchate: www.patriarchate.org
Greek Orthodox Archdioceses of America: www.goarch.org

1. Freedom of religion is a universal human right.

2. As a partner in the democratic community, the Turkish government must abandon policies that systematically persecute religious organizations.

3. We are committed to preserving the heritage and operation of the Ecumenical Patriarchate through dialogue and action.</description>
  <mission>"...safeguard the future of the Ecumenical Patriarchate whose existence is threatened by the policies of the Turkish Republic."</mission>
  <name>Religious Freedom Project for the Ecumenical Patriarchate</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5094</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2779</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">385.02</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SE/a5/we/4J/d2/oq/ZFCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
