<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>  
The Endometriosis Association
The Endometriosis Association was the first organization in the world created for those with endometriosis. As an independent self-help organization of women with endometriosis, doctors, and others interested in the disease, it is a recognized authority in its field whose goal is to work toward finding a cure for the disease as well as providing education, support, and research.

Founded in Milwaukee, Wisconsin in 1980 by Mary Lou Ballweg and Carolyn Keith, it is now a worldwide, independent organization. It has grown to such an extent that it now has a network of chapters, groups, sponsors, and women with endometriosis in 66 countries throughout the world. Information is available in 28 different languages.

Since its creation, the Endometriosis Association has achieved many goals, one being the undertaking of massive educational projects involving mailings to every gynecologist, hospital, and college health service in the US and Canada. It has also published two books: Overcoming Endometriosis and The Endometriosis Sourcebook. A wide range of literature, fact sheets, videotapes and audiotapes can also be obtained through the Association.

Operating as a non-profit organization, the Association aims to establish funds to enable more research into the causes of endometriosis. As part of its research program, the Association has established a special program at Dartmouth Medical School and has funded and assisted a number of researchers in various parts of the world. It also maintains a large data research registry and continues work on the relationship between dioxin and endometriosis, a relationship the Association discovered.

The Association has recently teamed up with the prestigious Vanderbilt University School of Medicine to create a dedicated research facility to address the mechanisms responsible for causing endometriosis.

Among other research projects supported by the Association are a study of the dioxin-exposed young women in Seveso, Italy; publicity and help obtaining patients and families for a genetic study at Oxford University, England; support for research on a non-invasive diagnostic technique by a U.S. researcher; and small grants and tissue samples for a number of researchers studying dioxin and related toxins and endometriosis.

For further information, contact:
Mary Lou Ballweg,
President/Executive Director,
International Headquarters,
8585 N. 76th Place,
Milwaukee, Wisconsin 53223, USA
(For a free packet of information call 1-800-992-3636.)
Tel: (414) 355-2200/ Fax: (414) 355-6065

 

1. Endometriosis is a major chronic disease affecting over 5 million women, most cases are still undiagnosed

2. Women suffering from endometriosis pain should not be stigmatized

3. Support research to find treatments and preventions for endometriosis</description>
  <mission>Find Cures and Preventions for Endometriosis and Spread Public Awareness</mission>
  <name>Support Endometriosis Research and Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5102</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6385</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">345.4</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uO/7w/uY/qX/eC/lZ/Sn/esS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
