<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Marlins had their best success under Jack McKeon, who led the Marlins to their only stretch of three consecutive winning seasons. Most of the time, however, the franchise has suffered from relatively low attendance. The Marlins management has insisted that a new baseball-only stadium with a retractable roof is imperative to survival in South Florida, and that if one would not be built, the team would seek relocation to another city. Although San Antonio, Texas, has pushed hard to receive the team, recent months have seen a new push for the Marlins to stay in South Florida, with the Miami suburb of Hialeah making strides in securing the stadium the team wants (see Possible relocation, below). The Marlins have also declined San Antonio's deadline of May 15, 2006 to accept their stadium funding proposal, signaling that the team may indeed stay in South Florida. MLB President Bob DuPuy informed San Antonio in a letter that the offer would be declined at this time, but left open the possibility of relocation in the future, if talks in south Florida did not lead to a stadium deal.

Under the current proposal it would cost an estimated $420-$435 million to build a stadium that would seat 38,000 fans. The ballpark would open in April 2008 and feature 62 luxury suites and 3,000 club seats. In order to pay for the stadium, the Marlins would commit $30 million for design development and construction expenses, and $192 million in rent payments. Miami Dade County would contribute $166 million that would come from sports facility taxes and hotel bed taxes. The city would contribute $28 million in tourist development taxes. The Marlins would be responsible for any cost overruns.

OUR GOAL: 30,000,000

1. This Stadium is in Coral Gables, not Miami

2. More Fans than Dolphin Stadium

3. Teams should not share</description>
  <mission>Raise the last bit of money for the stadium</mission>
  <name>New Stadium for the Florida Marlins</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5107</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Zn/k0/eK/zf/4i/q5/knFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
