<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Senate passed an extension to the current FAA funding bill; the House had passed an extension earlier. That means the current aviation taxes, and the FAA's authority to spend money, have been extended until Nov. 16, giving Congress a little breathing room to come up with a new FAA funding bill. The House has already passed its FAA funding bill, H.R.2881. The Senate Finance Committee recently approved the tax provisions of the Senate bill (S.1300). It's similar to the House version and much more palatable to general aviation. However, the $25-per-flight user fee on turbine-powered aircraft remains. The removal of that fee is essential to AOPA and the top priority when S.1300 goes to the floor of the Senate for a vote. But floor action hasn't been scheduled yet. When the bill does come to the floor, AOPA will be contacting members to ask their senators to vote to remove the user fee &#8212; assuming an agreement to remove it cannot be reached.

Stay tuned for more petitions to sign!!

"This isn't about blips, or funding, or whether individual pilots pay enough. It's about creating a radical new way to pay for government safety services and turning control of safety over to private industry. It's about cost, safety, and freedom. It's about preserving general aviation and the freedom of average citizens to fly for business and pleasure. " &#8212;Phil Boyer, Pres. AOPA


1. General Aviation user fees and tax hikes must be stopped. It is American's right to maintain the freedom they have enjoyed for over 100 years to safely fly without excessive fees.

2. The skies over the United States are a national asset. Future funding of the FAA must be ensured. 

3. The United States air transportation system is the world's largest, safest, and most efficient. Any system of user fees, even one that excludes all or some segment of general aviation is unacceptable. </description>
  <mission>Oppose Aviation User Fees and Avgas Tax Hikes in Senate Proposal S.1300 in order to protect General Aviation</mission>
  <name>Oppose Aviation User Fees</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5149</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">231</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1F/rQ/3K/ds/k2/Ty/Gi/TJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
