<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Earth Day Network (EDN) grew out of the original Earth Day in 1970. Earth Day Network is a driving force steering environmental awareness around the world. Through EDN, activists connect, interact, and have an impact on their communities, and create positive change in local, national, and global policies. EDN's international network reaches over 17,000 organizations in 174 countries. Our domestic programs engage 5,000 groups and over 25,000 educators coordinating millions of community development and environmental protection activities throughout the year. Earth Day is the only event celebrated simultaneously around the globe by people of all backgrounds, faiths and nationalities. More than a billion people participate in Earth Day each year.
 
The Global Footprint Network works to increase the effectiveness of the Ecological Footprint as a tool for promoting ecological, social and economic sustainability.

Please take just 5-10 minutes of your time and take the Earth Day Network Footprint Calculator and see what impact you're having on the planet!
http://www.earthday.net/ecofootprint
This quiz will not only let you know how you are impacting your planet, but gives you tips on how to reduce your ecological footprint and better your environment!

http://ww2.earthday.net/

http://www.footprintnetwork.org/

&lt;object width="425" height="353"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/Q5r6TqpOQGc&amp;rel=1"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="wmode" value="transparent"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/Q5r6TqpOQGc&amp;rel=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" wmode="transparent" width="425" height="353"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

1. Promote Civic Engagement

2. Broaden the Meaning of "Environment"

3. Mobilize Communities

4. Implement Groundbreaking Environmental Education Programs

5. Help Bring Clean Water and Sanitation to the World and more...</description>
  <mission>We seek to grow and diversify the environmental movement worldwide, and to mobilize it as the most effective vehicle for promoting a healthy, sustainable planet</mission>
  <name>Earth Day Network: Every Day for Everybody</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5158</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">788</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Bm/y1/jG/d6/I2/E1/5V/niS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
