<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>S.O.S. = Save Our Selves!!

Live Earth was a 24-hour, 7-continent concert series on 7/7/07 that brought together more than 100 music artists and 2 BILLION PEOPLE to trigger a GLOBAL MOVEMENT TO STOP THE CLIMATE CRISIS. 

Live Earth marked the beginning of a multi-year campaign led by the Alliance for Climate Protection, The Climate Group and other international organizations to drive individuals, corporations and governments to take action to solve global warming. Former U.S. Vice President Al Gore is the Chair of the Alliance and Partner of Live Earth. 

Live Earth staged official concerts at Giants Stadium in New York; Wembley Stadium in London; Aussie Stadium in Sydney; Maropeng at the Cradle of Humankind in Johannesburg; Makuhari Messe in Tokyo; the Steps of the Oriental Pearl Tower in Shanghai; Copacabana Beach in Rio de Janeiro; and HSH Nordbank Arena in Hamburg. Many other concerts took place simulatenously around the world for this cause including Antarctica!

With support from the U.S. Green Building Council,  Live Earth implemented new Green Event Guidelines. All Live Earth venues were designed and constructed by a team of sustainability engineers who addressed the environmental and energy management challenges of each concert site, as well as the operations of sponsors, partners and other Live Earth affiliates. Each venue was not only designed to maintain a minimum environmental impact, but showcased the latest state-of-the-art ENERGY EFFICIENCY, on-site power generation, and sustainable facilities management practices. 

Live Earth is a project of the SOS campaign to move people to combat the climate crisis.

The headliners included Madonna, The Police, Red Hot Chili Peppers, Kanye West, Fall Out Boy, Smashing Pumpkins, Beastie Boys, Black Eyed Peas, Duran Duran, Bon Jovi, Dave Matthews Band, James Blunt, Rihanna, Metallica and countless more! Join the cause to help save the earth.

***LIVE EARTH WAS A HUGE SUCCESS!! LET IT GROW***


1. TO RAISE AWARENESS

2. to prevent this problem from growing even further

3. above all... to save the globe for the future</description>
  <mission>To raise awareness around the world for people to be environmentally careful and to save the globe from the climate crisis.</mission>
  <name>Live Earth</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5162</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">39547</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">267.04</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7S/JV/mA/xL/sH/O3/BIGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
