<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Mount Tabor Convent and the Mar Dionysus Memorial Balika Bhavan. Bhavan which are working at Tengali near Thiruvalla are the completion of the wishes of Thoma Mar Dionysus. Along with the St. George Orthodox church. The Zacharias Mar Dionysus Memorial Balika which was inaugurated in August 2005 is also functioning under the Mar Gregorious chapel. Twenty five children are being sheltered and educated in this Balika Bhavan under the care and responsibility of the sisters of Mount Tabor Convent. A large number of children's are unable to continue their studies at home because of starvation and the drinking habits of their fathers. 

We cannot ignore such poor innocent children. So we started this endeavor to help such children and it is now limping forward with great financial difficulties and infrastructural shortages.

So far the Balika Bhavan has not been able to own land or building. Now it is working in a building attached to the Convent. The Balika Bhavan is a result, facing many problems to meet the daily expense of the children, buy enough educational materials, dress for children and their treatment. A total amount of $1,000,000 is estimated to meet in cost of land building teaching and medical treatment, study table, chair and bus for the conveyance of h children. We therefore appeal to all of you is ordered by H.H. Mar Baselios Mar Thoma Didymos I (Catholicos of the East and Malankara Metropolitan) to extend all sorts of help for the growth of this institution. And Sister Mariam, Mount Tabor Convent was appointed to collect the donations for this project. Donations may please be made in the name of Balika Bhavan by cheque or draft.

Rev. Sr. Mariam
Balika Bhavan
Thengali P.O., Kuttoor
Thiruvalla - Kerala 689106
Account No: 57068024964
State Bank of Travancore
Thiruvalla Br.

1. Teach the Children

2. Save the Children

3. Don't ignore the Children</description>
  <mission>help underprivilaged children to continue their studies in the Balika Bhavan</mission>
  <name>Mar Dionysius Memorial Balika Bahavan</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5199</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eI/Sf/SL/pe/zN/5p/4itS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
