<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Well I believe we have an issue

What issues are we mostly concerned about today well here is just 2 out of many
1. Global Warming
2. Aids

Lets start with global warming

~How do we know if this hasn't happened before~

Scientist cant go back enough in history to find out any evidence or information leading to this event happening previous to our existence

~How to help~ 

a.Try to tell your friends at school family to help I'm not saying give up everything, Just try to make a  change

b. Popular kids yea your so cool right,
WRONG 

All you are is talk i promise if it came to the right moment you wouldn't do anything so stop acting like a hero,and become one


2. Aids  
~What to do~

Thats a great question. This is hard to deal with. I honestly think that if people did what they should (read above) this would be most important to our government. Yet without our government thoughts this is most dangerous. Like I stated before we don't know anything about global warming. America has tried to figure this out since 1980 so if you ask me aids is a bigger crime to solve.

~What can we do~

Tell your friends to wear a condom. I am not joking about this yeah i heard not comfortable but hey listen to this
Have safe sex and yet enjoy it
                 or
Get a high risk of getting STD Die in a crappy death 

I'm sorry for saying it like that but my friend that is life.

Lastly I am not asking for you to give me money because honestly i don't trust most people with my money, but if you should give me money, I will find an organization i can trust to give it to

If you have any questions for me i will be honored to hear your comments 

A good website to know about aids is Avert.com

1. Global Warming- Try to tell your friends to help out and dont be shy to tell popular kids too 

2. Aids- Yes this is a hard thing to help with but you can give moeny to organization

3. Both- Help your town to fix the problem let people know of the damage that can happen</description>
  <mission>Save Lives of others
</mission>
  <name>PolarBear Community</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5218</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">72</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dY/OD/rX/7f/GW/kI/uwmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
