<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I believe that the first steps towards ending all major environmental issues today (such as Global Warming, GMO foods, etc.) as well as serious health problems we're seeing worldwide (obesity, diabetes, allergies, etc.) starts with the little things we do everyday.  With the choices you make as consumer: what you eat, what you wear, what you use to get around the city, and even what you use to brush your teeth and wash your hair with.

Ultimately the goal is to create awareness among consumers like you and me to make better decisions everytime you pull out that wallet to pay for something.  This will help us reduce our ecological footprint on this Earth and protect our environment: our air, soil, waters, wildlife, children.

Buy Organic
Buy Bio-degradeable
Buy from local farmers
Eating less meat
Buy products made from recycled materials

Use public transit/a bike to get around

In addition to this, it is not only about what you consume.  It is also how much you consume too.  The goal is not only to consume environmentally friendly products but to also to reduce our consumption as a whole.  

Conserving water usage.
Recycling.
'Flicking off', as well as using energy efficent appliances/electronics - and unplugging them when not in use.

Some useful links:

http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2205039739

http://www.bioregional.com/programme_projects/opl_prog/opl_programme.htm

https://www.spud.ca/teaser/10produce_reasons.cfm

http://www.thefutureoffood.com/

http://www.quantumshift.tv/v/1181042956


Help me further build this cause, I'm sure there are people out there who know more about these issues than I do.  Contribute links, ideas, info.


1. Consume Organic/Bio-Degradeable products and produce

2. Support local economy and local farmers

3. Eating less meat

4. Reduce, Reuse, Recycle.

5. 'Flick Off'

6. Conserve water use</description>
  <mission>Make conscious decisions as consumers to support a sustainable life style.</mission>
  <name>Organic/Sustainable Living</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/523</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">92356</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3419.13</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mSg/o0PS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
