<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&#8220;Most children in Laos have never read a book except for a few school textbooks, and some have not even read those&#8221; 

There is a significant shortage of books - of any kind - in Laos, and the situation is particularly bad in the rural areas. Although there are libraries in the larger towns, most village children do not have access to them - their villages are too remote, and their workdays too long. So, if we can&#8217;t bring the kids to the libraries, we&#8217;ll just have to bring the library to the kids! 

Traditionally, goods in Laos have been transported up the Mekong river and its tributaries. Many of the rural villages are located by the riverside and do not have road access. Therefore we will deliver the books by river, in traditional Lao-style. Yes, that&#8217;s right &#8211; we&#8217;re hoisting the sails of a Floating Library in the hope of bringing books to the children and fun into reading!

Fun aside, between being battered by the French, Americans, and Vietnamese - resulting in the mass exodus of educated Lao - and natural disasters and child trafficking, the obstacles that families face to support and educate their children are immense. The commitment to education is there, the support and the money to make that happen isn&#8217;t. It is particularly girls in the rural areas that are the most disadvantaged, with only around 30% of women having learned how to read and write. And this is where you can help us. Please make a donation to help us build the library boat, and invite your friends and family too!

More information about us and the library boat is available on our website www.riverbooks.org 

We also have another donation site at www.firstgiving.com/floatinglibrary


1. All Children Have A Right To A Decent Education

2. Every Child has a Right to Learn how to Read and Write

3. Books shold be Available to Anyone who wants to Read

4. Knowledge has no owner, yet everyone is entitled to it</description>
  <mission>to build a library boat to bring books to villages with no road access in Laos</mission>
  <name>River Books Library Boat for Children</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5250</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">149</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">190.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SG/PP/Rw/vI/YF/vo/wQiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
