<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Welcome to the ASPCA Cause on Facebook

Useful Links:

www.aspcafacebook.webs.com

www.aspca.org

E-mail us with your questions!

aspcamemberservices@gmail.com

Rules for the ASPCA Cause:

We like to keep a clean, positive page for all to enjoy! Listed below are some rules that are put in place to protect our cause! If broken the member will receive a e-mail from a admin, if broken again that member will be banned from the page. 

1. We are all adults here, if you would like to post a comment on The Wall, keep it CLEAN, even if you don't agree with a comment please use appropriate language and tone! 

2. All links and photos must be posted in the MEDIA BOARD area ONLY! No links on the wall. 

3. Petitions will be denied unless officially endorsed by the ASPCA.org website. Please DO NOT send request to approve any petition that is NOT related to the ASPCA! You will be banned from the cause if you continue to send these request. 

4. Questions, Compliments, Suggestions should all be sent to:
aspcamemberservices@gmail.com

5. This cause has been running for 2 years, we want to keep the cause clean and running smooth. We need your help in donating and recruiting!

Thank You for joining and supporting the ASPCA!


Jason H., Terri B, Christina B, and Abbie S.
Your ASPCA Facebook Admin Team


1. To Stop Cruelty To Animals

2. To End Shelter Cruelty

3. To Stop Killing Shelter Animals

4. To Prevent Circus Cruelty

5. To put an end to Backyard Breeders

6. To end the Declawing, Ear Clipping, and Tail Clipping of Animals for unnecessary reasons.

7. To put an end to Animal Neglect 

8. To Stop Puppy Mills/ Dog fighting

9. To End CRUEL Dog Racing 

10. To END Factory Farming

11. To End fear of Pit Bulls (Trained and healthy pit bulls are great dogs)

12. To End Debarking Surgery</description>
  <mission>To stop cruelty to animals.</mission>
  <name>ASPCA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/526</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">253902</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">40820.31</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eZ/zI/b1/Sk/Wf/3e/6I/mRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
