<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>African Leadership Academy (ALA) seeks to transform Africa by developing and supporting future generations of African leaders. Opening in 2008, African Leadership Academy will bring together 250 of the most promising 15-18 year old leaders from all 54 African nations for an innovative two-year program designed to prepare each student for a lifetime of leadership on the continent. 
Students will be selected to attend the Academy based on merit alone and will complete a unique curriculum with a focus on leadership, entrepreneurship, and African studies.  
ALA graduates will attend the world&#8217;s finest universities and will return to lead Africa toward a peaceful and prosperous future. ALA is a nonprofit institution located in Johannesburg, South Africa. 

To learn more about African Leadership Academy, visit www.africanleadershipacademy.org.



1. Address the Underlying Causes of Problems: We believe an undersupply of leadership across all sectors is the root cause of many of Africa's problems.

2. The Power of One: History has seen countless examples of the power of individual leaders to catalyze the actions of large groups of people and unleash massive positive change in society.

3. The Power of Youth: Many great leaders begin "changing the world" at a young age - when they believe the whole world is open to them and they are free to chase their big dreams.

4. The Need for Pan-African Cooperation: We believe that a pan-African approach is required to catalyze growth and development in Africa.

5. Entrepreneurship is Fundamental to Growth: Africa needs entrepreneurial leaders across all sectors who will throw off the constraints of existing institutions to change the paradigm and create value on the continent. </description>
  <mission>Developing the next generation of African leaders</mission>
  <name>African Leadership Academy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5294</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1790</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1834.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2Z/Pq/RK/4q/m7/dr/e51S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
