<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our Bodies Ourselves (OBOS), also known as the Boston Women&#8217;s Health Book Collective (BWHBC), is a nonprofit, public interest women&#8217;s health education, advocacy, and consulting organization. Beginning in 1970 with the publication of the first edition of Our Bodies, Ourselves, OBOS has inspired the women&#8217;s health movement by: 

-Producing books that makes accurate health and medical information accessible to a broad audience by weaving women&#8217;s stories into a framework of practical, clearly written text;

-Identifying and collaborating with exemplary individuals and organizations that provide services, generate research and policy analysis, and organize for social change;

-Inspiring and empowering women to become engaged in the political aspects of sustaining good health for themselves and their communities.

OBOS provides clear, truthful information about health, sexuality and reproduction from a feminist and consumer perspective. We vigorously advocate for women's health by challenging the institutions and systems that block women from full control over our bodies and devalue our lives. Our long-standing commitment to serve only in the public interest and our bridge-building capacity are our hallmarks. We remain one of the few women&#8217;s health groups in the U.S. that doesn&#8217;t accept funds from pharmaceutical companies and that tries to be scrupulous about conflict of interest. 

1. Women, as informed health consumers, are catalysts for social change.

2. Women can become their own health experts, particularly through discussing issues of health and sexuality with each other.

3. Health consumers have a right to know about controversies surrounding medical practices and about where consensus among medical experts may be forming.

4. Women comprise the largest segment of health workers, health consumers, and health decision-makers for their families and communities, but are underrepresented in positions of influence and policy making.

5. A pathology/disease approach to normal life events (birthing, menopause, aging, death) is not an effective way in which to consider health or structure a health system.</description>
  <mission>To empower women with information about health, sexuality and reproduction. We work to promote equality between women and men, and build bridges among social justice movements.</mission>
  <name>Our Bodies Ourselves</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5300</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">264</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1055.03</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eA/Ap/CI/MZ/hx/OM/buiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
