<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Deregulation is the process of lessening or complete removal of government regulations on an industry, especially concerning the price that firms are allowed to charge and leaving price to be determined by market forces. Deregulation is different from liberalization because a liberalized market, while often having less and simpler regulations, can also have regulations in order to increase efficiency and protect consumer's rights, one example being anti-trust legislation. However, the terms are often used interchangeably within deregulated/liberalized industries.

Laissez-faire is a French phrase meaning "let it be" (literally,"Let do"). From the French diction first used by the 18th century physiocrats as an injunction against government interference with trade, it became used as a synonym for strict free market economics during the early and mid-19th century. It is generally understood to be a doctrine that maintains that private initiative and production are best allowed to roam free, opposing economic interventionism and taxation by the state beyond that which is perceived to be necessary to maintain individual liberty, peace, security, and property rights. Free-market anarchists take the idea to its full length by opposing all taxation.

The invisible hand is a metaphor coined by the economist Adam Smith to illustrate how those who seek wealth by following their individual self-interest, stimulate the economy as a secondary effect and thus assist society as a whole. In The Wealth of Nations and other writings, Smith claims that, in capitalism, an individual pursuing his own good tends also to promote the good of his community, through a principle that he called &#8220;the invisible hand&#8221; of the market. Specifically, a free competitive market ensures that those goods and services perceived as most beneficial, efficient, or of highest quality will naturally be those that are most profitable. The mechanism for this, Smith saw as being the free price system.

1. End government subsidies to corporations (aka corporatism).

2. Abolish/Privatize federal regulatory agencies such as the FDA, FCC, FAA, etc.

3. Abolish the Federal Reserve system and allow monetary currencies to dictate themselves in a free market.</description>
  <mission>Promoting free markets through government deregulation.</mission>
  <name>Laissez-faire</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5307</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">72</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eU/JW/SI/UN/4B/o8/bLgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
