<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 1954, The National Kidney Foundation of Massachusetts, Rhode Island, New Hampshire and Vermont is one of 51 affiliates of the National Kidney Foundation (NKF), a major voluntary health agency.


** Through screening and community education,  we help high-risk individuals avoid kidney disease or get the best treatment as early as possible.

** Kidney disease patients at all stages turn to the National Kidney Foundation and its affiliates for critical information and support in managing their illness and their medical care.

** By increasing public awareness of organ transplantation and helping people find ways to talk about it with their loved ones, we help increase the supply of available organs of all types.

** Medical education and research supported by the National Kidney Foundation is leading to better and more consistent treatment for all patients at risk for kidney disease.

Our work is funded primarily by individual and corporate donations, which are tax deductible to the fullest extent allowed by law. Please consider making a donation that will support our vital programs and services.

~~ Taken from http://www.kidneyhealth.org/mission.html ~~

1. More than 20 million Americans - one in nine adults - have chronic kidney disease. Another 20 million Americans are at increased risk for developing kidney disease.

2. Each year, nearly 60,000 Americans die from causes related to kidney failure.

3. Kidney disease results in 27 million physician visits, 6 million hospitalizations and 2.5 million surgical procedures each year.

4. Over 84,000 U.S. patients are currently on the waiting list for an organ transplant.

5. Every 90 minutes, someone dies while waiting for a transplant of a vital organ.

6. Organ transplant demand rises 5 times as fast as supply. </description>
  <mission>to prevent kidney and urinary tract disease, improve the health and well-being of individuals and families affected by these diseases, and increase the availability of all organs for transplant.</mission>
  <name>National Kidney Foundation of MA/RI/NH/VT</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5320</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">142</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Dr/RY/bE/gK/zT/dP/IoES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
