<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our planet is slowly dying, no not from using too much electricity or warfare or fuel emissions.. it is from the scenesters, poseurs and hipsters that have taken it upon themselves to emit harmful and toxic emissions that can be possibly contagious to any person with a lack of character.

Unfortunately, this epidemic has caused: good drinks to be spilled, more people wearing earplugs, less people enthused by their surroundings, more meaningless tattoos on people and less overall intelligence.  However it has amazingly increased: blind political correctness, blindly patronizing several causes and more fans of family guy and Steve Colbert (because he is really smart and funny!)

Some indications that you might know someone who is irresponsibly emitting douche-vibes and ruining our planet:

- Wearing sun glasses in a club
- Wearing a Von Dutch cap
- Subscribing to the indie social movement
- Informing others about their own personal agendas, tastes and other irrelevant information when answering the question "whats the time?"
- Regulars at the drake hotel
- Wearing a scarf with a t-shirt
- Wearing a bhedioun scarf/turban as a fashion statement (person might seem to think they appear 'dangerous' so they might be packing some mace)
- A Frequent collar popper

These are generalized yet rapidly developing symptoms, not all people who display such qualities are culprits of killing our planet, but displaying a few of these symptoms can develop to more severe and heinous habits. 
Joining this cause will help spread the awareness and will also give you the self satisfaction of saving our planet today! not tomorrow. 

1. Join our cause

2. Spread the awareness

3. (optional) Help your friends if you feel you have to, but the symptoms usually wear off due to trendier habits and such</description>
  <mission>Eradicate douche-vibes and emissions from this planet that is caused by the ever growing conceited belief that anyone can be hip and make sure everyone else knows about it</mission>
  <name>Abolish douchebags and save the planet!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5324</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">235</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dc/s6/kI/6E/FJ/cy/1QhS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
