<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Pictured is one of Canada's worst pedophile priests, Anglican Church of Canada's Canon Walter Bockus, (who was honoured with the title "Canon" AFTER he had been caught molesting Anglican children!).
Walter Bockus molested many of my schoolmates, classmates and neighbours in Greenfield Park, Quebec. Five decades later, many of them have not healed.
When Bockus was caught by a parent, in lieu of calling in the police, the Anglican Church TRANSFERRED him to New Brunswick!
We now have learned from reliable sources that there are an untold number of Anglican priests across Canada who molested the children of their parishes, using the fear of God and their "respected" positions to force themselves on these poor innocents.
The Church knowingly moved these priests to new parishes where they molested more children!
Yet, the church did NOTHING for the children!
Many of these children, now adults and living coast to coast, need the financial support of the church to pay for the expensive counseling many still require.
These Victims deserve the peace and grace the pedophile priests received!
The Anglican Church of Canada, up to and including the Primate, the Church's Archbishop, continue to steadfastly REFUSE to make amends.
Until the Church puts out a call for all Victims to come forward for FULL subsidization of their counselling, PLEASE STOP PUTTING MONEY IN THEIR COLLECTION PLATES!
Perhaps, like me, you will cease atttending the Anglican Church of Canada altogether. 
In the NAME OF GOD they ALLOWED their priests to get away with molesting little parish children!!!!!
This organization STILL refuses to help the Victims with their recoveries. Therefore, the church MUST feel where it hurts the most: financially.
A donation to Starlight Starbright Children's Foundation is NOT required. In setting up this Cause, it just seemed right to suggest helping other children in need, because the Anglican Church of Canada REFUSED to help their own!

1. Please Help the Victims! It is time to fully BOYCOTT the Anglican Church.</description>
  <mission>We must force the Anglican Church of Canada to accept responsibility for the thousands of Victims molested by their priests.</mission>
  <name>Boycott the Anglican Church of Canada</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5342</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Kx/48/d6/jJ/O2/XF/NeSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
