<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Respect for other people is the key to peace. It is not a battle plan, a missile, a government policy, or something you can enforce. Respect is valuing other people no matter who they are, what they do, or what they believe in. It is not the same as supporting something, nor does it give the right to push your beliefs on other people. Given a fair, peaceful, open minded and honest ground, the greatest truths will surface or reveal itself to others without the need for arguing, wars, government policies, or picketing. 

Violence will never breed peace. Asserting ideals, no matter how good, through violence and wrong will only bring about evil, not peace.

Equality is not sameness. Two people can be of equal value, but not the same. No two people are the same so we must respect and value others despite differences.

You cannot respect and care for all people and expect peace to go hand in hand with greed. Greed cannot co-exist with peace because greed breeds envy and spite, setting people against each other. 

If enemies knew that we respected them, did not want to hurt them, take anything of their's, or push or change their beliefs, then what reason would they have for attacking us?

Tolerance is not silence about your own beliefs, but the open and respectful sharing of them. Any belief is acceptable as long as it done with respect for others. Respect is not respecting disrespect.

The surest sign of true progress is not merely the verbal or mental acceptance of the truth, but the living out and personal application. Until it has affected and transformed your life and actions, you have not actually grasped the truth at all.

1. Respect for others is the corner stone of peace. 

2. "You must be the change you wish to see in the world."</description>
  <mission>To spread peace through respect.</mission>
  <name>Respect and Peace</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5345</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">19</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/RX/Dq/gy/Hm/re/kt/N40S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
