<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>If the forefathers and mothers were to look at our country today, they would be in disgrace. The ability to find common-ground amongst political ideologies has been cast off in extreme polarization. Every issue and candidate has been thrown into this quagmire, and it is going to take an exceptional president to pacify the calescent climate.

It is our belief that this candidate is NYC Mayor Mike Bloomberg, for the following reasons:

1. Nonpartisan - Bloomberg is indebted to America, not its parties.

2. Non-DC candidate - Most candidates are connected to DC and are also collectively inept at solving our country&#8217;s issues.

3. New politics - A socially liberal business tycoon has successfully capitalized on Wall Street, and that success can easily move 200 miles south to Pennsylvania Ave.

4. Agrees with Americans on many issues - Increasing education advancement, real health (and not sick) care, job creation, balanced budget, raking in crime, and caring for the poor.

5. Not afraid to stand for tough issues:
   a. Opposes timetabled withdrawal on Iraq.
   b. Pro-gay marriage
   c. Revolutionary pro-environment, taxing carbon emissions, introducing traffic congestion taxes, and passing a city-wide ban on smoking and trans fats.
   d. Real immigration reform, starting at the roots of its cause in poor countries.

6. Independent of parties &amp; political donations - Each presidential candidate's campaign coffers have an IOU attached to them. Bloomberg, with an estimated bank account of $5.5 billion, does not.

7. Leads by example - Over the last four years, Bloomberg has donated at least $500 million to philanthropic causes, most to aid children, the poor, and the sick.

8. Knows and does what is best - Soon after being elected by a slim 50-48% margin, Bloomberg's approval ratings dropped. Yet Bloomberg stuck to his good managerial instincts and has led New York City into a more innovative, bold, and booming city. Our nation deserves the same


1. Draft &amp; elect Mike Bloomberg President of the United States</description>
  <mission>Draft &amp; elect Mike Bloomberg President of the United States in 2008</mission>
  <name>8 for Bloomberg in '08</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5351</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">22</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/M3/8U/Yb/mH/K3/31/8q3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
