<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Children's Miracle Network is the alliance of premier children's hospitals. Every year, Children's Miracle Network hospitals treat 17 million children for every disease and injury imaginable. Children's Miracle Network hospitals impact the lives of more children than any other children's organization in the world. Children's hospitals provide state-of-the-art care, life-saving research and preventative education for children 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. There is a Children's Miracle Network hospital dedicated to serving children in every community across the United States and Canada. These hospitals are committed to providing the best care for children when they need it. 



Children need the specialized care and equipment only children&#8217;s hospitals can provide. Children's Miracle Network hospitals:

    * Provide $2.5 billion in charity (uncompensated) care each year
    * Treat 98% of all children needing heart or lung transplants
    * Treat 88% of all children with cancer
    * Treat 76% of all children with cystic fibrosis
    * Treat 90% of all children with sickle cell anemia
    * Treat 72% of all children with pediatric AIDS
    * Devote 60% of their services to children under age six and 25% to newborns
    * Train 60% of pediatricians and 80% of all pediatric specialists
    * Educate families about issues like child safety seats, helmet safety and bike safety



&#8220;One hundred years from now, it will not 
matter the sort of house I live in, what my 
bank account was, or the kind of car I 
drove, but the world may be different 
because I was important in the life of a child.&#8221;

~Anonymous


1. help children in the US and canada

2. help families with sick children</description>
  <mission>helps ensure that children have the specialized care they need and deserve.</mission>
  <name>Children's Miracle Network: Kids helping kids</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5361</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">577</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cR/II/DU/ge/Uw/En/SLUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
