<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Michael&#8217;s Electric Health Campus is a new program proposal by Michael Oellig to help with America&#8217;s health and energy predicaments. The program is designed to round up all the morbidly obese people in American and force them to walk in turbines (like the one on the cover of this cause page. (I drew it in church)) and generate electricity. Did you know that walking is equivalent to about 235 miles per gallon and bicycling is equivalent to about 653 mpg? Therefore, I have realized that human &#8220;fat&#8221; is some of the most valuable energy in the world! The electrical generation program would not only be a clean and efficient method of generating energy, but also, one the greatest advances to public health since CPR and AEDs (Automated External Defibrillator). Morbidly fat people not only drain medical resources, but also drain our food supply. However, we can make them very useful by helping them get their life back on tack and healthy again. Now I am sure that many of you at this point are saying that I am a Nazi and/or this is totally inhuman. To this I say blasphemy! I would invite the Red Cross, Amnesty International, Human Rights Watch, or anyone you would like to come and check out the camps. For I say, is it not more of a human rights violation to have morbidly obese children who will suffer major health problems because of a morbidly obese person's poor heath choices? I think that smoking during pregnancy is more of a human rights violation then abortion, because the child will have to live with the repercussions. Therefore, if we do not take action now, we will have greater health burdens, and greater energy failures across the grid. So, please send this along to your local representatives and see if he or she has strong integrity to do the right thing and propose/vote on this new program.

1. Morbidly Obese people drain our food supply.

2. Morbidly Obese people drain our medical resources.

3. Morbidly Obese people would make good, clean, safe, efficient energy.</description>
  <mission>To fix: Energy shortages, reduce green house gases, improve human health, save our food supply, and save our health care programs.</mission>
  <name>Fix America's Problems</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5362</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">65.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/RS/1z/aV/Gd/zc/Ce/vWoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
