<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>NoStigmas is a grassroots project to collect stories, photos and art which inspire hope and erase the stigmas of suicide &amp; mental illness. Please visit us at www.NoStigmas.com to see the project in action.

If you have something to share, we would love to hear from you! By sharing your story with NoStigmas you become part of a community of survivors and stigma erasers. This is an important and brave step toward healing and letting others know that they are not alone. Please know that your story will be held with respect and dignity and only shared to the extent which you feel comfortable. You do not have to share specific names, places or dates and are welcome to submit anonymously. That being said, we encourage you to never be ashamed of the actions of your loved ones or your story. Only by making the topics of suicide and mental illness a part of our daily lives, can we truly begin to prevent suicide and erase stigmas.

What to share - We will gladly accept any story format or type of media you care to share; essays, letters, poetry, pictures, blogs, art, even audio &amp; video recordings. Around one page (1,000 words) is suggested. Get creative and feel free to mix different types of media. Just let the story flow! 

What to avoid - Our only request is that your submission has an overall positive message that inspires hope. Be careful of dwelling only on the sad side of the story. However, suicide and mental illness are quite emotional and raw subjects that deal with the very essence of life and death.  This will naturally be a part of your story.  Just remember that these stories are meant to be about the journey out of the darkness and into a place of healing.

How to share - You can submit your story or any questions via email to share@nostigmas.com or write:

NoStigmas                        
226 N Clinton St
Suite 608
Chicago, IL 60661
United States

NoStigmas&#8482; is not a registered 501(c)3 non-profit organization, crisis or counseling center. Visit www.suicidepreventionlifeline.org 
or call 1-800-273-TALK (8255) for crisis services in the USA. Contact your healthcare professional or dial 911 in case of emergency.

1. NoStigmas is a grassroots movement to raise awareness and erase the stigmas of suicide and mental illness.

2. We strive to impact individuals with fresh ideas promoting the NoStigmas message.

3. Since over 1 million people die by suicide each year (over 33,000 in the U.S.), we maintain a "no apologies" approach to suicide awareness.

4. We believe that our message is important to every individual and needs to be conveyed in an exciting and energetic manner which affirms life.

5. Learn more about us and how to be involved by getting info@nostigmas.com today. </description>
  <mission>NoStigmas is a grassroots project to collect stories, photos and art which inspire hope and erase the stigmas of suicide &amp; mental illness. Visit us at www.NoStigmas.com to share your story!</mission>
  <name>NoStigmas | Suicide &amp; Mental Health Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5363</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8619</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1772.82</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Gb/px/m1/XC/Bs/Tz/zn/mCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
