<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>HFC is an entirely volunteer-run organization; every dollar of sponsorship monies goes directly to your sponsored child in Ethiopia.

Today, there are over 1.2 million children in Ethiopia who have been orphaned by HIV/AIDS. By 2010, this figure is projected to reach over 2 million - 20% to 30% of all children under age 15.

On top of the overwhelming grief of watching one or both parents slowly die from AIDS, these children have to deal with ostracism, uncertainty, fear and starvation.

Together, we can offer hope to these children!

WHAT HFC DOES:

- Support a child sponsorship program - For $300 a year (less than $1 a day), you can pay for a child&#8217;s food, shelter, school fees and materials, and basic health care. Your sponsorship can mean the difference between life and death for a child.
- Support targeted projects at Hope for Children - Ethiopia (for more information, see the website on http://www.hopeforchildrenus.org/)
- Raise awareness and advocate for these most vulnerable, but often forgotten, victims of the AIDS pandemic - the children
- HFC-US is an independent organization that is not acting on behalf of any foreign organization. All funds raised by HFC-US are for specific projects that have been pre-approved by HFC-US&#8217;s Board of Directors as being in furtherance of our exempt purposes. HFC-US at all times exercises control and discretion as to the use of all contributions made to it. 

1. In the eyes of every child is the light of the future. If the light dims, so does the hope of this world.</description>
  <mission>Hope for Children United States (HFC-US) is a US-based section 501(c)(3) organization dedicated to improving the lives of AIDS orphans in Ethiopia.</mission>
  <name>Hope for Children US / Ethiopia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/537</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">277</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dna/xlPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
