<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The AZ Lost Boys Center is a welcoming haven for all Arizona Lost Boys. It is a place to support unity among Lost Boys, regardless of tribe affiliation, yet is supportive of the unique qualities that are a source of pride to each young man. The center provides a comfortable and safe refuge to gather and talk with community leaders, receive help from a tutor, listen to music, play cards, or watch a video in the company of friends. A gallery featuring photos of lost boys at work and play, and their artwork and writings, decorate the walls. 

Who Are The Lost Boys of Sudan?

Since the mid-1980's, Sudan (in East Africa) has experienced brutal civil war fueled by religious, ethnic and regional strife. Fleeing the violence and bloodshed of Sudan's internal conflict, thousands of innocent children have experienced mind-numbing horrors and intense hardship. Orphaned as young as four years old, they fled into the jungle and began walking to Ethiopia. They stayed in refugee camps in Ethiopia until the government overthrew the Communists in 1991 and forced the young boys to leave at gunpoint. When they returned to Sudan, they were again met with hostility.

Thus began another long walk&#8212;this time to a United Nations refugee camp in Kenya. They lived in Kakuma since 1992. Although hungry, frightened, and weakened, their spirit of hope remained strong through their unyielding faith in God, and their intense desire to become educated. Intolerable living conditions in the camp gave the United States government reason to resettle some 4,000 of these, now, young men in America. In 2001, some 550 &#8220;Lost Boys&#8221; have &#8220;found&#8221; Arizona and have made it their new home. They are bright with hope, full of smiles, and ready to become contributing members of their new communities.


visit website: http://www.azlostboyscenter.org/

1. Powered by Hope. Shared by all.</description>
  <mission>Empower the Lost Boys and Girls of Sudan to achieve their goals by supporting their educational, employment, cultural and emotional needs. </mission>
  <name>AZ Lost Boys Center</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5378</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">166</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mC/Lb/gE/o1/oj/wX/MmsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
