<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Through its Education programs, UPA provides support for educational non-governmental organizations, as well as, providing aid to worthy students in West Bank and Gaza through approximately ten local universities.

UPA's Child Sponsorship progam, one of its most popular, provides our sponsors the opportunity to sponsor children through local organizations and schools in West Bank, Gaza, and refugee camps in Lebanon. To date, over 600 children are sponsored. Sponsors develop lasting relationships with their children sometimes continuing to sponsor their university educations.

United Palestinian Appeal, Inc. is a non-profit, non-political, tax-exempt American organization, independent of any political affiliation. UPA maintains its independence and integrity as a strictly humanitarian organization by not accepting funds from political groups or from any source that may attach unacceptable conditions to its contributions. UPA is also registered with the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) as a private voluntary organization engaged in foreign aid, as well as with the Combined Federal Campaign, the national organization allowing for charitable solicitation of federal government employees. Its mission is to alleviate the suffering of Palestinians, particularly those in the West Bank, Gaza, and the refugee camps of Lebanon, and to contribute to the long-term socioeconomic and cultural development of Palestinian society.

P.S. UPA is a humanitarian non-political organization with a mission to alleviate the suffering of Palestinians. This cause was created by individuals, and UPA is not responsible for the cause in any way.

1. Provide support for educational non-governmental organizations

2. Provide aid to worthy students in West Bank and Gaza</description>
  <mission>Provide aid to worthy students in West Bank and Gaza</mission>
  <name>Support Education for Palestinians</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5390</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3752</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1313.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ax/HE/b4/Ho/Gt/vF/X02S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
