<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Please make your cause to be the prevention of  genocide and mass atrocities.

Together we can work to 
- end mass atrocities in Darfur
- campaign, educate people and push for policy changes to prevent the next genocide
- remember the victims of past genocides
- provide practical help and care for survivors.

Aegis established the Holocaust Centre in the UK and, together with Kigali City Council, built and manages the Kigali Memorial Centre in Rwanda.  

Major activities include running social programs for Rwandan survivors, the Protect Darfur campaign, an international Darfur Divestment campaign, and  assisting the All Party Parliamentary Group on Genocide Prevention.

We use your support to:
- provide practical help to survivors in Rwanda
- campaign to end the crisis in Darfur
- remember the victims of the Holocaust and of the  Rwandan genocide 
- educate hundreds of thousands of school children about genocide and the dangers of hatred
- conduct research into catching genocidaires, early warning of genocides, deployment of peacekeeping missions, power sharing systems, and improving the enforcement of international criminal law

We'd like you to sign up to this cause and join the Facebook group:
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2371714543

There you can see videos, learn more about Darfur and Rwanda, sign petitions, e-campaign and make your voice heard.

You can find out more at:
http://www.aegistrust.org
http://www.kigalimemorialcentre.org
http://www.holocaustcentre.net
http://www.darfurdivestment.org

1. Together we can prevent the next genocide 

2. Together we can end the ongoing mass killings in Darfur

3. Together we can remember the victims, educate people about the outcomes of hatred, and provide practical help to survivors</description>
  <mission>...is to prevent genocide and mass atrocities</mission>
  <name>Prevent genocide and mass atrocities</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5392</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1094</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">95.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/o1/4d/Tz/1Z/8t/H0/6gES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
