<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Almost a billion people lack access to clean, safe water.

Half of the world's hospital beds are occupied by patients suffering from water-related diseases.

The last time you flushed your toilet, you used more water than the average person in the developing world uses all day for washing, cooking, cleaning, and drinking.

Living Water International is addressing the most basic of physical needs by helping deprived communities acquire safe, clean water. Our goal is to substantially ease the global water crisis while addressing root causes such as injustice, oppression, and abject poverty. Our passion is to see communities and worldviews transformed, both among those in desperate physical need and among those who have been blessed with much.

LWI has completed more than 6,500 water projects which provide clean, safe water to more than 7.5 million people every day. The organization provides training and volunteer opportunities. LWI is currently at work in 26 countries: Mexico, Guatemala, El Salvador, Honduras, Nicaragua, Panama, Malawi, Haiti, Peru, Brazil, Liberia, Ghana, Nigeria, Central African Republic, Angola, Namibia, Sierra Leone, Sudan, Uganda, Kenya, Tanzania, Ethiopia, Rwanda, India, Zambia, and Romania.

You can make a difference! One dollar will provide clean drinking water for one person for one year.

Visit Living Water International's Facebook Page for photos, videos, discussions, etc...
http://www.new.facebook.com/pages/Living-Water-International/27435676592

1. Clean water changes everything.

2. 2.2 million people die every year because they lack access to safe water.

3. Those who have been blessed with much have a responsibility to help the neediest among us.</description>
  <mission>demonstrate the love of God by helping communities acquire desperately needed clean water, and experience "living water"--the gospel of Jesus Christ--which alone satisfies the deepest thirst.</mission>
  <name>Living Water International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5398</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">21481</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35914.24</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dX/Ec/OH/c3/FX/Ij/YD/NeS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
