<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Psoriasis affects an estimated 2-3 percent of the world's population. 

125 million people worldwide have psoriasis, according to the World Psoriasis Day consortium. 

11 percent of those diagnosed with psoriasis have also been diagnosed with psoriatic arthritis. This is a prevalence of 0.25 percent of American adults in the general population.2 

Psoriasis is not a cosmetic problem. Nearly 60 percent reported their disease to be a large problem in their everyday life.1 

Nearly 40 percent with psoriatic arthritis reported their disease to be a large problem in everyday life.2 

Patients with psoriasis covering more of their body (more extensive skin disease) experienced a greater negative impact on their quality of life.4 

Less than 40 percent of respondents indicated they were very satisfied with any of the four therapies assessed in the study (acitretin [brand name Soriatane], cyclosporine, methotrexate or PUVA [psoralen plus ultraviolet light A]).5 

Nearly 80 percent of persons who were very dissatisfied with their treatment did not have severe disease (less than 10 palms of coverage or &lt;10 percent BSA).1 

Members of the National Psoriasis Foundation reported their disease to be significantly less of a burden and were more satisfied with treatment.6 

Psoriatic arthritis usually develops between the ages of 30 and 50, but it can develop at any time. 

If one parent has psoriasis, a child has about a 10 percent chance of having psoriasis. If both parents have psoriasis, a child has approximately a 50 percent chance of developing the disease. 

1. Contact your senators and other representatives.

2. If you have Psoriasis, contribute a blood sample to the Biobank (http://www.psoriasis.org/research/biobank)

3. Invite others to join the group and donate their time and money.

4. 1 of 3 people with Psoriasis report a relative with Psoriasis

5. Psoriasis often appears between 15 and 25 (but it can show up at any age)

6. Psoriasis had a greater impact on the quality of life in women and younger patients.

7. Psoriasis prevalence in African Americans was 1.3 percent compared to 2.5 percent of Caucasians.

8. 2.2 percent of American adults have been diagnosed with psoriasis confirming that it is a common disease.

9. Studies have shown that 10-30 % of people with psoriasis develop psoratic arthritis

10. According to the National Institute of Health (NIH), 5.8 to 7.5 million Americans have Psoriasis.

11. *******************************************************

12. FEEL FREE TO POST ANY TREATMENTS THAT YOU THINK WORK WELL.  LETS HELP EACH OTHER HERE.

13. *******************************************************</description>
  <mission>LET'S GET THIS BILL PASSED AND MADE A LAW!</mission>
  <name>Psoriasis and a Psoriatic Arthritis Research, Cure, and Care Act (PPARCCA) of 2007</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5410</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1219</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/aU/4i/dD/MH/Z5/yP/MhAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
