<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>If you have items that you no longer want, donate them to eBoy and we will sell them and donate the proceeds to a cause of your choice.  We have years of experience on eBay, a MissionFish account, and are 501(c)(3) registered.  

eBoy was started by Alex Hodara, Jason Anderson, and Sal Esposito.  The founders started this foundation in high school.  This tri-pod of entrepreneurs met while playing on the Westfield Ice Hockey Team.  

-------------------------------------------

About the top executives at eBoy:
Mr. Esposito has a long past working with eBay sales.  He got his start as an auction writer at eBabe and eDude Auctions.  His fountain of knowledge which was taught by his eBay-Wizard boss has worked as a foundation for this entity.  

Mr. Anderson has spent years learning the ins and outs of eBay.  He has a long history of purchasing and selling items on eBay.  His nickname in high school was the buylow-sellhigh-guy.  We have been told that Mr. Anderson is quite the looker.  In fact, Anderson is currently studying to get his personal training license.  Anderson brings firepower, a couple muscles, and incomparable talent to eBoy.  

Mr. Hodara is a very hard worker, but he is always willing to curl up with a good book or schmooze with colleagues.  He is a world renowned yo-yo spinner, chess enthusiast, and table-tennis player.  He is a wiz in the kitchen and can cook over ten kinds of lean cuisines.  His entrepreneurial spirit and love for the game fuse together to make great contributions to eBoy.  

eBoy has a few helping hands that have brought their financial well-being to a new level.  Ariel Mone, the organizations special projects manager, has overseen tasks such as The Plainfield Homeless Shelter Sunday Bagel Breakfast, The Ring Toss (where she actually had to fight off someone trying to steal money), and The Kissing Booth hosted at Mr. Espositos residence.  

1. Don't throw it away, donate it to a good cause.</description>
  <mission>liquidate donated items by selling them on eBay and giving the proceeds to different causes.</mission>
  <name>The eBoy Charity Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5414</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">40</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/FA/kd/u3/rO/U4/nv/VTxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
