<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Under the current rules of the National Blood Service, you can NEVER give blood if you are a man who has EVER had sexual contact with another male.  

I personally met the (then) head of the group who made this policy and was fed a load of excuses that didn't quite add up.

The basic message I got down to - after questioning his reasoning - was "we just don't want gay blood cos we already have enough without it".

This is ridiculous and offensive!

I could go into figures and statistics, but - as a reasonable and intelligent person - I am FULLY confident from my research that it is absolutely safe to remove this rule.

Besides the statistics and common sense involved, it is important to remember that ALL donations are screened and tested anyway.

The THT support this rule - despite its lack of logic.  They are a gay HIV/AIDs charity and NBS use this fact to support their illogical and offensive rule-making.  THT are simply playing at politics - trying not to be contraversial - in order to gain support and funding for their charity.

Yes, this group is radical, but I feel this is a direct way to get the rule changed.  It may be changed for the wrong reasons - necessity as apposed to acceptence - but the outcome will be the same and changing the rule BACK would be very difficult for them to get away with.

1. Men who have had sexual contact with men should be allowed to donate if they fit the other requirements.

2. Nobody should give blood - in order to force a rule change.

3. The THT should not support this rule.

4. Safer sex should be taught more often and to a better extent in schools.

5. Safer sex education should target all sexualities</description>
  <mission>Remove the ridiculous rule that prevents gay/bi experienced men from donating blood</mission>
  <name>DON'T Give Blood Until The NBS Stops Being Homophobic</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5420</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">259</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dC/K6/h6/63/0x/SW/N6cS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
