<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Humane Society was founded in 1989 by nine concerned individuals who saw a need for an animal welfare organization in the community. It has since grown into an organization with over 700 members. 

The main objectives of the Humane Society are to improve the lives of animals in Lowndes County and surrounding areas and to put an end to the pet overpopulation problem. Our motto: "We Speak for Those Who Can Not Speak For Themselves," expresses a strong desire to help animals by giving them a voice through education, outreach, and advocacy.

Although often confused with the animals shelter, The Humane Society is not affiliated with Lowndes County Animal Services. We are two separate entities with different policies and procedures. 

WE DO NOT RECEIVE ANY FUNDING FROM THE NATIONAL HUMANE SOCIETY OR THE GOVERNMENT. Funding is raised through memberships, donations, fundrais, corporate donations, and grants.

We have many programs which include:
     *Amos Barfield Spay/Neuter Assistance Program
     *Foster/Adoption Program
     *Animal Cruelty Task Force (A.C.T.)
     *Pet Therapy Program
     *Junior Humane Society

The Humane Society is made up mostly of volunteers. The Humane Society would not exist without caring, dedicated volunteers. The annual membership fee is only $10. Just send in your donation and you will begin to receive our quarterly newsletter which will keep you informed of upcoming events, animal welfare issues, and other items that need special attention! 


Our Address is:                 Please send donations to:
Humane Society                Humane Society
307 E. Jane St.                  P.O. Box 5323
Valdosta, GA 31602           Valdosta, GA 31604

Ashley Aultman
Administrative Assistant
SNAP Coordinator


1. Pet overpopulation must be ended! Please Spay and Neuter your pet(s). Call our office for low cost spaying and neutering!

2. Animal Cruelty must stop! Our goal is to educate the public of Puppy Mills and Breeders.

3. Don't shop...ADOPT!! We are in SERIOUS need of foster homes. Countless numbers of helpless animals are being put out and/or euthanized daily!</description>
  <mission>advocate the elimination of animal abuse, pet overpopulation and homelessness among animals by promoting spaying and neutering of all pets, promoting adoptions, and by educating to the community.</mission>
  <name>Humane Society of Valdosta/Lowndes County</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5436</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">73</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">75.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bZ/Be/hV/x6/qE/E1/DW8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
