<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 1973, The Heritage Foundation is a research and educational institute&#8212;a think tank&#8212;whose mission is to formulate and promote conservative public policies based on the principles of free enterprise, limited government, individual freedom, traditional American values, and a strong national defense.

We are not afraid to begin our sentences with the words "We believe," because we do believe: in individual liberty, free enterprise, limited government, a strong national defense, and traditional American values.

We want an America that is safe and secure; where choices (in education, health care and retirement) abound; where taxes are fair, flat, and comprehensible; where everybody has the opportunity to go as far as their talents will take them; where government concentrates on its core functions, recognizes its limits and shows favor to none. And the policies we propose would accomplish these things.

Our expert staff&#8212;with years of experience in business, government and on Capitol Hill&#8212;don't just produce research. We generate solutions consistent with our beliefs and market them to the Congress, the Executive Branch, the news media and others. These solutions build on our country's economic, political and social heritage to produce a safer, stronger, freer, more prosperous America. And a safer, more prosperous, freer world.

As conservatives, we believe the values and ideas that motivated our Founding Fathers are worth conserving. And as policy entrepreneurs, we believe the most effective solutions are consistent with those ideas and values.

We believe that ideas have consequences, but that those ideas must be promoted aggressively.  So, we constantly try innovative ways to market our ideas.  We are proud of our broad base of support among the American people and we accept no government funds.

Our vision is to build an America where freedom, opportunity, prosperity and civil society flourish.

1. Free enterprise

2. Limited government

3. Individual freedom

4. Traditional American values

5. A strong national defense.</description>
  <mission>Advance conservative ideas and public policy in Washington and around the country</mission>
  <name>Advance Conservative Principles</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/545</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1793</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">135.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/b4/lh/df/Ic/1i/Al/mp/aKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
