<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>YOUNG LEADERSHIP
The Young Leadership Committee is dedicated to upholding the values and promoting the mission of Migdal Ohr. By developing creative programming, the Committee attracts young Jewish professionals, educates them about our mission, and encourages increased involvement.

The Young Leadership Committee is open to everyone interested in generating awareness for Migdal Ohr and affecting change in the lives of others. Our dynamic members come from varied backgrounds, and offer a broad range of perspectives and experiences. Together we plan and attend fundraisers and social events, meet hundreds of young adults in the New York area, and, best of all, help save children in Israel.

MORE ABOUT MIGDAL OHR
Migdal Ohr is Hebrew for "Tower of Light," named for our ability to illuminate a path to a better life for orphaned, abused, underprivileged, and new immigrant children in Israel.
Migdal Ohr, Israel's largest youth village, provides a nurturing home and outstanding education to over 6,500 orphaned, impoverished, underprivileged and new immigrant children. 
At Migdal Ohr, the children's individual needs are met with love, warmth and tremendous sensitivity. 
Each child receives a new set of clothing tailored to them, health and dental care, and all the emotional and academic support they need to become happy, successful and fulfilled adults.

1. All children deserve a safe home.

2. All children deserve an excellent education regardless of their background.</description>
  <mission>Save children from abusive, poverty stricken, and neglected homes in Israel and provide them with a nurturing home and outstanding education.</mission>
  <name>Migdal Ohr</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5458</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">120</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1511.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/CA/js/il/Mp/UE/0D/ffuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
