<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Sustainable Travel International www.sustainabletravel.com is a NGO that promotes responsible travel through programs that help travelers, businesses and destinations protect the environment, preserve cultural heritage and promote economic development.

Climate and Carbon Management Program has helped to recover more than 82 million pounds of CO2 emissions from the atmosphere through certified renewable energy, efficiency and reforestation projects. This represents: 
- Removing 6,847 cars from the road
- Preventing  86,939 barrels of oil from burning
- Allowing 958,562 seedling trees to grow for 10 years
- Preventing 261 acres of forest from being cut down

Sustainable Tourism Eco-Certification Program&#8482; is the world's first comprehensive sustainable tourism certification program offered by a NGO.  STEP received the highest rating of any related program in an independent study conducted by the UN Foundation in 2007.  

Education and Outreach programs help consumers demand positive change from companies, and provide assistance to companies in meeting those demands.  In 2008, STI provided:
- Climate and carbon management outreach to  46,000,000 consumers
- Sustainability education to 350 businesses
- Education via the web with over 6,000,000 visits
- Educational training to 1,000 business leaders

Travelers&#8217; Philanthropy allows travelers to support grassroots projects that make a difference. 

Many of the most beautiful cultures and eco-systems are located in economically depressed locations.  Sustainable Tourism Destination Management Services provide solutions for integrating sustainable tourism practices into destination management. 

Our Advisory Services, have helped industry leaders from American Express to Continental Airlines.  We worked with Natural Habitat Adventures to reduce their carbon footprint. Together, we created a carbon management plan unique to their needs, including a calculator which highlights Nathab&#8217;s commitment to carbon neutral travel and educates its clientele about climate change.

1. Responsible Travel

2. Ecotourism

3. Sustainable Development</description>
  <mission>TO LEAVE THE WORLD A BETTER PLACE</mission>
  <name>SUSTAINABLE TRAVEL INTERNATIONAL</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5463</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">543</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">46.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7C/wC/vt/It/8k/Yp/ag0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
