<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Black Warrior Riverkeeper's mission is to protect and restore the Black Warrior River and its tributaries. We are a citizen based non-profit organization dedicated to improving water quality, habitat, recreation, and public health throughout our patrol area, the Black Warrior River watershed. This vital river basin is entirely contained within Alabama, America's leading state for freshwater biodiversity. Patrolling waterways, educating the public, and holding polluters accountable has made us an important proponent of clean water throughout the basin. Our job is to identify major pollution problems and work on cleaning them up.

Founded in 2001 by David Whiteside and Roger Conville, our staff includes Nelson Brooke (Riverkeeper), Eva Dillard (Staff Attorney), John Kinney (Enforcement Coordinator), Jennifer Patterson (Program Director), and Charles Scribner (Executive Director). We also benefit greatly from the New Merkel Consulting Group's support. Named 2006 Watershed Organization of the Year by the Alabama Rivers Alliance, 2007 Conservation Organization of the Year by the Alabama Environmental Council, and 2008 Green Paddle Award winner by the American Canoe Association, Black Warrior Riverkeeper is a proud member of Waterkeeper Alliance.

As a citizen-based watchdog group, we rely on the public for pollution reports, donations and volunteering. If you would like to report pollution, volunteer, or donate to Black Warrior Riverkeeper please contact us at info@blackwarriorriver.org  or 205-458-0095. Donations through this facebook "Causes" page also go 100% towards our efforts.  Thank you!  

Follow us on social networking websites:

Twitter: http://www.Twitter.com/BWRiverkeeper

Facebook (Causes): http://www.Causes.com/BlackWarriorRiverkeeper 

Facebook (Fans) www.facebook.com/pages/Black-Warrior-Riverkeeper/137285055046 

MySpace: http://www.MySpace.com/Black_Warrior_Riverkeeper

1. Clean water is a basic human right

2. The Black Warrior River watershed has 16,145.89 miles of mapped water, entirely within Alabama, America's leading state for freshwater biodiversity

3. Riverkeeper investigates pollution problems, educates the public, and promotes practical solutions. </description>
  <mission>Our mission is to protect and restore the Black Warrior River and its tributaries. </mission>
  <name>Black Warrior RIVERKEEPER</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5466</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6151</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">7730.34</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wt/v4/M5/gQ/5J/O5/cc5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
