<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Friends of Indianapolis Animal Care &amp; Control Foundation is an independent 501(c)(3) charitable organization that strives to improve animal welfare by supplementing the work of Indianapolis Animal Care &amp; Control, Indiana's largest shelter.  The Friends Foundation was established through the dedicated efforts of concerned volunteers and leaders of Animal Care &amp; Control to address the problem of homeless and unwanted pets in our community.  Funds raised by the foundation are used for programs to decrease pet overpopulation, educate the public about responsible pet ownership and for specific shelter improvement projects.

The number of stray and unwanted pets in Indianapolis increases each year.  In 2004, Animal Care &amp; Control took in more than 19,000 animals.  Friends believes it can assist in the reduction of animal overpopulation in the Indianapolis community.

The Friends Foundation supports Indianapolis Animal Care &amp; Control (IACC).  IACC encourages the adoption of pets, enforces ordinances and laws regarding animal-related issues and conducts inspections for the licensing of facilities that sell, groom and kennel animals.

Services provided by IACC include the following:

~Pet First Aid sessions 
~Pet Adoption 
~Microchipping, the best and most reliable method of permanently identifying your pet 
~Kennel housing for stray animals. Check Animal Care &amp; Control if your pet is lost 
~Investigation of animals that are abandoned, not receiving proper care and treatment, sick or injured, aggressive and dangerous or barking 
~Animal bite investigations 
~Animal safety presentations 
~Medical treatment for injured or stray animals 
~Acceptance of stray or surrendered animals 


 
    
 
(Don't worry....your donations really will go to this  cause...it's not a scam)

    

    
 
  


1. Generate public awareness about the many adoptable pets at Animal Care &amp; Control; 

2. Support spay/neuter services to reduce the number of unwanted animals

3. Create educational programming for children and adults about responsible pet ownership. 

4. Put an end to animal neglect

5. Love animals like humans</description>
  <mission>Improve animal welfare</mission>
  <name>FRIENDS OF INDIANAPOLIS ANIMAL CARE &amp; CONTROL FOUNDATION</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5471</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">27</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Js/OL/0K/NF/ek/M5/tuJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
