<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Stop the insanity of a Coal-burning power plant in Midland. We do NOT need more pollution in our air and water. There is a wealth of information about the dangers of coal-burning, and NONE of them are safe. There is NO such thing as "clean coal".  The ultra-fine nano particles defeat ALL industrial filters and human barriers. They carry mercury and arsenic directly through our lungs, into our blood and pass the blood-brain barrier
&lt;br&gt;
 INFORMATION ON HOW TO HELP: www.midlandcares.org&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
        Need for a new plant based on the  Michigan 21st Century Energy Plan which assumed minimal efficiency and renewable energy efforts &lt;br&gt; 
    There are results from other states indicating an efficiency program can replace the need for a new coal plant at less than half the cost (financial and especially, environmental)&lt;br&gt;
         Renewable energy is a fast growing source of electricity with wind farms being constructed in the Thumb and solar production in Hemlock&lt;br&gt;
        A coal plant is paid for by ratepayers in monthly bills.  Efficiency and renewable energy can reduce electric bills&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Renewable Energy and Renewable Energy Programs Create More Jobs than Coal Plants&lt;br&gt;
       The Midland coal plant is projected to create only 100 jobs after construction. However, over 19,000 additional jobs can be created in Michigan and probably many in the Midland area by renewable energy and energy efficiency programs.  www.michigan.gov/gov/0,1607,7-168--166821--,00.html&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Health&lt;br&gt;
       A Lansing plant half the size of new Midland plant emits over 2 million pounds of toxic pollution a year including 500 pounds of airborne lead and 100 pounds of mercury
&lt;br&gt;scorecard.org/env-releases/facility.tcl?tri_id=48901LNSNG601IS&lt;br&gt;
         Electric plants use about 3 billion gallons of water a year for cooling. Can the Tittabawassee take such abuse? &lt;br&gt;
www.cleanwateraction.org/pdf/sd/BigStoneIIfactsheet_20070126.pdf 

1. The pollution from this coal-burning plant is not necessary or welcome

2. Our town has the capability to pioneer renewable energry programs, burning coal is unaccetable

3. Generations will be affected by this, it is our responsibility to stop it before it starts</description>
  <mission>stop the proposed coal-burning power plant from being built right in our backyard (saginaw and waldo)</mission>
  <name>NO COAL IN MIDLAND</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5473</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">51</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/BE/oV/7O/u0/Py/3s/rwTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
