<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Life is like a box of chocolates you never know what to expect - none of us are immune to sadness and pain and things going wrong around us. 

People are taken from us, relationships break down, jobs don't go as they should - life throws bad eggs as well as good - and it's at times like these, we need each other to keep us sane.

The Happiness Society is a bit like Facebook it keeps people sane and makes them realise in dark moments -they have support, are loved and not alone, that there are friends everywhere to guide and offer advice and its in dark moments when we put on a brave face to the outside world and pretend we are fine - that we need our friends the most. In America in the 1980's a man went around wearing a furry and comforting suit - asking complete strangesr if they wanted a hug - needless to say the majority said yes.  From the moment we are born, it is the comfort of cuddles that stops our cries - and this does not change in adulthood. We need each other to offer advice, words of wisdom and make one another smile again. So spread the word and spread the happiness, there is so much sadness in the world already  - we need to look at the wonderful things and focus on making each other happy. Life is short and we are so lucky to be here - let's enrich each others lives and support each other in times of need. Help by signing up to join the happiness society today across the world and spread joy, love and happiness.... xxx

1. Happiness is vital to our general wellbeing

2. Happiness and support heals in dark times

3. There is too much sadness already let's change this</description>
  <mission>Cheer people up and stop them feeling sad</mission>
  <name>The Happiness Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5479</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">82</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DB/5b/H0/Dv/Hk/Gy/N73S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
