<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Planned Pethood, Inc. is a non-profit, Northwest Ohio based organization who cares about the over population of dogs and cats in our community. We feel every companion animal deserves to live a life of dignity which includes adequate food, water, health care and a warm loving home. As a no-kill organization, Planned Pethood, Inc. provides medical treatment and behavioral rehabilitation for animals that come into our care and offers adoptable animals to the public. 

Thousands of dogs and cats are destroyed in local shelters every year as a result of pet overpopulation. To proactively solve this problem, Planned Pethood works with fifteen Northwest Ohio area veterinarians to provide affordable spay/neuter services. The organization works reactively through its creative adoption program by bringing the animals to the people who will provide suitable homes and loving care.

Did you know? In 2006, Planned Pethood saved the lives of over 2,500 dogs and cats! Pretty good for an all volunteer organization with no paid staff! We saved these dogs and cats with your help and the help of our volunteers. Our goal is to save 3,000 dogs and cats in 2007! Please help us meet this goal! We can't do it alone--we need your donations!

http://www.plannedpethood.org

1. Animals deserve to live a life of dignity which includes adequate food, water, health care and a warm loving home.

2. Provide medical treatment and behavioral rehabilitation for animals that come into our care and offer adoptable animals to the public. </description>
  <mission>To reduce the suffering and overpopulation of animals through education and low-cost spay/neuter programs and to rescue, vet, spay/neuter and place adoptable dogs and cats into good permanent homes.</mission>
  <name>Planned Pethood, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5486</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">29</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">200.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DQ/lC/yw/7K/Ux/8q/qhoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
