<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Did you know that 40,000 children will be born with a heart defect this year in the U.S alone?   We have seen about a 22% increase in the incidence of heart defects in live births over the years as well.  And, despite these defects being the #1 cause of death within the first year of life, the most common and most fatal of all birth defects, research in this area continues to be grossly underfunded.  We didn't know any of this, until it happened to us. 
In 2004, our daughter lost her battle with congenital heart defects at just four days of age. She underwent multiple open-heart surgeries and medical procedures to give her a chance live with Hypoplastic Left Heart Syndrome (there is no true "cure," but only palliative measures that can be taken.)  Sadly, she did not win her battle. It is our mission to support medical advancements that will improve outcomes for the defect that is responsible for taking more lives than any other defect.   We look to a day when more parents will enjoy watching their children grow and flourish as they beat these defects!  

 For the past 4 years, the Chloe Duyck Memorial Fund has been raising big hope for tiny hearts. Since the fund's inception, more than $160,000 has been raised. The primary source of funding is obtained through the annual event, Heart Day on the Square. We rely on donations and fundraising events to be able to fund ground-breaking research that will help ensure brighter tomorrows for the many children born with congenital heart defects. CHDs are the most fatal and most common birth defect with more than 40,000 children in the US being born with one of these defects each year.

In May of 2007, the research that the fund supported was chosen to be presented to more than 5,000 medical professionals from around the world at the most prestigious annual meeting held. This research could have an impact on any child that must undergo heart surgery.

Thank you for spreading the word and supporting the cause. The precious heart children and their families appreciate the support as it is every parent's hope to watch their child grow and flourish...Let's help these children defeat congenital heart defects!


1. To raise funding for research initiatives in the area of pediatric congenital heart defects and ultimately improving outcomes for these children.

2. To raise awareness of congenital heart defects which are not only on the rise, but are also the most common and most fatal of all birth defects.

3. To make a difference and bring hope to the many families who will be forced to deal with heart defects (now and in the future)</description>
  <mission>Raising big hope for tiny hearts through supporting research initiatives in the area of pediatric congenital heart defects. </mission>
  <name>Chloe Duyck Memorial Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5487</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1713</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2968.55</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/aF/S4/h4/nq/Oa/wb/sx/kKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
