<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For those of you who do not know, MaMa was my 95 year old great grandmother whom was beaten to death by her 71 year old roomate in a Northshore nursing home. This roomate had a violent history her 4 years at the home- my greatgrandmother was there 2 days and a night and a half before she was killed. The nursing home placed this wretched violent woman in a new room because of a dispute where she punched another woman in the chest over a cup of coffee...where did they move her? in a room with my Mama. This woman took a handle of a drawer and beat Mama to death. Mama could not cry for help, she had lost her voice due to an infection a week earlier that she was recovering from, and she couldnt move due to her broken hip. She was at this home to obtain therapy for her hip. 

This woman was charged with 2nd degree murder and placed in a home for the criminally insane...and the home? The place that put this woman in the room with Mama? Still up and running.

I am starting this group asking each and every one of you for help. We need as many believers and as many voices as we can get to shut these places down. Politics is a dirty dirty game; however, if there are so many voices, and so many believers, and so many people who say, "we are not fucking going anywhere," those senators know- if we don't pass this bill to protect the elderly we won't get re-elected.

Please help my family pass as many legislative bills as we can in order to protect those who can not protect themselves...those who could very well be your grandparent...

Dont let MaMa and all the others that wrongfully died without anyone knowing, die in vain. If you can't do this for me or even Mama, do it for your grandma or your grandpa..do it for yourself- you never know where you will end up at 70 years old.

Thank you for your support, and most importantly- your voice.

1. WWW.FORMAMA.ORG

2. &#183;	Please visit the site and take 2 minutes to read her story,

3. &#183;	read our positions, and sign the PETITION!!!

4. Thank you!</description>
  <mission>Get as many signatures on our upcomming petition to enforce laws that will protect the elderly</mission>
  <name>Dare to Care- Stopping Abuse in Nursing Homes Once and For all- "For Mama"</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5500</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1481</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pu/KY/Vp/2A/fa/5a/t4US.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
