<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>All money raised will go to CancerCare Manitoba to fund care and treatment programs and research in an effort to bring an end to breast cancer.

The Weekend to End Breast Cancer is a 60 km walk through the city of Winnipeg over the course of 2 days.

Year 3 here I come!  Okay I know it's ONLY 2007 but trust me it takes a long time to raise $2000 so I'm starting now to make sure that I have enough raised by the time 2008 rolls around, believe me it goes faster than you can imagine.  Plus I'm already behind the game there are a number of people on the top 10 fundraisers list for the 2008 walk.

In order to walk in the Weekend to End Breast Cancer I've agreed to raise a minimum of $2000.  Last year I just reached my $2000 goal and this year I would like to surpass that amount.

I'm dedicated to finding an end to breast cancer because it has personally affected my life.  My mom was first diagnosed with breast cancer in 1991 when I was 17.  Just 4 years later my grandmother lost her second battle with breast cancer.  Then 10 years later my mom was diagnosed again.  Both my mom and grandma were incredibly strong through their battles with the disease and endured surgeries, rounds of chemotherapy, rounds of radiation, and the constant worry of whether or not the treatment is going to work.  I don't want to see anyone else have to endure that, I don't want anyone else to have to watch their family member go through that and fear the outcome.

This weekend, this event, is quite simply incredible.  It is the most inspirational, fun, emotional, exhilirating, exhausting, unforgettable, weekend one can ever experience and it's all for a fantastic cause.

Please help me reach my goal, I'll go through the training, the work, the exhaustion, the tired feet, the blisters, if I can just raise the money.

To donate to me online or to print out a donation form that can be mailed in please go to:

http://www.endcancer.ca/site/TR?px=1233028&amp;pg=personal&amp;fr_id=1256

1. Let's put an END to breast cancer</description>
  <mission>See the link AT THE END for where to donate.

The Weekend to End Breast Cancer helps CancerCare Manitoba carry out leading-edge breast cancer initiatives.</mission>
  <name>2008 Weekend to End Breast Cancer - Winnipeg</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5503</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">80</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0i/AZ/hq/Z4/aX/BQ/QZ0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
