<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Love of Animals (LOA) started during Spring Break of 06' and was created during an Inclusive Leadership weekend long Adventure. Originally there were 10 students but now there is 7. Together the members decided to do something about animal cruelty. The members are trying to spread news about animal skinning, inhumane lab testing, animal cruelty, and other important topics. LOA is currently still together and is trying to get the facts across to smaller regions, which hopefully will spread as time goes on.

LOA Wants to Help This Organization. 


The Humane Society of the United States (HSUS) has worked since 1954 to promote the protection of all animals. We are the largest and most powerful animal protection organization with nearly 10 million members and constituents.

We celebrate the human-animal bond, and we fight animal cruelty and abuse in all of its forms. 

We work to reduce suffering and to create meaningful social change for animals by advocating for public policies to protect animals, investigating cruelty and working to enforce existing laws, educating the public about the issues, and assisting animals when disasters strike. 

Our major campaigns target four primary issues: 

1) factory farming
2) animal fighting and other forms of animal cruelty
3) the fur trade
4) inhumane sport hunting practices

Our other campaigns take on:

1) puppy mills
2) the private ownership of exotic animals as pets
3) greyhound racing
4) unacceptable animal research and testing practices

Our two signature programs&#65533;Pets for Life and Wild Neighbors&#65533;celebrate the benefits of the bond between people and animals who live with us or in our communities, and teach people how to solve human/animal conflicts humanely. 

http://www.hsus.org/

1. we provide direct care for thousands of animals at our sanctuaries, wildlife rehabilitation centers, and mobile veterinary clinics.</description>
  <mission>Celebrating animals, confronting cruelty.</mission>
  <name>Help Fight Animal Cruelty</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5510</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">90</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/JX/i5/hM/Ja/TG/og/XNpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
