<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>During WWII, the government of Japan orchestrated the enslavement of over 200,000 young girls and women from places such as China, Korea, Taiwan, Indonesia, and the Philippines to be sex slaves, euphemistically known as "comfort women."  These women were subject to horrific crimes such as gang rape, forced abortion, and repeated beatings.  These women were forced to "comfort" over 50 soldiers a day.  Only a small number survived the war and they are continuing to die of old age.

All these women want is for the Government of Japan to apologize and take full and unambiguous responsibility for their crimes, but Japan continues to deny any government involvement and is attempting to erase this issue from their history. 

Now, Rep. Mike Honda has proposed House Resolution 121 to demand an official apology from the Government of Japan.

Defend human rights and support the passage of House Resolution 121 that calls upon the government of Japan to apologize for its war crime of enslaving over 200,000 girls and women during World War II as "comfort women." The victims were referred to as "comfort women," but they were mostly girls under eighteen, some as young as twelve. 

Please understand that this is not an anti-Japan or a pro-Korea, China, Indonesia cause.  This is a pro-Human Rights cause. 


Note: Donations don't go anywhere, I just put Amnesty International because they are one of the organization supporting House Resolution 121.


------------------------------------------------------

Sign the Petition Online as Well!
http://labanforthelolas.blogspot.com/



121 Coalition
http://www.support121.org

------------------------------------------------------

House Resolution 121 has been passed unanimously in the House.  All we need to wait for now is for the Government of Japan must give an official, unequivocal apology to comfort women and take full and unambiguous responsiblity for their crimes. 

1. House Resolution 121 must be passed - Achieved! 

2. The Government of Japan must give an official apology to comfort women and take full and unambiguous responsiblity for their crimes.

3. Tragedies such as this must never happen again.</description>
  <mission>Support House Resolution 121 and the comfort women victimized by the Imperial Japanese Military</mission>
  <name>House Resolution: 121</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5515</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">108</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Av/YF/8H/7z/k0/CX/otNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
