<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In the year 2006, the Breast Cancer Site far exceeded its goal of 1000 free mammograms to women in need to reach 2447! The premiere sponsor of the Breast Cancer Site has agreed to donate an additional $20,000 to help fund free mammograms upon reaching the goal of 6 million clicks in the month of June. There are only four days left and the BCS has reached 74% of its goal, so please get to clicking! Be sure to invite others to the group as well. It doesn't cost you anything but a moment of your time!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Take a moment to look at my site and help &lt;a href=http://www.body-diamonds.com/pink-ribbon-jewelry.php&gt;fund FREE mammograms!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Your click on the "Fund Free Mammograms" button helps fund free mammograms for women in need &#8212; low-income, inner-city and minority women whose awareness of breast cancer and opportunity for help is often limited. Your click is paid for by site sponsors, and mammogram funding is provided to clinics throughout the U.S. through the efforts of the National Breast Cancer Foundation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A few facts:&lt;br&gt;
*In 2007, about 40,910 people will die from breast cancer in the United States (40,460 women, 450 men).&lt;p&gt;
*One in eight women or 12.6% of all women will get breast cancer in her lifetime.&lt;p&gt;
*Every 13 minutes a woman dies of breast cancer.&lt;p&gt;
*Breast cancer is the leading cause of cancer death in women between the ages of 15 and 54, and the second cause of cancer death in women 55 to 74.&lt;p&gt;
*Risks for breast cancer include a family history, atypical hyperplasia, delaying pregnancy until after age 30 or never becoming pregnant, early menstruation (before age 12), late menopause (after age 55), current use or use in the last ten years of oral contraceptives, and daily consumption of alcohol.&lt;br&gt;
*All donations to this cause go directly to the Susan G. Komen Foundation.*&lt;br&gt;
Resources:&lt;br&gt;
American Cancer Society&lt;p&gt;
National Cancer Institute&lt;p&gt;
Susan G. Komen Foundation&lt;p&gt;
The Breast Cancer Site&lt;p&gt;
The Y-Me Organization

1. Breast cancer education and early detection is vital to survival rates. The BCS contributes to early detection by funding free mammograms to women in need.</description>
  <mission>Help fund free mammograms to women in need, as well as support breast cancer research...</mission>
  <name>Support Breast Cancer Research and Help Fund Free Mammograms</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5518</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">33</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Id/0f/W4/qR/GS/OI/a5dS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
