<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What Is Cystic Fibrosis?

Cystic fibrosis (CF) is an inherited chronic disease that affects the lungs and digestive systems of about 30,000 children and adults in the United States (70,000 worldwide). A defective gene causes the body to produce unusually thick, sticky mucus that:

clogs the lungs and leads to life-threatening lung infections; and
obstructs the pancreas and stops natural enzymes from helping the body break down and absorb food.
In the 1950s, few children with cystic fibrosis lived to attend elementary school. Today, advances in research and medical treatments have further enhanced and extended life for children and adults with CF. Many people with the disease can now expect to live into their 30s, 40s and beyond.

Statistics: 
About 1,000 new cases of cystic fibrosis are diagnosed each year.
More than 80% of patients are diagnosed by the age of three.
At least 40% of the CF patient population is age 18 or older.
In 2005, the median age of survival was nearly 37 years.

The Cystic Fibrosis Foundation

Since 1955, the Cystic Fibrosis Foundation has been the driving force behind the pursuit of a cure. Thanks to the dedication and financial support from patients, families, clinicians, researchers, volunteers, individual donors, corporations and staff, we are making a difference. 
(www.cff.org)


One-hundred percent of the proceeds are presented to the CF foundation at The "Great Strides" walk-a-thon held nationally each year. "Great Strides" is the primary fundraiser for The Cystic Fibrosis Foundation. Ninety cents of every dollar given to the CFF goes directly to research for the cure and into finding new life saving medications so desperately needed for survival.


EVERYONE PLEASE MAKE ATLEAST THE MINIMUM DONATION. 

1. We are coming closer and closer to a cure for this disease, with the right funding we can help find a cure.</description>
  <mission>help raise money for CFF. ( Cystic Fibrosis Foundation)</mission>
  <name>Help find a cure for cystic fibrosis!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5521</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1533</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sD/Np/T5/7r/rt/jz/IPIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
