<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>   Regardless of what anybody thinks, the business/art/sport of professional wrestling places a very high demand on the physical and mental well being of its practicioners. As a result of this, many wrestlers make some very self-destructive choices that effect them for rest of thier lives. Some examples performing very high risk stunts in the ring, being away from thier families for countless days on end, the use of steriods, the use of recreational drugs and other hazards. Changes need to be made in the business wether they are self imposed or externally imposed, in order to stop the seemingly endless stream of deaths that happen yearly in wrestling. This is a call to the United States Congress to step in and do something about it if organizations like NWA-TNA and WWE fail to do so.       
   The following is a list of performers who have died before thier 50th birthdays in recent years. If I have forgotten anyone, please send me a message and  I will put it on here. We must all work hard to keep thier memories alive.
-John Kronus
-Chris Benoit
-Eddie Guarrero
-Earthquake (John Tenta)
-Owen Hart
-Crash Holly
-Roco Roc
-Johnny Grunge
-Sherri Martel
-Miss Elizabeth (Hulet)
-Pit Bull #1
-Ric Rude
-Davey "Boy" Smith
-Curt Hennig
-Road Warrior Hawk
-Adrian Adonis
-Andre the Giant
-Brian Pillman
-Big Boss Man (Ray Traylor)
-Louie Spiccoli
-Mike Awesome (Alfonso)
-Yokozuna
-Scott (Bam Bam) Bigalow  
-Chris Candido
-Nancy Benoit (Woman)
-Brian Adams      

1. There needs to be stricter drug testing policies for performers. 

2. There needs to be a cap on the maximum amount of matches a wrestler can work in a given period of time (example: 2 matches/week, 75 matches/year ect.) 

3. The senseless deaths of so many of these young men and women must stop.</description>
  <mission>make the professional wrestling industry impose changes that improve the quality of life of professional wrestlers both during and after thier careers. </mission>
  <name>Fans for a Congressional Investigation into the Wrestling Business</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5531</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">14</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/lt/Qo/rT/rt/YZ/ZI/ixnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
