<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Fibromyalgia is a common rheumatic disease with an estimated prevalence of 2.1% to 5.7% of the population. Women are much more likely to develop fibromyalgia than men by a ratio of 4:1. The incidence of fibromyalgia increases with age; it is most common in women 50 or older. This syndrome has been known by other names, including soft tissue rheumatism, fibrositis and non-articular rheumatism.

Characterized by debilitating fatigue and widespread pain in the muscles, ligaments and tendons, fibromyalgia can be a devastating condition. Doctors have only recently begun to diagnose and understand the syndrome. It is often mistaken for other conditions, so many people affected are subjected to a battery of unrevealing tests.

Rheumatologists first determined two criteria in particular for a diagnosis of fibromyalgia: widespread pain in combination with tenderness at 11 or more of the 18 specific tender points sites. However, the criteria for the classification of fibromyalgia were internationally agreed upon in 1990. Symptoms include: generalized pain in muscles and joints in at least three different parts of the body; sleep disturbance; intense fatigue; memory problems; dry mouth; difficulties swallowing; anxiety; depression; chronic headaches; irritable bowel syndrome; discoloured spots on the skin; morning stiffness; numbness; tingling; increased sensitivity to weather, temperature changes, light, stress and physical activity; skin-fold tenderness or numbness in the hands or feet without evidence of &#339;dema; restless leg syndrome; and diminished blood flow to the fingers and toes&#8230;

The cause is still unknown, and there is no known cure.

For more information, we strongly recommend:

FM-CFS Canada
99 Fifth Avenue, Suite #412
Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, K1S 5P5
1.877.437.HOPE
hope@fm-cfs.ca
www.fm-cfs.ca
Charitable #892417742RR0001

1. Fibromyalgia is not imaginary. It is most definitely real!

2. People with fibromyalgia and their loved-ones need help and support.

3. A cause and a cure must be found soon.</description>
  <mission>This Facebook 'cause' is dedicated to advancing Fibromyalgia education, research and treatment  to help the millions of Canadians affected by this horrible affliction (http://fm-cfs.ca/).</mission>
  <name>FIBROMYALGIA (FM-CFS Canada)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5535</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2893</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">182.06</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Vm/x1/qK/zf/in/Fm/82/7DS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
