<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We, as Jews in diaspora, reject the Israeli government assertion that it is "necessary" to subjugate Palestinians for the sake of keeping Israelis safe. We assert that security can only come from mutual respect, and that the occupation of Palestine is only worsening the position of Jews in the Middle East and around the world.
 
Jews against the occupation stand firmly against anti-Semitism and racism in all its forms. We see our historical struggle against anti- Semitism, a cornerstone of European white supremacist ideology, as inherently linked to all struggles against oppression. We therefore stand in solidarity with the Palestinian people in their struggle for land, freedom, and prosperity. We therefore stand in solidarity with the Israeli people that condemn of their government's violation of international human rights laws and treaties, realizing that such actions are both unjust, and used to justify threats to their own security.
 
Judaism is a religion. Jews constitute a cultural and ethnic group. Neither should be confused with Zionism, a political movement. 

Criticism of the state of Israel, its policies, or the idea of a Jewish state does not by itself constitute anti-Semitism. Dismissing critics of Israel or of Zionism as "anti-Semitic" is a means of stifling debate and masking the impact of the occupation. 

The original 19th century Zionist movement, before World War II, did not emphasize a Jewish nation-state, but rather fleeing government sanctioned pogroms, rape, and genocide in Eastern Europe. Before 1948, most Zionists envisioned a peaceful migration to Palestine, in a pluralistic political context that did not displace the indigenous peoples who also consider the land holy. At this time, Albert Einstein and Noam Chomsky both disapproved of the creation of a hegemonic Jewish state.

A resolution to the conflict would bring security, peace, and prosperity to both the Palestinian and Israeli peoples.

UPA, a Palestinian led and operated organization, was chosen to receive any cash donations. Disclaimer:

"UPA is a humanitarian non-political organization with a mission to alleviate the suffering of Palestinians. United Palestinian Appeal does not endorse this cause and is in no way responsible for its content."

http://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=669150401

1. No occupation in the name of Jews.

2. Restore all human and civil rights accorded under international law.

3. End U.S. military aid to Israel.

4. Stop economic attacks on the growth of the Palestinian economy and Palestinians abroad.

5. Grant Palestinians refugees a Right of Return.

6. Critiques of Israel are not innately anti-Semitic, but political.

7. The horrors of the Holocaust do not justify the oppression of the Palestinian people.

8. Hold the Israeli govt. and IDF accountable to international law, without preferential treatment.</description>
  <mission>End the Occupation</mission>
  <name>Jews Against The Occupation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5537</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">45</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">39.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/c4/W8/Ni/yJ/Hw/7V/usXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
