<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Thought before action
Strength without force
Clear light in the sky
The future of gods, icons and heroes

www.completehero.com

Our societies may well not survive unless we can find a new model for male behaviour
A new way for men to serve our societies without recourse to violence
A new way for men to be heroic

"I believe it really is no exaggeration to say that our societies may well not survive unless we can provide men with new ideas about serving their communities without the use of force. In effect we need a new definition of heroism for the 21st century where violence is relegated to the position of least valued and least relevant characteristic. The attempt to define a new kind of heroism is what this public art project is about. My thanks go to Nathan Fillion for agreeing to be the exemplar of this new breed of hero where kindness is seen as a greater expression of strength than cruelty."

Martin Firrell

Donations:
SEARCH FOR COMMON GROUND

http://www.sfcg.org/

Our Mission
Our mission is to transform the way the world deals with conflict: away from adversarial approaches, toward cooperative solutions. 

Our Vision
Our vision is of a world in which: 
Individuals, organisations, governments and societies respond to their differences in non-adversarial ways - where those differences stimulate social progress, rather than precipitate violence. 

Check the website for more info.








1. Our societies may well not survive unless we can find a new model for male behaviour

2. A new way for men to serve our societies without recourse to violence

3. A new way for men to be heroic</description>
  <mission>In effect we need a new definition of heroism for the 21st century where violence is relegated to the position of least valued and least relevant characteristic

</mission>
  <name>Martin Firrell's 'Hero' project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5545</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">73</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fc/im/5D/02/5C/yA/Qd5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
