<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>To read the description of this Cause, please review the following link.

http://tiger.towson.edu/~apeak1/writtenwork/thoughtpieces/capitalismtherevolutionaryliberalalternativetomarxism.html

(The image used in this Cause was designed by a libertarian living in Washington state.  In appreciation to him for allowing us to use his artwork, we are including this link to his CafePress page: http://www.cafepress.com/cp/browse/store/libertyrocks/380722 )

1. Free-market capitalism must be brought back, as both a popular philosophical model for prosperity, peace, and justice, and as a real and functioning system of voluntary interacting between consenting individuals.

2. Free market capitalism is a truly revolutionary approach to society, as it is an approach without central planners, but which rests upon the will of the people.

3. The natural right to the ownership of justly-acquired property is predicated on the axiom of self-ownership. Self-ownership was a rallying-cry of the American abolitionist movement, and the central argument to why slavery had to SEE LINK FOR FULL POSITION

4. Free-market capitalism is vastly misunderstood by the &#8220;left,&#8221; and has never truly been supported by the right. Hence the &#8220;left&#8217;s&#8221; penchant to oxymoronically conflate the free market with statism and the right&#8217;s procl SEE LINK FOR FULL POSITION

5. Capitalism, as the test of time hath proved, is the only system that remains truly radical and revolutionary. This revolution must be kept alive.

6. The free market, from a practical standpoint, is the best possible system for the progress of mankind. It is, quite literally, in the proletariat&#8217;s distinct favour.

7. Centralisation of coercive authority can never be conducive to Liberty, nor to the advancement of mankind. All authority should be devolved back to the individuals that constitute society, and without whom society could not exist.

8. The most oppressed group under our current system, which collectivises authority for the will and benefit of the ruling class, is the individual, as the individual is the smallest group, and thus left most vulnerable by the ru SEE LINK FOR FULL POSITION

9. Free market capitalism, unlike state capitalism and Marxist socialism, is the only movement advocating Power to the People.

10. Capitalism is inevitable.</description>
  <mission>To bring back free-market capitalism, and to keep the revolution alive.</mission>
  <name>Capitalism: The Revolutionary Liberal Alternative to Marxism</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5562</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">106</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/az/20/Vn/VJ/3F/Hs/mCWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
