<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"The World Society for the Protection of Animals (WSPA) is the world&#8217;s largest network for animal welfare. It brings together over 1,000 Member Societies in more than 155 countries and a whole community of individuals around the world who care about animal welfare.

WSPA&#8217;s animal welfare programmes include a mix of direct fieldwork, campaigning, education and training, and member society development. With so many global issues and limited resources, WSPA has created a framework for the prioritisation of its work.

WSPA&#8216;s work is focused on four priority animal welfare areas:

1. Companion animal - responsible pet ownership, humane stray management, and preventing cruelty.

2. Commercial exploitation of wildlife - intensive farming, and cruel management and killing of wild animals for food or products.

3. Disaster relief for animals - providing relief to animals in distress from man-made or natural disasters.

4. Farm animals - intensive farming, long distance transportation, and inhumane slaughter of domestic animals for food."

-http://www.wspa-international.org/

1. Animals have the right to live their lives free from avoidable suffering at the hands of humans, rather than be used simply as &#8216;raw materials&#8216; for the

2. It is the duty of humans to provide for the welfare of other species.

3. All animals kept by, or under the control of, humans must be kept in circumstances appropriate to their species. And, where the physiological and beha

4. Where the welfare of an animal under human control is in question, the animal must be given the benefit of any doubt.

5. The different purposes for which animals are used must be regularly re-evaluated.</description>
  <mission>To unite an informed, global animal welfare movement that helps and protects animals and creates a climate for change, leading to enforced legislation that transforms animals&#8217; lives.</mission>
  <name>WSPA - World Society for the Protection of Animals</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/557</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">71392</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">11099.89</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/QHK/KQFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
