<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>HELP US!!!

This is a fight!!! Not just any kind of fight... No this is a fight that killed more than 3.1 milion people in 2005... Thats 10 people per min... Dont you think thats alot of people?

The fight Im talking about is AIDS...

I know you all have heard that AIDS is killing people everyday... and to you that might not mean alot to you because it doesnt effect you... It effects someone!!! 

14,000 people... thats alot... 14,000 people become infected each day... Now do u want to change your mind? One of your friends could become infected with AIDS and not know it... what happens if they die?

More than half of the newly infected people are between the ages of 15 and 24... How many people/ friends do you know thats between those ages? Alot right?

Think about this...
AIDS kills one(1) child every minute... think about every minute in a day... Thats to many.... And how bout this... 14 million childeren are orphans because of AIDS... 

Almost half of the people living with AIDS are... women...
And in the past year the number of women and girls infected with HIV/AIDS has increased in every region of the world...

HIV is the virus that causes AIDS. AIDS is passed from one person to another through blood- to - blood or sexual- contact.

HIV damages the imune system, the part of the body that helps fight infections. Eventually the imune system becomes so weak that diseases and infections start to attack the body. As this gets worse the person is diagnosed with AIDS. 

If this has touched you then HELP US!!!

HELP US FIGHT AGENST HIV AND AIDS!!!

GO TO WWW.YOUTHAIDS-ALDO.ORG TO HELP WITH THE FIGHT AGENST HIV AND AIDS!!!


1. Aids is infecting 14,000 people every day, it need to be stoped.

2. Most of the people infected are women, someone needs to find a way to treat it and help styop it.

3. Almost half of the population comes from Africa, they dont have anything to treat or prevent it</description>
  <mission>help people find out and help prevent aids</mission>
  <name>FIGHT AIDS!!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5611</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wd/Np/KJ/yr/Ii/aN/3lNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
