<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>HOPE International (HOPE) is a global, faith-based, non-profit organization focused on poverty alleviation through microenterprise development. HOPE&#8217;s vision is to enable sustainable economic development that results in significant and lasting change, temporal and eternal, in the lives of many people living in poverty.

The products and services offered by HOPE are intended to help private entrepreneurs to grow their small businesses:

    &#8226; Microloans intended for business development  and growth
    &#8226; Consulting services in business planning
    &#8226; Training to enhance our clients&#8217; business capabilities

HOPE&#8217;s Microfinance Program is designed for those entrepreneurs who have no access to bank loans. The program enables people who run microbusinesses to access a loan without collateral. This is possible due to the use of a group guarantee principle where groups of three or more borrowers agree to cross guarantee each other's loans. The lending program is designed to ensure that loans will have a positive impact on the client's business and increased income for their family.

HOPE partners with the local church to run children&#8217;s ministries in the same regions as its microfinance. The ministries are staffed by local volunteers and used to strengthen areas where there is little evangelistic activity. 

At weekly clubs called &#8220;Tomorrow Clubs&#8221; and summer camps, children are introduced to the Gospel through games, music, skits, Bible stories, and Bible memorization. Tomorrow Clubs were pioneered in Ukraine, which currently has over 300 clubs operating throughout the country. These clubs minister to approximately 10,000 children each week

www.hopeinternational.org

1. Microfinance

2. HOPE Trips

3. Savings Led Initiatives </description>
  <mission>HOPE International's mission is to invest in the dreams of the poor in the world's underserved communities so that they might be released from physical and spiritual poverty.</mission>
  <name>HOPE International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5614</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6158</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5894.93</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/UW/t8/pf/xk/Wk/vL/cN/f2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
