<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Sitting in New York Harbor, across from the Statue of Liberty, is a dilapidated 1811 fort with an open courtyard that shares the identical blueprint as Shakespeare&#8217;s Globe. The New Globe (www.newglobe.org) plan re-imagines the fortification as a self-sustaining performing arts venue and a vibrant educational and cultural destination. The design by world-renowned architect Lord Norman Foster (e.g., British Museum, German Parliament) preserves this decaying monument, provides for exhibition and museum space, and incorporates a stage for world-class productions of Shakespeare as well as works by modern playwrights, classical and contemporary concerts, jazz performances, lectures, and a wide range of other events. Working in partnership with the immensely successful Shakespeare&#8217;s Globe in London, the New Globe&#8217;s Artistic Board includes actors Philip Seymour Hoffman, Kevin Kline, Al Pacino, Estelle Parsons, and Mark Rylance, as well as directors Kenny Leon and Sam Mendes.

1. CREATING A POWERFUL ICON IN NEW YORK HARBOR. The New Globe will be a dramatic tourist destination &#8230; even at this concept stage, the proposal has generated enormous international interest, with press coverage from London to Milan, Qatar to Tokyo.

2. PROVIDING AFFORDABLE TICKETS TO DEVELOP NEW AUDIENCES. Each performance will offer 400 tickets priced at $10, subsidized by 800 competitively priced gallery seats, thus offering 125,000 affordable tickets every year to world-class cultural attractions.

3. CELEBRATING CULTURAL DIVERSITY. The &#8220;New Globe for the New World&#8221; will build an acting company reflecting the melting pot of New York City and will provide programming that celebrates the cultural heritage of the world.

4. SUPPORTING ARTS EDUCATION. An extensive Education Program (modeled on London&#8217;s Globe, which serves 100,000 each year) will introduce people of all social, cultural and economic backgrounds to the performing arts.

5. PRESERVING A NATIONAL MONUMENT. Castle Williams is a dilapidated structure that stands empty in a state of decay. The adaptive reuse, prepared with New York&#8217;s leading preservation and landmarks experts, is reversible and environmentally sustainable.

6. CREATING AN ICON OF FRIENDSHIP. Since the 1811 fort was built to defend America against the British, it seems appropriate to work in partnership with our former foe to recast this symbol of war into an icon of friendship.</description>
  <mission>Rehabilitate Castle Williams in New York Harbor as a world-class performing arts center to educate and entertain the public with affordable, accessible, and stimulating programming.</mission>
  <name>New Globe Theater</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5636</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">138</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/iH/B7/nP/kK/Qv/Eo/ZPjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
