<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dr. Ron Paul is a committed defender of free-markets, property rights, a non-interventionist foreign policy, civil liberties and a limited government. Ron Paul is the only Republican primary candidate to have voted against the Iraq war resolution and the PATRIOT Act. Ron Paul will restore our federal government to its rightful, constitutionally-limited role. America needs a President who will lead this country back to its founding principles, which have stood as a bulwark against government tyranny for generations. That man is Ron Paul.

-------

Join your campus Students for Ron Paul chapter!
http://facebook.com/event.php?eid=4198119330

Don't see your school listed? Why not start your own chapter?! Fill out the form at this website:
http://tinyurl.com/25q9aa
Indicate that you are interested in creating a Students for Ron Paul chapter at your school.

-------

Some cool Facebook apps to help you show your support for Ron Paul:

Ron Paul TV
http://apps.facebook.com/ronpaultv/

(beta) Ron Paul Facebook App
http://www.facebook.com/apps/application.php?id=3372958801

Election '08
http://apps.facebook.com/elections/
(vote Ron Paul)

US Politics by Facebook
http://apps.facebook.com/apps/application.php?id=2359935501
(search or browse for Ron Paul and 'Support This Politician')

Ron Paul 2008 - Raising to Win
http://apps.facebook.com/rpraisingtowin/

Ron Paul Quotes
http://facebook.com/apps/application.php?id=4607811273

To learn more about Ron Paul and his policy positions, visit his campaign website at http://www.ronpaul2008.com. Also, don't forget to check out the national Students for Ron Paul at http://studentsforpaul.org/.

1. Ron has never voted to raise taxes.

2. Ron has never voted for an unbalanced budget.

3. Ron has never voted for a federal restriction on gun ownership.

4. Ron voted against the Patriot Act.

5. Ron votes against regulating the Internet.

6. Ron voted against the Iraq war.

7. Ron voted against NAFTA and CAFTA.

8. Ron votes against the United Nations.

9. Ron votes against the welfare state.

10. Ron votes against reinstating a military draft.

11. Ron votes for conservative principles.

12. Ron votes to cut government spending.

13. Ron votes to lower health care costs.

14. Ron votes to end the war on drugs.

15. Ron votes to preserve civil liberties.

16. Ron votes to secure our borders with real immigration reform.

17. Ron votes to eliminate tax funded abortions

18. Ron votes to protect religious freedom.</description>
  <mission>This Cause has one primary mission: to help nominate Ron Paul as the Republican presidential candidate in 2012 by raising donations from grassroots supporters.</mission>
  <name>Ron Paul 2012 - Hope for America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5656</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">19599</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2666.02</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/FU/Q3/5x/hl/jW/mn/7vSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
