<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Save The Bay was founded on the community&#8217;s desire to protect our most precious resource - Narragansett Bay. To do that, Save The Bay has focused on the development of a committed constituency for the Bay. Children and adults throughout this region have learned the tremendous value the Bay brings to our economy, our environment and our quality of life.
In defense of Narragansett Bay and its watershed, Save The Bay has watched over the activities and programs of the government and the citizenry that degrade the environmental quality of the Bay, basin, and watershed. Save The Bay provides educational opportunities for children and adults to explore the Bay, fostering a understanding and a sense of personal responsibility for the resource.

Save The Bay&#8217;s history is one of accomplishment for the Bay. Once choked by raw sewage and dying a slow death from industrial toxins, the Bay is now making a comeback. There is still room for vast improvement, but more people than ever before are able to swim, fish, sail and enjoy the waters of Narragansett Bay. What follows is a timeline reflecting Save The Bay&#8217;s history and charting important milestones we have achieved toward protecting Narragansett Bay.

1. Watching over the activities and programs of government and the citizenry that degrade the environmental quality of the Bay, basin, and watershed.

2. Leading the community by initiating programs and activities that increase the environmental awareness and knowledge of the public.

3. Initiating action that will directly clean up the Bay.</description>
  <mission>To ensure that the environmental quality of Narragansett Bay and its watershed is restored and protected from the harmful effects of human activity.</mission>
  <name>Save the Bay</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/566</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1131</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">85.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5xM/tj5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
