<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hope for a world where good people are not brainwashed into doing bad things.  

Because this, http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y_EKHK1C2IE should scare you.

I, for one, am tired of seeing people die because of what an old book says, tired of having our country turned into a Christan taliban, tired of beneficial research banned because of religious ideologies, tired of this that and the other minority being condemned to hell for committing vague, and unjustly labeled sins.

THIS IN NO WAY MEANS KILL RELIGIOUS PEOPLE OR PROHIBIT RELIGION, I want to stop the brainwashing. 
Violence should be abhorred by all rational people. Fundamentalists and extremists have seized religion, and it has long since been a major cause of global hostility, is best overcome by reason.
That being said violent suggestions will not be tolerated in this group. As a secular facebook 'cause', all human rights are acknowledged, including freedom of religion. It is just a point of fact that other rights (safety, freedom, education, etc.) trump religious freedom.

1. Fundamentalists should not have any say in our government. Maintain the wall of seperation of church and state.

2. Eliminate teaching religious doctrine as a fact from all schools. Creationism is not a science and damages the academic environment.

3. Children have a right to an environment free from religious hostility, in which to grow and learn.

4. Promote the questioning of dogmatically held positions, question everything.

5. Promote non-violence and an overall sense of well being without the artificial aid of religion. Celebrate the endurance of the human spirit. </description>
  <mission>To remove an excuse for bigotry, hate and segregation.</mission>
  <name>Anti-Religion</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5661</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24582</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">669.09</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/J6/7L/Mr/hV/Re/lr/D0vS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
