<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>CIGAR.

Either that word conjures distaste, disgust, and repulsion, or, if you&#8217;re a real man, it brings to mind a heavenly sense of relaxation and masculinity. In life, there&#8217;s nothing quite so fine as smoking a good cigar on a warm summers eve. Nor nothing quite as manly.

All real men smoke them. Winston Churchill. Ulysses S. Grant. Arnold Schwarzenegger. Jessica Simpson. Wait&#8230;forget that last one. 

A cigar also makes you appear rich. According to Wikipedia:
| - Cigars are often presented as stereotypical rich man&#8217;s accessory.
| - Cigars are often smoked to celebrate good fortune, like the birth of a |child, a graduation, a big business accomplishment, etc. . Some buy and |keep a cigar &#8216;for luck&#8217; with regard to a bet, with the intention of smoking it |after winning the bet.

CIGAR- a "tightly rolled bundle of dried and fermented tobacco, one end of which is ignited so that its smoke may be drawn into the smoker&#8217;s mouth through the other end."

Cigars are not to be compared to cigarettes - a punk kid&#8217;s pitiful attempt at rebelling against The Man. It&#8217;s pitiful because The Man actually smokes cigars. That&#8217;s what makes him The Man. Cigarettes are closer in size to punks, which why kids who smoke them are called "Punk Kids."

1. Cigars are often presented as stereotypical rich man&#8217;s accessory.

2. Cigars are often smoked to celebrate good fortune, like the birth of a |child, a graduation, a big business accomplishment, etc. .

3. Some people say smoking a cigar makes you a man.

4. In life, there&#8217;s nothing quite so fine as smoking a good cigar</description>
  <mission>Teaching Men how to become Real Men, Through Smoking Cigars</mission>
  <name>Be A Man ~ Smoke Cigars</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5668</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">230</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/EV/HW/TP/Kc/8V/Z3/HQ7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
