<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This Cause Is Looking For Big Brothers To Step Up And Take The Responsibility. Take One Day Out Of Your Week To Change A Child's Life. Find A New Friend And Feel Good About What You Are Doing. Help Me Make A Difference In Houston And Donate  To Big Brothers Houston Or Volunteer Your Time To Them. Thank You   

Agency Background

Big Brothers Big Sisters of Greater Houston is a private, nonprofit organization
and an affiliate of Big Brothers Big Sisters of America. Founded in 1952,
Big Brothers Big Sisters of Greater Houston serves more than 2,000 children
annually. Big Brothers Big Sisters of Greater Houston is a United Way agency
sponsored by the United Way of Texas Gulf Coast.

Agency Funding

The organization is funded primarily through private gifts and grants.
Special events including, Bowl for Kids Sake, Golf Tournaments and
an annual Gala are the agency's secondary source of support in
addition to the generous support of the United Way.


Impact

Public/Private Ventures conducted a comprehensive
study of boys and girls involved in a one-to-one mentoring
relationship through the Big Brothers Big Sisters program
in several cites across the United States, including
Houston.

The study found that children in our program are:

    * 46% less likely than their peers to start using
      illegal drugs
    * 27% less likely to start drinking
    * 52% less likely than their peers to skip school
    * 30% less likely to hit someone
    * 5 times less likely than other girls between the
      ages of 15 and 19 to become pregnant

Children/Littles

Big Brothers Big Sisters matches children between
the ages of 6-15 with volunteer adult mentors.
Both the children and their parents receive
training on communication skills and
empowerment in addition to invitations to
on-going training sessions and annual
BBBS events.

1. Build Better Schools!

2. Build Brighter Futures!

3. Build Stronger Communities! </description>
  <mission>Change a child's life by giving them a role model to follow and learn with.</mission>
  <name>Big Brothers Houston</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5669</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">21</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">250.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ky/BF/j6/vv/Wp/Jq/EGZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
