<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The National Students of AMF support network was founded in 2006 at Georgetown University. Since then, the organization has incorporated as a national, non-profit organization and campus chapters have been started across the country. Our mission is to support college students grieving the illness or loss of a loved one.

National Students of AMF is unique in that it is the only national organization that offers peer-led support dedicated exclusively to the needs of college students grieving the illness or death of a loved one. National Students of AMF is organized around the following model:

We provide grief support through:
&#61607;University-recognized peer-led groups on college campuses that allow students to connect with others who understand what they are experiencing
&#61607;annual education and awareness activities
&#61607;information and referral resources
&#61607;avenues for communication and story sharing

We offer opportunities for service open to the entire campus community to raise money and awareness for causes that have touched the lives of chapter members.

Go to www.studentsofamf.org or call 919.803.6728 to learn more!

1. 35-48% of college students have grieved the illness or death of a loved one in the last 2 years, which can significantly impact these students

2. All college students should be supported during times of grief

3. We value the power of friendships between students in taking care of one&#8217;s own, and watching out for one&#8217;s friends well-being during times of loss

4. We value the energy that college students have to fight for causes and their ability to bring about change</description>
  <mission>Supporting college students grieving the illness or death of a loved one.</mission>
  <name>National Students of AMF</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5677</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2062</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3532.23</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Mm/Pd/pR/Xh/VQ/sR/OD/JiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
