<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Cutting off a husky puppy's head with a chainsaw... sounds like a horror flick, right? Not this time... someone in South Africa did it recently to his own dog. 

THE WHAT... 
On 22 February 2007, Phillip Matthysen, a South African man reportedly killed his Husky puppy after it instinctively bit out at his parrot and killed it (News24.com, 19 June 2007). It was reported that along with an accomplice, he allegedly proceeded to hold the dog down and cut its head off with a chainsaw. Often, people committing similar hideous acts stand to walk free with little or no consequences - this site exists to help gather support to stop this from happening! 

THE HOW... 
I have spoken to Mr. G Schultz, the prosecutor on this case, and arranged to meet him on July 23rd. I plan to give him a minimum of 25 000 of our signatures. There is no guarantee that this action will have the desired effect however our hope is that at worst, the magistrate will know there are more people watching this case than just those sitting in the court room.

Please sign your name below and ask all your friends to do the same. If we sign this cause, we've all done a great thing and that poor husky did not die in vain! 
-JONO- ( jono@mybeat.net ) " 

Lara Pietersen. (If you would like to contribute to this site, please contact me). 

The intention of this petition 

We would like to commend the authorities on their swift action on this case. 
We support the magistrate's final decision , verdict and sentencing. 
We do not condone violence, or mob/vigilante justice. 
We support the right of South Africans to voice their opinions. 
 You can also sign the petition on the group Husky Justice at FaceBook.com instead, and join in the conversations.Our new goal is 50,000 signatures! Thanks to everyone who is making this happen!!

PLEASE GO TO THE LINK BELOW AND SIGN YOUR NAME 

http://www.ecosystem.co.za/HuskyJustice.asp
 

1. Please sign your name below and ask all your friends to do the same. If we sign this cause, we've all done a great thing and that poor husky did not die in vain! 

2. The intention of this petition is to raise awareness about animal rights issues in South Africa, and this case in particular. 

3. We stand behind the NSPCA's call for the establishment of specialized courts specific or dedicated to animal cases. </description>
  <mission>Jono Judelman is collecting signatures to petition our legal system to revise legislation in light of continuing violent crimes against animals .</mission>
  <name>Husky Justice</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5678</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3479</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/rh/UB/JU/ug/WD/7k/dm1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
