<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Please bear with me as with alot of things on Facebook, this is a work in progress. Native people in general need to look towards the future and realize that our beliefs, culture and potential future may perhaps be in danger of slowly disappearing through inadaquate action and lack of awareness. We need to change the image of what it is to be not only native, but Canadian as well. We all have alot to be proud of, no matter our pasts and personal regrets. If you are from any of the provinces or territories please join the group. I want to get a site going with discussion boards and a way to connect with other sites and groups promoting our beliefs. I am constantly looking for feedback, so send all email to ctestawich@hotmail.com or the_pepsi_guy@hotmail.com and lets start connecting and making real change. How might you ask? Lets get together and discuss... 

1. Protect the rights of Native Canadians

2. Create the atmosphere necessary for positive change from our cities to our reserves and beyond

3. Help others in need through support, discussion and interaction of all nations in our country.

4. Create a network of Native Canadians in all aspects of Canadian society (ex: Media, Film &amp; Television, Arts)

5. Eventually create a organization dedicated to our causes.

6. News organizations with opinion articles for writers and reporters

7. A online gallery for upcoming Native Art and Artists

8. Open casting calls and other related connections between Native actors, performers, artists, directors and anyone else related in any way in such industries. Promote ideas!</description>
  <mission>Unite as Native Canadians to further education, awareness, arts, beliefs, culture and goals through personal empowerment, discussion and awareness of events that matter to Native Canadians.</mission>
  <name>Native Canadian Youth Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5689</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">437</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vR/j5/PZ/ET/tp/dE/JtuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
