<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I am training to participate in the Nike Women's Marathon in San Francisco on October 21 as a member of The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society's Team In Training. All of us on Team In Training are raising funds to help stop leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin lymphoma and myeloma from taking more lives. 

I'm completing this event in honor of all individuals who are battling blood cancers and in memory of Margarita Matos Shirley. Margie was a very close friend of my family since I was a little girl. She was diagnosed with Leukemia in October of 2006. Tragically, Margie lost her battle with the disease within the month, leaving a void in the lives of everyone around her. 

Everyone who knew Marie would describe her as one of the most generous and caring people they knew. On one occaision she offered a room in her house to a woman she met at the train station. She had come into town to visit a friend and had trouble finding a hotel for the night. Margie took her generosity to the next level about a year before she died when she donated one of her kidneys to a woman at work. Margie and those currently battling blood cancers are the real heroes on our team, and we need your support to cross the ultimate finish line - a cure! 

Please donate here: www.active.com/donate/tntga/crodg121


1. The Society invested $61.6 million to support more than 480 researchers and projects in 15 countries on five continents. 

2. The Society also provides financial assistance to patients and runs dozens of Family Support Groups nationwide. 

3. The Society sponsors scientific conferences around the country; produces educational materials and videos. </description>
  <mission>Cure leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin's disease and myeloma, and improve the quality of life of patients and their families.</mission>
  <name>Team in Training - 26.2 Miles for Margie</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5692</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/30/DC/RZ/7Y/a3/Xc/LHfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
