<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Patagonian Foundation (TPF) has joined the fight against the damming of the Baker and Pascua rivers. In conjunction with a number of individuals and other environmental groups, TPF is helping to fund the dissemination of information regarding the environmental impacts of the proposed plants. TPF hopes to raise awareness on the impacts the dams will have on the local community and raise money to support the legal battle against Endesa (a Spanish electric company). 

Many rivers in Patagonia have been dammed to develop hydroelectricity. Some of these dams are important energy sources for the local community and were developed with the natural environment in mind. On the other hand, others were constructed without any regard for the environment. Currently, the residents of Chile&#8217;s Aisen region are in a desperate battle to save the Baker and Pascua Rivers, two of the most beautiful in the world. Endesa is threatening to construct two dams on the Baker and two on the Pascua. These dams significantly threaten the local environment and raise serious social concerns. 

1. These rivers are surrounded by thousands of acres of nature reserves and fragile ecosystems and species that would be completely flooded and/or permanently altered by the dams.

2. Endesa plans to send the energy generated by the dams 2,000 km north to Santiago. These high voltage lines will permanently alter the landscape and significantly diminish property values for local people who will receive little to no compensation.

3. Endesa hopes to pass these lines through at least one privately owned nature reserve and perhaps other important ecosystems. 

4. The temporary workforce that will infiltrate the largely rural area raises serious social concerns regarding housing, prostitution and crime.</description>
  <mission>To work with local Chilean environmental organizations to fight the damming of the Baker and Pascua Rivers in the Aisen region of Patagonia.</mission>
  <name>Save the Baker and Pascua Rivers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5696</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1226</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">36.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6e/0x/7Y/C5/Jp/qL/jWuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
