<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Safe Place program provides access to immediate help and safety for all young people in crisis.  A public/private network of thousands of sites across the country &#8220;extend&#8221; the doors of their local youth shelter by displaying Safe Place&#8217;s recognizable yellow and black diamond-shaped logo. Partnering businesses that cater to youth and community buildings &#8211; such as fast food restaurants, convenience stores, fire stations, public buses and libraries &#8211; connect kids looking for help with the youth service agency.

1. YOUNG PEOPLE ARE VALUED AND are capable of initiating the helping process and taking an active role in creating a healthier living situation.

2. YOUNG PEOPLE ARE VALUED AND are more likely to seek help in places that are familiar, safe and identified by a standard, recognizable logo.

3. YOUNG PEOPLE ARE VALUED AND have access to services on a nondiscriminatory basis.

4. SERVICES TO YOUNG PEOPLE focus on immediate interventions to address issues at the earliest possible stage of a crisis.

5. SERVICES TO YOUNG PEOPLE include advocacy and access to safe, supportive resources.

6. SERVICES TO YOUNG PEOPLE are evaluated on an ongoing basis. 

7. THE COMMUNITY takes an active, cooperative role in assisting young people in crisis.

8. THE COMMUNITY benefits when a young person can access safe, supportive assistance rather than dangerous alternatives.

9. THE COMMUNITY must be educated concerning issues relating to young people in order to improve the quality of services.</description>
  <mission>Safe Place provides immediate help and supportive resources for all young people in crisis through a network of sites sustained by qualified agencies, trained volunteers and businesses.</mission>
  <name>National Safe Place</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5706</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1250</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">624.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SZ/I8/JG/8j/bu/lv/iywS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
