<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Mission statement*:  

The United States Equine Rescue League (USERL) is a non-profit organization dedicated to the compassionate care of equines.  Our mission is to save, protect, and rehabilitate equines in need.  We rescue abused, neglected, or abandoned equines; provide them with care and rehabilitation; and finally find them a compatible, loving home.  We believe that education is the long-term solution to improving the lives of equines.
 
  
about userl*:
  
-The United States Equine Rescue League, Inc. (USERL) is a 501(c)3 non-profit organization, incorporated in NC in the year 1997. Tax ID# 56-2069469.
 
-Funded by private donations and fundraising
 
-Staffed mostly by volunteers
 
-Foster network involving almost 100 homes
 
-Averaging over 100 equine rescued per year
 
-Active Regions across North Carolina, Virginia, and Indiana  

*property of the USERL. I take no credit in the writing of any of the above texts.

All Positions are also property of USERL.

1. To educate horse-owners and the public about proper equine care, and the problems of neglect, abuse, and slaughter.

2. To rescue equines from neglectful and abusive situations by educating owners, helping to place at-risk equines and ultimately working within the bounds of the law to remove equines from their owner's care when deemed necessary.

3. To rehabilitate sick, injured and underweight equines and restore them to a state of health 

4. To end the suffering of those equines which cannot be rehabilitated by means of humane euthanasia.

5. To find all equines that come under the care of USERL a compatible, loving home.</description>
  <mission>save, protect, and rehabilitate equines in need.</mission>
  <name>United States Equine Rescue League. (USERL)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5721</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1248</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">205.4</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/b6/ug/37/bf/Qo/VE/0DCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
