<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>On Sunday, June 24, 2007, an illegal campfire rapidly burned out of control near the city of South Lake Tahoe, California.  The fire destroyed over 250 homes, many of them year-round residences.  While some homes were spared, many neighborhood blocks were leveled, with only chimneys and other stonework remaining.  Forced evacuations led many of the residents to South Lake Tahoe's Community Center and Red Cross Shelter, while others stayed in local hotels that opened their doors and provided free accomodations.  

June 28, 2007: The fire is considered to be under control due to the help of over 2,000 firefighters and no more homes appear to be in immediate danger, but fluctuating wind speeds in the Tahoe Basin have made fighting the Angora fire a slow and difficult process.

July 2, 2007: The Angora Wildfire is 100 percent contained at a cost of $11 million.  Damages have been estimated at over $100 million.

Since South Lake Tahoe and the rest of the Tahoe Basin provide welcome recreation spots for so many people from outside the area, it would be great if we could help those that help make that retreat what it is.  If you enjoy vacationing in the Tahoe area, show some love!  Please consider donating to the American Red Cross and/or spreading the word in order to help the residents who have been affected.  

1. Donations are needed to help those residents who have lost everything in the Angora Fire.

2. Donations go directly through the Sacramento-Sierra Chapter of the American Red Cross to provide disaster relief for those affected.</description>
  <mission>Donate to provide assistance for the victims of South Lake Tahoe's Angora Wildfire through the Sacramento-Sierra Chapter of the American Red Cross. </mission>
  <name>Assist the South Lake Tahoe Residents Affected by the Angora Wildfire</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5732</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">529</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jP/FA/mv/uR/H7/bM/87RS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
