<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>|FIRST STATEMENT 
"This is not a fight of whether or not abortion is wrong; the fight here is that FATHERS should have rights in the decisions surrounding abortion!"

|A MAN'S CHOICE

If he does not agree w/the abortion, his choices should be:
1.Try to convince his spouse otherwise, get signed/authorized note confirming.
2.Consent to the abortion.
3.Do not offer consent and take on FULL responsibility.

If he is indeed the one who wants the abortion but she does not, his choices should be:
1. Try to convince his spouse otherwise, get signed/authorized note confirming.
2. Keep responsibility of the child, including fulfilling all legal and financial obligations.
3. Relieve responsibility freeing him of ALL responsibilities- legal, financial, or other wise.


|MISSIONS
1. Create awareness nationwide and perhaps worldwide of the fact that there are men who actively would love to have their children and have the capabilities to do so, but women are making the decision to kill those men's children.

2. Petition the government to establish an Act or law forbidding abortion without the consent of the father and only if he provides proof of his capabilities to support the child with his agreement to take on full custody of that child upon birth.

3. FLIP-SIDE. Explained: flip-side is the term used when the man actually wants the abortion and the women does not. What is there to do about that?  As a supporter mentioned, in this case, there is no way to absolutely force a woman to get an abortion, therefore, the man should not have any legal or financial responsibility to that child whatsoever. The mother will be solely responsible for that child without any assistance from the biological father (the same as before where the father will have no assistance from the mother). Again a fight for the father's rights.

4. Provide counseling to those that have unfortunately already fallen victims to abortion


1. Fathers should have the right to consent to abortion.

2. Fathers should be rendered custody of the child if he is proven willing &amp; able, and the mother initially opted for abortion.

3. FLIP-SIDE:If He does not want the child, he should have the choice to relieve all responsibilities just like women now have that choice w/ abortion</description>
  <mission>M.V.A. is a non-profit that creates awareness for men not having rights when it comes to decisions surrounding the controversial topic of abortion. </mission>
  <name>MVA: Men, Victims of Abortion!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5752</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">75</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/aw/HW/Ou/0W/mZ/l4/7n/5dS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
