<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Breast Cancer 3-Day goals are to: 
&#8226; Raise funds to support breast cancer research, education, and community outreach programs 

&#8226; Raise awareness regarding the health threat of breast cancer and its impact on individuals, families and society, helping more people survive this deadly disease 

&#8226; Create a strong, positive community consisting of breast cancer survivors, persons currently undergoing treatment and others impacted by the disease that promotes and nurtures peer support, learning and sensitivity to issues surrounding breast cancer both prior to and on the events 

&#8226; Provide education to a broad constituency regarding breast cancer-related issues including the critical importance of early detection 

&#1048633; The 2006 Breast Cancer 3-Day raised $86 million through donations, contributions, and sponsorships. 

&#1048633; Of that, more than $61 million, representing 71% of funds raised, was invested in breast cancer research, education, and community outreach in 2006. 

&#1048633; The 71% return to charity exceeds the Better Business Bureau Wise Giving Standards for Charity Accountability. www.give.org 

&#1048633; As the primary beneficiary, Susan G. Komen for the Cure receives 85% of net proceeds and the remaining 15% goes to the National Philanthropic Trust Breast Cancer Fund. 

&#1048633; Since its inception in 2003, more than $220 million has been raised through Breast Cancer 3-Day donations, contributions, and sponsorships. 

&#1048633; For more information on the beneficiaries or grants made from Breast Cancer 3-Day funds, please visit the Grants &amp; Awards section at www.komen.org and About NPT/Special Projects at www.nptrust.org 

The Breast Cancer 3-Day is a project of National Philanthropic Trust and adheres to all industry accepted accounting standards including, but not limited to, the Better Business Bureau Wise Giving Alliance Standards for Charitable Accountability, AICPA SOP 98-2 and FAS 117. 

1. Breast cancer affects all of us - whether it is a mom, sister, aunt, friend, or other family member.

2. Everyone deserves a lifetime; don't you agree?</description>
  <mission>Benefit the Susan G. Komen for the Cure</mission>
  <name>The Breast Cancer 3 Day</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5763</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PB/oG/Nk/OL/Lp/HJ/aqIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
