<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Last printed 00/00/0000 00:00 Created on 25/06/2007 19:36
TOMOS CLAYTON                  
LIMITED/UNLIMITED TALENT_LTD_UNLTD_           &#169; 4/4 Bsharp /Beeflat /who cares!  www.myspace.com/talent_ltd
INVEST IN BIRMINGHAM CITY FC
To Whom It May Concern:
I TOMOS EDWARD CLAYTON, 7thMarch 1986 wish to invest in Our/Your/The future, on behalf of The Coalition of Artists, Singer-Songwriters, Journalists, Fathers, Mothers, Teachers, Students,Pensioners, Lawyers, Spin doctors who want Justice, on behalf of all those who are scared to speak up. Let the world know that instead of making idle promises, that if we insure our art, and sell our art, and make walls out of art, and fill our football stadiums to the rafters, that every anthem starts with one note. Make Art not Weapons. Instead of guns, sell roses. Workers of the WORLD unite. We CAN make the difference.
Thank you:
invest in local grass roots football, live,love, if you have shares in a football team, get everyone to invest in BCFC Birmingham City. If you have too much stuff, make sure it is insured, then sell it little by little and give it straight to where it's needed. stand for government. YOU can make the difference
Tomos Edward Clayton
Talent_ltd_edition_unlimited talent &#169; 2007- copy and paste this.print it off, trials soon
if you are Piers Morgan, Sarkozy, Clarkson, Tomos Clayton, Dave Shephard, Stephen Fry, or YOU are the NEXT BIG TALENT, let someone know. each week march to ST ANDREWS BCFC Birmingham UK, or to Barcelona, with loud drums, until the people in government actually start listening! who cares about ranting!! I certainly don't! BeeeCeeesharpFoootballlllovingClassyartistesoftheworldunite.plc.etc. 2007


1. live for every minute of every day, bring football back to the people

2. lower ticket prices at theatres, football stadiums. give everyone the chance to play for their local team

3. believe in each other, if someone wants to follow their dream, let them. thank you :) Tomos Clayton 1986- talent_ltd_edition etc.?????!!!!,,, :D 2007-</description>
  <mission>Last printed 00/00/0000 00:00 Created on 25/06/2007 19:36</mission>
  <name>Last printed 00/00/0000 00:00 Created on 25/06/2007 19:36</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5777</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1K/zU/zx/a4/pk/up/IIIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
