<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>When we buy a pet or even shop at a store that sells puppies, we contribute to a heartless underground industry that forces dogs to spend their entire lives in cages constantly breeding to support consumer demand for puppies. 

Life is particularly bad for "breeding stock," dogs who live their entire lives in cages and are continually bred for years, without human companionship and with little hope of ever becoming part of a family. These dogs receive little or no veterinary care and never see a bed, a treat or a toy. After their fertility wanes, breeding animals are commonly killed, abandoned or sold to another mill. The annual result of all this breeding is hundreds of thousands of puppies, many with behavior and/or health problems. 

Because a puppy mill is a business, the facility is designed purely for profit, not for the well-being of dogs. Laws are on the books to provide minimum-care standards for puppy-mill animals, but enforcement has historically been spotty at best. The U.S. Department of Agriculture licenses and inspects "commercial breeding facilities for violations of the Animal Welfare Act; likewise, a handful of states have laws that provide oversight of some breeding operations as well. But puppy mills can successfully navigate around these laws, either by selling directly to consumers (thereby avoiding USDA licensing requirements) or by simply avoiding the reach of law enforcement (with so few USDA inspectors and minor fines, it's easy to stay in business). 

1. Puppy mills must be banned from Canada and the United States.

2. People should NOT buy puppies from pet shops, and should not buy them from ads or the internet.

3. Dog owners should buy from a GOOD breeder, or from the shelter.</description>
  <mission>Help puppies and dogs get proper medical attention, and ban puppy mills throughout the world.</mission>
  <name>Stop puppy mills</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5799</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3234</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.25</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yq/4F/gI/nw/5D/yf/FF3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
