<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This cause is to help raise awarness about those millions of children all around the globe whos lives have been affected and ruined by war. 

War Child was created 1993 by two British film directors. They had recently arrived hom from a warzone in Yugoslavia.

7 years later in 2000, Chantelle Kreviask, and the Tragically Hip, held a one of the biggest benifit concert for Warchild Canada, in Winnipeg's history. 

Many Children all around the world have been affected by wars, and some are even forced to take part. Young children are obligated to carry weapons and kill.
That should never happen! Kids should have happy childhoors, childhoods ruined by wars and tragedies! 
Many war-affected children end up in great poverty, just like that, their lives can be ruined! More than 1 million children have lost their families. 

In the past ten years over 2,000,000 children have died because of war, and millions more have suffered. More than 10 million have been traumatised. 
You would be amazed to know over 90% of all deaths in armed conflict are of innocent civillians and more than half of them are adolescents! Over 43 million kids, are not able to go to school because they live in war affected areas! 

These children need our support and help! They need people like us, to try and understand how they feel; though many of us will thankfully never know, you can only imagine what it must be like. It would be much like a bad nightmare, but this would be reality! 

And even MuchMusic donates to the War Child foundation, when you sign up for a Much Music pre-paid Mastercard, 10% of net proceeds that MuchMusic receives from the card program is donated to Warchild Canada. 

      "I believe the lessons of peace are best learned through the stories of war.&#8221; Samantha Nutt, founder of War Child Canada
 
You can also contact or donate to War Child in Canada:
War Child Canada,
401 Richmond Street West,
Suite 204, 
Toronto, Ontario,
M5V 3A8,
Tel: 416.971.7474,
Fax: 416.971.7946 
For more information: http://www.warchild.ca/index.asp

1. Raising awarness about children and their connection to war

2. When wars take place it is more than just the soldiers that become affected.</description>
  <mission>Help bring peace and share what we have with less fortune war affected children around the globe. </mission>
  <name>War Child</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5802</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">447</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/el/Tx/oW/fB/nW/Ul/s4/zaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
