<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation was born from the most powerful force of all: a mother's love for her children. Elizabeth Glaser contracted the AIDS virus through a blood transfusion in 1981 while giving birth to her daughter, Ariel. She and her husband, Paul, later learned that Elizabeth had unknowingly passed the virus on to Ariel through breast milk and that their son, Jake, had contracted the virus in utero. 

The Glasers discovered, in the course of trying to treat Ariel, that drug companies and health agencies had no idea that HIV/AIDS was prevalent among children. The only drugs on the market were for adults &#8212; nothing had been tested or approved for children. Which meant that there was no medical treatment for the infection that was quickly destroying Ariel's life.

Ariel lost her battle with AIDS in 1988. Fully aware that Jake's life was also in danger, Elizabeth rose to action. She approached her close friends, Susie Zeegen and Susan DeLaurentis, for help in creating a foundation that would serve to raise money for basic HIV/AIDS research. The Foundation had one critical mission: to bring hope to children with AIDS. Few researchers were focusing on issues specific to pediatric HIV/AIDS, there were no drugs available for children, and the infection rate was rapidly rising. Elizabeth, Susie and Susan sought to change that harsh reality. 

What three mothers began around a kitchen table in 1988 is now the leading national nonprofit organization dedicated to preventing pediatric HIV infection and eradicating pediatric AIDS through research, advocacy, and prevention and treatment programs. 

1. Every child deserves a lifetime.

2. HIV/AIDS is a worldwide pandemic that effects everyone</description>
  <mission>The Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation seeks to prevent pediatric HIV infection and to eradicate pediatric AIDS through research, advocacy, and prevention and treatment programs. </mission>
  <name>Generation Free Campaign: The Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/583</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8871</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">4262.49</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/IO/8I/oA/ky/NU/Re/KU/DKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
