<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Salvia divinorum is a plant native to Oaxaca, Mexico that is used religiously and in shamanic rituals by the Sierra Mazatec indigenous peoples to induce visions.  It is a member of the Labiatae family, and is known to the Mazatecs as ska Mar&#237;a Pastora.  S. divinorum is one of several psychotropic plants consumed by the Mazatecs, including Psilocybe mushrooms and morning glory seeds, and was used in many types of physical and spiritual healing rituals.  Interest in the plant and its primary active ingredient, Salvinorin A, has risen in recent years, and the plant now has a market in the United States.

Salvinorin A may be consumed by utilizing several different techniques.  The traditional Mazatec method of consumption is by chewing freshly harvested S. divinorum leaves or by drinking the juices of crushed fresh leaves.  Fifty to one hundred leaves are rolled by hand and chewed, with the psychedelic effects resulting in approximately fifteen minutes.   The herb is chewed, rather than swallowed, because salvinorin A is quickly metabolized in the gastrointestinal system and is insoluble in water.   More popularly, S. divinorum is smoked.  Leaves strengthened by pure salvinorin A extract are readily available on the market, requiring a lesser volume of material smoked than regular fresh leaves.  The effects of smoking leaves or extract come on immediately, with the hallucinations being more intense yet shorter lived than the traditional methods of ingestion.

There is near limitless potential for the medical use of salvinorin A.  Salvinorin A has been shown to display antidepressant-like effects in patients of severe chronic major depression that do not respond to any of the traditional methods of treatment.  In addition, its effects at the &#954;-opioid receptor may unveil the precise chemical basis of several neurodegenerative disorders.  Because it would unquestionably hinder legitimate medical research pursuits, scheduling salvinorin A must not occur.

1. Campaign to halt the progress of current legislations attempting to ban S. divinorum

2. Encourage the responsible spiritual use of the herb

3. Unlock secrets of perception through medical research with the plants primary active componant, salvinorin A</description>
  <mission>We seek to defend the spiritual and medical use of Salvia divinorum</mission>
  <name>Save Salvia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5838</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">312</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yt/4K/qn/K2/pK/mV/mf8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
