<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Individual households are the prime generator of solid waste, yet so many of people do not live by any type of conservation regulations, let alone recycle. Studies prove that by recycling a ton of materials in a typical curb side recycling program, electricity, petroleum, natural gas, coal and other natural resources are conserved. If one aluminum can is recycled, it saves enough electricity to light a 100-watt bulb for three and a half hours. With the high prices (and low supply) of gas, everyone should make recycling a habit because by simply recycling one ton of glass, it saves the equivalent of nine gallons of fuel. 
	     Americans alone already send over two hundred thirty million tons of trash to landfills per year. Why do we continue to send recyclable materials there too? Land filling and incineration is the expensive process of burning and sandwiching trash between layers of soil in the attempt to prevent contaminants from leaking into groundwater or being discharged into the air. It isn&#8217;t one hundred percent precise, and more times than not, contaminants and emissions do leak out into the air and water. That&#8217;s real good for the environment.
      Much less energy is needed to make recycled materials into new products compared to beginning the process again from untouched natural resources. Not recycling can guarantee a huge waste of electricity and energy. Making sure proper materials are recycled is a way to reduce trash and the not so accurate land filling process. Recycling is the one easy, effective, cost efficient way to save energy and our precious earth.
      So, next time you chug down a soda or  clean the papers off you desk just remember to recycle. Once you start  recycling, I can promise you it will become second nature.

1. Americans alone already send over two hundred thirty million tons of trash to landfills per year. Why do we continue to send recyclable materials there too?

2. Land filling and incineration is the expensive process of burning and sandwiching trash between layers of soil in the attempt to prevent contaminants from leaking into groundwater or being discharged into the air. Why would we do this to recycleable mater

3.  Much less energy is needed to make recycled materials into new products compared to beginning the process again from untouched natural resources. Not recycling can guarantee a huge waste of electricity and energy.</description>
  <mission>To remind people to do the simple act of recycling.</mission>
  <name>START RECYCLING !</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5841</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">33</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yz/GF/Io/c7/a8/28/cXiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
