<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Center for International Relations is a nonprofit, tax exempt (501(c)3) organization based in the Washington, D.C. area unaffiliated with any group or ideology. We are devoted to the independent exchange of international affairs, intelligence and economics views and information. Our primary focus is the web site journal, IA-Forum.org. Through it, we strive to facilitate and enrich our readers' experience by providing: 

Non-Partisan Content - IA-Forum.org presents information in an unbiased manner, regardless of political creed to provide our readers an all-encompassing view of subjects. 

IA-Forum Content - IA-Forum publishes opinion pieces, essays, articles, and interviews with leading professionals and academics. 
Global Viewpoints - IA-Forum.org presents content from a global perspective. 

Full Range of Contributor Demographics - IA-Forum accepts and publishes content from contributors ranging from students to academics and experienced professionals. 

One Stop Portal for Research and Information - IA-Forum.org contains a database of information sources tailored specifically by topics, regions, and countries to ease and accelerate the search process. Links to specific news stories, publications, and organizations are stored in our database to ensure speedy retrieval of information. By providing international affairs, intelligence and economics specific links, the user can achieve a significant decrease in research time compared to using leading search engines. 

Other CIR Functions: 
Student Awards for Outstanding Submissions 
Special Events (roundtable discussions, etc.) 
Scholar Exchange Program 
Conferences 
Board of Directors



1. Objective Media

2. Global Perspective

3. Promote International Dialogue</description>
  <mission>Encourage International Understanding</mission>
  <name>Center for International Relations  learn about the $1000 Student Award</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5863</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sG/rs/Ji/BQ/0F/cn/qXUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
