<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>When asked what his ambitions outside of dancing were, Jes&#250;s Solorio replied:

&lt;i&gt;"My ambition is helping children in need. I love donating, I love donating my time, and that's what I want to do. I want to make enough money to help people out. You know, people have given to me, and I want to give back. I want to Pay It Forward."&lt;/i&gt;

Jes&#250;s was raised in the small California town of Paso Robles, growing up around the vinyards in the only work force that his family could be a part of. Unable to afford the costs of his education in dance, the people of his town would hold fundraisers to put him through training. Having been given the opportunity to put such a gift out there for the world to see, he now hopes to be able to do the same for other children in need. 

With partner Sara Kei VonGillern by his side, Jes&#250;s has done what he set out to do, inspiring fans everywhere to get up and dance. Unfortunately, this amazing dancer, who carries with him an incredible personality and heart, was cut from the competition after only three weeks. To honor him and his accomplishments, we would like to help him Pay It Forward.

And so we pose the question: &lt;i&gt;Why Would Jes&#250;s Dance? Why would you? Does dance exist to fulfill only those on the floor, or is it something to be shared for the bennefit of every person it touches?&lt;/i&gt;

We ask that members of this cause hold events in their hometown to raise money for Jes&#250;s' cause. Whether it be a formal dance showcase, or simply a chance for friends to get together on the dance floor, we hope to use what Jes&#250;s does best (No, not making wine... DANCE) as a fundraiser to make a donation to this site. We will then donate every penny raised to the Hispanic Scholarship Fund in California, making this contribution in his name to the youth and young adults of his own community so that they can alas achieve the education they would not otherwise be priveleged to gain.

1. Dance is to be shared with each and every person it can reach.

2. Every step can make a difference.</description>
  <mission>To support former SYTYCD 3 contestant Jes&#250;s Solorio in his desire to give back to the people who need it most.</mission>
  <name>WWJD: Why Would Jes&#250;s Dance?</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5865</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">22</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yi/2d/Rp/tL/M0/cu/SEsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
