<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Denver Rescue Mission provides
emergency services to the poor and homeless through overnight shelter, meals, food boxes, clothing, and a health clinic.

The Denver Rescue Mission is also an organization dedicated to helping the homeless start their lives over through a 5 phase program called the "New Life Program." 

5 Phases: 
Orientation: Residents identify goals such as obtaining sobriety, overcoming personal problems, and making educational progress. Using this treatment plan, counseling, addiction therapies, and education work begins. 

Stabilization: Residents accept and develop 
disciplines to reach established goals. 

Application: Residents attend church activities, complete educational track, may work part-time, and/or begin higher education classes. 

Initiation: Residents form new, healthy community relationships, continue higher education, mentor lower phase residents, and may work full-time. 

Independence: Residents develop an independent living plan and demonstrate self-sufficiency through career employment, financial savings, and spiritual maturity. 

--
Post-Graduate Program: Many New Life program graduates go on to the Post-Graduate Program, which provides further mentoring, accountability, counseling, and financial aid. Graduates mentor others and volunteer at the Mission, while continuing random drug tests.

1. We shall provide the message of the gospel of Jesus Christ.

2. We shall provide services which will meet the immediate needs of those seeking assistance.

3. We shall provide a program of rehabilitation to those people who wish to change their lives.

4. We shall be an advocate for the poor and needy through public education and awareness.</description>
  <mission>Text FEED to 40579 to donate $5. Your donation will help feed the hungry during the holidays. $5 will be added to your phone bill, standard messaging rates may apply.</mission>
  <name>Denver Rescue Mission</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5880</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1915</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">831.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ZN/Tp/Jo/Rp/Yx/f3/E5/4vS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
