<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I watched the movie Blood Diamond recently. It was horrible to see the atrocities committed by the RUF Rebels... Thankfully, the war is over now, but the country still needs dire help to rebuild. We may feel like we can't do anything, I feel that way too, but there are many things we can do. In Canada, diamonds can be found here and are also conflict-free. A conflict diamond, also referred to as a blood diamond, is an illegally imported diamond found in Sierra Leone, Guinea, Ivory Coast or Liberia. For more information on blood diamonds, visit http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conflict_diamond

Back to things we can do to help. Well, the first obvious one is money. Donations are needed everywhere, and even if only a small amount, if it comes from the heart, it has maintained it's value. You can also write a letter to a government, or look for an organization near your city that supports causes like the one in Sierra Leone.

The conflict is over, but Sierra Leone still needs your help. For more information on how to take action, visit these websites:
http://www.cryfreetown.org/
http://beehive.thisisessex.co.uk/default.asp?WCI=SiteHome&amp;ID=3341&amp;PageID=15881
http://stopblooddiamonds.org/

Additionally, you can view the country profile for Sierra Leone here:
http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/africa/country_profiles/1061561.stm

1. Sierra Leone is a war-torn country. It has undergone rebuilding but still requires a lot of money for everything to be "right."

2. There are many people who have been injured by the RUF Rebels and need dire financial aid.

3. Sierra Leone needs our help to be a corrupt-free country.</description>
  <mission>donate money to those in need in Sierra Leone</mission>
  <name>Help Sierra Leone</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5883</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">175</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zl/yZ/2X/vK/Qh/4b/euUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
