<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Depression is a serious medical condition that affects the mind and body. It is an illness, in the same way that diabetes, heart disease and cancer are illnesses. Depression is an illness that one in five people will suffer during their lifetime, the leading cause of alcoholism, drug abuse, and other addictions. 

Depression is not the same as a 'moody time'. It is not a sign of personal weakness or a condition that can be willed or wished away. People with a depressive illness cannot "pull themselves together" and get better on their own. Without proper treatment, depressive symptoms can last for weeks, months, or years, and lead to other conditions. 

Depression can strike anyone regardless of age, ethnic background, socioeconomic status, or gender. 

It is shocking that despite the magnitude and reach of this illness, we are spending little money towards prevention and treatment. It is treatable yet we do not put the resources towards treating it.

1. Though several organizations deal with mental illness, few, if any, actually focus internationally on depression in an encouraging, enlightening way.

2. iFred&#8217;s primary goal is to bring energy and information together from a variety of existing sources to educate, inform and change the way we look at depression today.  

3. We need to foster an environment where people feel comfortable getting help, they feel good about openly celebrating an individual&#8217;s ability to recover from a depressive episode, and support and applaud them in moving forward in a battle similar to that</description>
  <mission>dedicated to researching causes of depression, to support those dealing with depression, and to combat the stigma associated with depression. </mission>
  <name>International Foundation for Research and Education on Depression</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5884</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">165</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">110.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gB/JP/BG/BJ/Lw/6y/ESOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
