<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>*****PLEASE HELP RECRUIT OTHERS*****

This group was created to increase public awareness for children and families struggling with developmental disorders. It was also created to help others understand the life these people lead and the troubles they go through day to day. Our purpose is to educate the public, and help increase acceptance of the handicapped in our society. We also serve to raise money to help aid research foundations in developing treatment and cures for the many developmental disorders prevalent in today's society.

All Proceeds will go to St. Jude's Children Hospital to benefit Research and Care for children living with developmental disorders.

-----------------------

Developmental disability is a term used to describe life-long disabilities attributable to mental and/or physical impairments, manifested prior to age twenty-two. The term is used most commonly in the United States to refer to disabilities affecting daily functioning in three or more of the following areas: capacity for independent living, economic self-sufficiency, learning, mobility, receptive and expressive language, self-care, self-direction.

This is a group encompassing many childhood and birth disorders including most generally people with:

Mental Retardation
Cerebral Palsy
Autism Spectrum Disorder
Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorder
chromosomal disorders
Down Syndrome 
Fragile X Syndrome.


1. The Public needs to be more aware of the care of millions of individuals living with developmental disorders.

2. The Government should fund/increase aid and research to kids with Developmental Disorders.

3. Increase the acceptance of mentally/physically handicapped individuals within our society.</description>
  <mission>To inform the public of the care for millions of individuals living with developmental disorders.</mission>
  <name>Developmental Disabilities Awareness Coalition</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5885</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">987</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">70.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ro/q2/1r/8Z/zQ/Ve/8I/bnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
