<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>MENC: The National Association for Music Education serves as a leader and spokesman for music education in the United States. It is the only national association that addresses every aspect of music education - band, chorus, jazz, orchestra, general music, teacher education, and research. MENC's nearly 120,000 members represent all levels of teaching, from prekindergarten through postgraduate. Since 1907, MENC has worked to advance music education by encouraging the study and making of music by all through the improvement of music teaching and increased support for music education in schools and communities. 
Programs: The efforts of MENC: The National Association for Music Education include support to nearly 120,000 members in every level of education, community outreach reaching over 6 million children and adults with the National Anthem Project, internationally through our annual World's Largest Concert sing-along, sustained advocacy for arts awareness, the TriM international music honor society, and partnerships that benefit students, teachers, schools, and communities. Additionally, MusicFriends operates as an organization devoted to bringing together music supporters as a national coalition with one voice supporting music education for all. National and regional conferences are held in alternating years while state affiliates hold annual conferences. With strong local and national networks of committed members and supporters of music education, MENC is the leading organization committed to preserving music education in our nation's schools. 


1. Help preserve music education in our nation's schools

2. Help students perform at their very best 

3. Make Dreams come true.</description>
  <mission>To Improve every aspect of music education</mission>
  <name>MENC</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5904</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">251</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Uh/Y0/VG/qx/zB/DO/OxqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
