<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Hike for Discovery" is a non-profit endurance training program that benefits the Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society. The program is nation wide, dividing its hikers into groups and teams by region (i.e. East Coast, Southwest, etc.) and sending those groups on various locations across the country. Three-quarters of each donation goes directly to cancer research for leukemia, lymphoma, myeloma, and Hodgkin's disease, while the other quarter goes to training and travel. The money you donate will pay not only for research for a cure, but also for support groups, education programs and financial planning for afflicted families. 

This particular hike in October is located in the majestic Grand Canyon! The hikers will hike over 125 miles andl hike over 26,000 total feet of elevation during the course of training, as well as 3200 feet of elevation in a single hike. When the Hike is completed and the hikers reach their goal, they will have raised $172,500 for cancer research (Therefore, raising $4200 should be easy!).

The goal is to raise $4200 by September 10th ! IF YOU WILL PLEASE DONATE THROUGH: 
www.active.com/donate/hfdnmep/hfdEhuffma2

Please donate and join this cause! 
"I'm doing the work, but YOU will make the difference."


1. Honor those who are suffering and have suffered from blood cancers.

2. Accelerate the aquisition and application of scientific understanding to advance the treatment, diagnosis, and prevent of leukemia, lymphoma and myeloma.

3. Reach out to the patients at the time of diagnosis.</description>
  <mission>To Raise money for Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society www.active.com/donate/hfdnmep/hfdEhuffma2</mission>
  <name>Hike for Discovery</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5918</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">31</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4N/Zv/Dl/Dz/QZ/kR/33qS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
