<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Human trafficking is a modern form of slavery. Women, children, and men are bought and sold everyday, all over the world. In January 2004, Dateline NBC broadcasted "Children for Sale," an hour-long special report based on an investigation of brothels in Cambodia, specialized in the sexual exploitation of young girls, mostly from neighboring country Vietnam. The real life images of girls as young as 8 years old hit home to many people, especially the Vietnamese youth.

As a new and developing organization, VietACT works to not only raise awareness but to maintain awareness of human trafficking while initiating campaigns to influence public policy and public opinion to bring out about systematic changes. 

In late 2004 and 2005, VietACT's major activities include fundraising activities to support the work of Father Peter Nguyen Van Hung and victims services provided by VMWBO/TaiwanACT.   VietACT's members and volunteers in Orange County, Long Beach, Los Angeles, San Jose, San Diego, Minneapolis, Houston, Portland, Chicago, and Denver have and continue to actively build awareness, campaign, and fundraise money that are directly allocated to anti-human trafficking organizations such as VMWBO in Taiwan. 

In 2006, greater momentum picked up from the Vietnamese students and young professionals, with great community support, through the Union of North American Vietnamese Student Association&#8217;s Collective Philanthropy Project, the &#8220;Relay Against Trafficking.&#8221; Through this campaign awareness was increased to other parts of the United States, in places such as Atlanta, Austin, Boston and Orlando. 

Please see their website for more information and up-to-date news:

http://www.vietact.org/

**I am not affiliated with this Non-Profit Organization, but I thought this would be a great way to create awareness for such an important cause. 

**Please donate through their website and this will save them a 4.5% processing fee or you can still donate here. Anything helps! PLEASE DONATE.


1. Eradicate Human Trafficking.</description>
  <mission>To eradicate the human trafficking of Vietnamese victims through collaboration, advocacy, and education, for the purpose of supporting, protecting and empowering victims.</mission>
  <name>VietACT</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5932</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1116</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">65.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Vb/q5/lx/EL/Xk/7q/OHES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
