<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>See also http://www.facebook.com/home.php#/group.php?gid=2210900649

Physicians for a National Health Program (http://pnhp.org/) is a single issue organization advocating a universal, comprehensive single-payer national health program. PNHP has more than 14,000 members and chapters across the United States.  You don't need to be a physician to join this cause!

We endorse a fundamental change in America's health care - the creation of a comprehensive National Health Insurance (NHI) Program. Such a program - which in essence would be an expanded and improved version of Medicare - would cover every American for all necessary medical care.

The U.S. spends twice as much as other industrialized nations on health care, $7,129 per capita. Yet our system performs poorly in comparison and still leaves 46 million without health coverage and millions more inadequately covered.

This is because private insurance bureaucracy and paperwork consume one-third (31 percent) of every health care dollar. Streamlining payment though a single nonprofit payer would save more than $350 billion per year, enough to provide comprehensive, high-quality coverage for all Americans.

Our members and physician activists work toward a single-payer national health program in their communities. PNHP organizes rallies, town hall meetings, and debates; coordinates speakers and forum discussions; contributes Op-Eds and articles to the nation's top newspapers, medical journals and magazines;and appears regularly on national television and news programs advocating for a single-payer system. 

1. The US Healthcare system is by far the most expensive in the world

2. It wastes almost $350b a year on paperwork, leaves almost 50m Americans uninsured, and only ranks 37th in the world for quality

3. The US has the opportunity to greatly improve quality of care while actually reducing cost</description>
  <mission>Support a Single-Payer National Health Insurance Program for the US</mission>
  <name>Physicians for a National Health Program</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5946</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">339</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">120.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/QW/61/12/Ol/8O/eu/XiCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
