<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>( Our Youtube channel: http://www.youtube.com/user/PeakOilAwareness )

"What is Peak Oil?"

The global peak in world oil production. Here in the US, the oil peak has already occurred... in 1970...

"When is it coming?"

A large community of oil geologists, scientists, and engineers believe the oil peak is coming within the next decade (see links below).

"Who is responsible for this?"

We all are. It's not all ExxonMobil's fault. Here in the US, we use 20.7 million barrels of oil PER DAY (mbpd). The entire world consumes 86 mbpd.

"Why should I care?"

Because of the consequences to daily life once the world passes the oil peak. What happens when the world demands 86 mbpd, but it can no longer produce enough oil to meet that demand?

Sure, gas prices will go up. But this goes way beyond that.

THINK about how gas prices affect domestic/international shipping? How high gas prices send ripple effects through entire economies.

All pesticides and fertilizers are made from oil. 
THINK about how oil prices affect agriculture.

Plastics are made from oil.
All petrochemicals are made from oil.

Our modern daily life is built on cheap and abundant oil. 

"How can I help?"

Peak oil is addressed very poorly by the mainstream media. Please help us increase awareness by joining this cause and inviting your friends.

1. LEARN 
"Peak Oil Primer" (http://www.energybulletin.net/primer.php )
"Life after the Oil Crash"  (http://www.lifeaftertheoilcrash.net/ )
"Oil Scenarios. info" (http://www.oilscenarios.info/ )
"The Oil Drum" (http://www.theoildrum.com/ )

2. THINK
Look at the info and come to your own conclusions.

3. TALK
Talk to your family and friends. Write to your elected officials; tell them that you want a comprehensive energy plan developed to handle the peak oil issue. (The US Congress released a report that acknowledges such a plan really doesn't exist - http://www.gao.gov/new.items/d07283.pdf )

1. Do you know what "Peak Oil" means? Do your friends?

2. To become aware is to be forever changed.

3. Energy is 'the' defining issue of the next 50 years.

4. Peak oil is coming... but the global community can work together to overcome it.</description>
  <mission>Inform, educate, and advance discussion about the ongoing peak oil debate.</mission>
  <name>Peak Oil Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5947</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1181</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">150.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hz/B3/X1/I5/oH/Dc/q3QS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
