<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Polycystic Ovarian Syndrome (PCOS) is a health problem that can affect a woman's menstrual cycle, ability to have children, hormones, heart, blood vessels, and appearance. With PCOS, women typically have:

-high levels of androgens. These are sometimes called male hormones, although females also make them. 
-missed or irregular periods 
-many small cysts in their ovaries. Cysts are fluid-filled sacs. 

About one in ten women of childbearing age has PCOS. It can occur in girls as young as 11 years old. PCOS is the most common cause of female infertility (not being able to get pregnant).

The cause of PCOS is unknown. Most researchers think that more than one factor could play a role in developing PCOS. Genes are thought to be one factor. Women with PCOS tend to have a mother or sister with PCOS. Researchers also think insulin could be linked to PCOS. Insulin is a hormone that controls the change of sugar, starches, and other food into energy for the body to use or store. For many women with PCOS, their bodies have problems using insulin so that too much insulin is in the body. Excess insulin appears to increase production of androgen. This hormone is made in fat cells, the ovaries, and the adrenal gland. Levels of androgen that are higher than normal can lead to acne, excessive hair growth, weight gain, and problems with ovulation.

You can find out more about PCOS by contacting the National Women's Health Information Center (NWHIC) at 1-800-994-9662.

1. There needs to be more research towards the causes, treatments, and finding a cure for PCOS</description>
  <mission>Promote awareness and research of PCOS</mission>
  <name>PCOS Research and Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5954</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3233</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">133.45</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rq/pi/Jb/IN/7q/N8/8KES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
