<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>*Thanks to everyone who has joined the cause so far, I am so pleased that so many of you have taken this to heart! 
*I want to extend my thanks to Deepak at the Jungle Lodge in Chitwan National Park, a man who probably doesn't know that he inspired this cause through a brief conversation I had with him back in April 2007 - But I wanted everyone here to know because he's a brilliant guy with a lot of passion!
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
No official census of the number of tigers has been undertaken in Royal Chitwan National park now for around four years, numbers are estimated to be around 91 (overall total for Nepal is higher), however they face constant threat from poaching and with the anti-poaching forces in place not receiving enough funding, the future for the tigers of Chitwan is bleak. I heard this first hand whilst staying at 'The Jungle Lodge', and the statistics moved me to do something on my return to promote awareness, and encourage others to visit both Nepal and Royal Chitwan National park.
Some interesting wildlife facts about Nepal :
* 8% of the worlds bird species are present in Nepal
* 167 Mammal species (3% of the global population) inhabit Nepal, 1 is endemic, 18% are threatened
* Out of 5600 species of flowering plants 246 are found only in Nepal.
* All this in just 0.09% of the worlds total landmass. Yet, inspite of this only 10% of Nepals tourism is to see the wildlife.


- NEWS FLASH.......
In response to the Japanese government announcement that they plan to kill approx 1000 whales I have set up another cause; 'Condemn the Japanese whaling project' please spread the word.

1. Helping to raise awareness of the plight of Nepal's tigers

2. Raising awareness of Nepal : beyond the Himalayas</description>
  <mission>To raise awareness of the plight of the tigers of Nepal</mission>
  <name>Save the tigers of Nepal</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5959</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1186</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">30.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/LC/iQ/NB/a5/hJ/81/Md/OKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
