<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Donate money to the Vasculitis foundation at:

http://www.vasculitisfoundation.org/

Vasculitis results in inflammations of the capillaries, blood vessels, arteries, and veins (Vasculitis Foundation, 2006).


The reason that I am promoting The Vasculitis Foundation is that my father recently passed away. He was diagnosed with a rare autoimmune disease called Wegener's Granulomatosis (one of the diseases classified as Vasculitis). 

 It is my goal to make people aware of Vasculitis. Please join me in supporting this group of diseases. 

I love my dad and miss him more than anything in the world. I have made a donation in his memory via the Vasculitis foundation. I would like to thank all of my family and friends that contributed to this cause.

For donations to the Vasculitis Foundation please visit this website:
http://www.vasculitisfoundation.org/donate/amount

or contact:
Vasculitis Foundation
P.O. Box 28660
Kansas City, MO 64188-8660
USA

(800) 277-9474
(816) 436-8211 (Phone/Fax)

e-mail: [send email to vf@vasculitisfoundation.org via gmail] vf@vasculitisfoundation.org

Thank you for your help and support.

Lindsay Plumley



1. To prevent Vasculitis in potentially suseptible individuals

2. To provide effective treatment for patients  diagnosed with the group of Vasculitis diseases

3. To support and fund ongoing research regarding the causes, and treatments of Vasculitis

4. To research a cure. To determine the best possible medical treatment for individuals diagnosed with Vasculitis</description>
  <mission>Provide education, support, treatment, and research to patients and families diagnosed with Vasculitis</mission>
  <name>Vasculitis Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5961</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1984</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1521.31</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/u2/Gn/Fw/Rg/Sz/53/ze/InS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
