<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Ever tried to find your highschool friend but cannot b/c she is now Mrs. Trevor Andrews?  

Take away our names and we are, in a sense, nothing. Without a name, our friends cannot find us, our cultural identity is obscured and our history is lost.

Then why is it that every year approximately 3 million women abandon their names in favor of their husbands at marriage? This is approximately 90% of all marriages. This tradition of name-abandonment by women is so much a part of U.S. culture, that few recognize it for what it is: a powerful instance of sex discrimination which has a major effect on women.

The U.S. tradition is for children to be given the father's surname in approximately 95% of births to children to married parents. The message to mothers is: "Your name is not important. Your family history is not important." Of course, their children see the same message, "I have my father's name because my mother's pre-marriage name is not important."

This absence of Name Choice Freedom at marriage and in the naming of children communicates a major sexist message to those who have changed their names and to those whose names are affected by this sexist tradition (i.e. virtually all of us). That message is:
WOMEN ARE NOT IMPORTANT. THEIR IDENTITIES ARE NOT WORTH AS MUCH AS MEN'S.

The Lucy Stone League works to change the naming practices at marriage and at birth to a non-sexist tradition where the burden of name changes, if any, are shared by men and women; and the source of naming of children is shared by mothers and fathers.




1. Equal rights for women and men to retain, modify and create their names, because a person's name is fundamental to her/his existence.

2. Equal actual frequency of name retention, modification and creation between men and women at marriage and throughout life.

3. Equality of patrilineal/matrilineal name distribution for children.</description>
  <mission>Seek equal rights for women and men to retain, modify and create their names when marrying and naming children.</mission>
  <name>Lucy Stone League: Name Choice Freedom for Women &amp; Men When Marrying!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5966</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">129</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">60.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xC/SF/JO/wC/Ny/me/myQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
