<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> Unity08 is for people who are tired of partisan bickering in Washington, of special interests trumping the public interest, and of politicians ignoring the country's most pressing issues. Most importantly, it's for people who are ready to do something about it.

Iraq. Education. The national debt. Healthcare. Oil dependency. These are just a few of the crucial issues our country needs to address. But instead of talking about them, politicians in Washington are spinning their wheels with wedge issues like gay marriage and flag burning. They're way off track and we're here to bring them back. In 2008, we will nominate a presidential Unity Ticket (of one Democrat and one Republican, in either order) that will address these big issues and work to solve them.

Unity08 is important for every generation, but it is especially important for ours. We don't have to accept that we will inherit a broken system. You can help fix it by joining Unity08 right now.

Without a significant portion of the electorate, it won't matter how visionary Unity08 is. There will be no Unity08 Ticket. So go out there, talk to five friends (heck, talk to 30) and tell them to join us at www.college.unity08.com.

This site is part of the larger Unity08 effort. To learn more about Unity08, check out the FAQ or visit www.unity08.com. 


Please do all donations on the Unity '08 website since facebook wont allow a direct donation to the foundation. https://secure.ga6.org/08/unity08donate_dd

Recent News:
~Unity 08' is set to hit the 100,000 member mark this week! Please help by talking to your friends! (posted 7/31/07)

1. The election of a Unity Ticket for President and Vice-President of the United States in 2008 - headed by a woman and/or man from each major party or by an independent who presents a Unity Team from both parties.

2. For the people to pick that Unity Ticket in the first half of 2008, via a virtual and secure online convention in which all American voters will be qualified to vote.

3. A minimum goal of effecting major change and reform in the 2008 national elections by influencing the major parties to adopt the core features of our national agenda. With a group of voters who comprise at least 20% of the national electorate, we feel con</description>
  <mission>Nominate a presidential Unity Ticket (of one Democrat and one Republican, in either order) that will address these big issues and work to solve them.</mission>
  <name>Unity '08</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5978</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">58</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ak/wY/qx/KF/tC/hV/nGFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
