<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"The National Coalition for the Homeless, founded in 1982, is a national network of people who are currently experiencing or who have experienced homelessness, activists and advocates, community-based and faith-based service providers, and others committed to a single mission. That mission, our common bond, is to end homelessness. We are committed to creating the systemic and attitudinal changes necessary to prevent and end homelessness. At the same time, we work to meet the immediate needs of people who are currently experiencing homelessness or who are at risk of doing so. We take as our first principle of practice that people who are currently experiencing homelessness or have formerly experienced homelessness must be actively involved in all of our work."  See: http://www.nationalhomeless.org/

1. Every member of society, including people experiencing homelessness, has a right to basic economic and social entitlements of which safe, decent, accessible, affordable, and permanent housing is a definitive component.

2. It is a societal responsibility to provide safe, decent, accessible, affordable, and permanent housing for all people, including people experiencing homelessness, who are unable to secure such housing through their own means.

3. All people, including people experiencing homelessness, who are able to secure safe, decent, accessible, affordable, and permanent housing through their own means need economic and social supports to enable them to do so.

4. People experiencing homelessness deserve access to safe, decent, accessible, affordable, and permanent housing through the same systems and programs available to people with housing.

5. People experiencing homelessness have unique needs and life circumstances that may be addressed through housing programs designed specifically for them.

6. All people should have equal access to safe, decent, accessible, affordable, and permanent housing regardless of their unique needs or life circumstances.

7. Universal access to safe, decent, accessible, affordable, and permanent housing is a measure of a truly just society.</description>
  <mission>To fight homelessness in the United States through public education, policy advocacy, and grassroots organizing.</mission>
  <name>End Homelessness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/5987</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8627</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1004.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yd/ZJ/zY/Yw/pN/Oh/4jxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
