<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Over half of El Salvador&#8217;s population survives on less than $2 per day. They face circumstances of extreme injustice that leave them vulnerable to attacks on their human dignity. Many have lived through a brutal 12 year civil war, and now experience escalating threats to human rights, enduring structural poverty and inequality, increasing violence and environmental degradation.  But, as a hard working, generous, and loving people, the Salvadorans have persisted. And for 25 years, The SHARE Foundation: Building a New El Salvador Today has answered their call for accompaniment as they seek to construct justice, peace, and democracy. 
SHARE is about systemic change. The communities that we work with in El Salvador are changing the structures that keep people poor through an integrated effort that to reactivate sustainable local economies, create viable rural policies, and support the empowerment of women, development of leadership and community organizing in El Salvador and beyond.
SHARE invites people from all over the United States to accompany the Salvadoran people in their struggle by forming relationships of friendship and solidarity. Interested individuals or groups from high schools, colleges, and churches can initiate this process by joining a delegation to El Salvador. While the experience in El Salvador itself is life changing, the relationship is brought full circle as delegates return to the United States and can engage in advocacy and fundraising work to support their friends in El Salvador as they work for social justice. 
What can you do? To find out more, visit our website! Sign up for our e-newsletter to  educate yourself about the issues facing Salvadorans and Central Americans today and opportunities to engage in advocacy on their behalf.  Suport SHARE&#8217;s wok and find meaningful gifts through our Solidarity Gift  Program, or support positive change through our Campaign for Peace!


1. The people of the United States can promote change in El Salvador and around the world through partnership with marginalized communities who have organized themselves to fight for their rights. Salvador and beyond through partnership with the poor and mar

2. Citizens have the right and the responsibility to take action against injustices in their own communities and to promote policies that will best help them to build better futures for their children and their communities. 

3. Emerging leaders should be encouraged to participate in movements that will educate others and work towards a brighter future.

4. Women should be empowered to take on the challenges they face and to lead the charge against social injustice.

5. Citizens of the United States can be agents for positive change by ensuring that their government engages with El Salvador and encourages a positive path to development that promotes human rights and a sustainable environment. </description>
  <mission>The SHARE Foundation: Building a New El Salvador Today accompanies marginalized communities as they pursue economic justice, democracy, and sustainable development alternatives.</mission>
  <name>Social and Environmental Justice in El Salvador, Central America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/599</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1777</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">649.29</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/iz/Cf/yO/xn/pQ/8T/oB/CvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
