<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>     David S&#225;nchez Badillo, AKA &#8220;Tempo,&#8221; is one of the most iconic figure in the young history of urban Latin music.

     Tempo recorded the seminal &#8220;Game Over&#8221; and &#8220;New Game&#8221; albums. On these records Tempo defined himself as an articulate spokesperson for the dispossessed. At a time when Urban Latin Music was not even envisioned, both productions were certified Gold by the RIAA.

     Tempo was incarcerated in 2002; charged and later convicted, on purely circumstantial evidence, of conspiracy to distribute an ungodly and totally preposterous amount of hard drugs. This was not a case of gangster life catching up with Tempo, but the Feds taking their frustrations at not being able to contain and control the true criminals.

      Free Tempo is a non-partisan education and advocacy campaign dedicated to seeking timely justice for Tempo.

      Our mission is to build support for a state and federal review of the circumstances that led to the wrongful imprisonment of Tempo and to work towards his release from federal prison.

     Through our work we will educate the people on the life of Tempo, organize an army of supporters to fight for his release and ultimately obtain freedom for Tempo.

     At this time, his Appellant's Brief has been submitted for consideration to the Boston Court of Appeals. In 2006 Tempo will take his rightful place at the top of urban music&#8217;s pantheon of stars. AND with all of our help, Tempo will be free.


1. We believe that Tempo was wrongly accused by the federal government and later convicted on conspiracy charges to distribute drugs in Puerto Rico.

2. We believe Tempo is innocent of these charges. 

3. We believe the use of the conspiracy drug laws to convict Tempo to a sentence of 24 years without any physical evidence, a poor legal defense and a legally flawed trial is a clear and excessive violation of justice by the federal government.

4. We believe that Tempo is not the only victim of this type of injustice and others wrongly convicted under similar circumstances will benefit from our education and advocacy campaign.

5. We believe it is our responsibility to teach the principles of the American justice system and will work within its guidelines to educate, organize and fight for the release of Tempo and others wrongly accused under the conspiracy laws from prison.</description>
  <mission>To get David S&#225;nchez Badillo released from prison.</mission>
  <name>Free Tempo</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6011</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">82</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/re/3W/wE/kV/yK/5h/HerS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
