<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>After 9/11, it was Rudy who stepped up and helped pull the people of New York together.  Now as he runs for president, the same is true.  He&#8217;s had experience and he knows what is best for our country.  Rudy has proven himself to be an incredible leader with strong convictions and beliefs he follows and will not be swayed from in the face of opposition. He truly cares about the people he leads &amp; has great vision for the road ahead:::::::::::visit this website   http://www.joinrudy2008.com/  

1. Withdrawal from Iraq now would be a terrible mistake.  Rudy Giuliani believes winning the war on terror is the great responsibility of our generation. America cannot afford to go back to the days of playing defense.

2. Because of Rudy, New York City taxpayers saved more than $9 billion in taxes and enjoyed their lowest tax burden in decades, while the economy grew and city government saw its revenues increase from the lower tax rates

3. Rudy Giuliani supports reasonable restrictions on abortion such as parental notification with a judicial bypass and a ban on partial birth abortion &#8211; except when the life of the mother is at stake

4. Before Rudy became Mayor, New York City was averaging close to 2,000 murders a year and more than 11,000 major crimes per week. He put more cops on the street and more criminals in jail. He cut crime in half and reduced murders by two-thirds.

5. As Mayor, Rudy Giuliani worked to reform the nation&#8217;s largest public school system, with over 1 million school children. He increased school funding and hired new teachers, while insisting on reforms that ended social promotion.

6. Rudy Giuliani is a strong supporter of the Second Amendment. When he was Mayor of a city suffering an average of almost 2000 murders a year, he protected people by getting illegal handguns out of the hands of criminals. As a result, shootings fell by 72% 

7. Rudy believes marriage is between a man and a woman. He does not - and has never - supported gay marriage. But he believes in equal rights under law for all Americans. That's why he supports domestic partnerships that provide stability for commitment

8. Rudy Giuliani served as the third highest ranking official in Ronald Reagan&#8217;s Justice Department, worked as a US Attorney, and argued cases before the Supreme Court. He knows the responsibility the President has to appoint and nominate federal judge.

9. Before Rudy was elected Mayor, tax-and-spend policies created billion-dollar deficits and led to the loss of hundreds of thousands of jobs in New York City. Rudy restored fiscal discipline by controlling spending and cutting wasteful programs.</description>
  <mission>Get America to vote Rudy in the 2008 election</mission>
  <name>Join Rudy Giuliani for President in 08</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6023</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">602</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/s0/S1/HO/nU/18/3c/OlIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
