<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>NCCJ.ORG

To transform communities to provide fuller opportunity and to be inclusive and just &#8211; through institutional change &#8211; by empowering leaders. NCCJ's programming facilitates community and interfaith dialogues, provides workplace consultations, youth leadership development, seminarian and educator training.  

Our Guiding Beliefs and Principles:

We are not a neutral party in this work.  Our role is to advocate, educate and resolve conflict - relative to issues of discrimination and oppression of individuals and groups. In order to promote understanding and respect across groups we must acknowledge the dynamics of power and privilege and the role they play in creating attitudes, behavior, and practices that support systems of exclusion and oppression.

All members of society at some time may feel the impact of systemic oppression, either overt or covert, intentional or unintentional, conscious or unconscious.  In order to fulfill our organizational mission, our program efforts must be connected to creating inclusive, respectful and just communities.

NCCJ is the only national human relations organization that focuses on a broad range of "isms," the multiple manifestations of discrimination and oppression that are based on one&#8217;s religion, race, gender, sexual orientation, bias crimes to racial profiling - the challenges ahead are real.  To confront and overcome them, NCCJ maintains an abiding commitment to work with decision-makers and leaders to support their work to build an inclusive society.

1. Working to build an inclusive society.

2. NCCJ promotes understanding and respect among all races, religions and cultures through advocacy, conflict resolution and education.

3. Fighting bias, bigotry and racism.</description>
  <mission>To make our nation a better place for all of us. Not just some of us.</mission>
  <name>NCCJ</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6025</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">814</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/rh/4C/rD/CN/TE/13/JHCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
