<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We are currently developing a number of programs that will enable individuals to assist some of the poorest people in India. We are setting up a child sponsorship program, where you will be able to sponsor children at Snehalaya - a small NGO that provides a safe haven and opportunities for children from the slums, red light areas and other at risk children in the city of Ahmednagar.
 
We provide opportunities for midwives, medical clinicians and other medical professionals to provide advice and expertise as well as help to these children and other people who lack regular access to medical care. You will work with the Jamkedh rural health project, run by Dr. Arole.
 
A large problem in India is the rise in HIV infections. Our partner organization, Snehalaya, is working to provide medical care to HIV infected children from the slums and red light areas of Ahmednagar. They are short of funds and each month it is a struggle to decide which children get treatment and which do not. We are looking for donors to help fund the medical treatment of these children. If you are a medical professional and are interested in assisting with treating these children, please contact us on the contact page.
 
One other program we are developing involves studying and learning about life in Rural India. Many small villages in Maharashtra State face the problem of drought. Combined with the migration of young people to the cities and sanitation problems, this way of life is rapidly disappearing. A small number of villages are working to reverse this trend and are developing irrigation schemes as well as improving sanitation and getting young adults involved in day to day decision making. Spend some time living in these 'ideal' villages and learning how they are changing rural India. If you have a background in enviromental science and hydrology, you can provide expertise and help to the residents of these villages as well as learning a lot yourself!

1. People reaching out to others make a difference

2. We live in a global community and have aresponsibilty towards each other</description>
  <mission>provide opportunities and resources through which motivated individuals can make meaningful contributions to our world.</mission>
  <name>Changing Horizons</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6026</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2L/xm/c6/Gf/BR/A2/2JbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
