<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Let's take a closer look at this. The Baloch are originally an Iranian people which is said to have moved from the Caspian Sea to the area between the desert in SE Persia and the Arabian Sea the around the year 1000. The cattle-breeding nomadic tribes formed greater tribal confederations at several occasions. In the 18th century, the Khanate of Kalat included nearly the entire settling area of the Baloch and declared its independence in 1747. These data is meant to show the ability of these tribes to organise politically, and their experience in war-making. This didn't result in a nation, but in a national identity.
It was the British who divided the settling area of the Baloch in the course of the formation of British India in the 19th century. In 1871, they agreed with Persia on the so-called Goldsmith line, and established the border to Afghanistan with the Mortimer-Durand line in 1893. However, administration of Balochistan was not done by the British themselves, because it was thought that the peripheral areas of the empire were best pacified by granting the Baloch far-reaching autonomy, potentially including financial support for the tribal chiefs, the sardars. The situation only changed after 1947. The British had withdrawn from India, but independence was not granted to the Baloch. The tribal areas were now administered by the newly formed state of Pakistan, which ruled centrally and did not recognise Baloch sovereignty. Three wars were fought between the state of Pakistan and the Baloch nationalists, not only about the demand for independence, but also about the distribution of the mineral resources. The fiercest conflicts started in 1973. They cost the lives of 5000 Baloch and 3000 Pakistani soldiers and ended only in 1977..........

1. This conflict must be stopped now before it is too late</description>
  <mission>Inform the world - rarely mentioned in the media</mission>
  <name>Against a Civil War in Belutschistan</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6045</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/UC/p5/xI/wA/dh/OM/3czS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
