<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The cause is simple: Despite what some may say, those who oppose illegal immigration don't necessarily oppose immigration in general.

We simply err on the side of the law - those that wish to come to the greatest country on earth can do so if, and only if, they follow our rules, abide by our system and speak our language.

Those that come to our country illegally and then protest our legislators for the passage of laws to protect their illegal status deserve no rights until they go to the back of the line and start the process over just like everyone else. If they do so, I will be the first person to welcome them to our country and congratulate them on becoming a true American citizen.

Opposing illegal immigration is not un-American, in fact it is just the opposite. To support an amnesty plan (or an amnesty plan in sheep's clothing) does nothing more than degrade the dignity of being an American, and further degrades those people going through, or previously having been through, the legal process of becoming a citizen.

We are a country of immigrants, a melting pot of cultures and a people dedicated to the rule of law, preservation of our basic rights and the ability to achieve dreams and goals - legally.


1. Support legal immigration.

2. Do not grant amnesty.

3. Oppose the term "illegal immigrant" because the word "immigrant" infers legality.

4. Support legislators that will take this issue seriously and enforce pre-existing mandates to build a protective fence on our southern border.

5. Urge legislators to take back America and support a plan that secures our country and our citizens both physically and financially</description>
  <mission>promote U.S. security, the enforcement of pre-existing immigration law, seal our porous borders and return the dignity to true and legal immigration. </mission>
  <name>Protect America - Stop Illegal Immigration</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/605</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4747</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.29</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hMd/rV7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
