<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Not much has changed in the ways of treating the disease. Even the operation is basically the same for Ulcerative Colitis. Thank GOD for medicare. The Asacal and Azathioprine are very expensive. 
&lt;p&gt;
It's time for a cure!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;b&gt;CROHN'S DISEASE:&lt;/b&gt;

Crohn's disease is characterized by inflammation which penetrates the entire thickness of the bowel wall. It may attack at any point of the gastrointestinal system from mouth to anus. Neither surgery nor drugs can cure Crohn's disease as it may recur in other parts of the digestive tract.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;ULCERATIVE COLITIS:&lt;/b&gt;

Ulcerative colitis attacks the inner lining of the large bowel (colon) with inflammation, ulceration, bleeding and scaring. The disease can cause sudden life-threatening complications, but is usually controlled by drug and surgical therapies. Removal of the colon can permanently eliminate ulcerative colitis.
&lt;p&gt;
FACEBOOK doesn't have a Canadian Beneficiary so go to the link below. It's the Canadian foundation and you can make your donations there if you'd like or just get recruited and educate yourself and others on Crohn's &amp; Colitis.
&lt;p&gt;
http://www.ccfc.ca/English/index.html
&lt;p&gt;
http://www.ccfc.ca/English/about/nationalsponsors.htm#mm


1. The Crohn's and Colitis Foundation of Canada (CCFC) believes that a cure will be found for Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis. To realize this, the CCFC is committed, first and foremost, to raise increasing funds for medical research.

2. The CCFC also believes it is important to make all individuals with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) aware of the Foundation, and educate these individuals, their families, health professionals and the general public about these diseases.</description>
  <mission>Find a cure</mission>
  <name>Crohn's and Colitis</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6060</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">17</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/f2/tD/Ud/WZ/Wc/e4/WobS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
