<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Citizens Assembly on Electoral Reform has proposed a referendum on the ballot for the next provincial election on October 10, 2007 the people of Ontario are going to be asked as to whether they want the current Single Member Plurality System (a.k.a. First Past the Post System, and Winner Takes All System) or a Mixed Member Plurality System.

Under the current Single Member Plurality System the person with the most number of votes wins, this does not even need to be a majority of 50 + 1; the candidate will be elected if they can get 1 more vote then his closest opponent.

Under the proposed Mixed Member Plurality System there will still be a certain number of members who are voted in under the Single Member Plurality System but in addition every party will be given a number of additional seats based on the percentage of the vote that the party received province wide the members who will be selected are from a party list of additional candidates.  Under the proposed system there will be better representation of the vote of the Citizens of Ontario and it will also ensure that no party can have a majority of the seats with a minority percentage of the popular vote. The proposed system will be extremely advantageous to parties like the Green Party who although always gets a percentage of the vote never has been able to elect a single member.

Every vote counts on this referendum since the Election Ontario has placed a threshold of 60% of those who vote have to be in favour of the measure or else it fails

When You Vote this October 10 remember it is not just a candidate you are voting for but also for change.  For More information please visit http://www.citizensassembly.gov.on.ca.

Unfortunately there is no Canadian Ballot Initiative Strategy Centers of Foundations so we have to piggy back off of the American Ballot Initiative Strategy Center Foundation.

1. Ontario Needs Greater More Proportional Representation.</description>
  <mission>A Vote For This Referndom is a Vote for a Better Ontario</mission>
  <name>Ontario Electoral Reform</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6063</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fa/ZB/dm/2E/oI/v3/jrMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
