<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Kabbalah Centre is a spiritual and educational organization dedicated to bringing the wisdom of Kabbalah to the world. The Centre itself has existed for more than 80 years, but its spiritual lineage extends even further &#8212; to Rav Isaac Luria, in the 16th century, and through Rav Luria to Rav Shimon Bar Yochai, who revealed the principal text of Kabbalah, the Zohar, more than 2000 years ago.

The Kabbalah Centre was founded in Jerusalem in 1922 by Rav Yehuda Ashlag, one of the greatest kabbalists of the 20th century. When Rav Ashlag left this world, leadership of The Centre was taken on by Rav Yehuda Tzvi Brandwein. Before his passing, Rav Brandwein designated Rav Berg to continue the lineage of Kabbalah as Director of The Kabbalah Centre. And today, some 30 years later, co-directs The Centre together with his wife, Karen.

Although there are many scholarly studies of Kabbalah, The Centre understands this wisdom not as an academic discipline but as a way of creating a better life. Through The Kabbalah Centre, the practical tools and spiritual teachings of Kabbalah are accessible to everyone for personal change and transformation. This is the foundation of everything we do.

1. For thousands of years, the great kabbalistic sages have taught that every human being is born with the potential for greatness. Kabbalah is the means for activating that potential. 

2. Kabbalah has always been meant to be used, not just learned. Its purpose is to bring clarity, understanding, and freedom to our lives &#8212; and ultimately to erase even death itself.</description>
  <mission>bring clarity, understanding, and freedom to our lives &#8212; and ultimately to erase even death itself.</mission>
  <name>The Kabbalah Centre</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6074</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">819</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">130.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mS/wm/Gs/2j/DS/vr/G44S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
