<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Each year in the UK alone approximately 1,000 million animals are farmed and killed for food - and that figure doesn't include fish.
The average meat-eater consumes around 2,000 animals in their lifetime (excluding fish). Think of all the lives YOU will save simply by turning vegetarian! As well as being more humane, vegetarianism is healthy, environmentally friendly and a better way to use the world's precious resources. Most people regard horse racing as a harmless sport in which the animals are willing participants who thoroughly enjoy the thrill. The truth is that, behind the scenes, lies a story of immense suffering.
Approximately 15,000 foals are born into the closely-related British and Irish racing industries each year, yet only a third go on to become racers. Those horses who do not make the grade may be slaughtered for meat or repeatedly change hands in a downward spiral of neglect. Of those horses who do go on to race, around 375 are raced to death every year.

Each year inside British laboratories, approximately 3 million animals are experimented on. Every 10.5 seconds, one animal dies. Cats, dogs, rats, mice, guinea pigs, rabbits, primates and other animals are used to test new products, to study human disease and in the development of new drugs. They are even used in warfare experiments. Animal Aid opposes animal experiments on both moral and scientific grounds. Animals are not laboratory tools. They are sentient creatures capable of experiencing pain, fear, loneliness, frustration and sadness.

To imprison animals and deny them their freedom to express natural instincts and to deliberately inflict physical pain in the name of science is unacceptable. All the more so because the experiments are bad science in the first place: they do not produce information that can be reliably applied to people. Ending vivisection will benefit people as well as animals.


(animal aid)


1. End vivisection NOW

2. Ban game hunting

3. Ban horse/greyhound racing

4. Animals will have a cruelty-free lifetime

5. Fur trade will be banned

6. Ban unessasary slaughtering</description>
  <mission>To raise awareness of animal rights.</mission>
  <name>Animal Rights</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6082</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">165</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uo/SD/N5/pX/eX/Hq/kDyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
