<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.ammanimman.org/

&#8220;Water is Life.&#8221;

This could not be truer than in the Azawak region of Niger, where during nine months out of the year there is no water.

A vast plain, 200,000 km2 (larger than the state of Florida and &#8531; the size of France) on the edge of the Sahara, the Azawak is the poorest region in Niger, considered the poorest nation in the world. Living on the brink of survival, the region&#8217;s 500,000 inhabitants walk up to thirty miles a day for water. They have no access to roads or schools, and health centers are a two-day donkey ride away. Few organizations or government agencies work to improve their lives.

If you were to travel there, the Azawak people would welcome you in a princely fashion. They would travel miles to obtain a goat to slaughter in your honor and share their last bowl of frothy camel milk. You might ask for water, then turn away in disgust at the cup of brackish liquid brought to you. You would feel ashamed learning that they generously offered you their last cup set aside to drink for the day.

Clean water is there, in aquifers at an average depth of 650-1300 feet. Amman Imman is raising funds to drill permanent sources of water. Our goal is to provide these resilient people a chance to live without the indignity of daily thirst and fear of water-borne illness. With your contribution, we can accomplish this goal.

Water is life. One water source at a time, we can bring hope to people who have nowhere else to turn. Please help fulfill this dream. The children of the Azawak deserve a better future.

Update: Since July, 2007, an Amman Imman borehole, which includes a faucet system and  separate animal troughs, has been bringing crystal clear water to the people and animals in Tangarwachane.  See the wall post below for pictures and details!

June 2010: The Montessori Well of Love borehole opened in Kijigari village, providing water to 6000 villagers, surrounding communities and up to 35,000 people and animals in the dry season.

Find out more at these websites: 

http://www.waterishope.org/

http://montessori-amman-imman-project.blogspot.com/

Follow us on Twitter:
http://twitter.com/AmmanImman


1. All people deserve access to water, a basic necessity of life.

2. Attention needs to be given to the water crisis in this vast region.

3. Currently, no other aid organizations are helping bring water to this region by building borehole wells.

4. Amman Imman hopes to act as a catalyst for other aid organizations to bring much needed infrastructure to help the people in the region.

5. The people of the Azawak say that their greatest need is access to water in order to save the lives of their children and preserve their way of life.

6. Please help!</description>
  <mission>Amman Imman is dedicated to improving and saving lives among the poorest and most abandoned populations by supplying permanent water sources to the people living in the Azawak Valley, West Africa.</mission>
  <name>Amman Imman: Water is Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6105</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">803</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2807.51</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/r5/I3/jf/F7/bp/3X/uh/LYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
