<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.worldchanging.com/
WorldChanging.com works from a simple premise: that the tools, models and ideas for building a better future lie all around us. That plenty of people are working on tools for change, but the fields in which they work remain unconnected. That the motive, means and opportunity for profound positive change are already present. That another world is not just possible, it's here. We only need to put the pieces together.

http://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/01/fashion/01gside.html
Tread Lightly, Fly Directly - July 1, 2007
- 1. Replace meat with soy or other vegetable protein in your diet.  It takes eight times as much energy to produce  a pound of meat as it does a pound of tofu.
- 2. Replace your light bulbs.  Compact fluorescent bulbs use 75 percent less energy and last 10 times as long as incandescent bulbs. To save even more, turn off the lights when you leave the room.
- 3. Sub-size it. Houses between 1,500 and 2,000 square feet consume about 40 percent less energy than McMansions over 4,000 square feet.
- 4. Downsize your car. Every extra 100 pounds a car weighs requires 2 percent more fuel to move it.
- 5. Fly direct. Takeoffs and landings are where the most fuel is burned. Takeoffs alone can burn 25 percent of the energy used on a short trip. For trips shorter than 600 miles, consider taking the train.
- 6. Pull the plug. Appliances like televisions and VCRs still suck power when turned off. An estimated 95 percent of the energy consumed by cellphone chargers comes when they are left plugged in.
- 7. Skip the bottled water. For every one million bottles of water that are manufactured and shipped to consumers, 18.2 tons of carbon dioxide emissions are pumped into the air.
- 8. Vote. 

OTHER WEBSITES:
http://www.webbyawards.com/webbys/current.php?media_id=96&amp;season=11
http://feeds.feedburner.com/worldchanging_fulltext

1. The use of brands with "eco-friendly" labels is not enough to fix global warming or ozone depletion, nor help Darfur's children or animal sustainability.

2. Buying a Lexus LS 600h, although it's a hybrid, does not make you a better person.

3. Flying across the world for vacation, despite the fact that you buy carbon offsets beforehand, does not make you a better person.

4. Spending a week driving golf balls made from compacted fish  food at an eco-resort in the Maldives does not make you a better person.

5. Reducing your ecological footprint does make you a better person.</description>
  <mission>Decreasing consumption is the only way to help the environment.  We cannot buy a better planet.  All donations will go to Worldchanging.com, an online newsletter (READ MORE BELOW).</mission>
  <name>My Footprint</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6108</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">60</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Gs/r0/3h/8e/5m/Dn/4IES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
