<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>American education is dismal, and never let anybody tell you otherwise.  

Need proof?  Have a look at these charts from the National Center of Education Statistics:
(http://nces.ed.gov/nationsreportcard/ltt/results2004/nat-reading-perf.asp and http://nces.ed.gov/nationsreportcard/ltt/results2004/nat-math-scalescore.asp)

The test scores reflected in these charts show that there is a little improvement in education of readin and math, respectively, for ages 9 and 13 from 1971 until 2004, but the scores for our graduates at age 17 have not changed in reading and "did not show a significant change when compared to the score in either 1973 or 1999." in math. (NAEP Key Findings on NCES).  

Compare this to our per pupil spending which has doubled from $4,479 to $8,996; this is adjusted for inflation (http://nces.ed.gov/programs/digest/d04/tables/dt04_163.asp)

The government has next to no improvement (and I feel like that's generous) for twice as much money!  There are a number of factors contributing to this, but the key to them all is that

 ***They have your money.  It's not going anywhere***

This group is about actively bringing into place a nationwide voucher system that will create a government funded free market education for your children through awareness.

In the common tongue: instead being required to go to the nearest school, you will be able to select the best education system for your children like you choose restaurants to eat at.  And WE'RE GOING TO MAKE THAT HAPPEN!!!

Yes, this means that some schools will go out of business.  It also means that you will be offered improvements and incentives for your money, and the schools that are effective-- the ones you want your children to go to-- will succeed!

1. Free Market Education will improve the learning industry the same way breaking the AT&amp;T monopoly improved communications.

2. Spreading understanding will make a difference!

3. It is up to us to actively bring about change!</description>
  <mission>Create space for a free market public education system</mission>
  <name>Restart</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6126</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/HP/at/m3/T6/Vv/e2/4ieS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
