<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The time has come for change. Suffering does not have to be an inheritance, regardless of what politics or history have taught us. Democrat, Republican, conservative, liberal, extremist, anarchist, etc etc etc.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;i&gt;Done&lt;/i&gt;. No more.&lt;br/&gt;
We are facing crisis- and not just one, but MANY. &lt;br/&gt;Environmental &amp; economic problems, poverty, murder, rape, genocide, and so much more. As my brother would say, "this is not just a democrat/republican issue anymore.. and I think everyone is starting to realize that."  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

This world needs to open its eyes. Look what our leaders have led us into! Look at the wars we are paying for, or even the wars we aren't paying for... Look at the killing going on, everywhere.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

I know, we're conditioned to believe that there is a good side, and a bad side.. But at this point, we have to take a step back from that conditioning and realize....

&lt;i&gt;We Are All Human&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;


What we need now is not someone who will run us, change us, or fix things for us- we are already running just fine. We are already changed- the change is happening &lt;i&gt;now&lt;/i&gt;. When things need fixing, we are fixing them.&lt;br&gt;
What we need is someone who will be able stand up and unite us all as &lt;i&gt;Human&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

Stop dividing us into good and evil.&lt;br/&gt;
Stop trying to convince us.&lt;br/&gt;
There is too much violence.&lt;br/&gt;
Too much imaginary difference.&lt;br/&gt;
Too much bickering.&lt;br/&gt;
Too little time.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Join the cause.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

Stop the political divide.&lt;br/&gt;
Rise up simply, as Human.

1. the time has come for change

2. suffering does not have to be an inheritance

3. love and humanity will reign</description>
  <mission>End the political divide, and rise up simply as Human.</mission>
  <name>I Am Human.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6130</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">397</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/c7/f4/dN/UZ/Og/a1/5ZKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
