<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis is a progressive neurodegenerative disease that attacks nerve cells in the brain and spinal cord resulting in muscle weakness and atrophy.

Motor neurons reach from the brain to the spinal cord and from the spinal cord to the muscles throughout the body. The progressive degeneration of the motor neurons in ALS eventually lead to their death. When the motor neurons die, the ability of the brain to initiate and control muscle movement is lost. With voluntary muscle action progressively affected, patients in the later stages of the disease may become totally paralyzed.

A-myo-trophic comes from the Greek language. "A" means no or negative. "Myo" refers to muscle, and "Trophic" means nourishment---"No muscle nourishment." When a muscle has no nourishment, it "atrophies" or wastes away. "Lateral" identifies the areas in a person's spinal cord where portions of the nerve cells that signal and control the muscles are located. As this area degenerates it leads to scarring or hardening ("sclerosis") in the region.

As motor neurons degenerate, they can no longer send impulses to the muscle fibers that normally result in muscle movement. Early symptoms of ALS often include increasing muscle weakness, especially involving the arms and legs, speech, swallowing or breathing. When muscles no longer receive the messages from the motor neurons that they require to function, the muscles begin to atrophy (become smaller). Limbs begin to look "thinner" as muscle tissue atrophies.

1. To empower people with ALS and provide hope to those who are fighting the disease.

2. Every 90 minutes an American dies of ALS.

3. To show our strength and give scientists a reason to push forward for a cure to this dehibilitating disease.</description>
  <mission>is to lead the fight to cure and treat ALS.</mission>
  <name>ALS-Lou Gehrig's Disease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6145</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2903</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2076.13</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4i/Bt/Yz/z2/uV/d2/fGdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
