<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Exopolitics Institute is a 501 (c) (3) non-profit educational organization dedicated to studying the key actors, institutions and political processes associated with credible evidence that extraterrestrial civilizations are visiting, monitoring or residing on Earth. The Institute supports the study and dissemination of information and technologies from 'whistleblowers' or 'private citizens' who claim to have physically interacted with extraterrestrials, or had access to covert military-corporate programs involving extraterrestrial technologies. The Institute promotes 'citizen diplomacy initiatives' for peaceful communications and interactions with extraterrestrial civilizations that evidence suggests are interacting with or monitoring humanity. The Institute seeks to prepare humanity for interacting with extraterrestrial civilizations whose existence is supported by credible evidence, and supports full public disclosure by government authorities of all evidence concerning the extraterrestrial presence. The Institute supports the vision of an interconnected global human society that interacts with extraterrestrial civilizations in a peaceful, harmonious and mutually respectful manner. 

For more information about the Exopolitics Institute, visit URL http://www.exopoliticsinstitute.org

1. There should be research into the key actors, institutions and processes associated with evidence of an extraterrestrial presence.

2. There should be peaceful cooperation with extraterrestrials that evidence suggests are aligned with the advancement of global peace, human empowerment, and human sovereignty.

3. There should be full public disclosure through an accelerated release of all evidence concerning an extraterrestrial presence in terms of history, agreements, technologies and activities.</description>
  <mission>support and promote the Exopolitics Institute</mission>
  <name>Exopolitics Institute Support</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6146</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/z4/XK/Do/dM/tg/uT/SV1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
