<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>2007 Theme: Better Schools. Better Retention Rates. Decreased Child Labor.

To commemorate Work an Hour's tenth year of unique fundraising, Asha for Education is highlighting projects that focus on decreasing child labor in India through increasing school retention rates and decreasing drop-out rates. Child labor has reached epidemic numbers in India with statistics varying from 12 million to over 40 million child laborers in the country. According to UNICEF, India has the world's largest number of child laborers under the age of 14. Along with Asha for Education, major international organizations, such as UNICEF, ILO and the World Bank, have recognized that part of the solution to combating child labor around the world lies in strengthening school retention rates.

&lt;b&gt;Read more at www.workanhour.com&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;a href="http://www.workanhour.com/donate.php"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Donate through the website here.&lt;/a&gt;
100% of your donation will go towards the education of the children (minus the credit card transaction fee).&lt;/b&gt; Donations through facebook are subject to a 4.5% transaction fee while the Work an Hour website is only about 3%.

1. 246 million children around the world are child laborers. (ILO)

2. The largest number of working children - 127 million - age 14 and under are in the Asia-Pacific region. (ILO)

3. 73 million working children are less than 10 years old. (ILO)

4. Every year, 22,000 children die in work related accidents. (ILO)

5. An estimated 14% of the child population in India between the ages of 5-14 years of age participates in child labor. (UNICEF)

6. Only 59% of India's male children enroll in secondary school and not even half - 47% - of India's female children enroll in secondary school. (UNICEF)

7. India's children cost cheaper than buffalos. While buffaloes may cost up to 15,000 rupees ($350), children are sold at prices between 500 and 2,000 rupees ($12 and $45). (Save the Childhood Movement, India)

8. 47 out of 100 children in India enrolled in class I reach class VIII, putting the dropout rate at 52.79%. (Sarva Shiksha Abhiyana, Indian government's Educational For All Movement)

9. One-third of the population or nearly 300 million people in the age group 7 years and above are still illiterate in India. (UNICEF)

10. Approximately 16.64% of villages in the country do not have facilities for primary schooling. (UNICEF)

11. 42 million children in the age-group 6-14 years do not attend school in India. (UNICEF)</description>
  <mission>Raise $200,000 for 12 existing schools in India to enable children to go from work to school. We ask for only an hour's worth of your pay towards this program.</mission>
  <name>Work an Hour 2007 (Asha for Education)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6152</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">27</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ce/hx/8T/lQ/lG/jt/8PrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
