<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Democrats can't protect America's power 
Republicans can't protect Americans' rights
------------------------------------------
I am creating a new political party called the Patriot's Party.  
------------------------------------------
It will be conservative when dealing with foreign affairs; it is important to appear strong-willed when dealing with other countries and terrorists.
------------------------------------------
It will be liberal in its domestic policies; individuals must create their own sense of morality, assuming it does not harm others.
------------------------------------------
Most people feel obligated to agree with one side and only one side of politics.  However, many times, people's views dissent from those of their party's on particular issues, often leading to a lack of interest in politics because neither side can satisfy.
------------------------------------------
My party will take into account the social needs of all people of America, AND will be sure to fight back against terrorism when necessary.
------------------------------------------
http://berkeley.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2395548871

1. Social conflicts such as gay marriage and abortion will be left up to every individual's own sense of morality

2. America will not appear weak in the eyes of terrorists.  Terrorists will not take advantage of us.

3. The main goal of this party concerning the economy will be to pull ourselves out of the enormous debt that has built up over the years and to be less depedent on other countries. </description>
  <mission>To spread the idea of a new political party - telling people about it! Get the message out there!!

Invite people to join this cause!</mission>
  <name>New Political Party: The Patriot's Party</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6153</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">43</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8t/TV/ra/2r/Z6/MV/SC4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
