<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;The amazing Skepticality Moderator, Dr. Mabuse, finally has a chance to contribute to the skeptical happenings at Dragon*Con 2007! And he needs your help! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
http://www.skepticality.com/p_sponsorsupport.htm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Historically, it is through the generosity of skeptics that people have gone to conventions like TAM and Skeptics Society conventions in the past. Continuing that tradition, we'd like to get more exposure for skeptics at Dragon*Con 2007 - a convention that is not only MASSIVELY POPULAR but will support getting the message out to fellow Science, Fantasy and Gaming communities out there! 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help with this - we need Dr Mabuse! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The moderator Dr Mabuse is resident in Sweden and due to the flight costs is looking for support - he's done the background work, so he is 'cleared' to come to the States and join us... just needs to re-coup some cash to make the journey. There he will work (in person!) and finally meet some of the folks who come here all the time - and to meet the Skepticality presenters Derek, Swoopy and the Skeptic.com crew too! 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
ANY SMALL AMOUNT (or large, let's face it) will be appreciated. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
DONATE HERE!  http://www.skepticality.com/p_sponsorsupport.htm
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also on the Skepticality.com 'donate' page there is a button to help bring Dr. Mab to the con; Skepticality would love to see you there too and would appreciate any support!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
http://www.skepticality.com/p_sponsorsupport.htm
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
You may also like to support Skeptic Society, which is the Non-Profit group who support Skepticality. 
However, it is through the links above that you will be able to donate specifically to get Dr Mabuse to the convention. Thank you!


1. That Skepticality Rocks - Help Them Get The Skeptic Word Out at Dragon*Con!

2. That Dr Mabuse is a Vital Part of Said Rocking

3. Derek and Swoopy Appreciates Your Support!</description>
  <mission>Get the Mod with a Mission to the Convention Sensation of 2007!</mission>
  <name>Skepticality Mod to Dragon*Con 2007</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6160</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/H0/cm/OW/rM/aZ/WE/jb3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
