<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Marijuana, common name for a drug made from the dried leaves and flowering tops of the Indian hemp plant Cannabis sativa. People smoke, chew, or eat marijuana for its hallucinogenic and intoxicating effects. It is known by a number of slang names, including &#8220;pot,&#8221; &#8220;grass,&#8221; &#8220;reefer,&#8221; &#8220;weed,&#8221; and &#8220;Mary Jane.&#8221;

The flowering tops of the Cannabis plant secrete a sticky resin that contains the active ingredient of marijuana, known as delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol (THC). The plant has both male and female forms, and the sticky flowers of the female plant are the most potent. Hashish is a similar drug prepared from the same plant. It differs from marijuana in that it is comprised of only the resin from the plant, whereas marijuana is made up of flowering tops and leaves.

Known in India, Central Asia, and China as early as 3000 bc, marijuana has long been used as both a medicine and an intoxicant. It gained widespread use in the United States in the 1960s and 1970s, becoming the second most popular drug after alcohol. In subsequent decades its use continued to increase, particularly among American teens. According to a survey prepared in 1998 by the United States Drug Enforcement Agency, marijuana use among teenagers increased almost 300 percent from 1992 to 1998.

Most countries consider marijuana an illegal substance, but individual countries vary on how they prosecute the use and possession of marijuana. Some countries only impose small fines, while others impose harsher punishment, including imprisonment.



1. No death was ever recorded!!!!

2. THC (tetrahydrocannabinol) which is found in Marijuana can be used for medical purposes.

3. Some might disagree, but simply just for recreational purposes...lol</description>
  <mission>To Spread this knowledge to all of my fellow herbalist. </mission>
  <name>Project Legalize Ganja</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6169</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">104</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Bl/bu/AV/oD/JF/m7/gcNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
