<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> Home School Legal Defense Association is a nonprofit advocacy organization established to defend and advance the constitutional right of parents to direct the education of their children and to protect family freedoms. Through annual memberships, HSLDA is tens of thousands of families united in service together, providing a strong voice when and where needed.

HSLDA advocates on the legal front by fully representing member families at every stage of proceedings. Each year, thousands of member families receive legal consultation by letter and phone, hundreds more are represented through negotiations with local officials, and dozens are represented in court proceedings. HSLDA also takes the offensive, filing actions to protect members against government intrusion and to establish legal precedent. On occasion, HSLDA will handle precedent-setting cases for nonmembers, as well.

HSLDA advocates on Capitol Hill by tracking federal legislation that affects homeschooling and parental rights. 

HSLDA advocates in the media by presenting articulate and knowledgeable spokesmen to the press on the subject of homeschooling. 

HSLDA advocates for the movement by commissioning and presenting quality research on the progress of homeschooling. Whether it&#8217;s in print, from the podium, or on the air, HSLDA provides insightful vision and leadership for the cause of homeschooling.

Home School Legal Defense Association . . . tens of thousands of American families working through more than 50 dedicated staff members to preserve each other&#8217;s right to homeschool . . . together, &#8220;Advocates for Family &amp; Freedom.&#8221;



1. They denfend the constitutional right of homeschooling and the rights of homeschoolers in court.

2. They legally advocate on issues that affect homeschooling and christian families.

3. They keep homeschooling in the view of the nation, advocating and advancing homeschoolers and christians.  </description>
  <mission>Advocates for Family and Freedom</mission>
  <name>Home School Legal Defense Association</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6176</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1838</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8F/y4/3o/C0/ID/HK/ES3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
