<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There's no doubt that these days everybody is into something for something in life, that could be, the want for money, for power, for pride etcetc.
And having and working for it is totally perfect.
But people shouldn't get so much into it that they forget who they r, how they wanted life to be, what there dreams were when they were very young, the way they laughed with there heart out at anything and everything without thinking abut people around or the way one has to behave in a place... 

Dont live on how people tell you too, or how may they feel about you.. Live it how you want too.

Just for once do things with ur heart than ur brains, and trust me life would be so beautifull....

And if you Love someone dont love her and expect that he or she will love you too but love him/ her to that extent that she/he falls in love with youu....

But never stop falling in love till you get someone who loves you more than you could ever love thamm.. 

So just be happy and smile with all your heart and try to make others smile with you.. And the more you spread happiness accorss the more it will come back to you. 

And trust me Life would feel so worthwhile...



1. For a truely happpy life...

2. For the true happiness which no money can buy...

3. To never loose hope in love...Cauz love is painful but really beautiful. And there would surely come a time when u get the one whoz made for you.. So keep on tryng &amp; keep on smilin</description>
  <mission>To make people realise to live there life's the way they always wanted to or they dreamt off &amp; not cauz of any materalistic reasons or cauz of any pressures.</mission>
  <name>Smiling with your heart out</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6190</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">78</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/M7/ee/23/qt/y6/YD/2x0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
