<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>     Mother Teresa and the missionaries of Charity were no strangers to poverty. Since 1950, when the religious order was first founded by Mother Teresa, the nuns reached out to refugees, sick and abandoned children, ex-prostitutes, AIDS victims, and those suffering from natural disasters and poverty around the world. 

     However, Mother Teresa found more poverty in the United States than one could imagine: abortion. "It is a poverty to decide that a child must die so that you may live as you wish," the saint said among one of her visits to our beloved country. "Any country that accepts abortion, is not teaching its people to love, but to use any violence to get what it wants."

      When facing the difficulties of an unwanted pregnancy, many women underestimate the power of adoption. Abortion is not the answer. Mother Teresa never turned a child away no matter how crowded her shelters were.  "Please don't kill the child", Mother Teresa would plead when facing the issue of abortion, " I want the child. Please give me the child. I am willing to accept any child who would be aborted, and to give that child to a married couple who will love the child, and be loved by the child. From our children's home in Calcutta alone, we have saved over 3,000 children from abortions. These children have brought such love and joy to their adopting parents, and have grown up so full of love and joy!"

    What can we do today? Let those you love know that abortion is not the solution to an "inconvenient" pregnancy. She left us with so much to learn.  We can all strive to love and respect life as Mother Teresa did in every day situations. 

     "I feel that the greatest destroyer of peace today is abortion, because it is a war against the child, a direct killing of the innocent child, murder by the mother herself."
    
" Being unwanted, unloved, uncared for, forgotten by everybody, I think that is a much greater hunger, a much greater poverty than the person who has nothing to eat...We must find each other."


    Mother Teresa was recognized and acclaimed throughout the world. Pope John XXIII honored her with the "Peace Prize" in 1971. 



1. To respect and care for each individual's life because each person  is a child of God.

2. To not be afraid to stand up for the life of an innocent child no matter how difficult or unpleasant it may be.

3. To kindly reach out to women facing the difficult decision of an abortion not through stubborn arguments, disrespect, or anger but through LOVE.

4. "And if we can accept that a mother can kill her own child, how can we tell other people not to kill one another?" - Mother Teresa.

5. To support the adoption services in this country, such as the one listed above, in order to ensure that every woman has an option and every child may </description>
  <mission>Spread the loving messages of Blessed Mother Teresa. Abortion is not the answer. And every life is one to be loved and valued :)</mission>
  <name>Pro-Life messages of Mother Teresa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6206</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1431</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Jj/vF/NX/Xr/ae/gC/a8uS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
