<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>My friend, Sameer Bhatia (www.helpsameer.org), has been diagnosed with Acute Myelogenous Leukemia (AML). He is in urgent need of a bone marrow transplant. Sameer, a Silicon Valley 31 year old just got married last year. His diagnosis was confirmed just weeks ago.

Sameer, a Stanford alum, is known to many for his
efforts in launching the American India Foundation,
Project DOSTI, TiE (Chicago), and other causes focused on helping others. Now he needs our help in giving him a new lease on life. He is undergoing chemotherapy but needs a bone marrow transplant to sustain beyond the next few months.

Fortunately, you can help.

Things You Can Do
1. Get registered.
Getting registered is quick and requires a simple
cheek swab (2 minutes) and filling out some forms. Registering and even donating if you&#8217;re ever selected is VERY simple.

Another friend of ours, Vinay, was also diagnosed with AML and requires a transplant. We have joined forces with Team Vinay (www.helpvinay.org) in order to get South Asians registered in the bone marrow registry. Both Sameer and Vinay need a match from another South Asian, however, very few South Asians are actually in the registry. This is why we need your help.

We are supporting Team Vinay in organizing drives
nationwide, and I need you to get registered by
visiting a local drive. Drives are currently taking
place all over the country. Please see the full list of locations here: http://www.helpvinay.org/

2. Spread the word.
Please share this message with at least 10
people (particularly South Asians), and ask them to do the same. Please point your friends to the local
drives and ask them to get registered. If you can,
sponsor a drive at your company or in your community. Drives need to take place in the next 2-3 weeks to be of help to Sameer and Vinay.

Thank you for getting registered to help Sameer and
Vinay win their fight against leukemia &#8211; and for
helping others who may face blood cancers in the
future.

1. Help Find Bone Marrow Matches For Leukemia Patients

2. Increase The Number of Minorities In The National Marrow Donor Program 

3. Increase Awareness About Being A Bone Marrow Donor</description>
  <mission>Raise Awareness and Registrants in the National Marrow Donor Program</mission>
  <name>Helpsameer.org</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6229</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">146</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">150.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/T6/nm/pz/Su/oe/gx/3qQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
