<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The world's current rate of CO2 emissions is likely to hurt our economy and health in the future. These costs are not well-accounted for in the current energy market, for two reasons:

1) Costs are uncertain and long-term.
2) These costs are externalities -- they are borne by people other than the purchaser or seller of polluting energy. 

To take an example: a coal power plant in Colorado produces CO2 emissions, which (we think) contribute to global warming. Warming feeds into problems such as the long-term risk of flooding in coastal Florida. It is very unlikely that this risk is properly factored into the price of coal energy in Colorado, because the Colorado consumer is not the one most directly at risk.

Because of this, the price of carbon-based energy is too low -- it does not really reflect the full cost to society of using such energy. As a corrective measure, we argue for estimating the future social costs of C02 pollution, and then building that cost into the price of carbon-based energy.

There are two popular ways to accomplish this. One is a carbon tax, which directly chooses the price of emitting a ton of C02. Second is a cap-and-trade regime, which chooses a maximum quantity of emissions-- the market then chooses the "price" of emitting a ton of C02.

Both are plausible approaches, but we argue more heavily for a direct carbon tax, because:

1) Cap-and-trade regimes may be more subject to meddling from big energy companies, during the policy-design phase;
2) Cap-and-trade requires a permit system, which is a non-trivial logistical and monetary hurdle;
3) A carbon tax will have a steady, predictable tax rate, whereas a cap-and-trade approach can lead to wildly fluctuating C02 price rates. A stable price rate should help innovation, because it makes the business environment more predictable (and thus more favorable) for alternative-energy entrepreneurs. 

1. The United States must establish a price on carbon emissions.

2. A carbon tax is preferable to cap-and-trade.

3. Carbon price regimes are most effective when created in concert with other countries.</description>
  <mission>Establish a carbon price to reduce C02 pollution and to incentivize the development of alternative energy sources.</mission>
  <name>Carbon Tax</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6240</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">82</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yL/H2/UO/kC/7r/hd/dsqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
