<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Food For The Poor (FFP) ministers to spiritually renew impoverished people throughout Latin America and the Caribbean. Established in 1982 as a 501(c)(3)corporation, our goals are to improve the health, economic, social and spiritual conditions of the men, women and children we serve.

Food For The Poor raises funds and provides direct relief assistance to the poor, usually by purchasing specifically requested materials and distributing them through the churches and charity organizations already operating in areas of need. In this way, the organization serves the poor with dignity and ensures the most appropriate use of donors' funds.

Our ministry reflects God's unconditional love, which surrenders all, inspires trust and faith, and embraces all people regardless of race, status or creed. We believe that Christ is alive, and that we can best serve Him by being of assistance to those in greatest need (Matthew 25:31-46). Finally, we stress the need for regular prayer to guide and maintain the purity of our mission.

Our mission is to link the church of the First World with the church of the Third World in a manner that helps both the materially poor and the poor in spirit. The materially poor are served by local churches, clergy and lay leaders who have been empowered and supplied with goods by Food For The Poor. The poor in spirit are renewed by their relationship with and service to the poor through our direct ministry of teaching, encouragement and prayer. Ultimately, we seek to bring both benefactors and recipients to a closer union with our Lord.

www.foodforthepoor.org

1. Serves the poorest of the poor in 16 countries throughout the Caribbean and Latin America.

2. Not only provides food for the starving, but also builds small houses for the destitute, digs water wells for parched villagers, provides medicine and medical equipment for the sick.

3. Reputable cause.  In 2006, Forbes magazine rated Food For The Poor as having an efficiency level of 96% in charitable commitment and 97% in fundraising efficiency.

4. It is the third-largest international relief organization in the United States, according to the Chronicle of Philanthropy.</description>
  <mission>We provide food, housing, health care, education, water projects, micro-enterprise development assistance and emergency relief to the poorest of the poor.</mission>
  <name>Food for the Poor, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6252</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">726</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2092.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Jj/lF/13/RD/6G/SJ/grkS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
