<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The United Nations Children's Fund (or UNICEF) General Assembly was created on December 11, 1946. In 1953, its name was shortened from United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund, but is still known by the popular acronym based on this old name. Headquartered in New York City, UNICEF provides long-term humanitarian and developmental assistance to children and mothers in developing countries.

partly voluntarily funded agency, UNICEF relies on contributions from governments and private donors. Its programmes emphasize developing community-level services to promote the health and well-being of children. UNICEF was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1965 and Prince of Asturias Award of Concord in 2006. In the United States, Canada and some other countries, UNICEF is known for its "Trick-Or-Treat for UNICEF" program in which children collect money for UNICEF from the houses they trick-or-treat at on Halloween night, sometimes instead of candy.

Following the reaching of term limits by Executive Director of UNICEF Carol Bellamy, former United States Secretary of Agriculture Ann Veneman took control of the organization in May 2005 with an agenda to increase the organization's focus on the Millennium Development Goals. Total income to UNICEF for 2006 was $2,781 million.

The heart of UNICEF's work is in the field, with staff in over 150 countries and territories. More than 120 country offices carry out UNICEF's mission through a unique program of cooperation developed with host governments. Seven regional offices guide their work and provide technical assistance to country offices as needed.

Overall management and administration of the organization takes place at its headquarters in New York. UNICEF's Supply Division is based in Copenhagen and serves as the primary point of distribution for such essential items as lifesaving vaccines, antiretroviral medicines for children and mothers with HIV, nutritional supplements, emergency shelters, educational supplies, and more.

Many people in industrialized countries first hear about UNICEF&#8217;s work through the activities of 37 National Committees for UNICEF. These non-governmental organizations (NGO) are primarily responsible for fundraising, selling UNICEF greeting cards and products, creating private and public partnerships, advocating for children&#8217;s rights, and providing other invaluable support. The U.S. Fund for UNICEF is the oldest of the National Committees, founded in 1947.[7]

UNICEF is supported entirely by voluntary funds. Governments contribute two thirds of the organisation's resources; private groups and some 6 million individuals contribute the rest through the National Committees.

Guiding and monitoring all of UNICEF's work is a 36-member Executive Board which establishes policies, approves programs and oversees administrative and financial plans. The Executive Board is made up of government representatives who are elected by the United Nations Economic and Social Council, usually for three-year terms.




1. Freedom from Discrimination (Article 20)

2. Family (Article 5)

3. Identity (Article 8)

4. Education (Article 28)

5. Protection in War (Article 38)

6. Protection from Neglect (Article 19)

7. Freedom from Discrimination (Article 2)

8. Freedom from Child Labour (Article 32)

9. A Protective Environment  (Articles 3, 9)

10. Self Expression (Article 13)</description>
  <mission>Help poor and needing children around the world</mission>
  <name>Unicef</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6254</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">788</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ah/T1/Jm/Cq/Fj/JH/xXNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
