<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is bullying...!?
We all picture the stereotypical playground story. However, many of us are not aware of the extremes bullying and harassment have taken throughout every age group. 
Bullying is any negative act taken by a person, in belief of their own superiority, over a person of assumed weakness. These acts include, but are not limited to: deliberately leaving someone out, saying hurtful and negative things, spreading rumors, and physical acts. Recently cyberbullying has become more prevalent. Verbal bullying, or harassment, is now easier and faster through email and instant messaging.
NO, this not something we have to go through as a part of growing up! Please, do not listen to these misconceptions! 
Bullying effects its victims for the rest of their lives. It causes a loss of self confidence for starters. Furthermore, after a certain point, victims feel as though everyone is out to get them. Through this mentality they suffer anxiety and/or depression. All these effects ultimately effect the victim's success. 
In the news:
&#8220;You could have been great. I could have been great. Ask yourself what you did to me to have me clean the slate.&#8221; -Seung-hui Cho, Virginia Tech Manifesto
The scottsman.com writes, "The gunman behind the Virginia Tech massacre killed two pupils who had attended his high school - where he was bullied, mocked over his shyness and told to "go back to China".
Cho Seung-Hui was taunted over his race during his time at Westfield High School.
The experience may have contributed to the mental instability, anger and persecution complex revealed in the killer's chilling videos, posted to an American broadcaster while Cho was in the midst of the worst campus shooting in US history" (http://news.scotsman.com/international.cfm?id=608052007). Please help spread your awareness of this problem in today's society. Lets start with today's youth to stop tomorrow's tragedy. 



1. Bullying is not just part of growing up.

2. It effects its victim's self esteem, potential, and ultimate success.

3. It starts with one! Help spread the word and start with today's youth!!</description>
  <mission>A program for increased awareness of bullying/harassment and its effects.</mission>
  <name>"It Starts with One"</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6257</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">98</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GU/uP/dX/pR/xX/hJ/LXpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
