<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>(Taken From the "SAVE RANDHURST" Group, all credits go to Andrew Hoefert.)

(At this time please do not donate anything, I know many of you will not have tried regardless. This is 100% Donation free, But we are still trying to get what we can get done.)


This is a group for people who are trying to salvage one of the oldest standing "Tourist Attractions" in Mount Prospect. Randhurst used to be a rip roarin' place but now the only people you can find there are Asians, elderly people getting their exercise, and yes...the elite group of mallrats trying to save one of their favorite places to waste time. If you ever bought a plate of delishously unauthentic Chinese food from Wing Pei at Chi Gi or ever convinced the lady at Boardwalk Fries (may it rest in peace) to give you free cheese on your seasoned fries then this is a group for you. If you ever spent the better part of an hour looking through all of the crap at Hot Rags (where did that place move by the by?) then this is a group for you. If you like making fun of the toolish security guards who like to check themselves out in shop window reflections, then yes...this is a group for you. If you've ever taken a picture with the cardboard cutout of the large bald black man outside of vitamin world and/or discussed the health benefit of protein supplements with one of its many fine employees then this is indeed a group for you. Please act before its too late!

Feel free to share your opinion and/or tell your favorite Randhurst memory below.

At the time of its opening, it was the first enclosed regional mall in the Chicago area and the largest enclosed air-conditioned space in the United States. Just in case you were wondering.

BAD MOUTHING RANDHURST OR ANY NEGATIVE COMMENTS WILL NOT BE TOLERATED!


1. We Must Save Randhurst

2. We Must Bring New Business

3. We Must Re-Ignite The Flare of Randhurst</description>
  <mission>Save the wonderful mall we all know and love, Randhurst Shopping Center</mission>
  <name>Save Randhusrt</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6261</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4n/rl/yE/DB/gK/nL/izOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
