<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Macular Degeneration, leading cause of irreversible vision loss in the United States. This incurable condition attacks the central portion of the retina, the part of the eye that receives light patterns and transmits them to the brain. Macular degeneration progressively damages or destroys the part of vision used for reading and seeing fine details, while leaving the peripheral vision generally unaffected. People who have this disorder develop an area of vision loss that increases in diameter until they are unable to read or even see groups of two to three words at normal reading distance. Macular degeneration usually develops in both eyes, with one eye generally more affected than the other.

Although children can develop forms of macular degeneration such as Stargardt's disease, 99 percent of the cases occur in older people. Age-related macular degeneration (AMD) may affect as many as 15 million Americans over the age of 50, and one-fifth of people over 75 show at least some symptoms.

AMD targets the most sensitive part of the retina, a cluster of cells called the macula located directly in its center. There are two forms of AMD, dry AMD and wet AMD. In the dry form, which accounts for about 90 percent of AMD cases, the macular cells slowly waste away, causing gradual vision loss. In most cases this vision loss progresses no further than permanent blurring of the central field of vision. In the wet form, abnormal growth of blood vessels beneath the macula causes bleeding and scarring. The result is severe damage to the macula that may completely destroy the patient&#8217;s central vision.

No treatment is available for most cases of macular degeneration.

1. We all deserve the rights to sight.</description>
  <mission>Promote awareness for this disease, and hopefully promote the research to find it's cure.</mission>
  <name>Macular degeneration. Help find a cure.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6272</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1619</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">450.44</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/63/Pk/cI/yh/xa/VY/nyCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
