<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The James Randi Educational Foundation (or JREF) is a not-for-profit organization that was founded by in 1996 by magician and skeptic James Randi. 

JREF's goals include:

* creating a new generation of critical thinkers via lively classroom demonstrations and by reaching out through scholarships and awards;

* demonstrating to the public and the media (through some very cool educational seminars) the consequences of accepting paranormal claims at face value, and without question them;

* supporting and conducting research into paranormal claims through well-designed experiments that utilize "the scientific method", and by publishing these findings their newsletter and other periodicals;

* providing trustworthy information about the paranormal and pseudoscientific claims by operating an expansive library of books, videos, journals, and archival resources that is open to the public;

* assisting those who are attacked as a result of their investigations into the paranormal, by maintaining a legal defense fund that is available to assist these individuals;

* and to raise public awareness of these issues by offering a $1,000,000 prize to anyone who can demonstrate any psychic, supernatural or paranormal ability of any kind under mutually agreed upon scientific conditions. 

JREF is located in Fort Lauderdale, Florida, and is funded through member contributions, grants, sales of books and videos, seminars, and conferences.

You can find more info at: http://www.randi.org/

1. Keep up the fight against superstition in the world today.

2. Promote critical thinking about the supernatural and paranormal.

3. Provide scholarships to students who show promise in spreading critical thinking in their chose fields.

4. Challenge those who would deceive the public for profit or political gain.

5. Organize international meetings that bring the critical thinking community together.

6. Maintain vigilance over media organizations that will sacrifice the truth for higher ratings.</description>
  <mission>promotes critical thinking by reaching out to the public and media with reliable information about the paranormal and supernatural.</mission>
  <name>The James Randi Educational Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6275</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3209</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1384.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ku/V3/Qp/sx/wh/l7/Mm4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
