<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Mike Gravel is a real guy. 
He doesn't have a lot of money to campaign, 
only debts to maintain. 

The thing about him though, is, 
he's been around. He knows his shit. 
He's got real wisdom, and real compassion. 
His past shows he follows through with what matters to him. He's influenced a lot of powerful people to change their minds and made ideas &amp; filibusters go through &amp; actually have an affect. He sticks to his guns, he doesn't care if you don't agree. He's going to be real. He isn't going to hide an opinion because it doesn't add up to you, even though he's got his reasons, that people neglect to inquire about. He's smart -- A lot smarter than these people who pay people to tell them what to say. His weight is at 0 to 1 percent in the polls, and this is because people don't know about him. Tell people! Enlighten them! A cause is for an effect, change the standings, call up the democrats! Mike knows what's good, but most people won't even give him a word in edgewise on the news because he's so damn broke and they think it's pointless. Have a little faith! We could at least pull him up a little he deserves it! He's thought things through. He's seen it. He's been a part of it. His wisdom comes with experience. He's blunt, and a lot of people don't like that because they don't want to hear what they don't want to realize, but if you think over his stances openly, he says what he says for good reason. It's rare you come across something real in politics today. Even if you think Hilary or Obama or whoever is real, they're doing it to get elected, and yeah, that's smart for them -- but be smarter than them. The things they say are unrealistic and too perfect. There's got to be a flaw there, because there is no such thing as perfection. 

It's still early. There's still time for change. Invite your friends. Let 'em know. 

He's also terribly witty. &amp;hearts; 

Core beliefs - Cite: ontheissues.org</description>
  <mission>Increase awareness of Mike! Put sincerity, wisdom &amp; compassion in office.</mission>
  <name>Support for Mike Gravel</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6276</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">100</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/rq/nq/0H/Lh/Kh/yh/tigS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
