<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Horses   Healing   Hope

Every day, there are so many children of our community are struggling in ways that most of us could barely comprehend. During this time of intense emotional turmoil, they need love, support, and a sense of safety and belonging and somewhere to have some fun and feel joy and peace again.

Fidelis Foundation has the opportunity to offer HOPE, HEALING, and SANCTUARY to children with our equine-assisted programs. 
The Fidelis Foundation partners with local agencies and provides time with our foundation horses and trainers to teach children personal responsibility, trust, confidence, courage and leadership. Our barn provides a fun environment where they can feel safe, play and enjoy being outdoors. This positive, loving environment promotes healing and a healthy outlook for the future.

We&#8217;re so thankful for how the foundation has grown, and with this growth comes an increased opportunity to help the children by having weekly riding opportunities as well as exciting events for the children and their families.


How You Can Help
Without our generous contributors, our foundation could not provide the support to our community&#8217;s children. If it is in your heart to volunteer or donate to our organization, there are many ways you can help, whether it be through donations to support our horses and programs, volunteering your time or simply helping us spread the word. 

Please call or email if you would like to find out more information about how you can contribute.

Sunshine Meadows Equestrian Village 
16668 Winners Circle, Barn 8  
Delray Beach, FL 33446 
Phone: 561-860-4567 
info@fidelisfoundation.com
www.fidelisfoundation.com




1. Fidelis Foundation provides equine programs to children in need.</description>
  <mission>We provide equine assisted programs and events to our community's children in need.</mission>
  <name>The Fidelis Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6279</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">536</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45.01</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fB/Uo/lO/Xx/Iv/VB/g6/h6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
