<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>PICTURE:  Thousands of people march in the streets...
BILBAO, SPAIN: Thousands of people march in the streets of Bilbao, northern Spain, 31 January 2004, during a demonstration organized by pro-peace Basque group "Gesto por la Paz" (A gesture for Peace). Banner reads "Peace and Freedom" in Basque and "Pluralism and Convivence" in Spanish. AFP PHOTO / RAFA RIVAS (Photo credit should read RAFA RIVAS/AFP/Getty Images)

Main Entry:
    plu&#183;ral&#183;ism 
    \&#712;plu&#775;r-&#601;-&#716;li-z&#601;m\ 
Function:
    noun 
Date:
    1818

1: the holding of two or more offices or positions (as benefices) at the same time2: the quality or state of being plural3 a: a theory that there are more than one or more than two kinds of ultimate reality b: a theory that reality is composed of a plurality of entities4 a: a state of society in which members of diverse ethnic, racial, religious, or social groups maintain an autonomous participation in and development of their traditional culture or special interest within the confines of a common civilization b: a concept, doctrine, or policy advocating this state
(merriamwebster.com) 


plu&#183;ral&#183;ism:
   a. 1. The condition of being multiple or plural.
   b. 1. A condition in which numerous distinct ethnic, religious, or cultural groups are present and tolerated within a society.
      2. The belief that such a condition is desirable or socially beneficial.
      3. Ecclesiastical. The holding by one person of two or more positions or offices, especially two or more ecclesiastical benefices, at the same time.
    c. Philosophy.
         1. The doctrine that reality is composed of many ultimate substances.
         2. The belief that no single explanatory system or view of reality can account for all the phenomena of life.
(answers.com) 

check this out for more information: http://www.socialstudieshelp.com/APGOV_pluralism.htm

Pluralism is used, often in different ways, across a wide range of topics:
(wikipedia.com)


1. INCORPORATE 

2. WHAT PEOPLE

3. GIVE YOU. </description>
  <mission>DESTROY IGNORANCE with AWARENESS, WISDOM &amp; RESOURCES. 

ask questions &amp; open debates. </mission>
  <name>PLURALISM &#9829; </name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6285</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/f1/uW/lQ/oS/0A/bT/CLhS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
