<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This Facebook cause supports Susan G. Komen for the Cure&#174;. Bank of America is a proud supporter of Susan G. Komen for the Cure&#174; and is a National Series Sponsor of the Susan G. Komen Race for the Cure&#174; Series and the Breast Cancer 3-Day&#174;. Bank of America also provides additional support to Komen with co-branded credit cards, debit cards and checking accounts, encouraging customers to Make Every Purchase Pink&#174;: When you go shopping, buy groceries or make other eligible purchases, Bank of America contributes to Susan G. Komen for the Cure&#174; at no additional cost to you. Learn more at www.bankofamerica.com/KomenCauses

A specialty account set-up fee may apply to Pink Ribbon Banking deposit accounts opened in Banking Centers and over the phone in some states. Other accounts and services, and the fees that apply to them, vary from state to state.  Please review the information for your state in the Personal Schedule of Fees (at www.bankofamerica.com/feesataglance or at your local Banking Center) and in the Online Banking Service Agreement at www.bankofamerica.com/serviceagreement.

Bank of America, N.A. Member FDIC &#169;2010 Bank of America Corporation

1. We are local activists in 125 cities and communities, mobilizing more than one million friends and neighbors every year through events like the Komen 

2. We are advocates at the local, state and federal level, fighting for the screening and treatment programs that save lives and the research that brings

3. We are global citizens working with local health groups around the world and through our web site, komen.org, to help millions of women in nearly 200 </description>
  <mission>To save lives and end breast cancer forever by empowering people, ensuring quality care for all and energizing science to find cures. </mission>
  <name>Susan G. Komen for the Cure&#174;</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/629</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">969688</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">201348.18</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zH/Y8/N1/GO/gz/iD/S3/4wS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
