<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Ann Coutler is an American conservative columnist and political commentator. She is also a best-selling author of five books.
    Ann Coulter, in "Godless", referred to the 9/11 widows as "harpies" ,"I've never seen people enjoying their husbands' deaths so much"
   "These broads are millionaires, lionized on TV and in articles about them, reveling in their status as celebrities and stalked by grief-arazzis." 
    Coulter also made a reference to Timothy McVeigh regarding regarding The New York Times, who she has had long-running animosity toward. 
    "Is your tape recorder running? Turn it on! I got something to say...'My only regret with Timothy McVeigh is he did not go to the New York Times Building."
    In an interview with Bob McKeown, for CBC television's "The Fifth Estate", an investigative journalism program, Ann goes to say, 
    "Canada used to be...one of our most...most loyal friends, and vice versa. I mean, Canada sent troops to Vietnam. Was Vietnam less containable and more of a threat than Saddam Hussein?"
    This, along with countless other inaccurate, and often hateful, statements throughout her political commentary career, just proves her illegitimacy in anything and everything she forces herself into. She is nothing more than an obnoxious, hateful, and unprofessional women who as nothing to say that holds any insight or legitimate viewpoints  about what she criticizes or comments on. She merely makes insulting, hateful, and inaccurate statements about big issues that she knows nothing about, just to get her face on the news, get publicity, and make money. 

1. She makes hateful, inaccurate, and obnoxious comments to get on tv.

2. she avoids and dodges questions that may contradict her statements.

3. she is hypocritical and unprofessional </description>
  <mission>Show your dislike and distrust for this obnoxious, conservative "harpy".</mission>
  <name>Against Ann Coulter!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6297</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">102</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/S7/eB/gG/HV/mF/Ub/CwoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
