<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Who are we?
We are a diverse group of individuals, faith communities, human rights advocates, and grassroots organizers.
	
What do we do?
We are engaged in direct and symbolic action to save lives, advocate for immigration policy reform, and raise public awareness about the present-day crisis of migrant deaths in the deserts of the Southwest. 

How do we do this?
Some of our efforts include:
&#8226;Staffing desert camps which provide direct humanitarian assistance to migrants through search &amp; rescue patrols
&#8226;Staffing medical clinics in Northern Mexico to respond to the urgent needs of newly deported migrants
&#8226;Monitoring the current enforcement of the US Immigration Policy by the Border Patrol
&#8226;Documenting human rights abuses against migrants
&#8226;Creating a bi-national network of migrant service providers
&#8226;Engaging in local outreach to raise awareness &amp; gain support for our work
&#8226;Organizing opportunities for individuals to experience first-hand the reality of migrants&#8217; struggles 
&#8226;Encouraging local &amp; national media to address these issues
&#8226;Creating faith-based principles for immigration reform &amp; seeking endorsements of these principles 
&#8226;Collaborating with partner organizations to build solidarity &amp; increase volunteer involvement

Why do we do this?
The current border enforcement strategy is a failed policy. Since 1998 more than 4200 migrants - men, women, and children - have lost their lives in the deserts of the US-Mexico borderlands trying to make their way into the United States. The border blockade strategy that has militarized the U.S-Mexico border drives migrants into remote desert regions and fails to stem the flow of immigration to the United States. We recognize the right of a nation to control its borders, but the enforcement measures must be applied proportionately, humanely, and with a conscience to protect the people and the land. No More Deaths refuses to accept that the deaths of men, women, and children along the border are inevitable.


1. The current border enforcement policy is fundamentally flawed.  Over 4200 people have died as a direct result.

2. We have a moral imperative to help our brothers and sisters, no matter who they are.

3. The root causes of migration lie in environmental, economic, and trade inequities.

4. We will act under the principles of civil initiative.  Our work is nonviolent, truthful, all-embracing, dialogical, germane, volunteer-based, and community-centered.

5. The deaths in the desert must end.</description>
  <mission>End the deaths of migrants crossing the Sonoran Desert.</mission>
  <name>No More Deaths</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6298</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1732</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2670.03</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/OS/NZ/H3/Qv/hO/7U/QU7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
