<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This organization is for anyone who has been in any way affected by the disease of cholangiocarcinoma.  Cancer of the bile ducts is treatable, but this cancer quickly metastasizes and destroys vital organs of the body, especially the liver.  It can spread to various places, such as the abdomen, pancreas, and lymph nodes.  Researches have worked hard to create treatments such as Photofrin, laser treatment to the affected regions of the biliary tract.  The cancer is fast acting, and if not caught nearly immediately, the affected victim has a near definite mortality rate.  It is time to act and time to raise awareness.  If you have a friend or family member who has this terribly fatal disease, join my cause.  If you have a friend or family member who has lost anyone to this terribly fatal disease, join my cause.  We have to start somewhere, and the time is now.  

For more information on the disease, view the wikipedia file.  It is very informative.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cholangiocarcinoma

I would like to encourage anyone with this disease or anyone involved in the battle to seek hope through the University of Virginia's Cancer Center.  They have performed miracles for my family and they can for yours also. 

Also, I strongly encourage everyone to tell their stories.  I want people to tell their stories and we can all relate to each other.  Through many, one can find hope.  This is also a place to cope, share, and find hope in a very dismal setting regarding an ill-fated disease.  

Thank you.

1. Research for cholangiocarcinoma must be funded!

2. We will do whatever it takes to fight this disease.

3. Visit www.cholangiocarcinoma.org for more information.</description>
  <mission>To raise awareness about bile duct cancer and find a way to save lives.</mission>
  <name>Cholangiocarcinoma: Research and Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6302</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">708</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">285.02</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yj/Ad/GI/5p/WO/7K/aS0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
