<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Outright Vermont (ORVT) is one of the longest standing queer organizations in Vermont and the only one that works specifically with young people. By striving to empower queer youth, model positive cross-generational learning and leadership, and to address lateral oppressions including racism, classism, heterosexism, ORVT is building a safer, healthier, and more supportive world for all young people. 

Founded in 1989 by local gay and lesbian activists, ORVT helped to create visibility, support, and advocacy throughout the 90s for the queer youth community in Vermont. Our work has now expanded to encompass Education and Outreach, Health and Wellness, Direct Services, and Social Justice Organizing. 

We envision a world of compassion, love, and understanding where:

*all young people's lives are celebrated; 
*young queer people are given the information and tools to make healthy life decisions, especially concerning intimacy and sexual relationships; 
*bullying, taunting, harassment, and other forms of oppression are not tolerated; and 
nonconforming gender roles and sexuality are no longer targeted as justifications to be cruel, dominate, or control others. 


Our programs, groups, and services (unless otherwise stated) are for young LGBTQ (or queer) people, ages 22 and under. Our office, staff, and resources are available to queers and their allies of all ages. During business hours this space is a working office. (While staff are always accessible, they may not always be available. Please ask for time, instead of assuming time.)


1. Everyone deserves to live free from bullying and harassment

2. Nonconforming gender roles and sexualities deserve to be celebrated rather than ridiculed</description>
  <mission>build safe, healthy, and supportive environments for gay, lesbian, bisexual, transgender, queer, and questioning youth.</mission>
  <name>Outright Vermont</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6318</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">214</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">318.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/BP/MN/tz/tY/Co/OB/LYTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
