<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Help to change the world - one magazine at a time... MagazineLiteracy.org is the first and only global, magazine industry-wide campaign to help kids and families learn to read and to build their self-esteem.

Learning how to read is vital to a child's ability to succeed in every school subject and in life. MagazineLiteracy.org mobilizes business and community literacy partnerships that provide wonderful magazines to schools, shelters, and other reading programs. Your support unleashes the awesome potential of magazines as a powerful literacy resource for teachers and other literacy agents who are passionate about helping kids and families learn to read.

Learn more at: http://magazineliteracy.org/

If your eyes light up when your magazine arrives in the mail or when you see your favorite magazines on a newsstand, then you know the joy of a child or family that receives their very own magazine.

There are many easy and powerful ways to support MagazineLiteracy.org and to help kids and families learn to read and succeed. Visit our web site to learn more about the following:

* Publishers, Editors, Circulation Directors - visit or website partners page to learn about mission critical, win-win stakeholder collaboration.

* Media advertisers - spotlight yours and ours via cause relating marketing campaigns for child and family literacy.

* Individuals, businesses, organizations, and schools - Support community literacy programs that need your help or find others in your community.

* Donate funds. 100% of local sponsor donations are used to provide direct help to the kids and families in community literacy programs.

* Volunteer to help. Wonderful people who volunteer are the lifeblood of our mission. We need your help to reach more children.

1. A child unable to read is a child lost.

2. Adults unable to read were once children who did not learn how.

3. Learning how to read is vital to success in every school subject and in life. </description>
  <mission>Feed kids &amp; families hungry to read &amp; succeed by getting wonderful magazines into the hands, homes, and hearts of those who want to learn and love to read.  Change the world - one magazine at a time!</mission>
  <name>Magazine Publishers Family Literacy Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/632</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">82</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">75.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/e0/3T/Bb/3z/1n/S6/sRES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
