<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF)  works on cutting-edge issues defending free speech, privacy, innovation, and consumer rights today. From the beginning, EFF has championed the public interest in every critical battle affecting digital rights.

Blending the expertise of lawyers, policy analysts, activists, and technologists, EFF achieves significant victories on behalf of consumers and the general public. EFF fights for freedom primarily in the courts, bringing and defending lawsuits even when that means taking on the US government or large corporations. By mobilizing more than 50,000 concerned citizens through our Action Center, EFF beats back bad legislation. In addition to advising policymakers, EFF educates the press and public. Sometimes just defending technologies isn't enough, so EFF also supports the development of freedom-enhancing inventions.

EFF is a donor-funded nonprofit and depends on your support to continue successfully defending your digital rights. Litigation is particularly expensive; because two-thirds of our budget comes from individual donors, every contribution is critical to helping EFF fight &#8212;and win&#8212;more cases.

www.eff.org

PS: If you live in Norway, check out Electronic Frontier Norway, www.efn.no .

1. Everybody has the right to free speech and privacy.

2. If you buy something, you own it. You should have the same rights when you buy a digital file as when you buy a CD, DVD or book.

3. Culture should be free (not necessarily gratis), and available to all.

4. Innovators have the right to invent new technologies, and people have the right to buy and use them.

5. When culture goes digital, civil rights and consumer rights must do so too.</description>
  <mission>Support the EFF's Work to Defend Your Digital Rights</mission>
  <name>EFF: In Defense of Your Digital Rights</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6327</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">274</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/TW/YW/cK/f2/I4/ex/lnwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
