<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Built in 1926 as one of America's most elaborate "movie palaces", the Tampa Theatre today is a fiercely protected and generously supported landmark. Designed by famed theatre architect John Eberson, the Theatre is a superior example of the "atmospheric" style of theatre design. Inside the Theatre, audiences are transported to a lavish, romantic Mediterranean courtyard replete with old world statuary, flowers, and gargoyles. Over it all is a nighttime sky replete with twinkling stars and floating clouds.

For several decades, the Tampa Theatre remained a jewel and the centerpiece of Tampa 's cultural landscape. People grew up, stole their first kisses in the balcony, followed the weekly newsreels, and celebrated life week after week by coming back to the Theatre.

But by the 1960's and 70's, times had changed. America 's flight to suburbs was having a damaging effect on downtown business districts across the country. Hardest hit were the downtown movie palaces which dotted America's urban landscapes. Audiences dwindled and costs rose. Many of our nation's finest movie palaces were quickly demolished before anyone noticed because the land beneath them became more valuable than the theatre operation.

Today, the Tampa Theatre is a remarkable success story, presenting and hosting over 600 events a year. With a full schedule of first run and classic films, concerts, special events, corporate events and tours, the theatre is one of the most heavily utilized venues of its kind in the United States.

The Tampa Theatre was named to the National Register of Historic Places in 1978, is a Tampa City Landmark, and is a member of the League of Historic American Theatres.

1. The Tampa Theatre deserves to have a future free of financial burden.</description>
  <mission>To support one of America's most elaborate movie palaces, the Tampa Theatre.</mission>
  <name>Support the Tampa Theatre</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6333</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">28</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zb/yu/38/dj/fe/Em/uGcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
