<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Man gets 40 years for deadly"mistake.

This is the article published Sept 12/07
Bradenton- 
Williams, 40 had fatally shot his ex-girlfriend, amid a disput about their failed relationship. Ms Sheflin was shot seven times the night of March 3 2006 gun fire that erupted in the presence of her 4 year old son.
Mr Williams said"I just exploded in front of the judge and begged the judge not to lock him up in prison for what could be the rest of his life. Like a flash, it happened".
The judge was  not moved by Mr williams request so  he  sentenced him to 40 years for second -degree murder. Mr  Williams plead no contest to the charge of murder and faced 25-40 in prison. He confessed to the shooting, which he states  stemmed from a domestic feud about infidelity. The Public DA called this a crime of passion not a calculated killing, stating this man suffers from depression and anxiety, Mr Willimas got  so angry he was not  concerned for the child, after  he shot Ms Sheflin he grabbed his son and drove off. He dropped his son off with a relative and abandoned his car at a local walmart and walked to the poilce station miles away.
Many relatives spoke up and suggested that Mr Willimas be prosecuted for first degree murder saying that he thought about killing way  before  he pulled the trigger. He was  so angry that Ms Sheflin was seeing another man, Mr Willimas  pleads the court not to give hime jail time and suggest he might be the victim in this case and that he might of been under  alot of stress. He has a depraved mind. His 11 year old step daughter,who was the only father figure she ever had stood up in court and spoke, about how she will never be able to paint her nails with  her mother and never shop for dresses.  I thought I could trust you she said," Williams's son the boy  who saw the shooting is so restless at night and  still has many nightmares,  he clasped his hands together in front of a mirror pretending to fire a weapon at his reflection.
One irrational mistake cost Mr Willimas everything.

This was what the  newspapers reported It makes me so mad that this happened to such a loving mother, daughter sister and all he had to  say was he just exploded. How can we achive any type of peace in this world war crime will it ever end... I created this group for people to speak out stand  up and say enough is enough this happened. Is it right that this man only got  40 years for  his crime I say NO.... 
This child is living in fear and that's no way for him to live.
He is a black child and is  so scared of men of his  same race.  When will the violence ever stop...
so I ask those  who join this group please post your stories and let the world know this  is wrong and has to stop we as mother's  sister's daughter's wife's won't take it any more  and the  children who are in the middle of it should not be living  in fear.
So speak out and let the world know it has to stop.

1. Violence

2. Stop, crime

3. Women and Children</description>
  <mission>Women shot to death</mission>
  <name>violence</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6338</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">32</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/A5/Zm/Im/ew/In/SU/Xc/RGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
