<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hi, my name is Audrey... this summer i went to Africa. I can honestly say that i have never been on a trip quite like this one. To tell you the truth, i have never experienced anything as humbling as seeing the way these people live. The Massai is one of the oldest tribes in Africa. Our main focus is in the Mayroa region. Women and children are starving and abused by the men in the village, and it is my goal as well as others to put a stop to the degration and suffering of these women and children.Soon we are going to be selling jewelry made by the Maasai to raise funds for them, but at the moment this is what we are doing to make a difference.

 Soon we are going to be selling jewelry made by the Maasai to raise funds for them, but at the moment this is what we are doing to make a difference.

(Pictures and prices of jewlery will be posted when ready!)


Donations Accepted 

(Donated money will go to buying supplies)



Goat = 
Baby goat $20 
Two mature goats, one of each sex $100
(a source of income and food to be given to one of the poorest families.  They use the milk, they don't eat the goat :] ) 


Sponsoring a child = $360.00 a year ($30.00 a month)


This pays for weekly meals, medical care and other needed items


Feel free to message me if you are interested in helping in any way.  100% of any donated money will be used on children and families in Tanzania; or on specific things such as goats and sponsorships.  




1. Female Genital Mutilation is performed on the tribal women. The men are circumcsed around age 10 and are beaten if they flinch during the process.

2. Women aren't loved.  They have to have sex with any man within her husbands' age group if they tell her to.  

3. -Children are considered nothing.  The only reason for having kids is to use them as a retirement plan.

4. Men will steal little girls &amp; make one of his wives raise her.  When older he will then have sex with her and sell her for cows.

5. Men will usually have up to 60-80 children and wont known who theirs are, where they sleep, if they eat or that they were ever born.  

6. If a child is sick they are taken away from the village and left for an animal to eat. 

7. Sponsored children are fed twice a week...the others must scrape the bottom of the bean pot to eat a spoonful</description>
  <mission>Provide support for Women and Children in the Massai </mission>
  <name>Love for Massai</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6340</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ZJ/ZF/ZO/w5/ve/vE/lftS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
