<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>THE PROJECT OF LOVE - "In those days, there was a famine upon the land." The people have farmed the barren slopes of the mountains of Esquipulas, but they have found nothing but poverty, drug and alcohol abuse, and human depravity. The Project of Love in Esquipulas has become a monument to vision, creativity, drive, and resourcefulness. It is a beacon of hope in a lost society, teaching the Word of God along with new techniques that bring agricultural abundance to ground that was previously devoid f nutrients. It is a light of love, the hand of Christ upon a people too long ignored by the Church, the nation and the world. With your help, born again people will arise from the dust of this earth, just as the multipurpose center has arisen from the ashes of a barren land. With your help, the Gospel of Christ will go forward and lives will be changed. Ministry will pour forth from the kitchen, the clinic, the farming center, and the sanctuary. Depraved men will be saved from their sins and their wives and children will be saved from a life of unbelieveable misery and abuse.

And the ministry opportinities continue

1. to preach the gospel of Jesus Christ to the poor

2. to offer them one more day of food, one more day of life, that there may be one more day of hope in which to find the one on whom the world awaits

3. to teach them lay down their nets, leave their boats behind and follow Him so they may become fishers of men and proclaim the Gospel everywhere.</description>
  <mission>to preach to the poor and to provde one more day of food that there may be one more day of hope in which to find the one on whom the world awaits (Luke 7:18-19). </mission>
  <name>Cocina Del Amor</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6357</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gB/ZT/ND/6j/oM/2j/57NS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
