<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is a nation wide event threwout the year that supports the National Multiple Sclerosis Society. It is helping victims of MS and their families on a daily basis all over the nation. 
  	I am riding this weekend in The MS 150 of Denver. I am riding on behalf of my aunt Pam who has been battling MS for over 50 years. I am riding 150 miles in two days in support of Multiple Sclerosis. My goal is to raise one thousand dollars for the National Society. Uses for the money are broken down in the pie chart directly below.
   I am riding with a team sponsored by Daniel's College of business, the institution I am currently attending.  There are 10 of us riding together over the weekend that will all greatly appreciate any donation you would care to gift. Many people are suffering from this illness every day, you can help!

   To donate or just see how I am doing towards my goal or the goals of my team simply go to the web link below. Then if you look directly above the thermometer tracking my fundraising there is a DONATE TO ZACHARY button to click that will lead you threw the donation process with a credit card. Donations are tax deductible, and have a deadline of friday but will accept donations until July 30th.

www.nationalmssociety.org/site/TR?pg=personal&amp;fr_id=3940&amp;px=3619153

Please check out the sight and let me know if you have any questions.

thanks so much for your support and have a fantastic day.
P.S. If you know anyone that would be interested feel free to fwd this to them!


1. A society can be judged on how it treats the weekest among them. </description>
  <mission>To end the devistating effects of Multiple Sclerosis</mission>
  <name>MS 150 Bike Tour</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6369</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">37</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8X/uV/7r/wk/MD/DG/4jpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
