<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Your contributions make it possible for the SPCA to:

* Care for nearly 50,000 domestic, farm and wild animals in need;
* Provide emergency rescue and treatment for thousands of injured animals;
* Carry out nearly 6,000 animal cruelty investigations;
* Advocate higher standards for the 100 million farm animals raised in BC every year, and press for stronger national laws to protect the 600 million farm animals transported throughout Canada;
* Advocate on issues such as rodeos, avian influenza and national farming codes of practice;
* Oversee SPCA Certified, a food labeling program that assures consumers the products they choose are derived from animals that have been raised according to the BC SPCA's high standards of animal welfare;
* Reduce the tragedy of pet overpopulation through low-cost spay/neuter programs across BC;
* Present programs to increase empathy and respect for animals to thousands of BC children through summer camps, the BC SPCA Kids Club and school presentations;
* Advocate for stronger anti-cruelty laws to protect animals from abuse and neglect;
* Provide life-saving rescue and rehabilitation for injured wildlife.

Please visit www.spca.bc.ca/walk/about.shtml for more information or provide help or donations to one of our other MANY SPCA fundraising campaigns.

1. HEY ALL - It turns out that Causes on Facebook are, as yet, only set up for US- based non-profits, so please do NOT give me any donations HERE.

2. Instead, please visit my SPCA Paws for a Cause donation page by searching for my name at:  http://my.e2rm.com/personalPage.aspx?SID=2282920

3. Tons more info there on the work we do, and the costs we need to cover every day.</description>
  <mission>To provide urgently needed care for thousands of animals each year. </mission>
  <name>BC SPCA Paws For a Cause</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6375</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">628</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">328.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jL/ob/ME/7H/Qw/DG/hhlS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
