<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Federal Reserve Act of 1913 concocted legislation, to be foisted upon the People's Congress of the United States, that empowered and commissioned this secret cabal of World-dominant bankers to PRINT UNITED STATES CURRENCY, a usurpation of our Constitution's explicit edict empowering ONLY THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT to print and coin currency. This world banking empire used their stolen power to print, out of thin air, paper currency which, in no way represents the gold and silver reserves that authentic currency is supposed to represent. Thus, the Rothschilds, the Morgans and the Rockefellers connived the power to pick the pocket of *EVERY* American, from the small child buying a loaf of bread to bring home, to the father of a household, working his life away to feed, clothe and shelter his family. 

source:http://www.federal-reserve.net/thefederalreserveact.htm

The federal government and the federal reserve run together.  The reserve, an independent agency run by bankers lends the government money to run it's business.  In turn the government must pay back the money with interest to the reserve.  This money in addition to the interest paid on it goes to the reserve.  Under the force of the government, to pay the bankers, the people are in servitude to the federal reserve.  If you want a government that is run by the people and not power elites, I would hope you would join this cause.



1. Repeal the Federal Reserve Act

2. Return the constitutional power to congress to coin and regulate the value of money

3. Reinstate the gold standard

4. Repeal the 16th Amendment

5. Eliminate the Internal Revenue Service</description>
  <mission>Abolish the Federal Reserve</mission>
  <name>Abolish the Federal Reserve</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6381</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4835</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">124.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Bf/OV/gF/zw/PA/DJ/HpcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
