<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For clarification's purposes we can say that communism, socialism, social democracy, progessive, leftist, and statist ideals all fall under collectivism.

It is wrong morally as it deprives the free man his money and labor through means of brute force.

It is wrong empirically because the power elites' control of wealth is used to serve their own means while ignoring the needs of their people.

It is wrong socially, as it is the state and not the people who determine worth and need individual lives.

It is wrong historically as it has seen the deaths of millions through central planning, war, and neglect.

It is wrong spiritually as the will for greatness and triumph is undermined.

It is wrong ethically as man is regarded as a sacrificial animal to serve the needs of others under the altruist doctorine.

The only way to cure this great cancer that has killed and will continue to kill is to support a capitalist system with no shame.  Our ancestors who brought about more wealth than has ever been seen in history have done so through this system.  Man's functional and spiritual highest point has been when he is left without burden of government or force to create.  Innovation and human progress have been in the dark ages for thousands of years until the enlightment period where individual wealth was discovered as a right.  And if you want to destroy the darkness that plagues humanity, please consider joining the fight to destroy communism.

1. Destroy Communism

2. Promote Capitalism</description>
  <mission>destroy socialist, altruist, and collectivist ideals that have plagued the world and killed millions</mission>
  <name>Crush Communism</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6385</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">85</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Im/Fb/UZ/fC/AL/vf/tnhS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
