<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I am a grade 8 laptop student at Nashwaaksis Middle School. Recently the government made an announcement that the school laptop project will be cut due to the fact that principal of Leo Hayes thinks that it is not fair that there will be other classes in grade 9 without laptops. His opinion on this program is to go all out with this wonderful project or ditch it completely. He has decided to ditch it completely, but he clearly hasn&#8217;t considered the many, many benefits if this program. 

First, it increases our typing skills which we all know we use very often, our overall understanding of computers and how to use them. We also learned how to use programs such as Microsoft Publisher, Word, Power Point and Excel. These are extremely useful skills to have in almost every job, you use a computer at some point and at the rate technology is increasing it will become an everyday thing to use these programs, and many other that we haven&#8217;t had a chance to even scratch the surface of if this project is cut. 

I think it would be a huge mistake for the government to get rid of this fantastic program. It has only been active for a few years why not give it a few more years to see how it goes?  There will always be anti-technologists in this world but I urge you as a first hand member of the this program I have witnessed it flourish and grow. So we all know the government never makes mistakes cutting this program would be a big one.   

Kyle Forbes

1. We belive that the laptop program was a great thing

2. WE think it was wrong and crule to take it away</description>
  <mission>save the NB laptop program </mission>
  <name>WE LOVE OUR LAPTOPS!!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6402</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">54</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/I5/h2/mm/3U/li/du/WUsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
