<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Do you want to help people on the autistic spectrum?
Do you have family or friends on the spetcrum?
Do you really know what is going on in their lives?

Imagine your mind and body being in a constant state of red alert due to differences in the way you experience the world...and imagine not being able to tell someone about it.

Imagine having your only methods of coping with these differences forced out of you without those issues being addressed.  Imagine constantly being compared to a cancer, a kidnapping victim or an epidemic.  

Imagine being written off as a human being altogether...

If you can imagine this, you might have a small idea of what being autistic is like.  

Since its "discovery" in the mid-40's, autism has been largely treated as just a behavioural disorder ... yet very few autistic people are feeling or seeing the benefits for themselves as they grow into adulthood.  

Time and time again, professionals do not address the very real possibility that those "behaviours" they work so hard to train out might be the reaction to something that is not being addressed: the core issues.  Core issues can range anywhere from sensory integration issues to digestive problems which are often neglected, leaving an autistic person to pretend to be normal without their real needs being met.  

No longer is autism such a mystery to behold for autistic people all over the world are speaking out and saying what they have gone through, what they need, etc.  

It's time to start listening and then using that knowledge to provide appropriate, beneficial and empowering services to autistic people.

It's time for perspectives to change.  It's time for communication and Theory of Mind to work both ways.

Let's open the lines of communication and help each other!

1. Promote quality of life, beneficial services and acceptance for autistics

2. Promote positive 2 way communication between autistics and the medical community, public

3. Promote positive community support and awareness of all aspects of autism</description>
  <mission>Promote positive solutions, awareness and 2 way communication between autistics and the community</mission>
  <name>Autism Awareness - A New Perspective</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6407</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">89</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Hd/TB/a3/Iu/5k/7w/vEuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
