<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This was something a friend of mine and I started a few years back... I'm gonna go off of a limb and say it was a pretty successful for 2 teenage boys who didn't have much time. 

The Eden project was started based upon what we witnessed through the Washington Leadership Conference with our FFA Chapter. We picked fresh produce and it went to the food pantry. That got us thinking; the best food for people are the healthy kinds. How can people that cannot reach healthy foods use them to nurish your body? Then our idea came to life.

When 2 farmboys got together they could only think of one thing, plant a big garden. Of course it was a lot of work, but we took a lot of good stuff to local food pantries and it made us feel great. We were helping people a way we knew how. Giving them food, giving them nurishment and possibly hope. 

I ask that you help our cause, make an effort to help this. It can be good, I know it can. I want to start building more gardens and growing more food. God said,"Let the earth bring forth grass, the herb that yields seed, and the fruit tree that yields fruit according to its kind, whose seed is in itself, on the earth." (Genesis 1:11) So if the earth was put here to grow plants, that we should do. "Moreover, the profit of the land is for all; even the king is served from the field" (Ecclesiates 5:9)

It is amazing a little a person has to to to make a difference... how great would our world be if everyone just planted one more seed?

1. Nutrition it very vital, and a vast majority of people who are needy, do not get what they need.

2. Children need the proper nutrients to grow, develop and achieve.

3. eden.project@hotmail.com</description>
  <mission>Give nutritious, raw fruits and vegetables to those whole need it most. </mission>
  <name>The Eden Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6408</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">55</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3J/Ga/Ke/Ok/Hv/0r/waXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
