<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>STAND: A Student Anti-Genocide Coalition, formerly known as Students Taking Action Now: Darfur, serves as umbrella organization for student groups active in promoting awareness advocating for an end to the current genocide in Darfur, Sudan and working to create a permanent anti-genocide student movement. STAND has become a student movement that encompasses over 600 college, university, and high school chapters across the United States and around the world. Each new STAND chapter is formed independently by students at their respective institution. STAND national seeks to unify, resource and empower all of these chapters so that, together, these individuals and communities can prevent and stop genocide. Each STAND group is comprised of dedicated and energetic students concerned with raising awareness, fundraising, and advocacy for the genocide and humanitarian issues in Darfur, and the world. The coordination of these groups by STAND national helps improve the impact students across the globe can make on government policy, the situation on the ground in Sudan, and the permanent prevention of genocide in our world. STAND is headed by a student Executive Director and a Managing Committee comprised of student leaders in schools across the US who work on the issue&#8217;s different elements such as programs, resources, media, advocacy and outreach. Through an extensive outreach network, comprised of six outreach coordinators on both the college and high school levels, STAND national works to coordinate, unify and stay in touch with the vibe of the student movement so that it can best provide strategic guidance and resources. STAND is the student division of the Genocide Intervention Network (GI-Net). 

1. The genocide in Darfur, Sudan, and in other parts of the world must end immediately.

2. Genocide can be stopped if and only if we stand together, as students and citizens of the world.

3. We need to educate those around us so that our anti-genocide message can spread. Raising awareness means raising money to stop genocide.</description>
  <mission>Empower individuals and communities to prevent and stop genocide. </mission>
  <name>STAND</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6418</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">65</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oy/5n/vq/En/mD/Gt/J4uS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
