<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Marijuana (grass, pot, weed) is the common name for a crude drug made from the plant Cannabis sativa. The main mind-altering (psychoactive) ingredient in marijuana is THC (delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol), but more than 400 other chemicals also are in the plant. A marijuana "joint" (cigarette) is made from the dried particles of the plant. The amount of THC in the marijuana determines how strong its effects will be. The type of plant, the weather, the soil, the time of harvest, and other factors determine the strength of marijuana. The strength of today's marijuana is as much as ten times greater than the marijuana used in the early 1970s. This more potent marijuana increases physical and mental effects and the possibility of health problems for the user. Hashish, or hash, is made by taking the resin from the leaves and flowers of the marijuana plant and pressing it into cakes or slabs. Hash is usually stronger than crude marijuana and may contain five to ten times as much THC. Pure THC is almost never available, except for research.


if you read up on the history and medical, you'll find that it helps nausea in cancer patients, hiv patients, anorexics are helped by cannabis, even the obese.

also THC has been known to have positive effects on MS patients.

it's a diuretic and helps with hypertension (if not inhalated) 

it helps with joint pain along with rheumatoid arthritis.

headache... blindness, eye pain.

if ingested it can help with colon disorders.

1. Freedom of choice</description>
  <mission>They are trying to reclass cannabis in the UK, from a class C drug to a class B drug! </mission>
  <name>Legalize Cannabis in the UK</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6434</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2977</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.03</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/MZ/0q/5e/4G/lV/lY/z6lS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
