<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>(PS) ProgressiveSociety 

ProgressiveSociety is a non-heiarchichal division and organization that continually seeks the liberation of any oppressed being. PS is inherently a part of all of us that seek to change our reality and those of our mutually oppressed fellow citizens. Therefore the discussion of key issues shall not be limited to a few main ones, but will stretch across all boundaries to heed the call of the individual. In these hegemonic times when domination and imperialism seek to globalize an ever shrinking world, we must all strive to slow the machine, to change the structure, to change our world. We are not republicans nor are we democrats, seeing as both of these parties are more alike than different and neither truly represent the social and political needs and aspirations of a terribly confused and hopeless nation. The hope would be that ProgressiveSociety would not only begin and end in Santa Fe, but that it could be to some degree a nationwide movement in which rallies, protests, events, and gatherings would be held and or staged by the PS operation in whichever city/town/district/place you call home.

Thought and reason being the key virtues of any woman/man/child/being, we must never sacrifice our beliefs for the domination paradigm that will continue to attempt to keep us all quiet as we grow old on drugs that they feed us, food that they tamper with and messages that have been programmed and trained into our very reality. We are not merely discussing a reform within the system, but moreso a reform of the entire system, of any system. The path to self-realization is deep within every one of us and to those that sit by apathetically and wait for true liberation to be given to us on a silver platter will become only smaller and smaller numbers of to the mechanized death industry that is global capitalism and domination.

Stand together as one, true solidarity, continual freedom and liberation for all who strive for it.



1. Social Liberation

2. Nationalized/Socialized Medicine

3. Education Reform</description>
  <mission>Awareness, Self-Realization, Politcal and Social Radicalism</mission>
  <name>ProgressiveSociety</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6435</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">30</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sV/aQ/Fu/zx/r5/3N/q77S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
