<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I had a vision one day about 5 years ago and it keeps resurfacing in my daily thoughts. Walt Disney is probably my main inspiration for this effort however there are many motivators in a world like this.

My plan is to build a hospital free to children with terminal illnesses. The hospital will be free to international patients who require the medical attention and a process to determine if the patients family is the most benificiary to the program. 
The hospital wil be powered souly on alternative power such as soalr,  hydrogen, wind ect... There will be several guest houses to accomodate visiting families and friends. These facilities will also be free to the families.


The hospital will be joined to a huge zoo designed around the wonders of the world and will help with numerous breeding programs for endangered species. The  zoo and hospital's designs will be state of the art and made to maek the children and animals feel like they are in heaven.  One of the key aspects of this facility will be a train that travels from inside the hospital to around the outside zoo/theme park area. The train will be suited for terminally ill children.

The park will be open a few days a week to the public and several ongoing programs will be run to maintain the park, the hospital and their employees.

THis project is obviously very early in it's stages. Please join this cause if you agree with the idea. I do not expect anyone to donate any money. 

If you do wish to help or want more detailed info on the plans, please email me at risingfromashes@hotmail.com.

Thank you for your time,
Shelby Taylor
:)

Please do not donate any money here. I am currently selling tickets on paypal for artwork that will be raffled off. Please look it up in the facebook marketplace.


1. We must protect the weak, the innocent, and those without voices.

2. We must work together to show those who need our help that they are not alone.

3. We need to combine different worlds of perception to understand a better way of life.</description>
  <mission>To help protect the weak, the innocent, and those without a voice.</mission>
  <name>Shelby Taylor Foundation (to be determined)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6439</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2F/Us/xl/Yc/U4/4K/PnJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
