<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Cabaret 101: Why It's Illegal to Dance in Most Places in NYC

The city began a system in Prohibition-era 1926 to control entertainment in clubs. All clubs were required to obtain a cabaret license to operate, a labyrinthine process entirely controlled by the city. The law states that an establishment must be licensed if the club features three or more musicians, or if any of the instruments is percussion or brass, or if there are three or more people moving in synchronized fashion.

In the late eighties, after a five year legal battle on behalf of the Musicians Union led by New York University Law Professor Paul Chevigny, the courts declared the three musician rule unconstitutional and accepted live music in zones where bars and restaurants are permitted. But nothing was done to lift the stigma of dancing.

Nightclubs are also restricted in zoning, meaning cabaret licenses are only granted to venues in major commercial centers, industrial or manufacturing districts, effectively making it illegal to dance in any residential area. In 1960 there were 12,000 cabaret licenses in the five boroughs. Now, in 2006, there are less than 200.

In 1997, Rudy Guiliani created the multi-agency Nightclub Enforcement Task Force to crack down on clubs as part of his "Quality of Life" campaign. Deputy Mayor Rudy Washington goes on the record stating, "We've been closing down these little buckets of blood (nightclubs) for about three years and paralyzing them." Coney Island High, Baby Jupiter, Hogs &amp; Heifers, Vain, Rivertown Lounge, No Moore, Knitting Factory and Lakeside Lounge are just a few of the places that have been fined or padlocked for illegal dancing.

www.metropolisinmotion.org- sign the local petition and write to your congressman etc

1. The right to dance without cabaret laws

2. Dancing should not be a crime</description>
  <mission>Not Allow the Cabaret Laws to go into Place!</mission>
  <name>Stop The Cabaret Laws!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6463</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7m/Mr/76/Iz/ID/UP/TDvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
