<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>DID YOU KNOW THAT: 

-1 US dollar = 50 Afghanis?
-Afghanistan is one of the poorest nations in the world?
- 69% of children are suffering from severe malnutrition and are underweight?
- The literacy rate for females is a mere 13%
- Because immunization coverage is still very low, preventable diseases kill thousands of children annually. 
- The lack of water and food will exacerbate the outbreak of disease and malnutrition among children.
- Infant, under-five, and maternal mortality rates in Afghanistan are among the world&#8217;s highest. 
- 25% of children die before reaching their fifth birthday.

[Statistics courtesy of Afghanistan Relief Organization]

We have been blessed with so much, and are in a position to make a real difference in the lives of these people. Why can't we turn a portion of these blessings to those in need? 

All proceeds are automatically forwarded to the registered charity: Afghanistan Relief, a certified JustGive 501(c)3 nonprofit charity,  to ensure your donations securely reach those who need them. (Website: http://www.afghanrelief.com )

Donations are tax deductible. When filing your taxes, you should name JustGive as the recipient charity. JustGive's tax identification number is 94-3331010.

***SKEPTICAL ABOUT DONATING?***
Find out exactly where your money goes and how Facebook causes work http://apps.facebook.com/causes/help

OR click to donate through the more familiar Bayat Foundation ( 501(c)3 pending ): http://bayatfoundation.org/donate.php

Even the smallest of contributions have the potential to help those most in need, whether in the form of monetary donations, by inviting people to this cause to spread awareness, or simply by joining and strengthening the cause. 

May you be rewarded for your efforts,

God Bless.

Keywords: Medical, health, humanitarian aid
Contact: Afifa Sarwari, cause creator and host.


1. Medical care shoul be available to all.

2. Afghan orphans need our help and support, they have been hit the hardest by the wars. Let us unite for their sake, delivering a message of hope &amp; love

3. The basic human rights/needs of Afghans are often neglected. This sad truth can become a thing of the past with your support. Lets make a difference.</description>
  <mission>The focus of this cause is to raise funds for Afghan Orphans, and to help rebuild medical facilities in Afghanistan at this critical time.</mission>
  <name>Afghanistan Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6464</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2013</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">654.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fs/RV/HN/ww/2E/IC/gEtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
