<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Why is it that society protects the abuser. Or shall I say let a innocent  NATIVE CHILD fall through the cracks of the system at a very young age of 7 yrs old, seems like society likes to push it under a rug like it never happened. Had me and my boy not leave  the situation, and go to the native shelter in Oshewken, I would have never found out about  what my boy disclosed when he was 7 yrs old to the native workers.. I didnt even know it was happening to my son until we got to the shelter we stayed at for about a month. When I told him I was proud of him, he said mom I knew the natives would protect us.

 By the time they reach 13 yrs old,  is when society will listen but in the meantime he has been touched inappropriately in 2001 and  in 2005, but not considered a sexual act when a paternal grandmother greets her grandson on by reaching down and squeezing his penis on 4 occasions and laughing  in front of of my son...CCAS here in Hamilton, had the nerve to ask me if this was some kind of culture greeting...she had no kids, she mentioned to me, told her  she should be fired..  She did say sometimes when parents go through a separation a  child can say stuff that aint true..I told her  believe my son...The sad part is my boy told his dad,  his dad told him was *DON'T TELL NOT EVEN YOUR MOM*.he was 7 at the time.

  In 2005 while my boy was tying his shoes  bent over  his dad decided to stick his fingers  way down his bumcrack moving up and down and laughing about it with other people present on 6 different occasions, and calling it a plumbercrack.  All I am told is its not considered a sexual act  by the poilice station , and told this is for family court mam..because my boy was not penetrated this man was allowed access to my boy from the courts.. I still never gave up!!.

 There is a dvd at the police station that was viewed  my boy told the police on Mother's Day back in 2005  what his dad was doing to him . but all he got was a stern strong warning about his inappropriate behaviour towards his son and allowed access with another family member present. per police and CCAS . I even tried to have these people charged, even got a letter from the judge of the peace to give to the police station to address these womens concerns , and still nothing..even went to the victims unit at the poilce station and told to get a lawyer..this is so wrong..

 Or shall I say what did society do to protect this from happening to my son,  absolutely nothing. I strongly feel the are responsible for allowing my boy to be touched period!! A Native child has more rights than you and I. There should have been a court order to protect my boy from these people back in 2001 when it first happened to him, without even a report from investigating these people , or from CCAS, how can a judge make a decision , wiith no evidence if front of it, but when i had the shelter report with me, he throws it on the desk and says it has no merit, and says i acting inappropriately for taken my son too a shelter, should have called my ex on his cell phone, therefore order access to this man..had i not had a different judge and had the same judge i first had, i strongly believe things would have been differently , cuz he order them to not be lefted alone with my son until the CCAS had the report..

 I have even email the governement to help save my boy still never heard back from anyone.  But I nevered gave up, and fought to have my boys words heard,  finally he recieved his own Child's Lawyer June 2007.   There has been a victory, and  his words was finally heard, he never gave up , and  I never gave up!!!. took him until he was 13 yrs old. before anyone listen to him..thats the sad part..

 MY HEARTS GOES OUT TO MY SON FOR NEVER GIVEN UP ON HIS MOM!!!aND BELIEVIN IN HOPE!!                    </description>
  <mission>To Protect A Native Childs Rights or ANY CHILD  We Teach Our Children To Tell Just 1 Person.</mission>
  <name>***Native Child Of The Corn***</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6476</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">22</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7w/yM/O8/BZ/2t/QY/8TzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
