<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>     During the Vietnam War, the American Military was responsible for many horrible events. Such events that are universally known are the napalm bombs and the agent orange attacks that were used. Both of these actions taken against the Vietnamese were horrible, but no actions like those taken at My Lai, are capable of indicating the horrors that the American military particitated in. The My Lai incident, was one of particular horror. In a single day, U.S soldiers massacred over 500 innocent Vietnamese civilians. They started in the morning and did not stop until the late afternoon, however during the course of destroying the village of My Lai, the soldiers found the time to have a lunch break and continue the decimation after a brief respite. As horrifying as this was, the actions that the upper echleons of the military partook in hiding this event were incredibly disturbing. They told the press that My Lai was "an enemy stronghold" and the "body counts" they used as evidence simply supported them. However, when the truth finally broke out, they used the scape goat of a Mr. Medina.

     The simple truth is that there is no way that we can ever truly repent for the horrible actions that took place that day. However, one thing we can do is to help rebuild the village and more importantly help the families of the villagers who unjustifiably lost their lives, as well as healing the whole country from the effects of a war that some people think is "ancient history".


1. The events at My Lai should never be repeated

2. To make up for My Lai, money should spent in rebuilding.</description>
  <mission>To make up for atrocities committed at My Lai</mission>
  <name>My Lai Peace Park</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6484</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ns/Uh/Pl/4u/Om/uV/NbcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
