<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In 2007, I've committed to finishing at least one race each month in order to raise funds for Girls on the Run Bay Area.

You can read my Race Reports here: http://laurafrofro.typepad.com/the_fro_fro_blogfinally/race_reports/index.html

Thanks in advance for your support!


ABOUT GIRLS ON THE RUN BAY AREA:

Mission

The mission of Girls on the Run of the Bay Area is to educate and build confidence in young girls through non-competitive, curriculum-based running programs in San Francisco, Alameda, San Mateo, and Contra Costa Counties.

 
History

Founded in 2002, Girls on the Run of the Bay Area is a 501(c)(3) nonprofit and an Independent Council of Girls on the Run International. Girls on the Run of the Bay Area launched its first program in fall 2002 with five girls. Today, more than 500 girls participate in our programs each year and we continue to add new program sites throughout the Bay Area.

 
About

Girls on the Run of the Bay Area provides an innovative running program for girls ages 8 to 13 that uses experiential learning to teach very specific and well-defined social and personal skills. The program culminates in a non-competitive community running event that gives the girls a chance to shine and an overwhelming sense of accomplishment. Girls on the Run of the Bay Area offers 10-week programs during the fall and spring seasons. Volunteer coaches engage the girls in games and running-based workouts that encourage emotional, social, psychological and physical development. The girls meet twice each week after school for a total of 20 one-hour sessions.




1. it is critical to reach girls at an early age in order to teach them these important life lessons and to prevent at-risk behavior such as eating disorders, substance abuse, depression, obesity, and adolescent pregnancies</description>
  <mission>My mission is to support Girls on the Run Bay Area, so that a new generation of girls will run to raise even money for worthwhile causes.</mission>
  <name>Laura's Running for Girls On the Run Bay Area</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6486</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oT/3p/dV/kN/Or/So/HjgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
