<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A network of volunteers and staff committed to research, teach, and apply the principles of nonviolence as taught and lived by Gandhi and King on behalf of sexual and gender minorities. Wherever you are on your journey of faith,  Whatever your sexual orientation or gender identity, Whatever your religion, race, age, ability, color, or creed, You are welcome to join us in learning, teaching, and applying the 'soul force' principles of relentless nonviolent resistance as taught by Gandhi and King as we work together to stop spiritual violence against Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender people that flows out of the teachings and actions of religious leaders and their communities of faith.

When we take one step in the direction of doing justice, it renews our spirit (releases our own "soul force") as it helps transform our society.

1. We were created to do justice.

2. When we take one step in the direction of doing justice, it renews our spirit (releases our own "soul force") as it helps transform our society.

3. Religion has become the primary source of false and inflammatory misinformation about lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender people.

4. Anti-glbt religious teachings lead to discrimination, suffering, and death.

5. Our duty as humans is to confront and eventually replace these tragic untruths with the truth that glbt people are God's children, too, created, loved, and accepted by God exactly as they are.</description>
  <mission>The purpose of Soulforce is freedom for lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender people from religious and political oppression through the practice of relentless nonviolent resistance.</mission>
  <name>Soulforce</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6499</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1452</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">779.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Og/Ib/KN/lp/rd/mj/YlgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
