<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The National Space Society (NSS) is an independent, educational, grassroots nonprofit organization dedicated to the creation of a spacefaring civilization. Founded as the National Space Institute (1974) and L5 Society (1975), which merged to form NSS in 1987, NSS is widely acknowledged as the preeminent citizen's voice on space. NSS counts thousands of members and over 50 chapters in the United States and around the world. The society also publishes Ad Astra magazine, an award-winning periodical chronicling the most important developments in space.

NSS Organization and Leadership
NSS leadership is provided by an elected all-volunteer Board of Directors that governs the Society. Our Board of Governors and Board of Advisors provide additional expertise and visibility. International, education, publication, technical, and policy committees offer guidance.

The Chairman of the Board of Governors is Mr. Hugh Downs, former host of ABC's 20/20. The Board of Governors includes Dr. Buzz Aldrin, Apollo 11 astronaut, Tom Hanks, Norman Augustine, General Simon "Pete" Worden, and many other notable figures. The NSS President and Chairman of the NSS Board of Directors is Mr. Kirby Ikin. The day-to-day affairs of the society are managed by a headquarters staff lead by NSS Executive Director George Whitesides. 

1. NSS believes that space development and settlement will occur most efficiently, and humanity's survival and prosperity will be best ensured, if nations cooperate on space research and development, and leave competition to individual companies. 

2. NSS believes that space development and settlement will occur most efficiently, and humanity's prosperity will be best ensured, if national governments fund the research and development of space technologies deemed too "high risk" by their industries. 

3. NSS believes that one of the goals and benefits of space development and settlement is to restore and enhance the biosphere of the planet Earth. </description>
  <mission>To serve the space community and to support the creation of a spacefaring civilization. </mission>
  <name>National Space Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6522</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1601</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">513.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dN/GR/Bc/Av/4N/Cf/EPLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
