<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We are a charity organization working in rural Tanzania to promote community development through education, vocational training, health awareness, and life skills development.

The Hoja Project believes that only by investing in the people of Tanzania can sustainable community  development take place.  By providing access to educational resources in communities where there are few to no educational options, we allow academically able but financially disadvantaged students access to precious educational resources.  Hoja focuses on education as we believe it gives people the power to help themselves out of poverty.  In the words of Nelson Mandela, &#8220;Education is the most powerful weapon which you can use to change the world.&#8221;

Hoja aims to improve education generally as well as providing new centers for and supporting any existing institutions of vocational, health, human rights and agriculture education.  As across much of sub-Saharan Africa, HIV/AIDS is a significant issue, and one of our aims is to promote awareness about both the nature of the disease, and the social issues that surround it.  We have conducted research to determine the needs that the villagers feel are most important to them, in order to help provide what they ask for, thereby ensuring that Hoja assists community members to implement local solutions to solve local problems.

1. Education should be accessible to all worldwide.

2. All people should be empowered with the knowledge and skills to make good decisions about their health.

3. Participation by community members and local leadership is the only way to create lasting change.</description>
  <mission>To promote community development in rural Africa by increasing access to education and reducing the spread of HIV/AIDS by providing health education and fostering life skills development.</mission>
  <name>The Hoja Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6527</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">79</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">205.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3p/Ks/SE/zL/CY/rj/TT/W3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
