<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>
Addison's disease is a rare endocrine, or hormonal disorder that affects about 1 in 100,000 people. It occurs in all age groups and afflicts men and women equally. The disease is characterized by weight loss, muscle weakness, fatigue, low blood pressure, and sometimes darkening of the skin in both exposed and nonexposed parts of the body.

Addison's disease occurs when the adrenal glands do not produce enough of the hormone cortisol and in some cases, the hormone aldosterone. For this reason, the disease is sometimes called chronic adrenal insufficiency, or hypocortisolism. 
 

    * Causes 
          o Primary Adrenal Insufficiency
          o Secondary Adrenal Insufficiency 
    * Symptoms
    * Diagnosis
          o CRH Stimulation Test
          o Other Tests 
    * Treatment
          o Special Problems
                + Surgery
                + Pregnancy 
    * Patient Education
    * Suggested Reading
    * Other Resources 


Cortisol is normally produced by the adrenal glands, located just above the kidneys. It belongs to a class of hormones called glucocorticoids, which affect almost every organ and tissue in the body. Scientists think that cortisol has possibly hundreds of effects in the body. Cortisol's most important job is to help the body respond to stress.

 The condition is named after Dr Thomas Addison, the British physician who first described the condition in his 1855 On the Constitutional and Local Effects of Disease of the Suprarenal Capsules. The adjective "Addisonian" is used for features of the condition, as well as patients with Addison's disease.

1. My Father Suffers From This Disease

2. No One Should Spend More Time As A Child In A Hospital Than Their Own Home.

3. Like All Other Diseases Addison's Is Equally Important.</description>
  <mission>Help Find A Cure To This Disease.</mission>
  <name>Fight Addison's Disease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6528</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1620</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">308.6</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/U3/Ed/IK/Pc/Hu/Lr/BGmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
