<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Brethren Volunteer Service is a ministry of the Church of the Brethren. BVS has been a major program in this Christian denomination since 1948. We invite you to participate in the BVS family and a new adventure in service.

BVS works to place you in a project where your skills are used and the need is greatest. We expect your service to contribute to the goals stated above. We see BVS as sharing God&#8217;s love through acts of service.

The art of serving is a process of both giving and receiving. We need to be able to freely give of ourselves and freely receive what others can offer and teach us. It is our hope that this art will move beyond a one- to two-year program and will become a lifestyle that continues after BVS.

A part of preparation for your service is participation in a 10-day to three week orientation unit. With this group of 10 to 30 people, you will examine issues related to service, personal and spiritual growth, group living, adjustment to new situations, living simply, and cross-cultural sensitivity. Growing out of the relationships and community spirit developed during the orientation, unit members can provide mutual support for each other.

We believe that your service will be more meaningful and of greater value to others and to yourself if you seek to nurture your faith pilgrimage. Therefore, we encourage you to participate in a faith community as you serve in Brethren Volunteer Service.

Exciting times are ahead if you are willing to take the risk of service!

1. Advocating Justice

2. Working for Peace

3. Serving  Human Need

4. Care for Creation</description>
  <mission>Sharing God&#8217;s love through acts of service.</mission>
  <name>Brethren Volunteer Service</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6530</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">600</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">340.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/NE/LF/PG/TY/SG/53/sgcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
