<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hydrocephalus comes from the Greek: "hydro" means water, "cephalus" means head. Hydrocephalus is an abnormal accumulation of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) within cavities called ventricles inside the brain. CSF is produced in the ventricles, circulates through the ventricular system and is absorbed into the bloodstream. CSF is in constant circulation and has many important functions. It surrounds the brain and spinal cord and acts as a protective cushion against injury. CSF contains nutrients and proteins necessary for the nourishment and normal function of the brain. It also carries waste products away from surrounding tissues. Hydrocephalus occurs when there is an imbalance between the amount of CSF that is produced and the rate at which it is absorbed. As the CSF builds up, it causes the ventricles to enlarge and the pressure inside the head to increase.

How Is Hydrocephalus Treated?

There is no known way to prevent or cure hydrocephalus. The most effective treatment is surgical insertion of a shunt.

About Shunts

A shunt is a flexible tube placed into the ventricular system that diverts the flow of CSF into another region of the body where it can be absorbed, such as the peritoneal (abdominal) cavity or the right atrium of the heart. The shunt tube is about 1/8 inch in diameter and is made of a soft and pliable plastic that is well tolerated by our body tissues. The valve in the shunt maintains the CSF at normal pressure within the ventricles. 

In many cases, prompt treatment can reverse many of the symptoms of hydrocephalus, restoring much cognitive and physical functioning. If left untreated, however, symptoms can become quite disabling, leading to severe cognitive and physical decline.

1. Health education is a universal right</description>
  <mission>Provide information</mission>
  <name>Hydrocephalus</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6546</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1404</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4E/T4/82/Z2/r3/5d/WFHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
