<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Calves raised for veal are taken from their mothers immediately after birth and raised so as to deliberately induce borderline anemia. Denying calves their basic needs, including access to their mother&#8217;s milk, to pasture, to exercise, and often, even to any movement at all, leads to the pale-colored flesh for which veal is coveted.

Calves confined in veal crates, usually measuring 2-feet-wide, cannot turn around, stretch their limbs, or even lie down comfortably. This severe confinement makes the calves' meat "tender" since the animals' muscles cannot develope. 

Scientific research indicates that calves confined in crates experience &#8220;chronic stress&#8221; and require approximately five times more medication than calves living in normal conditions. Researchers have also reported that veal calves exhibit abnormal coping behaviors associated with frustration. 

These include;
-head tossing
-head shaking
-kicking 
-scratching and
-stereotypical chewing behavior. 

Confined calves also experience leg and joint disorders and an impaired ability to walk.

In addition to restricting the animals' movement, veal producers severely limit to what their animals can eat. Veal calves are fed an all-liquid milk substitute which is purposely deficient in iron and fiber. It is intended to produce borderline anemia and the pale coloured flesh fancied by 'gourmets.' At approximately sixteen weeks of age, these weak animals are slaughtered and marketed as "white" veal (also known as "fancy," "milk-fed", "special-fed," and "formula-fed" veal).

1. Calves confined in veal crates, usually measuring 2-feet-wide, cannot turn around, stretch their limbs, or even lie down comfortably!

2. Calves raised for veal are taken from their mothers immediately after birth and raised so as to deliberately induce borderline anemia!

3. Confined calves also experience leg and joint disorders and an impaired ability to walk!</description>
  <mission>Is to educate others about this abuse!</mission>
  <name>Say NO To Veal!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6551</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">184</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ru/yh/dc/7G/0I/Ez/ipZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
