<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Simply put, 826 Valencia is dedicated to supporting students aged 6 to 18 with their writing skills, and helping teachers get their students excited about the literary arts. Our work is based on the understanding that strong writing skills are fundamental to future success and that great leaps in learning can be made when skilled tutors work one-on-one with students. 

We offer a variety of free programs and services throughout the school year and summer months including drop-in tutoring, field trips, specialized workshops, in-school assistance, and extensive student publishing. Our drop-in tutoring program provides students with homework help from knowledgeable tutors, and up to four times a week we welcome an entire class for a morning of high energy learning in our specialized field trips. Our workshops are project-based and cover a variety of areas that schools can&#8217;t typically include in their curriculum, such as cartooning, college entrance essay writing, journalism, SAT prep, and starting a &#8216;zine. We dispatch teams of volunteers into local schools at a teachers&#8217; behest to provide one-on-one assistance to students as they tackle various projects. Through all of our programs students have the opportunity to publish their writing in an array of publications ranging from smaller chapbooks and &#8216;zines to professional-quality books with a national audience. 

Whether the students are working in the realm of fiction, nonfiction, or English as a second language, we are here to help them explore their love of writing, and to help students better express their ideas through the written word. 

In addition to our founding site at 826 Valencia in San Francisco, we also have 826 chapters in NYC, Los Angeles, Michigan, Seattle, and Chicago.

1. Supporting children developing their writing skills essential to their future.

2. Helping teachers get their students excited about the literary arts.

3. Giving the children personalized, one-on-one instruction to maximize their leaps in learning.</description>
  <mission>support students aged 6 to 18 and help develop their writing skills, and helping teachers get their students excited about the literary arts.</mission>
  <name>826 Valencia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6556</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">77</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hA/aG/Ym/gd/qT/GJ/T7DS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
