<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 2004, Generation Rwanda, Inc. is a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization dedicated to helping orphans and other socially vulnerable young people in Rwanda pursue a university education and ultimately become leaders in fostering economic development and social reconciliation. Currently, Generation Rwanda provides 172 university scholarships to talented orphans and vulnerable young people who have overcome tremendous challenges as a result of the 1994 genocide and diseases such as HIV/AIDS. 

In a developing country such as Rwanda, a few hundred college graduates can have a tremendous impact on the entire country. Rwanda's development depends upon its ability to harness its intellectual and entrepreneurial talent. For this to be possible, all students who excel &#8211; not only the elite, but women, orphans, and other vulnerable youth &#8211; must have the opportunity to obtain a university degree and fulfill their potential.

The students we support are united by a desire to create a brighter future for themselves and for their country. Generation Rwanda invests in these promising leaders &#8211; providing them with housing, tutoring, computer training, healthcare, and other holistic support &#8211; so that they will be prepared to create meaningful and lasting change in Rwanda.

To learn more, please visit our website:
http://www.generationrwanda.org

Follow us on Twitter:
http://twitter.com/generationrw

And like us on Facebook: 
http://www.facebook.com/pages/Generation-Rwanda/112017542178355?ref=ts

1. Generation Rwanda's basic model is one of direct support to individuals. Ultimately, however, we hope to effect change on a systemic level.

2. Generation Rwanda aims, over time, to dramatically increase the number of university graduates and enhance the diversity of the university population.

3. We believe that Rwanda's development depends upon its ability to harness its intellectual and entrepreneurial talent.</description>
  <mission>Helping orphans and other socially vulnerable young people in Rwanda pursue a university education and ultimately become leaders in driving economic development and social reconciliation.</mission>
  <name>Generation Rwanda</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6566</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4275</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5894.46</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/BL/UM/2i/LD/1A/aP/bp/vzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
