<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Before you start reading about what VCFS is, let me start off by saying that the reason I started this cause is because I, myself, h ave VCFS. When I was born, I had quite a few surgeries. 2 on my heart and 2 on my cleft palate. Im not afraid or embarassed to admit that I have VCFS. If anything, Im proud of it. I managed to beat the odds when I was born. I survived and overcame a lot of obstacles. I know that there are many people out there who arent so lucky. So when reading the following, please take everything to heart. 

Velo-Cardio-Facial-Syndrom is a genetic syndrome with 180 different clinical features. However, not all of these features are found in each child that is born with VCFS. The most common features for VCFS are as follows: cleft palate (opening in the roof of the mouth), heart defects, characteristic facial appearance, minor learning problems and speech and feeding problems. VCFS wasn't recognized until 1978 by a man named Dr. Robert J. Shprintzen of the Center for Craniofacial Disorders at the Montefiore Medical Center in Bronx, New York. The cause of VCFS is still unknown. What is known is that it's a genetic disorder. This means that there is a problem with one or more of the genes which are found in every cell of the body that contain the instructions that tell cells what to do. Although the gene or genes that cause VCFS have not been identified, most of the children who have been diagnosed with this syndrome are missing a small part of chromosome 22. Scientists and physicians know that VCFS is an autosomal dominant disorder. This means that only one parent needs to have the gene for VCFS in order to pass it along to their children. How common is VCFS? Well, Cleft palate is the 4th most common birth defect affecting approximately one of every 700 live births. VCFS occurs in approximately 5 to 8% of children born with a cleft palate. It is estimated that over 130,000 individuals in the United States have this syndrome. 
http://www.vcfsef.org

1. to raise awareness</description>
  <mission>To raise awareness</mission>
  <name>Velo-Cardio-Facial-Syndrome (VCFS)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6574</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1576</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">674.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mA/Pv/nD/4f/OF/lO/ZqLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
