<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Otter Lake - Just north of North Bay, Ontario Canada is being put up for sale by the City of North Bay ( Mayor Victor Fedeli ) for the cost of around a million dollars.

This short term gain for the city's coffers = long-term sacrifice of a precious resource that should be enjoyed by the community for generations to come.

At present the City of North Bay is accepting offers on the property surrounding Otter Lake, until August 22nd, at which point the City will re-open discussion with the public regarding the sale of Otter Lake lands.

Groups in the area ( TLCA, NBHA, etc ) have begun a petition to STOP the complete blockage to the public to this beautiful lake.  A walking trail was cut in by volunteers from the groups in order to sustain a means for Nature lovers to be able to reach the lake as the City of North Bay has gated and locked the roads leading to the lake.

Please lend your support and download and sign the petition ( in PDF format at the following address  


http://venturenorth.com/otterlake/

You can also voice your opinion with the Mayor directly at victor.fedeli@cityofnorthbay.ca

Further contact information with the city is : 

So go ahead and voice your opinion and make sure the City knows that Otter Lake is NOT FOR SALE.

Jim Manning
Purchasing Manager
City of North Bay
PO Box 360
North Bay, Ontario, Canada
P1B 8H8

P: (705) 474 0626 ext 233
F: (705) 495 1024

jim.manning@cityofnorthbay.ca

1. Conservation of public access to Otter lake ( Near North Bay, ON )

2. Allow nature lovers access to the Otter Lake area 

3. Respect original sale of land from Ministry of Natural Resources to the City (Supposed to have sections of the area to remain parkland, with public acess trails allowed. (Something the city is re-negging on: BREECH OF TRUST? )</description>
  <mission>Conserve public access to Otter Lake (Third largest lake in the North Bay Region )</mission>
  <name>Save Otter Lake ( North Bay, Ontario )</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6579</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">21</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nA/VT/1G/JI/Z6/vh/UZvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
