<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The average american views Barack Obama as a moderate, likeable guy. Well, the average american is dead wrong. Barack Obama is the most liberal canidate out there, I mean, he makes Hillary Clinton look like Ronald Reagan. 

Some Barack Facts

- As a Illinois Senator Barack Obama voted against a law that would have protected the life of infants that survive partial birth abortion attempts. A similar law was passed unanimously by the US Senate. I know that people have diverse views regarding abortion, but I think that almost everyone can agree, that when a child is out of the mother's womb, breathing on its own, its alive. If you kill a human that is alive, its murder, in this case, infanticide.

- He is opposed to school vouchers. So if your stuck in the inner city, at some shitty-ass school, its your only choice. God forbid we privatize education, our kids might actually learn somthing.

- He's got some shady connections to a guy named Antoin Rezko. Rezko is an Illinois restaurant and real estate developer currently facing federal charges of attempted extortion, money laundering, and fraud. Rezko and Obama have done real estate deals together (that are being investigated). Rezko raised $60 grand for Obama's campaign. Obama then awarded a coveted internship with his Senate office to a Rezko business associate. (Incidentally, the business associate, John
Armanda, has donated $11,500 to Obama&#8217;s campaigns.) And he seemed like such a clean cut guy.

- And lets not forget that he supports "Universal Health Care" a euphemism for a socialist system in which we will have to wait months for basic treatment, that will be far inferior to current treatment. The real way to fix our healthcare system: stop illegal immigration, or atleast make them pay for the FREE treatment they currently recieve. Or should I say, the treatment YOU pay for them to have.



1. Barack Obama sucks

2. socialism sucks

3. freedom, and a free market, are great things</description>
  <mission>Prevent the election of socialist canidate Barack Obama</mission>
  <name>I'd Rather Vote For Hillary</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6585</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">21</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rd/oO/CI/DA/BX/TK/vdQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
