<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.edhifoundation.com/

Edhi foundation is a Non-Profit organization that has been in the business of providing desperately needed social services like medical care, emergency services, air ambulances, burial services, mental habitats, old homes, child welfare services, abused women safe houses and training facilities for the disadvantaged in South Asia.

Edhi plans mass campaigns against narcotics, illiteracy, population control and basic hygiene; along with providing maternal and infant in areas of high infant death rates. 


Edhi Foundation is the largest and most organized social welfare system in Pakistan and is a unique example of what ordinary people can achieve through sincerity of purpose, dedication and perseverance. By focusing on alleviation of human sufferings, Edhi Foundation has broken religious geographical and racial barriers, thus fostering the notion of welfare for all mankind. The broad ideological base provided by these aspects of the Foundation's work has helped to develop an exemplary social welfare institution within third world nations.

Edhi Foundation has a long history as a reputable, transparent organization, as well as its strong network in the Northern Areas and current mobilization.




1. A responsibility to help the disadvantaged.

2. International Relief will make our world beer.

3. Help struggling and developing nations reach their potential.</description>
  <mission>providing desperately needed social services in South Asia; to ensure international development and relief, to secure the futures of children internationally.</mission>
  <name>Edhi International Foundation: Aiding South Asia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/659</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4451</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2589.04</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Xrp/E7zS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
