<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Incentive Mentoring Program is a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization that provides intensive academic and social support to Baltimore City teenagers who are in immediate danger of being expelled from high-school. IMP has achieved a 100% graduation and 100% college acceptance rate by engaging students in activities that build self-worth, academic pride, and social responsibility. IMP strives to unite the people and resources of Baltimore in an effort to break the cycle of poverty, drugs, and lack of education. Generations of IMP alumni will create a powerful force of social change and establish a new cycle of learning, service, and social well-being. 

Although only 38.5% of Baltimore City children will receive a high school diploma on time, all fifteen members of the original IMP class of 2007 graduated high school with a combined total of 123 college acceptances and $1,000,000 in scholarships. IMP alumni are currently attending:

    * Bowdoin College

    * Purdue University

    * Frostburg State University

    * University of Maryland Eastern Shore

Only 2 of our students have not yet secured enough financial support to cover their tuition. Please donate if you can. No amount is too small, every dollar counts!

To join the IMP mailing list, please visit www.dunbar-imp.org

1. Participating in community service is an empowering experience for teenagers.

2. Social support, advocacy, and financial assistance are necessary in order to allow youth to make education a priority. 

3. Every individual has the power to succeed and should be encouraged to "dream big."</description>
  <mission>to change the life paths of students failing high school in Baltimore City.</mission>
  <name>Believe in Baltimore's Youth</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6590</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">184</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">77.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qR/fo/fi/oL/Uu/yA/w3/4xS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
