<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Covenant House Pennsylvania (CHPA), one of the most recent affiliates of Covenant House, was established in Philadelphia in 1999. Services began with a Community Outreach Center that worked predominately with street youth. Young people were offered a place to eat, do laundry and get referrals for more complex needs such as housing and medical care. Immediately it became obvious that we needed to expand services due to the large number of homeless youth who came to our doors with no place to go. 

Today we have grown to a diverse agency that provides a full continuum of services to meet the complex needs of homeless and runaway youth. These include Street Outreach, a 51-bed Crisis Center transitional living programs Rights of Passage (ROP) and Rights of Passage Apartment Living (ROPAL) and Community Service Center (CSC)."


http://www.covenanthousepa.org/aboutus/aboutus.htm


1. "The young people who come to Covenant House are welcomed without question or cost."

2. "Covenant House provides a safe haven from the hardships of the street and emphasizes the inherit worth of the young people we serve." 

3. "The program at covenant House is structured in order to help find direction and give them support."

4. "We enter into a relationship with our young people based on honesty, love, trust and respect."

5. "Our goal is to empower the youth we serve...The must choose to change and Covenant House helps them make informed decisions abut their future."</description>
  <mission>provide shelter for youth 21 and under. CHPA also offers vocational, educational, counseling and medical services to youth free of charge.</mission>
  <name>Support the Covenant House Philadelphia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6602</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eC/CK/EW/sN/ei/kv/XVRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
