<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;A HREF="http://www.operaamerica.org/"&gt;www.operaamerica.org&lt;/A&gt;

OPERA America - the nonprofit service organization for opera &#8211; leads and serves the entire opera community, supporting the creation, presentation, and enjoyment of opera. Artistic services help opera companies and creative and performing artists to improve the quality of productions and increase the creation and presentation of North American works. Information, technical, and administrative services to opera companies reflect the need for strengthened leadership among staff, trustees, and volunteers. 

More Information: 
OPERA America publishes both print and online newsletters and bulletins. These include Opera America magazine, addressing opera company news, issues in the field, repertoire, and updates on OPERA America programs and activities, and several membership directories to facilitate communications.

OPERA America has established itself as the authoritative source for information on the opera field. Its Information Service collects, analyzes, and disseminates data on the opera industry in North America, including performance activity and financial trends. Special research projects focus on specific issues, such as public perception of opera. Consulting services give member companies direct access to expert faculty in a variety of subjects (board development, marketing, fundraising, education, and more).  

OPERA America has been a leader in encouraging new works for more than two decades. Several special initiatives beginning with Opera for the 80s and Beyond approached the development of new work. Today, The Opera Fund makes grants from an endowment to encourage the creation, presentation, and enjoyment of new works. 



1. Raise the profile of opera across the country

2. Provide information on the opera field

3. Encourage and promote new works </description>
  <mission>To lead and serve the entire opera community, supporting the creation, presentation, and enjoyment of opera.</mission>
  <name>OPERA America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6605</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">281</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fd/Ty/jD/PM/ug/0Q/am/eeS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
