<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>News Flash: &#8220;Global Warming&#8221; Isn&#8217;t the End of the World

Whenever I hear the latest emanations from environmental hysterics, I think of England.  No, not like that &#8211; though, certainly that&#8217;s what I&#8217;d counsel politicians and others forced to nod politely along with mad rants on the subject for the sake of their own political viability to do.  

I&#8217;m thinking of England more than a thousand years ago &#8211; on December 31st in the year 999.  The people there were, based upon reasons which are obscure today, convinced that the world would end upon the arrival of the year 1000 so, on New Years&#8217; Eve, they all went outside to wait the return of Christ and, with that, the conclusion of human existence &#8211; and, of course, the world didn&#8217;t end and eventually everyone had to go back inside and get on with living their lives.  All that was suffered was a little embarrassment &#8211; and they all got a lesson.  So far as I&#8217;m aware, there&#8217;s no record of people ringing in the end of the world of December 31st 1009, or in 1019 or so on.  In that sense, at least, I suppose that it&#8217;s safe to say that our long-forgotten ancestors possessed a little more common sense than those who we are stuck with today.

Because, of course, this has &#8211; as the saying goes &#8211; all happened before...

Continued Here:
http://www.adamyoshida.com/2007/05/news-flash-global-warming-isnt-end-of.html

1. Climate change is primarily a natural, rather than man-made, phenomenon.

2. In any case, it won&#8217;t be the end of the world

3. It might actually be a very good thing for the West.</description>
  <mission>stand athwart the hysterical mass, driving us towards the cliff, yelling &#8220;stop.&#8221;</mission>
  <name>Stop Climate Hysteria</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/664</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">133</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/AU5/CBXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
