<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>An Iraqi girl, hands soaked in her dead father's blood, whose little brother does not yet understand that his childhood just came to an end. Fearing for their lives, US soldiers killed the parents in the front seat of the family car. Demons will likely haunt their nights. Stuff happens. Rumsfeld and Wolfowitz, bless their souls, will sleep well tonight. 

Wars never fail to produce their share of pithy lines. Tommy Franks made sure this one would be no exception. "We don't do body counts," crowed the general, who really meant to say that he does not do "dark-skinned body counts" (he counts the others just fine). Lucky for us that he doesn't run a Swedish newspaper, or it would have splashed the headline: "Tsunami kills 2,000 Swedes&#8212;and a few locals." But today's tactical thinking packs a wallop of self-righteous denial. We don't tally the children we kill for the same reason monsters don't buy mirrors: That's how they go through life thinking they're angels. 

We've snuffed out innocent lives in numbers that insurgents and terrorists could only dream of. But we avert our eyes. We bury our heads in the sand and turn a blind eye to our moral cowardice, thus pulling off the amazing feat of being ostriches and chickens all at once. We owe this marvel of ornithology to the inexorable fragility of human illusions. To quote James Carroll, "we avert our eyes because the war is a moral abyss. If we dare to look, as Nietzsche said, the abyss stares back." George Bush, the philosopher, has updated Berkeley's riddle: Do Iraqi children scream when the bombs fall if there is no one in the White House to hear them? 

"Cherishing children is the mark of a civilised society."

1. 400,000 Iraqi children suffer from chronic diarrhea and dangerous deficiencies of protein, according to a UN development report. Iraq's child malnutrition rate now roughly equals that of Burundi--a war-torn central African nation.

2. Malnutrition among small children in Iraq is widespread. Nearly one-quarter of Iraqi children now suffer chronic malnutrition, and 8 percent suffer acute malnutrition.

3. Illness levels among Iraqi children are also high, which is partly the result of unsafe drinking water and poor sanitation.</description>
  <mission>Raise money to help the Children of Iraq</mission>
  <name>Iraqi Children Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6649</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1313</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">635.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4S/uH/Oo/F3/8G/DL/boES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
