<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In the light of the recent attempted attacks on our great city of London; It is more than ever very important for us believers to stand with full of faith and pray for our city.


It is by the works of God that the recent attempted attacks was found out and prevented.


2 Chronicles 7:14 read "if my people, who are called by my name, will humble themselves and pray and seek my face and turn from their wicked ways, then will I hear from heaven and will forgive their sin and will heal their land. Now my eyes will be open and my ears attentive to the prayers offered in this place."


We, as the people of God (Church) are the answers and the solutions to all the problems in this city.


We are people called out and set apart for the world to know that we serve a living God. We are living in exciting times and as things seems to be getting worse, we are not to be afraid or be shaken as the world does. We are to stand firm, full of faith with our heads lifted up and our eyes on the Lord knowing that as situations grows worse our redemption is drawing near.


The Lord has promised to be with us even to the end of time and we know that He&#8217;s faithful to all his promises. Just as David said in Psalm 91: those who dwell in the shelter of the Most High will rest in the shadow of the almighty.. we will not fear the terror of night nor the arrow that flies by day... for though a thousand may fall at our side and ten thousand at our right hand, it will not come near us&#8230;


It&#8217;s time we let our little light of us shine. The people in our world more than ever needs to see and know the confident we have in our Lord.
For as the world goes in confusion and terror, we are to stand firm and be those who bring hope and assurance to them.


May the Almighty be with u all.


1. Therefore Pray for all the believers in this city to be able to stand and be ready to give an answer to the hope of which they professed.

2. Pray for all the churches in London, that they&#8217;ll be one as the father and the son are one and also to love each other, for it&#8217;s through this that the world will know that they are of God.

3. Pray for the outpouring of the spirit on the churches and the spirit of wisdom and revelation, so that they may know the Father better and understand the times they are living in and be ready.

4. Pray for the Leaders in the churches that they will seek God in all that they plan to do and be led by the spirit.

5. Pray for the prime minister and the local leaders in this city for Devine wisdom in their decisions and choices in these coming days.

6. Pray for the hand of the Almighty to be on the city of London to protect and thwart every evil plans that have been set for this city.

7. Finally as Jesus warns: "Be careful, or your hearts will be weighed down with dissipation, drunkenness and the anxieties of life, and that day will close on you unexpectedly like a trap. For it will come upon all those who live on the face of the whole ea</description>
  <mission>To pray for Healing and Protection of this great City</mission>
  <name>7-7-7: A DAY OF PRAYER FOR THE CITY OF LONDON</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6652</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">29</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Xw/Nw/3M/nP/h8/YH/UCaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
