<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>My goal is to raise money for the cure of Multiple Sclerosis. Though I do not have MS, i have come to know a hand full of people that do and i feel that i need to act and do something about it. 

SO, i have decided to take the challenge of this killer bike ride to Cedar Point in Sandusky, OHIO. it is going to be a 75 mile bike ride, and it is not going to be easy especially with my lack of time to train. This for me will definately be a challenge.. but its only for one day.. 7-8 hours tops, but for people with MS ..the challenge last much longer. This is the least i can do and any help or donations, support or love that you can give me is very much appreciated.

anyone can come and join me. just register at www.MSohiobike.org. its a $40 registration fee, however for a person to actually be able to ride...
they have to raise atleast $250.

if you feel like this is too much of a challenge for you then just come for support. 

come to Cedar Point meet me at the finish line and then lets have some fun at the amusment park. 

IF YOU ARE WILLING TO DONATE, TO HELP ME RIDE CONTACT ME PERSONALLY THROUGH FACE BOOK OR 440.227.3481

THE BENEFICIARY LISTED HERE GOES DIRECTLY TOWARDS THE NATIONAL MS SOCIETY RATHER THAN THE ACTUAL BIKE RIDE


THANK YOU FOR ALL YOUR LOVE AND SUPPORT.

"Ya know.. some people just don't get that peace comes from giving your life away... once you understand that... your golden."
-Chris Zeruca



Every hour of every day someone new is diagnosed with MS. This unpredictable disease can prevent people from continuing their careers, raising their families or simply walking from one place to another! 

While many of us will never know what it's like to live with MS, we can do something for those who do. Willpower vs. Fatigue. Training vs. excuses. You vs. yourself. It really doesn't matter where you start, because we all share a common finish. So, lets ride...and together, we can "Start to Finish MS."




1. Position #1</description>
  <mission>raise money to find a cure for MULTIPLE SCLEROSIS</mission>
  <name>Start to Finish MS - Pedal to the POINT</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6657</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0e/8N/vT/4x/TG/rO/5qDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
