<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>STUDENTS AGAINST SWEATSHOPS
Donate, Comment, or even take individual action.

A sweatshop is a factory where workers are forced to work with low wages, no benefits, long hours, cramped and unsanitary conditions. Many companies who use sweatshops prefer to use children so they can pay even less or nothing at all. Most sweatshop laborers don't even get paid enough to survive on. Thousands each year die from exhaustion caused by over work(12+ hours per day,7 days a week), injury from machinery, abuse by factory management, and sickness due to unsanitary conditions. Children are the majority of the people who die due to this immoral exploitation of workers.

Check the labels of the clothes you are buying.  Do some investigating.  Ask a store personnel if you're not sure.  Most clothing chains made outside of North America are in question.

** Refuse to use products made by the following companies: 

Nike, Adidas, The Gap, Old Navy, Disney, Kohl's, Reebok, Banana Republic, Tommy Hilfiger, Wal-Mart

** A small list of countries where sweatshops operate:

Mexico, China, Colombia, Pakistan, Bangladesh are just a few countries wherein sweatshop labour remains rampant.

** There are sweatshop-free alternatives to everything you need to buy:

*IKEA
*American Apparel
*Le Chateau 
*Purchasing used clothing through the thousands of second-hand shops located all over Canada
*No Sweat Apparel
http://www.nosweatapparel.com/miva/merchant.mv?Screen=PLST&amp;Store_Code=N
STUDENTS AGAINST SWEATSHOPS

1. Sweatshop labour cannot be tolerated on any scale

2. Every human is entitled to healthy work conditions and labour laws

3. Child labour must be prohibited</description>
  <mission>Spread awareness on the ongoing global problem that is the operation of sweatshops and unfair labour laws</mission>
  <name>Students Against Sweatshops</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6659</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">182</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Jg/1P/2H/OG/X8/rE/81NS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
