<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.chimphaven.org/index.cfm 
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eNIDva_SXyQ
http://www.chimphaven.org/news/Meet%20the%20CARE%20chimpanzees_18June07.pdf

Chimp Haven, Inc. is an independent, nonprofit organization whose mission is to provide lifetime care for chimpanzees no longer used for medical research, as pets or entertainers. The organization was founded in 1995 by professionals from the primatological, pharmaceutical, animal protection, zoo and business communities. Chimp Haven also provides education programs to students of all ages.

Our goals to design, construct, and manage humane, cost effective social housing for government-owned and other unwanted chimpanzees has become a reality. Chimp Haven may also serve as an umbrella organization for several national sanctuaries. We will build additional sanctuaries in warm weather regions that provide the most naturalistic environment for chimpanzees. Phase I construction is complete with construction for Phase II now underway for the first sanctuary in Keithville, Louisiana.

This new model of care for surplus chimpanzees will provide the following:

    * a permanent home where chimpanzees can live out their lives in large, naturalistic enclosures in complex social groups;
    * opportunities for education and behavioral studies;
    * an inexpensive low-maintenance facility design;
    * an endowment plan for the lifelong care of each chimpanzee; and
    * an organization managed by concerned individuals who specialize in chimpanzee care and management.



1. Provide lifetime care for chimpanzees no longer used for medical research, as pets or entertainers.

2. Design, construct, and manage humane, cost effective social housing for government-owned and other unwanted chimpanzees

3. Serve as an umbrella organization for several national sanctuaries</description>
  <mission>Provide lifetime care for chimpanzees no longer used for medical research, as pets or entertainers.</mission>
  <name>Chimphaven</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6675</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">345</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">585.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/XJ/4e/Y5/K2/wj/d6/XlqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
