<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>my name is Victor  Lopez an this is what i got to say.
Opression envy hate and people trying to step in our way is what LATIN ROOTS ENT has seen since we did our first event on march 14 2007 (LATIN SERIES THE BEGGINING). prove of this is what happen last WEDNESDAY JULY 4 2007 -- more the 1000 young latinos from across the GTA - and event ottawa showed up in front of BODY ENGLISH nIGHTCLUB. to be part of the much antisipated REGGAETON EN EL BARRIO 2 Organized by my good friend and a strong latin roots warrior george sanchez. all the artist mcs and djs where outside of the club from 7 pm. but the doors never opened and david winter the man incharged of special events for the club,, Never picked up no phone. actually the phone just went right to the machine.. everyone though the club managment was just delayed so they waited.  .line up starting forming and  by 9 pm ther was hundrends of people in the line up, lots of cars full of people in the parking lot, but yeat no one even there to say they were not opening the door...  by 10 pm.. it was ovious Body english Night club was not opening the doors...

NOW THIS IS THE QUESTIONS... WHAT THE FUCK HAPPEN..
LATIN ROOTS ENT GROUP AND BODY ENGLIGH HAD AN agreement .. the doors where to open on july 4..  so what went wrong..  ARE THIS WHITE PEOPLE IN POWER AFRAID OF LEETING LATIN ROOTS CONTINUE OUR MISSION..  are they afraid of  LATINOS UNITING.. ARE THEY AFRAID OF A PERUBIAN AND A COLOMBIAN THAT WANT MORE FOR ALL LATINOS... 

 MR SANCHEZ AND ME PAISA VICTOR LOPEZ.. where in the office of this club shaked hads whith owner and managment and they sayid the doors will be open the 4th..  we did our end.. now WHY THEY DID NOT OPEN THOSE DOORS..
people say sue them.. but can 2 spic ass imigrants really sue this millionare club owners 

Victor Lopez
Paisa Productions
Latin Roots Entertainment Group.\

LATINOS STAND UP!!!!  YA SE ACABO.

1. LATINOS STAND UP!!

2. LATINOS UNITE!!!

3. LATINO ROOTS ES FUTURO!!!</description>
  <mission>STOP RACISM STOP OPRESSION</mission>
  <name>BADYEGLISH SLAPS 1000 LATINOS</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6677</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nZ/P3/Qk/UJ/o0/Pv/U1mS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
