<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Rutgers Hillel creates opportunities for all Jewish students at Rutgers University&#8217;s New Brunswick/Piscataway campus to deepen their connection to Jewish identity and community. Hillel&#8217;s goal is to enrich the lives of Jewish undergraduate and graduate students so that they may enrich the Jewish people and the world.

Hillel is dedicated to creating a welcoming and inclusive environment for all Jewish college students, where they are encouraged to grow intellectually, spiritually and socially. Hillel helps students find a balance in being distinctively Jewish and universally human by encouraging them to pursue tzedek (social justice), tikkun olam (repairing the world) and Jewish learning, and to support Israel and global Jewish peoplehood. Hillel is committed to excellence, innovation, accountability and results.

Rutgers Hillel is the main gateway for Rutgers students to get involved in the many facets of Jewish life on campus.  With our students, faculty and staff we continuously strive to create a broadly defined Jewish campus culture, which is intrinsically intertwined with the culture of Rutgers University.  With approximately 5,000 Jewish students, Rutgers has the fourth largest Jewish population of any campus in the country, comprising 16% of the student body.  In addition, there are over two dozen different Jewish student groups working in partnership with Hillel or under Hillel auspices, which sponsor over 1,000 events and activities each year.

1. To be the main gateway for Rutgers students to get involved in Jewish life on campus.</description>
  <mission>The foundation for Jewish campus life at Rutgers University.</mission>
  <name>Rutgers Hillel</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6694</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">38</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Do/Th/wH/2q/vt/Mm/N0MS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
