<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>    The Nova Scotians, Ontarioans, Quebecoix and New Brunswickers have had there days in the Beer Aisles for far too long!!  
    Too many times, a Newfie has had to settle for the 'National' brands such as Canadian or Blue. If we must, we choose beers such as Moosehead, Sleeman's or Keith's for an actual 'beer' taste. As far as the Breweries are concerned, Keith's IS the East Coast beer. It may be a good beer. It may be a Damn Good beer! But it's not the Best East beer, that distinction belongs to BLUE STAR. 

     Blue Star is a brand of Bavarian-style lager beer, marketed in Newfoundland by Labatt Breweries of Canada.
Prior to its purchase by Labatt several decades ago, it was a very successful, independent Newfoundland
brewery. Throughout the '70s and '80s, its fortunes sagged, as consumers gravitated to the more mainstream
brands, such as Labatt Blue, Labatt Lite, Molson Canadian, and a competing local brand, Black Horse. (This concerns itself with the role of advertising in Blue Star's return to popularity over the five year period from
1990 to 1995.)
    
     It is high time that any Newfoundlander or Labradorian be able to walk into a Liquor Distributor or Cold Beer &amp; Wine Store anywhere in Western Canada &amp; buy cold Blue Star. Even if we could buy warm, that at least would be a start.
     Everytime you walk into a Liquor Store or Beer Store in BC or Alberta, we must demand that the start stocking BLUE STAR beer.

1. BLUE STAR beer is the best beer in Canada.

2. BC &amp; ALTA store immediately stock BLUE STAR Beer.

3. Bottles OR cans must be available</description>
  <mission>A day when any Ex-Patriot Newfoundland &amp; Labradorian to be able to buy Blue Star Beer ANYWHERE in BC or Alberta.(cold)</mission>
  <name>Blue Star Beer in Western Canada!!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6695</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">42</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2Q/uJ/WR/FM/fY/ej/wbuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
