<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>JOIN US SATURDAY OCTOBER 16TH @ BATTERY PARK AS WE WALK TO FIGHT, RAISE AWARNESS &amp; ULTIMATLEY FIND A CURE FOR LUPUS!

NEARLY 5 MILLION AMERICANS HAVE IT:: THATS MORE THAN HAVE AIDS, CEREBRAL PALSY, MULTIPLE SCLEROSIS, SICKLE-CELL ANEMIA, AND CYSTIC FIBROSIS COMBINEDDD!!! now tell me that isnt shocking and just down rights CRAZZZZZZZYYYYYYYYYY. . . .DOESNT THAT MAKE U WANNA JOIN MY TEAM, DONATE AND FINALLY FIND A CURE TO THIS FICIOUS DISEASE. . . .COME ON NOW. . .

3 SIMPLE STEPS::
1. STAY IN FOR A NIGHT (SAVE YOUR $)
2. DONATE $ YOU WOULD HAVE SPENT GOING OUT TO *LUPUS*
3. GET 3 FRIENDS TO JOIN YOU AND DO THE SAME =)

SIMPLY HAVE A NIGHT WITH US ON LUPUS! 
SIT A NIGHT OUT AND SKIP THE MOVIES, BAR, CLUB, DINNER, BOWLING, POOL, OR WHATEVER YA LIKE TO GET INTO. . . .
TAKE THE $ YOU WOULD HAVE USED FOR THAT NIGHT OUT AND DONATE IT TO A WORTHY CAUSE. . . .
THEN JOIN ME FOR OUR CELEBRATORY BLOCKBUSTER NIGHT TBA OR HAVE YOUR OWN IN HONOR OF LUPUS!!! =)
HAVE A NIGHT TO RELAX AND FEEL GOOD ABOUT YOURSELF FOR BECOMING PART OF THE CURE AND DONATING TO AN AMAZING CAUSE!

AND DONT FORGET TO JOIN TEAM BLU FOR OUR WALK!!!


**BUT WHAT IS LUPUS YA SAY. . . .
Lupus is a chronic, autoimmune disease that can damage any part of the body (skin, joints, and/or organs inside the body). Chronic means that the signs and symptoms tend to last longer than six weeks and often for many years. In lupus, something goes wrong with your immune system, which is the part of the body that fights off viruses, bacteria, and germs ("foreign invaders," like the flu). Normally our immune system produces proteins called antibodies that protect the body from these invaders. Autoimmune means your immune system cannot tell the difference between these foreign invaders and your body&#8217;s healthy tissues ("auto" means "self") and creates autoantibodies that attack and destroy healthy tissue. These autoantibodies cause inflammation, pain, and damage in various parts of the body.

However, the onset of the disease may be triggered by environmental factors such as infection, sunlight, or stress. In autoimmune disorders such as lupus, the immune system, which is designed to protect against infection, mistakenly attacks the body&#8217;s own tissues and organs. The major hallmark of this autoimmune attack is inflammation.  The course of the disease is unpredictable, with periods of illness (called flares) alternating with remissions. **


**WHAT ARE THE SYMPTOMS OF LUPUS AND HOW IS IT DIAGNOSED?!?!**
Unfortunately, the warning signs of lupus can mimic the warning signs of other diseases. Common symptoms of lupus include persistent low-grade fever, extreme fatigue, and painful or swollen joints. The so-called lupus rash, which often manifests as a butterfly-shaped reddish or purplish rash across the bridge of the nose and cheeks, is another common medical sign. However, no single test can be used to diagnose lupus, and it may take several months or years after symptoms first appear for doctors to make a definitive diagnosis. There are blood tests that a doctor can use to help diagnose lupus, but none of these tests are definitive. 



1. FIND A CURE FOR LUPUS

2. RAISE AWARNESS OF LUPUS

3. GET PEOPLE INVOLVED</description>
  <mission>TO BECOME PART OF THE CURE!!!</mission>
  <name>ALR LUPUS WALK *TEAM BLU*</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6702</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">40</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">60.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xJ/HO/eA/5o/b5/1U/5PBS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
