<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is ijtihad? 

Ijtihad (pronounced &#8220;ij-tee-had&#8221;) is Islam&#8217;s lost tradition of independent thinking. In the early centuries of Islam, thanks to the spirit of ijtihad, 135 schools of thought thrived. Inspired by ijtihad, Muslims gave the world inventions from the astrolabe to the university. So much of we consider "western" pop culture came from Muslims: the guitar, mocha coffee, even the ultra-Spanish expression "Ole!" (which has its root in the Arabic word for God, "Allah"). 

What happened to ijtihad? 

Toward the end of the 11th century, the "gates of ijtihad" were closed for entirely political reasons. During this time, the Muslim empire from Iraq in the east to Spain in the west was going through a series of internal upheavals. Dissident denominations were popping up and declaring their own runaway governments, which posed a threat to the main Muslim leader -- the caliph. Based in Baghdad, the caliph cracked down and closed ranks. Remember those 135 schools of thought mentioned above? They were deliberately reduced to four pretty conservative schools of thought. This led to a rigid reading of the Koran as well as to a series of legal opinions -- fatwas -- that scholars could no longer overturn or even question, but could now only imitate. To this very day, imitation of medieval norms has trumped innovation in Islam. It&#8217;s time to revive ijtihad to update Islam for the 21st century. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve created Project Ijtihad. 


1. To replace jidhadists with a new generation of "ijtihadists"

2. To build the world's most inclusive network of reform-minded Muslims and Non-Muslim Allies</description>
  <mission>To promote the spirit of Ijtihad, Islam&#8217;s own tradition of critical thinking, debate and dissent. </mission>
  <name>Ijtihad</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6705</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">60</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7g/6j/Fv/OJ/IK/Wj/AHjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
