<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>WE ARE SORRY TO ANNOUNCE BUT LYNK IS DEAD. HE HAS BEEN REPLACED BY EETH UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE. DONT REST IN PEACE LYNK, YOU ARE HURTING. ALTHOUGH EETH IS NOT HAPPY ABOUT THE NEW UPDATE, HE HAS NO CHOICE IN THE MATTER UNTIL SOMEONE ELSE IS FOUND TO FILL THE POSITION. 

WE ARE SORRY TO ANNOUNCE BUT LYNK IS DEAD. HE HAS BEEN REPLACED BY EETH UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE. DONT REST IN PEACE LYNK, YOU ARE HURTING. ALTHOUGH EETH IS NOT HAPPY ABOUT THE NEW UPDATE, HE HAS NO CHOICE IN THE MATTER UNTIL SOMEONE ELSE IS FOUND TO FILL THE POSITION. 
This cause should not be ignored, as it is a significant aid in the help of a young childs dreams.  Help us save the Lynk. 


If you do not know the Lynk, let me explain a little bit. 

As far as anyone knows, Lynk grew up on a farm in mexico, he had no family, and obviously no friends. He used to get stones thrown at him by little mexican kids while he walked around, he had no where to go.

He was diagnosed in his first year upon arrival to Canada with down syndrome but eventually the doctors realized thats just how he acts. Very low IQ.

This poor child has been through many studies, one doctor once called his deficiency: Daniella Lynkosis
The other doctors Didnt really seem to care all that much, they just laughed..  This is not a laughing issue people! This is serious!


 Ever since the Lynk came to this planet he's been cursed with what some people have said to be  the worst luck ever reported in history. I wouldnt doubt this for a second.  Now this isn't just a normal case of bad luck, were talking about some sick type of luck where anytime something comes out of his mouth, people cannot help but laugh and ridicule. Imagine living though this, i magine how it would affect your day to day life. 

This disease is very life threatening.

Please join us in fighting to find a cure for this poor childs illness. Please donate rdiculously.

1. The Lynk must not Survive, HES DEAD

2. Help find a cure. TOO LATE

3. Some call him lynk, some call him danny, hahah no just lynk. BUT HES DEAD NOW SO IT DOENT MATTER</description>
  <mission>WE ARE SORRY TO ANNOUNCE BUT LYNK IS DEAD. HE HAS BEEN REPLACED BY EETH UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE. 
</mission>
  <name>LYNK IS DEAD</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6708</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">17</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fw/y4/o5/fc/58/10/mpIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
