<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Birthright Israel, is an organization dedicated to helping Jews, aged 18-26, who have never been to Israel on an organized trip to travel to Israel for FREE. Birthright Israel's goals are to diminish the growing division between Israel and Jewish communities around the world; to strengthen the sense of solidarity among world Jewry; and to strengthen participants' personal Jewish identity and connection to the Jewish people.

As of Summer 2007, over 145,000 individuals from fifty-one different countries have participated since the trips began in the winter of 2000.

This Group is created for everyone who: has been to Israel, been on Birthright Israel, people who support Birthright Israel, to encourage all their Jewish friends to come and visit Israel.  We hope in the next five years hundreds of thousands more young Jews come to their Jewish Homeland.
**************************************
PLEASE INVITE YOUR JEWISH FRIENDS WHO HAVE BEEN TO ISRAEL OR HAVE YET TO COME!

Feel free to make a donation so Birthright can continue to bring Thousands of Jews a year to Israel.

Feel Free to Post Photos or Comments about Israel, what it means to you, your thoughts, etc!!
******************************************
This is not an official birthright Israel group

1. Israel is the Jewish Homeland

2. Every Jew has a RIGHT to visit and/or live in Israel

3. To be elegible for Birthright Israel, you must have a Jewish Father OR Mother

4. Every Jew should claim their Birthright!

5. You must have never been on a peer-education trip to Israel before to be elgible</description>
  <mission>Encourage every Jew to claim their Birthright by visiting Israel!</mission>
  <name>Birthright Israel: Claim Your Birthright!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6710</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1420</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Gq/1i/xb/3o/E4/lR/sgdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
