<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Many people across the United States believe that it is acceptable to own exotic felines as pets. The Exotic Feline Rescue Center in Center Point, Indiana rescues these felines from their abusive situations. The goal of the Exotic Feline Rescue Center is to not only provide a permanent home for abused felines but to educate the public about these felines. The Exotic Feline Rescue Center is currently home for 190 cats which include lions, tigers, leopards, cougars, bobcats, servals, ocelots, and one lynx. All money donated will go directly towards the Exotic Feline Rescue Center which is a non-profit organization. Donations are used to build new habitats, improve old habitats, provide food for the felines, and provide veterinary care for these felines. Please visit http://www.exoticfelinerescuecenter.org/home.html for more information.

The photo is a picture I took of George, one of the leopards we have at the EFRC. George and his brother Rodney were found in a home in Long Island, NY when the cops went to arrest a man for domestic abuse charges. The two leopards were running free with the children while the wife was chained to the staircase. This was not the first time the man had been in trouble for owning leopards. It is illegal to own any exotic animal in the state of New York.

1. Provide a permanent home for abused exotic felines.

2. Educate the public on exotic felines.

3. Prevent the further abuse of exotic felines.</description>
  <mission>Provide permanent homes for exotic felines that have been abused, abandoned or for some reason have nowhere to live out their lives, while educating the public about these beautiful cats</mission>
  <name>Exotic Feline Rescue Center</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6711</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2037</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">412.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/rt/ZK/xi/qx/A8/W3/CLpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
