<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Support Me in Walk Now for Autism!

I will be walking in Autism Speaks' Walk Now for Autism fund-raising event. Please support me with a donation by selecting the "Click Here to Sponsor Me" button. Together we can make a difference by advancing and accelerating autism research. So let's get walking and Walk Now for Autism!


I am actually doing this for people to sponsor me for the Walk Now for Autism walk that will be occurring this fall in Austin.  I am asking that you visit this site 

http://www.autismwalk.org/goto/heathernicole424

  You can either make a donation right there on the page....OR if you do not want to do it on the internet all you have to do is send me a message and i can give you my address where to send the check money order or whatever you decide to send.

Thank you everyone!

this really means a lot to me

Heather



what is autism?

autistic disorder, infantile autism, Kanner's syndrome or Kanner syndrome) is a neurodevelopmental disorder that manifests itself before the age of three years.[1] Children with autism are marked by impaired social interaction, impaired communication, and restricted and repetitive behavior.[2] These three characteristics reflect Leo Kanner's first reports of autism emphasizing "autistic aloneness" and "insistence on sameness".[3]

Autism is one of the five pervasive developmental disorders (PDD) or autism spectrum disorders (ASD), which have no outward physical characteristics. In most cases the causes of autism are not known and are controversial. Genetic risk factors have been confirmed; many environmental risk factors such as exposure to vaccines have been proposed but have not been confirmed by reliable studies.[4]



1. Autism needs to be cured.

2. There needs to be funding to help find a cure

3. This can make a difference in many peoples lives.</description>
  <mission>raise money for the Autism.</mission>
  <name>Autism Speaks &amp; Cure Autism Now</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6744</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3094</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">483.08</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/a1/ri/8G/0Q/RO/jT/OvTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
