<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For our community we will:

    * Visibly advocate for justice on behalf of all lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender (lgbt) people.
    * Reach out to lgbt persons and allies who share a connection with Mennonite and Church of the Brethren heritages.
    * Provide opportunities for lgbt persons and allies to nurture relationships, celebrate community, and build networks of solidarity, empowerment, support and care.
    * Provide intentional support and advocacy for lgbt youth and young adults.
    * Connect people with lgbt-positive theological and spiritual resources.
    * Empower individuals and groups to advocate for justice and work for change.
    * Acknowledge the limitations of our worldviews and commit to broadening our understanding and appreciation of human diversity.

For the church we will:

    * Be a persistent voice for an open and inclusive church.
    * Call congregations to be actively open and inclusive communities.
    * Hold denominational leadership accountable to their denomination&#8217;s vision of social justice, expecting fair play, honesty, integrity, risk and courage. 
    * Develop denominationally sensitive theological, biblical and spiritual resources.
    * Provide educational opportunities for our denominations and related educational institutions.

For society we will:

    * Participate in the broader social justice movement for lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender people by building alliances with other denominational and secular organizations who share similar concerns.
    * Responsibly advocate for religious practices and policies that support democratic visions and an inclusive society.
    * Intentionally connect our experiences of injustice with other forms of social discrimination and commit ourselves to resist oppression in all its forms.

http://www.bmclgbt.org</description>
  <mission>To cultivate an inclusive church and society and to care for the Mennonite and Brethren lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and allied community.</mission>
  <name>Brethren Mennonite Council for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Interests</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6762</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">554</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">365.04</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yr/4s/L0/1z/MI/rW/wT/XOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
