<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Trichotillomania and Dermatillomaina are what is known are Impulse Control Disorders. Sufferers from these afflictions are unable to control the impulse to pick at their skin or their hair. Although not specifically classified as OCD or Self Harm, both Trich and Derma sufferers often do have some sort of OCD attached to their behaviours.










1. Trichotillomania (Trich for short) is the name given to an impulse control disorder where sufferers, quite often unknowingly, pull out strands or clumps of hair. Sufferers are known to pull hair from their scalp, eyelashes, eyebrows, pubic region, and gen

2. Trichotillomania is often accompanied by Trichophagia. This is the impulse to eat hair or the roots of hair strands. After pulling out hair, many Trich sufferers will eat the white root of the hair stand and, in some more extreme cases, eat the entire hai

3. Dematillomania is an inpulse control disorder whereby the sufferer will pick at skin and scabs on the body. When accompanied by Trich, sufferers will often pick at their scalp. This behaviour causes scaring of the skin. Also associated with nail bitting, 

4. Dermatophagia is much like Trichophagia, whereby sufferers pick, chew and eat skin or scabs from their body. This is probably the least well addressed of the ICD's and there is very little support for sufferers.

5. To provide information for sufferers of Trich and Derma

6. To act as a support network for Trich and Derma sufferers

7. To promote awareness of Trich, Derma and other ICD's</description>
  <mission>Provide awareness, information and support for Trich and Derma sufferers.</mission>
  <name>Trichotillomania, Trichophagia, Dermatillomania and Dermatophagia Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6779</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">287</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PF/bV/xl/FT/Gw/6x/cGKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
