<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Have you ever been to "Exotic Wings &amp; Pet Things" in St. Clements, Ontario? Have you ever purchased a parrot from this party? Have you had an experience you'd like to share?

I personally have been to this "store/breeder" and am fully disgusted in the way they raise their birds. Their babies are kept in the basement with NO sunlight. They are stuffed in under-sized cages with barely any toys. They house birds together that are not compatible and end up harming their cage"mates".

I also purchased a parrot from these people and will share my experience...
I paid $1500 for my Lesser Sulphur Crested Cockatoo. I came to visit him 3 times/week. I was never allowed to see where he was kept. 2 days before I went to pick him up he has ALL of his tail feathers and the entirety of his wing feathers completely mutilated by his cage"mate" which turned out to be a Bare-Eyed Cockatoo (which tend to be more aggressive than lessers). I was not made aware of this until I came to pick him up (even though they had my phone number) and it was a part-time worked there that brought my bird to me. She had no idea what happened and when she went upstairs to get one of the owners, he blew me off telling the girl to say he was too busy to talk to me. Now that's customer service...

I called them later that night and was laughed at. They thought it was hilarious that the birds cage"mate" had "over preened" him. That was NOT preening...that was terrorizing! They didn't bother to offer any compensation and blew me off when I asked for it. I also e-mailed them a few times and they refused to reply.

I am sickly disturbed by the way they raise their birds, and I can't even imagine how the breeding pairs are housed. I'm guessing not very well since they seem to have every species under the sun in their stock.

They need to be stopped! If they want to raise parrots, then they need to do it right!

1. Parrots need spacious cages, a clean environment, TLC and toys!

2. Budgies, Cockatiels, Finches and Canaries cannot be kept in the same cage!

3. Exotic Wings needs to treat their birds properly or be shut down!</description>
  <mission>Shut down Exotic Wings &amp; Pet Things</mission>
  <name>Protect the Parrots</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6781</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">44</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hq/Co/ag/Tx/jg/ew/HYRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
