<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Agra should be promoted as a Lovers Paradise where every lover in the world would do anything just to be in a place which has the Most Magificant Symbol of Love ever could be made... Taj Mahal

Come on guys and girls everybody who ever feell in love, who knows what it is to be with the person whom u love, everyone who knows the value of true love &amp; even those who got hurt by falling in Love and suffer a lot of pain cauz it was that pain which changed u and made u what u are....

Love is happiness as well as pain.
And
Taj Mahal is its true Symbol, Cauz it was Shah-Jah's love to Mumtaz which made him make this for her for her happiness, while the construction ended with the pain in the heart that she is no more there to seee ittt...
But it was that love, which even after centuries exists everywhere, in everyone &amp; without which we cant even imagine what life would be or could ever bee..

So Never Stop Believing In The True Spirit Of Love.... Cauz even if you try to it will come knock your doors in one way or other at some point in your life.....

Trust me it would, otherwise facebook is here, this cause is here and i surely would always be here tooo... So if you ever think it isnt true, you surely could come here and say whatever you want toooo...

1. Agra has Taj Mahal but not the infastructure to compare that place with Paris or Rome. That the only reason rome, paris recieves ten times more foreigners than Agra do

2. If every individual do good on his part to help make Agraa that world place, i think we could make an drastic change.

3. To make not everybody just know Taj, but to make everybody see Taj &amp; fall in Love with the Symbol of Love</description>
  <mission>TO make Agra that amazing a place that people from all over the world just cannot resist comming here to experience it.</mission>
  <name>East or West Taj Mahal has Come up in the list of 7 Wonders of the World &amp; thats the best.......</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6790</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">16</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sn/Zk/u8/p8/U5/f5/AWfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
