<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Americans have always risen to meet the most important challenges to our nation&#8217;s and the world&#8217;s future.

Join us in persuading the American people &#8212; and people elsewhere in the world &#8211; of the importance and urgency of adopting and implementing effective and comprehensive solutions for the climate crisis.

The Alliance for Climate Protection is undertaking an unprecedented mass persuasion exercise based on scientific facts. Through a new combination of non-partisan alliances with Americans from all walks of life and innovative and far-reaching communication techniques the Alliance will focus on presenting the facts about climate change and its solutions to the general public in an accurate, clear and compelling manner.

Together, we can address the climate challenge domestically and provide a robust economy for now and for our children.

1. Move the USA past a &#8216;tipping point&#8217;, beyond which the majority of leaders in both major political parties and all sectors of civil society compete to offer genuinely effective proposals, policies, programs and laws that will sharply reduce emissions o

2. Generate overwhelming support&#8212;within the US and around the globe&#8212;for new American leadership in the international efforts to solve the climate crisis.

3. Pursuade individuals, families, communities, states, corporations and other organizations to begin to quickly and meaningfully reduce their own global warming pollution &#8212; and to offset the remainder &#8211; in order to become &#8216;carbon neutral.&#8217;

4. Create a critical mass of public opinion in support of active US participation in the international effort to enact a genuinely effective new treaty to reduce global greenhouse gas pollution.</description>
  <mission>The Alliance for Climate Protection (ACP), chaired by Al Gore, is addressing the climate crisis by enabling real, meaningful personal change.</mission>
  <name>People acting to solve the climate crisis</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6798</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1723</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">210.03</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nC/oV/Bx/6Y/vZ/5d/JqrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
