<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Welcome to the Sinfonia Educational Foundation! It is an exciting time for us as we work together to provide resources to enrich the lives of our current and future members and advance music in America.

MORE THAN JUST SCHOLARSHIPS:

The new Foundation is about more than just scholarships.  We breathe life into the Fraternity's mission and indirectly help to teach our members about philanthropy.  From Leadership Institute for collegians, to music outreach programs for children's hospitals and the elderly, to alcohol education and hazing prevention programs- the Foundation is the vehicle for enriching the Sinfonia experience for the next generation.

It is an exciting time in Sinfonia and the Fraternity is poised for a period of substantial growth.  An expansion in programs for the future of Sinfonia has emphasized the need for a more robust Foundation.  Advanced leadership training, professional development and philanthropic education represent the best of the fraternal tradition Sinfonia has to offer.  

THANK YOU FOR YOUR SUPPORT!

1. The vision of the Sinfonia Educational Foundation is to build a sizeable endowment and sustaining support for the strategic growth of Phi Mu Alpha.

2. Scholarships for collegiate students to recognize and encourage academic achievement.

3. Grants and awards to individuals and chapters in support of projects that further the educational goals of Phi Mu Alpha Sinfonia.

4. Sponsorship of educational and leadership development programs.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to enrich the lives of collegiate Sinfonians and advance music in America by supporting scholarship, education, and the development of leadership and noble ideals.</mission>
  <name>Sinfonia Educational Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/680</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4264</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2633.58</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/iHy/FvgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
