<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is not a cause to raise money!!  I am only aligned with this project because I was forced to do so in order for this cause to be heard.  If you choose to donate to the cause listed it it is entirely up to you, however I donot sanctify this group or any other.  It is only a personal decision, which I believe has the most power, for action and in the cause which I am trying so hard to instill not only in myself but in those around me,  speaks louder than throwing money at a cause but doing nothing in your daily life that  actually affects it. 

 Be Impeccable with your word.  This little endeavor is actually a social calling to raise awareness in the power that each one of us possesses to change the world.  To hate takes effort... but to love is only a heart beat away, only your heart can donate the life force which is needed. To spread the love through all human kind, only takes one breath: one breath to change the world; to make it a more powerful and loving place or to make it a more hateful place.  Each and every one of us has the power to change the world for better or for worse- we make a concious decision each time we open our mouth or respire, to either create black magic or white magic, each concious or unconcious decision we make will either add peace to the world or it will spread poison...either way it will culminate in a butterfly effect.   What mark shall we make upon the world... the choice is up to you. 

 May the wind be always on your back, may the sun be always on your face, may a smile be always in your heart, a song upon your lips, a dance in your step, and may you always feel peace, no matter which path you take.  Most importantly, may you find solace in who you are!! For this is the essence of being human!!  This is my wish for everyone of you!!    Smile and the world will smile with you, snarl- and you'll get better sevice..    Cheers to you all and may you always find joy within your soul and peace in your life...:)

1. Peace

2. Love

3. Understanding</description>
  <mission>To spread the love!!!</mission>
  <name>Peace and love for all</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6801</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ry/W2/fO/Lx/VH/8k/jJbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
