<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>2007 Weekend to End Breast Cancer

Last year, I joined an amazing group of people in a quest to raise money for important Breast Cancer research, education, services, and care.

My feet survived the walk and more importantly, helped to raise 4.5 million dollars in hope that, someday, there will be a cure for Breast Cancer. 

The spirit of this event was like no other and I will be forever touched by the profound support of friends, family, fellow walkers, and the community-- not to mention a few volunteers who set out to meet 1600 women in a single weekend!

Our endevour brought much laughter, a few tears, and a well deserved stop at Starbucks. 

Kidding aside, this was an irreplaceable experience which has reminded me that there is HOPE and that WE CAN make a difference. 

It is these reasons in which I find myself, once again, asking for your generous support as I tie up my laces for the 2007 Weekend to End Breast Cancer to take place August 10-12, 2007. Again I walk in memory of my mom, Brenda Hamer who lost her battle with breast cancer in August 1993.

Should you wish to donate, do not press DONATE- rather follow the Weekend to End Breast Cancer link on the below  (don't want to be giving our $$$ to the Americans!)

The Weekend to End Breast Cancer is a two-day, 60-kilometre walk through the neighbourhoods of Edmonton.

Proceeds benefit the Alberta Cancer Foundation.


1. Improve screening, education, and services

2. Provide Hope

3. Honour survivors and those who lost their battle with this dreaded disease</description>
  <mission>End Breast Cancer</mission>
  <name>Weekend to End Breast Cancer benefiting the Alberta Cancer Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6803</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fb/8c/0b/73/zc/Ws/sOwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
