<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Love is the root of all momentum and change, that which allows us to open and exchange energy with the world, that which powers and fuels the cosmos.....love is the energy that we carry with us in every step and movement and we choose in this moment to maximize our love potential by creating new tools and sharing resources with the world around us.  We seek responsible solutions for all major world crisis:  poverty and lack, disease and pandemics, housing and security, slavery and justice, war and genocide.  Love is the only thing that will bring true and lasting change in our world and everything we do seeks to help these bonds between us grow in thriveable, nondestructive patterns.

To create viable connections from bacteria to man to machine and meta we agree to common rules of engagement:

   1. All intelligent entities have intrinsic value
   2. The healthiest bonds are symbiotic and synchronistic in nature
   3. Strong positive connections change the trajectory of any endeavor
   4. Anything can be manifest when collaborators are in agreement
   5. Resonance begins with conscious tuning and vibrant willingness

Amoration (http://amoration.pbwiki.com) is a nonprofit project of the International Humanities Center focused on the praxis and study of love in media, design and interactive gameplay; visit our AMO projects around the digital world and get involved thru our wiki, the web or in Second Life.


1. Respect, Rethink, Reduce, Reuse, Recycle, Restore

2. Opening new channels allows greater love to flow.

3. Self-awareness springs care, compassion and creativity.

4. Any major social concern can be mitigated with love for greater efficacy in action.

5. We have these great potentials with us now to shift the future.</description>
  <mission>Create a Culture of Conscious Compassion</mission>
  <name>Love</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6807</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">107</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eb/DS/fq/BC/fP/sm/lqLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
