<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In a remote village located in the Kangra district and the foothills of the Himalayas, there lives a wonderful woman named Urmila. Her life was filled with pain and poverty; she was abused and battered. She was in deep despair. Urmila sought the help of Chinmaya Development Project in Sidhbari. She decided her children needed to be helped, so she built a home for them - brick by brick with her own hands. She learned to read and write. She joined the Mahila Mandal group (Women's Club) which met weekly. Here, each woman contributes $1 per month. The money is used when another woman comes in desperation. Here the women talk about their joys and sorrows, their ambitions and aspirations. They are gearing to make a change. Urmila began mushroom farming in her own home. Through the sale of the mushrooms, she educated her children. Urmila became instrumental in helping other women. Income generation schemes were rising all over the place and in many villages: animal husbandry, milk pasturizing, garden nurseries, honey production, etc. Voices together were making choices for a better future. Urmila did not stop. She, with a few other women, learned orchid growing. Through sterile methods of growing, they grew orchids and sold them all over India. Urmila is now a leader among women. Her experience from poverty and illiteracy to comfort and knowledge were now her very own tools to go forth into neighboring villages and show them that a woman is the pivoting force of change within a family. Today Urmila shines as a star of Chinmaya Tapovan Trust. You, too, can give a hand in providing the stability of women, such as Urmila, in the poor villages of India, by donating your contributions to Chinmaya Organization for Rural Development for the aid and teaching of these women. Your donation will be DOUBLED with the help of CIDA (Canadian International Development Agency). If you want to help, please don't wait. Your donation could help save a life today. So please act now!

1. To aid poverty-stricken rural communities become self-sufficient. 

2. To assist the disadvantaged with the basic necessities of life.</description>
  <mission>To alleviate suffering by providing training programs for mandatory education, preventative health care, and income generation techniques to raise standard of living and self esteem within families.</mission>
  <name>Chinmaya Organization for Rural Development</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6815</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">372</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">609.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xy/dw/Xj/y3/Qg/fj/dL/r3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
