<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&#8220;You don&#8217;t have to have a lump to have breast cancer.&#8221; &#8211;www.ibcresearch.org

Inflammatory Breast Cancer (IBC) is the most aggressive form of breast cancer and has a faster doubling time than other breast cancers. IBC usually grows in nests or sheets rather than a solid tumor, and causes inflammation because the cancer cells block the lymphatic vessels in the skin of the breast. IBC is hard to diagnose&#8212;it is not usually detected by mammograms or ultrasounds unless there is a defined tumor. Its symptoms resemble that of mastitis, a benign breast infection, as well as other diseases, and thus diagnosis may take a long time to occur. A biopsy that includes the skin and tissue in the layers below the skin&#8217;s surface is often the test that diagnoses IBC.

Symptoms of Inflammatory Breast Cancer
- Rapid, unusual increase in breast size
- Redness, rash, blotchiness on breast
- Persistent itching of breast or nipple
- A bruise on the breast that doesn't go away
- Lump or thickening of breast tissue. You may find pink or reddened areas often with the texture and thickness of an orange.
- Stabbing pain and/or soreness of breast.
- Feverish breast
- Swelling of lymph nodes under the arm or above the collarbone
- Dimpling or ridging of breast
- Flattening or retracting of nipple
- Nipple discharge or change in pigmented area around nipple

The Inflammatory Breast Cancer Research Foundation is a non-profit corporation dedicated to the support of research and public awareness. 100% of all donations go directly to support the mission and goals of the Foundation. The Foundation has no corporate sponsors and receives no grants; we rely solely on many small, tax-deductible voluntary donations to pursue our commitment to finding the causes of IBC. Please visit http://ibcresearch.org for more information.

1. To ignite interest in the study and research of inflammatory breast cancer at every level.  From researchers to physicians, educators and scientists, the IBC Research Foundation seeks to support and inspire those seeking to identify the cause(s) of inflam

2. To support research, the purpose of which is to reach an unambiguous definition of inflammatory breast cancer.  The clinical/pathological definition in use since the late 1800s with little change in the 1900s is ambiguous and doesn't result in a diagnosis

3. To increase awareness of IBC for primary care physicians, nursing professionals, and medical technicians in order to minimize the time from presentation of symptoms to correct diagnosis of inflammatory breast cancer.

4. To increase public awareness in an effort to encourage women to seek medical attention for common inflammatory breast cancer symptoms soon after they appear and to empower patients, caregivers, families and friends to pursue meaningful paths in support of</description>
  <mission>To assist scientists and researchers in their quest to determine the causes of inflammatory breast cancer so that effective detection, diagnosis, prevention, and treatment can be achieved.</mission>
  <name>Inflammatory Breast Cancer Research Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6820</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1919</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">138.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Oi/Ja/c2/US/mR/cJ/lofS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
