<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>UNAIDS and the WHO estimate that AIDS has killed more than 25 million people since it was first recognized in 1981, making it one of the most destructive epidemics in recorded history. Despite recent, improved access to antiretroviral treatment and care in many regions of the world, the AIDS epidemic claimed an estimated 2.8 million (between 2.4 and 3.3 million) lives in 2005 of which more than half a million (570,000) were children.

Globally, between 33.4 and 46 million people currently live with HIV. In 2005, between 3.4 and 6.2 million people were newly infected and between 2.4 and 3.3 million people with AIDS died, an increase from 2003 and the highest number since 1981.

Sub-Saharan Africa remains by far the worst affected region, with an estimated 21.6 to 27.4 million people currently living with HIV. Two million [1.5&#8211;3.0 million] of them are children younger than 15 years of age. More than 64% of all people living with HIV are in sub-Saharan Africa, as are more than three quarters (76%) of all women living with HIV. In 2005, there were 12.0 millionAIDS orphans living in sub-Saharan Africa 2005. South &amp; South East Asia are second worst affected with 15%. AIDS accounts for the deaths of 500,000 children in this region. Two-thirds of HIV/AIDS infections in Asia occur in India, with an estimated 5.7 million infections (estimated 3.4 &#8211; 9.4 million) (0.9% of population), surpassing South Africa's estimated 5.5 million (4.9&#8211;6.1 million) (11.9% of population) infections, making it the country with the highest number of HIV infections in the world.[110] In the 35 African nations with the highest prevalence, average life expectancy is 48.3 years&#8212; 6.5 years less than it would be without the disease.

1. No children must die from AIDS/HIV

2. Children affected by HIV / AIDS must get support

3. www.childliteracy.org</description>
  <mission>Helping children fight the challenges of HIV / AIDS</mission>
  <name>Help Children affected by HIV / AIDS</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6833</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">546724</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5411.92</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qw/lE/1t/TB/S3/PP/aSAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
