<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The public Nepali citizens are the ultimate sufferers of politicians' fight for power in Nepal. Prachanda's rage against Girija killed someone's father who was a simple policeman with a stick. Girija's defense killed the new 13 year old Maoist recruit. The World Bank's generous contributions went to the Swiss Bank Accounts instead of the poor and Gyanendra doesn't mean anything when he addresses "Fellow Countrymen.." Nepali lives are not worthless expenses for these political games!


A meek submission when one is chafing under a disability or a grievance which one would gladly see removed, not only does not make for unity, but makes the weak party acid, angry and prepares him for an opportunity to explode.
The widows and the orphans have been and are being helped, but we cannot &#8216;bless the souls of those who died without knowing why,&#8217; if we will not acquire the ground which has been hallowed by innocent blood and then erect a suitable memorial for them. It is not to serve, if I can help it, as a reminder of the foul deed but it shall serve as an encouragement to the nation that is better to die helpless and unarmed and as victims rather than as tyrants. I would have the future generations remember that we who witnessed the innocent dying did not ungratefully refuse to cherish their memory. It will be the spirit in which the memorial is erected that will decide its character.
- Mahatma Gandhi
Neither a Saint nor a Politician.
Young India, May 12, 1920



1. We do not need more politicians, We need patriotic heroes

2. Killing a poor farmer doesn't make you a hero.

3. Bombing the local policestation doesn't establish order, it simply establishes fear.

4. "Whatever it takes!" - Malcolm X</description>
  <mission>To Stop Political Conflict Which Runs On The Expense Of Nepali Lives.</mission>
  <name>Hamro Nepal</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6842</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5479</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.19</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/BC/3h/xD/PF/Rj/Wo/DapS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
