<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The pain and suffering of blindness is incalculable.&lt;br&gt;

The restoration of sight is priceless.&lt;br&gt;

In 1992, a call came from the Armenian Minister of Health: &#8220;Help us fight the growing wave of blindness.&#8221; Years of tragedy had taken a heavy toll on the dark eyes of Armenia, a country about the size of Maryland with three and one-half million people struggling toward a brighter future.&lt;br&gt;

Nestled between Turkey, Iran and Azerbaijan, Armenia suffered a devastating earthquake in 1988 that killed more than 50,000 and injured many more. The same year war broke out between Armenia and Azerbaijan, lasting six destructive years. By 1991, a major health care crisis existed and the call for help was issued. Teams of American ophthalmologists, many returning to their homeland, embarked on a mission to Armenia, taking with them medicine and equipment. Greater than half of the patients they treated were children and almost all were war casualties. Armenia&#8217;s critical need for eye care is caused by a variety and severity of eye diseases not seen in other countries combined with serious, long-term eye trauma complications &#8212;many from the land mines that still dot playgrounds and schoolyards. Particularly troubling is the alarming rate of childhood eye disease found in Armenian youth, including glaucoma and diabetes-related eye disease almost never seen in American youth and not manifested in Americans until their later years.&lt;br&gt;

More information could be found at www.eyecareproject.com

1. The restoration of sight is priceless.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to eliminate preventable blindness in Armenia, and make eye care accessible to all.</mission>
  <name>The Armenian Eyecare Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6845</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">123</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/QG/Yx/jD/84/65/IB/MjHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
