<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Employee Treatment Issues:
The average employee makes only $15,000 a year for full-time work. Most are denied even this poverty income, for they&#8217;re held to part-time work. While the company brags that 70% of its workers are full-time, at Wal-Mart "full time" is 28 hours a week, meaning they gross less than $11,000 a year.

Health-care benefits? Only if you&#8217;ve been there two years; then the plan hits you with such huge premiums that few can afford it-only 38% of Wal-Marters are covered.

"Wal-Mart is opposed to unionization," reads a company guidebook for supervisors. "You, as a manager, are expected to support the company&#8217;s position.

Wal-Mart is in fact rabidly anti-union, deploying teams of union-busters from Bentonville to any spot where there&#8217;s a whisper of organizing activity. "While unions might be appropriate for other companies, they have no place at Wal-Mart," a spokeswoman told a Texas reporter who was covering an NLRB hearing of the corporation.

Sidney Smith of Texas was the first Wal-Mart employee to join start a Wal-Mart union. "We signed [union] cards, and all hell broke loose," says Sidney Smith, one of the Jacksonville meat-cutters who established the first-ever Wal-Mart union in the U.S., voting in February 2000 to join the United Food and Commercial Workers. Eleven days later, Wal-Mart announced that it was closing the meat-cutting departments in all of its stores and would henceforth buy prepackaged meat elsewhere.

Wal-Mart is an unrepentant and recidivist violator of employee rights, drawing repeated convictions, fines, and the ire of judges from coast to coast. For example, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission has had to file more suits against the Bentonville billionaires club for cases of disability discrimination than any other corporation.

Workers&#8217; compensation laws, child-labor laws (1,400 violations in Maine alone), surveillance of employees-you name it, this corporation is a repeat offender.

1. Wal-mart must allow employees to join unions.

2. Wal-Mart must follow government regulated environmental standards.

3. Walmart is to be shut down... 

4. No more peonage in Bangladesh

5. No interderence from D.C., you are getting placed people killed</description>
  <mission>To Put An End To Walmart and End Wage Slavery</mission>
  <name>Anti-Walmart</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/685</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9800</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.37</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jb4/iitS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
