<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In addition, our mission is to activate the international grassroots support for Kevin Rudd by getting people involved over the internet.


Contact Info

kevin.rudd.mp@aph.gov.au.
http://www.kevin07.com.au
http://www.alp.org.au
==============
http://www.pm.gov.au/
==============
Griffith Electoral Office
630 Wynnum Road, Morningside
Brisbane, QLD, Australia 4170, Australia



There are generally two ways to introduce me. "I'm Kevin, I'm from Queensland, and I'm here to help", or alternatively, "His name is Kevin, he comes from Queensland and he is a menace," to quote Mr. Costello (not my biggest supporter).


I have been married for more than twenty-five years to my lovely wife Therese. I have three wonderful kids, a golden retriever called Abbey, and Jasper the cat.


Group Info also at http://facebook.com/group.php?gid=2408624482



Thank You!



================================
Federal Labor Launches Its Official 2007 Election Slogan
================================
Media Statement - 15th September 2007

Federal Labor today (September 15 at 10.45am) launched its official 2007 election slogan.

&#8220;New Leadership&#8221; was unveiled at the Dame Joan Sutherland Performing Arts Centre in Penrith.

Federal Labor Leader, Kevin Rudd, was the keynote speaker at the community gathering.

Mr Rudd outlined his vision for Australia&#8217;s future:

* Education revolution;
* National plan to fix our hospitals;
* Decisive action on climate change;
* Balance and fairness in the workplace;
* Maintaining our national security; and
* A strong economy that delivers for working families.

He was joined by Deputy Labor Leader, Ms Julia Gillard and Federal Labor candidate for Stirling, Mr Peter Tinley.

A number of senior Shadow Ministers and Federal Labor candidates also attended.



================================
KEVIN RUDD'S PLAN FOR AUSTRALIA'S FUTURE.
================================

An education revolution
My goal is for Australia to be the best educated nation in the world. We need an education revolution that starts at pre-school, includes state-of-the-art trades training centres in every Australian secondary school and flows through to TAFE and university.

A national plan to fix our hospitals
I will end the buck passing between Canberra and the States by investing $2 billion to take pressure off emergency departments and reduce waiting lists. If States don&#8217;t cooperate I&#8217;ll seek a mandate for the Commonwealth to take over delivery of health care services.

Decisive action on climate change and water
I will ratify Kyoto, set emissions targets, support clean coal technology, renewable resources like solar and wind power. I&#8217;ll also act to help secure our water supplies.

Balance and fairness in the workplace
I support balance and fairness in the workplace. I will get rid of the unfair WorkChoices laws and AWAs. Our unfair dismissal laws will provide special protections for small business.

Maintaining our national security
I will work with our allies and neighbours to strengthen Australia&#8217;s national security. I will negotiate the phased withdrawal of our combat troops from Iraq in consultation with our allies.

A strong economy that delivers for working families
I&#8217;m an economic conservative committed to budget surpluses and maintaining the independence of the Reserve Bank &#8211; all designed to put downward pressure on interest rates. I will keep the economy strong by investing in skills and infrastructure. I&#8217;ll also make sure our economy delivers for working families with policies on housing affordability and the cost of living.

KEVIN RUDD &amp; LABOR. NEW LEADERSHIP


================================
This cause initiated and created by Scott Lunammachak
================================</description>
  <mission>Elect Kevin Rudd for Prime Minister of Australia in 2007!    Join over **Six (6) Million* (6,015,885) people with this cause, and a World Record!</mission>
  <name>The Honourable Kevin Rudd | Our New Prime Minister of Australia! on Saturday November 24 2007!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6850</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3415</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bp/OL/uQ/ff/Mh/nu/md/0MS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
