<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>'' If you are not ready to die for it, then take off the word ' freedom ' from your vocabulary" - Malcolm X.

'Disastrous' is a simple word that sums up what happened to our country from destruction and corruption. 5000 thousand years ago our ancestors were the ones who spread civilization to the old world, they were the ones who established the early form of 'state' ruled by law and order , anyway, i am not giving all of you  history lessons because all of us know these facts.
What matters to us, are the recent events that really shook our country and totally annihilated hundreds of thousands of iraqis. Due to the awful lack of security, innocent civilians were caught in the middle, between the hammer of alqaeda (supported by our arab and Muslim brothers) and the anvil of the iraqi corrupted system and law forces. 
The Chaos is now really deep, it became a part of our daily living: the absence of strict law enforcement, is really clear in everywhere you go in iraq , our country is divided upon itself and our enemies around us are fulfilling their agendas. Do you know why, because a free and one iraq represents a threat to them. First of all establishing a democratic state in the heart of a troubled middle east, forms a direct threat to the totalitarian and corrupt arab governments. we, Iraqis from different sects and doctrines, should really overcome our differences and historic dilemmas, i know this is all fancy and dreamy, but, the change really starts in us. National reconciliation emerges from the public not from politicians.
I tried to be brief and I skipped going into politics and the explain the conspiracy against our country, I really hope that you spread the word of this cause and invite all of your friends. 

Thank you.



1. Living in our land is our right 

2. Iraq's revnues should be for all iraqis not for few 

3. Living peacfully together is necessary to rebulid what was destroyed </description>
  <mission>The name of this cause really stands for itself,bottom line we want IRAQ to rise again!</mission>
  <name>Free IRAQ , One IRAQ</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6860</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4669</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.13</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/n4/Du/lp/mB/WB/pc/bE/wES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
