<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Many atheists have experienced discrimination, mainly from religious entities. These may not always be so severe as to be called persecution, but they are indicative of the social rejection atheists have suffered through the ages. Persecution of atheists has persisted for the last two thousand years, and continues in most Islamic countries, Africa, Southern Asia, Latin America, and throughout the United States.

In the 1988 U.S. presidential campaign, Republican presidential candidate George H. W. Bush reportedly said, "I don't know that atheists should be regarded as citizens, nor should they be regarded as patriotic." In the United States, there is widespread disapproval of atheists. For example, according to motherjones.com, 52% of Americans claim they would not vote for a well-qualified atheist for president. More recently a 2007 Gallup poll produced nearly identical results. A 2006 study at the University of Minnesota showed atheists to be the most mistrusted minority among Americans. Notwithstanding such attitudes, atheists are legally protected from discrimination in the United States. They have been among the strongest advocates of the legal separation of church and state. American courts have regularly, if controversially, interpreted the constitutional requirement for separation of church and state as protecting the freedoms of non-believers, as well as prohibiting the establishment of any state religion. Atheists often sum up the legal situation with the phrase: "Freedom of religion also means freedom from religion." 

SOURCE: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discrimination_against_atheists


1. Atheists are forced to abide by laws that favor religion in even a secular nation such as the U.S.

2. Religion gets WAY TOO MUCH respect to the point where we're persecuted, and now's not the time to be nice about it!

3. One day, we'll look back on this injustice just as we do the slavery era and bang our heads on concrete.</description>
  <mission>To let people, especially our birdbrained politicians, know that pouncing on atheists and allowing the KKK to roam freely on the streets is characteristic of a mental disorder.</mission>
  <name>Enough with the atheist discrimination!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6861</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">650</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qK/Ux/p2/rO/XS/Gs/xsUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
