<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Multidisciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies (MAPS) is a membership-based, IRS-approved 501 (c) (3) non-profit research and educational organization. We assist scientists to design, fund, obtain approval for and report on studies into the risks and benefits of MDMA, psychedelic drugs and marijuana.

MAPS' mission is to sponsor scientific research designed to develop psychedelics and marijuana into FDA-approved prescription medicines, and to educate the public honestly about the risks and benefits of these drugs. Read our strategy statement for more information.

We need your support so together we can make a difference. In addition to general membership donations, MAPS is seeking to raise funds for specific research projects. These are our funding priorities and here are our financial reports.

With sound research results, psychedelic psychotherapy and medical marijuana research have the potential to help millions of people in alleviating the pain, psychological distress and other symptoms of such illnesses as cancer, AIDS and addiction. Research will also help us to better understand our human potential and bring the tools of science to the study of spirituality, meditation and mental functioning.


1. Scientific research designed to develop psychedelics and marijuana into FDA-approved prescription medicines should be sponsored.

2. The public should be realistically educated about the risks and benefits of psychedelics and marijuana.

3. The risks and benefits of MDMA, psychedelic drugs and marijuana should be scientifically studied and documented. </description>
  <mission>To assist scientists to design, obtain approval for, fund, conduct and report on research into the healing and spiritual potentials of psychedelics and marijuana.</mission>
  <name>Multidisciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6870</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3336</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2474.95</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/UP/Wr/TH/Cr/hp/Rx/t1/LbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
