<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Golan Heights is a region in southwestern Syria, occupied by Israel since the war of 1967. Prior to 1967 the Golan Heights was home to approximately 100,000 Syrians. But when Israel invaded the region in 1967, most of the Syrian population was forced to leave. Today, their number exceeds 500,000. They are still not allowed to go back to the homes and lands they left 40 years ago.

Few thousand Syrians remained in the Golan after 1967. Today they number about 16,000 who live in four villages. Most of the villages that existed before 1967 were destroyed by the Israelis, sometimes to pave way for illegal Israeli settlements. Despite condemnation from the UN and the international community, Israel has built more than 30 illegal settlements on the occupied territory.

Syria attempted to regain the Golan Heights during the war of 1973. Cease-fire agreements signed after the war granted Israeli withdrawal from a narrow strip of land that included the city of Quneitra. Syrian refugees returning to Quneitra in 1974 were shocked to find that most of their city had been razed to the ground. The city was systematically stripped by the Israelis before their withdrawal. The empty buildings were pulled apart with bulldozers. To this day, the flattened buildings still lie where they fell.

The Golan was the main topic in the Syrian- Israeli peace talks between 1991 and 1999. The talks reached a deadlock because of Israel&#8217;s refusal to withdraw from the Golan and implement UN resolutions 242 and 338, which demand a complete withdrawal from occupied Arab territories and resolution 479 which confirms the illegality of Israel's annexation of the Golan. For the past few years Israel has been persistently refusing Syrian calls to resume peace talks on the Golan Heights.

The suffering of the Golanis, living under occupation, in Israeli prisons, or awaiting their return to their homeland, still continues. Our mission is to support and promote their cause.

1. Israel must abide by international law and return the Golan Heights to Syria

2. Illegal Israeli settlements should be dismantled

3. Golani prisoners in Israeli jails must be released immediately

4. Syrian refugees from the Golan should be allowed to return to their homes</description>
  <mission>Support the cause of the occupied Golan Heights and its people</mission>
  <name>Free Golan</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6876</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6249</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.04</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tk/Gq/Jq/lI/HX/Ld/Ny/1LS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
