<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>While we are focused on serving the poor, sick and hungry, it has been overwhelming to see the changes that occur in our volunteers as they develop a greater global consciousness and desire to serve others. It is our belief that selfless acts of service will yield more humanistic doctors and altruistic members of the global community.

The success of our organization depends on active participation by both our student and alumni members. This aspect is what makes us different from most large international medical service organizations. We openly search for volunteers who have a desire to pursue service in their lives. Medical students often say, &#8220;I want to help people.&#8221; Physicians for Humanity provides opportunities for students and doctors to truly fulfill this goal.

We have made our vision clear to our new members. Our desire to continue giving back as professionals is well understood by participants (though not mandatory). Our current goal is to attain greater than 200 physicians over the next ten years who have participated in the Physicians for Humanity program. At that time, we will have an operating rotation cycle of physicians and students &#8211; working together at a myriad of clinics, hospitals and wellness centers.

As participation grows, we will broaden the range of clinics to serve other regions of Ecuador, new countries and underserved regions of the U.S. where medical and humanitarian relief is not needed. 

Please visit www.physiciansforhumanity.org for more information. 

1. To provide modern medical care to all who need this service, regardless of culture, religion, way of life, or geographic location.

2. To practically apply the Osteopathic philosophy (mind-body-spirit) in all medical and social interactions with the people we serve.

3. To provide ongoing opportunities for young volunteers to work and for those people in need of our services.

4. To serve and show sincere interest in the people and culture of those we are working for and with. Seeing and respecting those we serve is fundamental to the development of long term trust.</description>
  <mission>Physicians for Humanity(PFH) is a 501(c)3 non-profit corporation which provides medical and humanitarian service to indigent and marginalized populations.</mission>
  <name>Physicians for Humanity</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6884</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">203</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bH/dm/7Y/SN/ax/fk/0sHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
