<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Six years ago, physician and surfer Dr. Dave Jenkins went on a surf charter to the Mentawai Islands with one goal in mind: to find perfect waves.

The surf proved to be everything he had hoped for. What he also found, though, were the Mentawai people suffering and dying from the ravages of malaria and other preventable diseases. Troubled by the inequity of lifestyles and moved by compassion, Dr. Jenkins went on to establish SurfAid International, a non-profit organization dedicated to the alleviation of human suffering through community-based health programs.

In the years that have elapsed since the founding of SurfAid, others have joined in the effort, including individuals, international corporations, government agencies, and global health organizations. Coupled with the support of volunteers, the international surfing community, and most importantly the Mentawai people themselves, SurfAid has come to exemplify the healing power of cross-cultural partnerships.

SurfAid has expanded to include 53 villages and over 37,000 beneficiaries in our programme, which is a community development health initiative focusing on malaria control and childhood health. SurfAid is also laying the foundations for the communities to run their own health programs and build on the prevention of other diseases.

For more information, visit: http://www.surfaidinternational.org

1. SurfAid seeks the alleviation of suffering through health projects that enhance local capacities and promote community-based, self-help solutions, guided by the aspirations of its beneficiaries.

2. SurfAid embodies positive values inherent in surfing, namely individualism, courage, dynamism, and adaptability, and seeks to harness these attributes in implementing projects with measurable results. 

3. SurfAid believes that development should be sustainable and encompass the social, spiritual, cultural, and economic wellbeing of its beneficiaries.

4. SurfAid believes that the ultimate test of development policy is its long-term effect on the most vulnerable sectors of society, particularly women and children. To this end, SurfAid values and supports the central role of women in development.

5. SurfAid is a grassroots organization that recognizes that its strength lies in the strong participation of its members. SurfAid recognizes the value of an involved membership and seeks to encourage that involvement with accurate and transparent communicat

6. SurfAid believes that in all promotional activity, members should ensure that the dignity of beneficiaries is recognized and advanced.

7. SurfAid recognizes and values the professionalism, skills, and experience of our staff and their contributions to institutional learning and development.

8. SurfAid operates independently of any religious or political affiliation, while respecting diversity of race, gender, ethnicity, age, religion, and political affiliation. 

9. SurfAid believes that issues of justice, peace, human rights, and the protection of the environment cannot be separated from development. 

10. SurfAid embraces the spirit of surfing exploration and works to ensure that the consequences are positive for communities of surf-rich areas. </description>
  <mission>To improve the health of people living in isolated regions connected to us through surfing.</mission>
  <name>SurfAid International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6893</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">240</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/B1/Zf/SA/j6/zb/fX/yQaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
