<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Since 1927, St. Joseph's Indian School has been serving the Native American people in South Dakota. By responding to the needs of the whole child through an enriched and integrated living and learning environment, we provide opportunity for a balanced, healthy lifestyle through education, group home living, the development and appreciation of spirituality and culture, and the promotion of personal growth and self-esteem.

St. Joseph's Indian School has over 200 Lakota youth in grades one through nine, high school and college. Additionally, St. Joseph's is home to the Akta Lakota Museum &amp; Cultural Center. Visited by 30,000 persons each year, this museum was established to honor the Lakota people through cultural appreciation. The museum is home to numerous artifacts, artwork, pottery, dioramas and educational display cases. St. Joseph's also has pastoral outreaches on two reservations and a shelter for battered women and youth.

How to Contribute:
To make a contribution, you can donate here on Facebook (*) or you can donate through one of the methods located on the http://www.stjo.org/index.cfm?cat=97 St. Joseph's Indian School website.

Notes:
* For more information on how donations are handled through Facebook and Project Agape, visit their website. Project Agape uses JustGive.org which deducts 3% of donations to cover the transaction costs. Project Agape also deducts 1.5% of donations to help cover costs with providing this service on Facebook.

Visit us online http://www.stjo.org.

1. Every child should have the opportunity to develop emotionally, physically, cognitively, and spiritually

2. A child-centered approach is best facilitated through a team model

3. Children placed at St. Joseph's have a need to be here

4. Children model adults

5. Responsibility and accountability teach responsibility

6. Support from others builds self-esteem

7. Courtesy, mutual respect, honesty and shared commitment provide the best condition for success

8. Teaching a child to manage behavior will aid the child in learning self-control

9. Cultural diversification is an asset to the programming at St. Joseph's

10. Every person can learn and realize success

11. Spirituality is an integral part of each person</description>
  <mission>To provide the Lakota children with an enriched and integrated living and learning environment that responds to the needs of the whole person.</mission>
  <name>St. Joseph's Indian School</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6896</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">302</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1251.08</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jW/AP/lW/OS/bZ/BC/2kJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
