<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The problem. - 
Qualified, hardworking Americans are denied job opportunities, fired or otherwise discriminated against for reasons that have nothing to do with their performance and abilities. Employment discrimination based on sexual orientation or gender identity and expression, whether such orientation is real or perceived, effectively denies qualified individuals equality and opportunity in the workplace. Those who experience this form of discrimination have no recourse under current federal law.

Employment discrimination strikes at a fundamental American value &#8212; the right of each individual to do his or her job and contribute to society without facing unfair discrimination. Currently, federal law provides basic legal protection against employment discrimination on the basis of race, gender, religion, national origin or disability, but not sexual orientation or gender identity and gender expression.

What is the Employment Non-Discrimination Act? - 
ENDA is a federal bill that would address discrimination in the workplace by making it illegal to fire, refuse to hire or refuse to promote employees simply based on a person&#8217;s sexual orientation or gender identity. It would reinforce the principle that employment decisions should be based upon a person&#8217;s qualifications and job performance.

What about state laws? - 
In 33 states, it is legal to fire someone based on their sexual orientation. In 42 states, it is legal to do so based on gender identity.

What is HRC doing? - 
The Human Rights Campaign is working with its allies in Congress to pass the Employment Non-Discrimination Act, which would prohibit discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity, providing basic protection to ensure fairness in the workplace for Americans who are currently denied equal protection under the law.

Visit http://www.PassENDANow.org or http://www.hrc.org for more info.

1. Federal law should protect people from discrimination based on sexuality or gender identity.

2. Each individual has a right to do his or her job and contribute to society without facing unfair discrimination.

3. Employers should judge people based on workplace performance, and not unfounded biases or stereotypes.</description>
  <mission>Pass a federal workplace law ensuring that employees cannot be fired based on their sexual orientation or gender identity.</mission>
  <name>Employment Non-Discrimination Act</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6907</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">204</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ln/wI/TF/5T/iG/4p/nv2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
