<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>No child should live in a silent world!

The Auditory Verbal approach teaches deaf and hard of hearing children to listen and speak without the use of sign language or lip reading. 

Deaf and hard of hearing children CAN become independent communicators living in our hearing society with no limitations!

To hear and see the amazing work thats being done at the Auditory Verbal Center, visit the website at www.avchears.org and click on "Hear our kids!" for a one minute video of three of our Graduates.

-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*

As one Graduate, Samantha, said:

My parents found out that I was born profoundly deaf when I was 2 years old and the doctors said I was never going to be able to hear and speak. Instead of accepting what we've been told, we immediately started Auditory Verbal Therapy which taught me to hear and speak without the use of sign language and lip reading.

I guess AVC proved them wrong! : ) 

Now, as a graduate, I wear a hearing aid and an Advanced Bionics Cochlear Implant to help me hear enabling me to be an independent communicator living my life like any other hearing person! I can talk on the phone, listen to music, go to college, talk with my friends and I can even get a job wherever I want. Even though I'm profoundly deaf, I'm not limited on what I can do!

I just hope when other parents find out that their child was born deaf or hard of hearing, that they know there are other options besides sign language and lip reading.

-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*-*

Deaf and hard of hearing children CAN learn to hear and speak through the Auditory Verbal approach!

Check it out...
www.avchears.org






1. No child should live in a silent world!

2. Auditory Verbal approach is the way to go!

3. Deaf and hard of hearing children CAN learn to hear and speak without sign language or lip reading.

4. Deaf and hard of hearing people shouldn't be limited!</description>
  <mission>Giving voice and sound to the deaf or hard of hearing</mission>
  <name>Auditory Verbal Center, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6909</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">394</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ih/bB/HA/TF/mA/uC/2S6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
