<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>An Undeserved Reputation: A well-trained and socialized Rottweiler can provide the right owner with a great deal of exercise and loving companionship. They are usually quick to learn and have a strong desire to please their owners. They are intelligent, to the point that they shouldn't be left to their own devices, and are happiest when mentally stimulated. Despite this, they can also be strong willed at times, and should be taught in a firm, consistent manner. This is generally a calm breed. That said, they are playful animals, usually very excited at the first sign of fun. Rottweilers thrive on attention from their owners and need their people to be happy. If a Rottie has been neglected excessively, it will usually strive, creatively, to get the owner's attention.A Few Bad Habits: The Rottweiler is typically a dominant dog, and they can resort to aggressiveness in unfamiliar situations. The Rottie's large size and incredible strength make this an important point to consider, and for this reason the Rottweiler is a breed that only experienced dog owners should consider. Rottweiler owners who don't understand the breed's nature can face significant problems in handling such dogs when they reach adulthood. Early socialization with as many people, animals, and situations as possible is very important in order to produce a dog that is tolerant of strangers.

Bad Press: In recent years, the breed has received some negative publicity, primarily due to a lack of understanding of the breed and canine nature on the part of the owner, and indiscriminate breeding on the part of the breeder. Unscrupulous breeders have produced dogs with highly aggressive tendencies and some owners have used the dogs to boost their macho images. Other owners may acquire a Rottweiler for a family pet, but neglect to properly socialize and train the animal, resulting in a dangerous, unpredictable dog who makes the rules.




1. please help save what is left of my reputation

2. If u love this breed it needs all the help we can give it!!</description>
  <mission>to give it a name that it diserves to have.</mission>
  <name>save the Rottweilers reputation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6928</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5733</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.14</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cV/H3/VM/DS/AT/kb/Lv/UyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
