<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Tommy Thompson: A Reliable Conservative

    
* Tommy Thompson is the father of welfare reform, creating the groundbreaking Wisconsin Works program in Wisconsin that became the model for national and international reforms.
    
* Tommy Thompson created the first school choice program in the nation, giving thousands of Milwaukee students the choice of where they go to school &#8211; no matter where they live or how much money their parents make.
    
* As Governor, Tommy Thompson cut taxes 91 times to save taxpayers $16.4 billion.
    
* As Governor, Tommy Thompson used his veto pen more than 1,900 times to save taxpayers $287 million.
    
* Governor Thompson&#8217;s policies helped create more than 742,000 jobs.
    
* Governor Thompson signed a ban on partial-birth abortion.
    
* Under Governor Thompson, the number of adoptions in Wisconsin increased by 22 percent, while the number of abortions decreased by 37 percent.
   
* Governor Thompson appointed strict constructionist judges who do not legislate from the bench.
    
* Governor Thompson introduced truth-in-sentencing to Wisconsin, eliminating the charade of parole and mandatory release programs.
    
* Governor Thompson signed legislation that banned Wisconsin communities from passing anti-gun ordinances that are stricter than state law.
    
* After 10 years of failed attempts, Tommy Thompson led the way in introducing private-sector competition to the government-run Medicare program as part of the new prescription drug benefit.
    
* Tommy Thompson rebuilt an essentially non-existent bioterrorism defense capability in the Department of Health and Human Services &#8211; making federal, state and local governments better prepared to respond to an attack.

1. Proven Common sense Leadership

2. Strong Midwestern Values

3. A Remarkable Record as 4 term governor of Wisconsin

4. Career dedicated to public service and problem solving</description>
  <mission>Elect Tommy President in 2008</mission>
  <name>Tommy Thompson 2008</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6939</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dJ/je/uO/dc/Lf/tX/F31S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
