<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> 
There are two types of diabetes. With type 1 diabetes people don't make any insulin&#8212;a hormone that allows glucose (sugar) to enter the cells of your body to produce energy-and people with type 2 don't make enough insulin or are unable to utilize it properly (insulin resistance). A third of people with type 2 diabetes don't know they have it, and oftentimes people don't learn they have diabetes until they have eye problems, kidney damage, gum or nerve damage. 
Risk factors for type 2 diabetes include: 

About 18 million Americans have either type 1 or type 2 diabetes, and until recently, the two types&#8212;one caused by bad genes, the other by bad habits&#8212;seldom overlapped. But with the growing rise of childhood obesity, researchers are now finding that many kids are showing signs of both. 
eight-high body mass index (BMI) 
High blood pressure (hypertension) 
High cholesterol 
A history of diabetes during pregnancy (gestational diabetes) 
Ethnicity-African-American, Hispanic, or Pacific Islander 
A family history of the disease 
Physical inactivity  

 incidences of "double diabetes"&#8212;children with symptoms of both forms of the disease. 
About 18 million Americans have either type 1 or type 2 diabetes, and until recently, the two types&#8212;one caused by bad genes, the other by bad habits&#8212;seldom overlapped. researchers are now finding that many kids are showing signs of both. 

 where an equal mix of African American and white children diagnosed with diabetes were followed for nine years. The study found that 25 percent of the children originally diagnosed with type 1 diabetes went on to develop features of type 2 diabetes. Conversely, 50 percent of children with type 2 diabetes also had features of type 1. 

1. to find or support a cure for type 1+2 diabetes

2. developing ways to treat it more efficiantly(if no cure is to be found)</description>
  <mission>help cure diabetes</mission>
  <name>diabetics cure</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6940</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">112</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vT/NF/b7/vk/qa/7r/th/5kS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
