<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Scleroderma is an incurable auto immune disease that causes the body to over produce collegen (scar tissue.) This unneeded scar tissue, causes the body to become rigid and stone-like. It causes crippling of the hands and feet and an in-elasticity of the body's organs. This inelasticity, causes these organs to cease their function and can be the cause of a patient's death. many patients die from or Renal failure.

 It is most often found in young women. It tends to develop between the ages of 19 and 50, however there are cases of girls developing the most severe form of the disease in their early teens.

Scleroderma often strikes young mothers soon after childbirth. This can be a double whammy to the family of our patients.  These patients are often abandoned by family and  can barely take care of themselves much less infants and toddlers.

Although it affects over 300,000 people, Scleroderma is an ophan disease. It is hard to find research dollars or even doctors willing to investigate this uncurable illness.
 

The Scleroderma Foundation, is a national organization that sponsors research, patient support and awareness about this killing and crippling disease. This cause is about raising money, volunteers to support our patients and awareness about the disease both among doctors and patients as well as among the general public and the US Congress.

1. ERADICATE SCLERODERMA IN OUR LIFETIMES

2. Support PEER REVIEWED research projects

3. Increase federal funding for these research projects

4. Support patients through volunteerism, and finacial support for educational materials and support groups

5. Raise awareness about the disease by helping to focus media and word of mouth attention on the plight of those affected</description>
  <mission>Eradicate Scleroderma in our Lifetime</mission>
  <name>Eradicate Scleroderma</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6950</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">55</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">135.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/VA/wQ/Ao/G1/uP/e8/QvRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
