<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.vhemt.org/aboutvhemt.htm#vhemt - (pronounced vehement) 
 Advanced by people who care about life on planet Earth. We're not a bunch of misanthropes and anti-social, malthusian misfits, taking morbid delight when disaster strikes humans.  VHEMT is the humanitarian alternative to human disasters. We don't drone about how the human race has shown itself to be a greedy, amoral parasite on the once-healthy face of this planet. That type of negativity offers no solution to the inexorable horrors which human activity is causing. VHEMT presents an encouraging alternative to the callous exploitation and wholesale destruction of Earth's ecology. Each time another one of us decides to not add another one of us to the burgeoning billions already squatting on this ravaged planet, another ray of hope shines through the gloom.
 Being VHEMT is a state of mind. It's is a concept to be added to existing belief systems, not a complex code of behavior to live by. No committee of movement shakers decides what position everyone else should take.  
 The only action required for becoming a VHEMT Volunteer or Supporter is not adding another human being to the population. A couple could conceivably be expecting and decide to become VHEMT. That new human would be the last one they produced. VHEMT Supporters are agree that no more of us should be created at this time. 
 Volunteers are diverse in religious, political, and philosophical views that it would be divisive to begin formulating official movement positions. Beware of dogmas. We speak with our own voices. 
 We are millions of individuals, each doing what we feel is best. VHEMT requires more awareness than funds, and since Causes app requires a registered charity to exist, proceeds will go to an organization with a parallel ultimate objective.
 Please read about page before making critical assumptions. 

1. May we live long and die out.

2. VHEMT Supporters are not necessarily in favor of human extinction, but agree that no more of us should be created at this time.

3. We are a movement, not an organization</description>
  <mission>Phasing out the human race by voluntarily ceasing to breed will allow Earth's biosphere to return to good health.</mission>
  <name>The Voluntary Human Extinction Movement</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6954</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">224</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.04</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/EP/QT/pt/hH/CX/kL/imXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
