<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Capetonians are sharing some warmth this winter by donating blankets, clothes and food to the needy in the Mother City thanks to an initiative spearheaded by Good Hope FM. Good Hope FM, the Cape Town City Improvement District and Community Chest have once again joined forces for the worthy "Keep Cape Town Warm" campaign which supports communities most severely affected by the adverse Cape winter weather conditions. Listeners are asked to donate clothes, blankets and non perishable foods to help those in desperate need. Good Hope FM has put its full resources behind the project. Nigel Pierce is also challenging listeners and corporates to donate blankets through his Nigel Pierce's Make a Blanket Statement. DJ Suga is challenging corporates to set-up drop off points at their offices. Employees are asked to call in to the station every week to update Suga on the amount of donations collected. The company that collects the most will win a Cape Town Shakedown live broadcast from their offices. Sfiso Maggz is focusing on the food and challenging people to donate non-perishable foods in a campaign entitled The Maggz Munchies. Ryan O'Connor will be visiting various soup kitchens in the city to cook and serve meals to the homeless people. The drop -off points for the donations are at Good Hope FM studios at 209 Beach Road in Sea Point; the Terraces Building on 34 Bree Street or at the Information Centre in St George's Mall. The blankets will be distributed to NGOs and charities in Cape Town. Join in the challenge and show that you care. 

1. Help Cape Town's Needy</description>
  <mission>Join in the challenge and show that you care.</mission>
  <name>Keep Cape Town Warm with GHFM</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6961</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ya/yN/3Q/YU/p8/Vw/fgjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
