<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>At the turn of the 19th Century there were 1 million rhinos across Africa and Asia.  Today there are fewer than 21,000, with three of the five species being classed as critically endangered. This dramatic decline can be solely attributed to the actions of man, be it through poaching or habitat destruction.

At Save the Rhino, we work to increase rhino numbers in the wild by providing financial and in-kind support for rhino projects and for community-based initiatives. 

Aims:
To increase the number of rhinos in genetically viable populations in the wild 
To provide financial and in-kind support for projects focused on all five of the rhinoceros species 
To encourage and enable the sharing of information, experience and skills between rhino projects 
To measure and improve the effectiveness of our grant-making activities

What we fund:
Community conservation programmes that develop sustainable methods by which local communities can creatively manage natural resources 
Environmental education programmes that teach children and adults about the importance of preserving natural resources and address human-wildlife conflict issues 
Anti-poaching and monitoring patrols, which detect and deter poachers and gather information about rhino ranges and numbers 
Translocations, so that rhinos from established populations can be reintroduced to former habitats 
Research into the threats to rhino survival and alternatives to the use of rhino horn 
Veterinary work, such as the implanting of transmitters into horns, or removal of snares

1. We employ a pragmatic approach focused on viable populations, and are not sentiment-driven 

2. We support the sustainable use of natural resources for the mutual benefit of wildlife, habitat and local communities

3. We do not create or run our own projects in the field; rather, we find rhino conservation projects that we think are doing a good job, and then fund them

4. We prefer to work with projects on a long-term basis, rather than making one-off or ad hoc grants

5. SRI is a fundraising organisation, not a campaigning one: we do not get involved in political lobbying or petitioning

6. We believe in the value of partnership working with other in situ and ex situ NGOs and conservation organisations</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to conserve genetically viable populations of critically endangered rhinoceros species in the wild.</mission>
  <name>Save the Rhino International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6968</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2581</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">745.55</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/k4/rZ/Ev/ak/rZ/Mw/CsYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
