<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;NYCwireless (http://www.nycwireless.net) is a non-profit organization that advocates and enables the growth of free, public wireless Internet access in New York City and surrounding areas. NYCwireless, founded in 2001, is an all-volunteer organization with seven (7) board members, five (5) special interest working groups and serves thousands of individuals throughout the New York City metro area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among U.S. cities, New York has been a hotspot of activity with respect the development and use of public wireless access to the high-speed (or broadband) Internet. NYCwireless has been leading that movement. Originally started as an informal group of wireless technology enthusiasts, NYCwireless has grown into a multi-faceted organization that helps individuals and communities all across New York City to use wireless technology to provide free, public Internet access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past several years, NYCwireless has built free, public wireless networks in over ten New York City parks and open spaces through partnerships with local parks organizations such as the Bryant Park Restoration Corporation and business improvement districts such as the Alliance for Downtown New York. These include networks in Bryant Park, Union Square Park (in partnership with commercial wireless Internet provider TowerStream), Tompkins Square Park, Bowling Green Park, City Hall Park, and the South Street Seaport among others. In addition, the organization has created community engagement programs that take advantage of wireless networks in Manhattan, such as our annual wireless arts festival, Spectropolis (http://www.spectropolis.info).&lt;/p&gt;

1. Public internet access should be available for free for everyone

2. Everyone should have access to affordable, high-speed internet access at home and at work</description>
  <mission>Bring free Wi-Fi to public places in NYC</mission>
  <name>NYCwireless</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6971</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">32</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fv/gn/AS/5h/Y6/yt/ZWAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
