<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It was observed first in WWI in an effort to reduce fuel costs of lighting, but this has a backwards logic when we 'spring ahead' and suddenly it's dark again during the school year. Natural light in the morning reduces energy costs, and doesn&#8217;t translate into an extra hour of lighting energy in the evening.  People will get up at the same time everyday regardless, but then with night coming 'sooner', our bodies naturally fall into their sleep cycles. This consequentially leads to a better slept population, which is happier, more productive, &amp; better adjusted. The change of just one hour can affect one's circadian rhythms adversely. There are several studies which show an increase in traffic accidents the day following the spring ahead, which are causally linked to the hour&#8217;s loss of sleep. Links can even be made to &#8216;darker&#8217; days furthering Seasonal Affective Disorder (SAD). Finally, during the summer, the workforce and businesses can benefit from the productivity gained by earlier rising with the sun, rather than later bedding. It has been proven that people who are early risers have better attitudes and can generally out perform those who postpone sleep or sleepiness. Extra time in the morning, even if spent at home relaxing or getting chores done before work, promotes a less stressful existence and balances good health habits with productivity.

When did the US govn&#8217;t get so high on their own egotism to they think that they can legislate time; can they legislate the sun to set an hour later?

For years, farmers have rallied against the use of daylight savings time.  It&#8217;s of no use to them since they have to get up with the sun irregardless, nor does it help the crops.

And as a final thought, who can actually give a compelling argument for it?


1. reduce energy costs due to artificial lighting in the mornings

2. promote a healthier society by allowing circadian rhythms to flow naturally

3. promote safety of children walking to the bus in the morning

4. help farmers and the farming community

5. who wants to change their watch just for a day trip to Chicago, and how can you ever really be sure?</description>
  <mission>To abolish the now defunct and otherwise antiquated system of daylight savings (God bless Ben Franklins heart though).</mission>
  <name>Abolish Daylight Saving</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6973</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">70</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ob/DK/O8/WG/i0/yx/F7tS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
