<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Trafficking of human beings is a widespread phenomenon in almost all countries of the world, whether on the supply or demand side. This appalling phenomenon is not new; it has plagued history for years under the label of slavery. Today, slavery is outlawed in almost every country, however the practices continue to thrive under a different title &#8211; human trafficking.

This highly lucrative &#8220;business&#8221; is a denial of the basic human rights that are provided to every person in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. &#8220;No one shall be held in slavery or servitude; slavery and the slave trade shall be prohibited in all their forms.&#8221;  Despite this, modern day slavery is still largely deemed 'acceptable' through a lack of uniform and robust international action. Only in the past few years has the international community began to address this issue, however the action initiated still leaves much to be desired. &#8220;[The Human Trafficking Report states that] no country is immune from trafficking,&#8221; and estimates that approximately 800,000 to 900,000 people are trafficked across international borders worldwide. This figure doesn&#8217;t include internal trafficking, which some observers estimate would raise the number to more than 2 million.  Sadly, the report adds that &#8220;human trafficking not only continues but appears to be on the rise worldwide,&#8221; the overwhelming majority of victims are women and children. 

Victimization of the most vulnerable sections of the global society will continue unabated and genuine protection avoided unless the international community recognizes this injustice and calls for change.

Some Important Informational Links:

&#8220;Trafficking in Human Beings.&#8221;
http://www.answers.com/topic/trafficking-in-human-bein

"Human Rights Watch: Trafficking."
http://hrw.org/doc/?t=women_trafficking&amp;document_limit=20,20

"U.S. Department of State: Trafficking in Persons Report." [PDF]
http://www.state.gov/documents/organization/47255

1. The international community must take steps to end human trafficking.

2. The rights of all human beings must be protected.</description>
  <mission>to raise awareness of human trafficking as a means to ending it.</mission>
  <name>Stop Human Trafficking!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6979</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">98</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/El/tX/Bl/px/yb/TT/CzoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
