<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>United Jewish Fund and Council (the Jewish Federation of Greater St. Paul), supports critical programs and services that tens of thousands of Jews, both locally and abroad, rely on. As the economic situation worsens, we know that thousands more may seek help. From hunger relief to job training and placement, from counseling to financial assistance, we are committed to continue providing these services to those who need them most. 

But we need your help. NOW MORE THAN EVER.  Your gift makes a difference!  Please support your local and overseas community by donating today.  THANK YOU.

UJFC Beneficiary Agencies:

-American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee 
-Hillel: Foundation for Jewish Campus Life at the University of Minnesota
-The Jewish Agency For Israel 
-The Jewish Community Center of the Greater St. Paul Area 
-The Jewish Community Relations Council of Minnesota and the Dakotas 
-Jewish Family Service of St. Paul
-Sholom Community Alliance 
-The Talmud Torah of St. Paul
-Chabad Lubavich Cheder
-The Minnesota Jewish Theater Company

1. GIVING TO THOSE IN NEED:  Funding local programs helping the elderly &amp; families with food, healthcare, housing, counseling &amp; social activities.

2. GIVING TO ISRAEL &amp; THE WORLD:  Providing food, clothing and educational needs to Jews in Israel &amp; 65 other countries.

3. GIVING FOR THE FUTURE OF OUR COMMUNITY:  Funding Jewish K-12 education, providing scholarships &amp; Jewish youth programming.

4. Watch a video about what we do &amp; learn more at http://www.jewishstpaul.org</description>
  <mission>Support Jews in need through the United Jewish Fund and Council: the umbrella fundraising organization for local and overseas Jewish community programs, services and humanitarian aid since 1935.</mission>
  <name>Kosher Meals on Wheels</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6980</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">70</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">106.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/AK/cg/Ih/Va/ze/nN/fY/nLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
