<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Obstetric fistula is a childbearing injury that affects over two million women in the developing world, leaving them physically and socially debilitated.  Caused by an obstructed labor that can last up to five or six days, a woman often loses her baby and is left with damage so extensive from the constant pushing that she develops holes - or fistulas - in her birthing canal, causing her to leak urine or feces or both continuously for the rest of her life.  

Luckily, fistula repair surgeries are available for women which can repair their fistulas and give them a new chance at a normal life.  However it is estimated to cost approximately $350 for each repair surgery - far too much for women living with fistula who are often the most removed and poor of African societies.

LOVE, LABOR, LOSS is a film-based campaign that seeks to educate and mobilize new audiences in the fight to end fistula.  We provide a compelling 15-minute Advocacy Video about obstetric fistula in Niger that can be screened at fundraisers, on college campuses, at high schools and with community groups to raise awareness and funds for fistula repair and prevention programs.

To learn more about fistula and to order a copy of the film to screen in your community, please visit www.lovelaborloss.com.



1. Safe pregnancy and delivery is a right for all women.

2. Obstetric fistula is both preventable and treatable.

3. Change begins with consciousness.  Educate yourself and others about fistula.</description>
  <mission>is a film-based campaign to raise awareness, raise funds and influence legislation to help end obstetric fistula.</mission>
  <name>LOVE LABOR LOSS (www.lovelaborloss.com)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6981</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">611</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">5.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3v/ds/Ot/hl/xa/4a/AY5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
