<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>HIV/AIDS is a worldwide epidemic. There are currently 39.4 million people living with HIV/AIDS, including 37.2 million adults and 2.2 million children. In 2004, 3.1 million people died from the virus, while 4.9 million new cases were reported. There is no proven effective cure to HIV/AID so the importance of raising awareness to preventative measures is imperative.  This need to be done throughout the world, however especially within the countries where HIV/AIDS is spreading most rapidly&#8212;which is by and large Sub-Saharan Africa where the adult prevalence rate stands at 8.8% (as compared to a 1.1% global rate or that of the next highest region, the Caribbean at 2.3%).  In 2000, alone, there were 3.8 million newly infected persons in Sub-Saharan Africa, 71.7% of those in the World.  

While the international community has begun to recognize the threat that HIV/AIDS poses to the international community&#8217;s well-being, not enough is being done, especially in the areas in which help is direly needed.  For this reason the members of Student World Assembly recognized HIV/AIDS as 2006&#8217;s most pressing global issue.  The international conference in 2006 highlighted numerous aspects of the HIV/AIDS epidemic in the form of workshops, panel discussions, and keynote addresses.  Conferences such as this are just the beginning; SWA seeks to raise awareness of HIV/AID worldwide by sponsoring events and encouraging members in the prevalent regions to take action.

Some Important Informational Links:

"AEGIS - The History of HIV / AIDS"
http://www.aegis.com/topics/timeline/default.asp

"U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services - Centers for Disease Control &amp; Prevention: HIV / AIDS Prevention"
http://www.cdc.gov/hiv/dhap.htm

"Kaiser Family Foundation - AID information homepage"
http://www.kff.org/hivaids/index.cfm

1. HIV/AIDS is an uncurable and fast-spreading epidemic.

2. Awareness and prevention are the greatest tools we have to fight HIV/AIDS</description>
  <mission>prevent the spread of HIV/AIDS throughout the world and raise awareness.</mission>
  <name>HIV/AIDS</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/6989</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2u/8M/Md/yb/pX/GF/N0uS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
