<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Corporate PR departments want America to mistrust whistleblowers. It is tough to sell their products when the public mistrusts them. They have a strong, primary interest in keeping revenues as high as possible through the management of public perceptions. To do this, they use their extensive resources to generate media coverage intended to lead media audiences to believe that the most outrageous self-seeking claimants are typical of whistleblowers. 

Sounds cynical? Well the public relations game is about the most cynical innovation in human history. 

We need whistleblowers. When polluters, employers, government bodies, and all the other powerful entities in society which we must trust with our lives know they're being watched, and that they have to toe the line, they do a better job. We need whistleblowers to trust that when they encounter wrongdoing, the kind of wrongdoing that they are uniquely qualified to help the public redress, they will not be discouraged by the expectation that their claims will be met with widespead public contempt. All whistleblowers have a hard road: they have to face the personal risks associated with media scrutiny and loss of income. Let's not make public justice any harder than it has to be. Tell the media, tell the corporations, tell the government, tell the world: Thank You Whistleblowers.

1. Corporate PR campaign work hard to paint whisteblowers in general as attention-seeking troublemakers or self-interested advantage-seekers. This is a strategy to sow mistrust of whistleblowers' claims in the public mind, in service of the creation of an un

2. We support, in general, strong public policies that protect whisteblowers from retaliation by those alleged wrongdoers whistleblowers identify, public and private. 

3. Hell, let's have a "National Whisteblower Day"</description>
  <mission>Demonstrate public support for people who put their security, welfare and livelihoods at risk in order to protect the public from deliberate and concealed harms to the public. </mission>
  <name>Thank You Whisteblowers!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7010</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/in/q2/Q7/I7/NZ/Fv/0EwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
