<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A short recent synopsis...

Floods submerge 30 plus villages of Jafferabad&#8217;s Gandakha

JAFFERABAD: Flash floods bursting into over thirty villages of Tehsil Gandakha here in the district of Balochistan have submerged and the locals have started shifting from the marooned villages.

On the other hand, the flash flood level in Thar canal is persistently rising. Deputy Chairman Senate, Mir Jan Mohammad Jamali told that several areas including Ustamohammad and Jafferabad were threatened by more floods, as the flash flood level in Kirthar Canal was mounting.

Meanwhile, the flood-affected areas of the district Jacobabad&#8217;s Jhal Magsi, Naseerabad, Jafferabad and Bolan were facing acute shortage of kitchen items. The suburbs of Dadu have also gone under floodwater. Scores of villages of Qambar, Wara and Taluka Miro Khan&#8217;s Union Council Khabar were also inundated by floodwaters.

Sindh chief minister&#8217;s Advisor, Sultan Khawar told Geo News that the threat to Shahdadkot town by flood waves has somewhat lessened and Saifullah Magsi Canal&#8217;s embankments were being extensively guarded. 

There are more People like this in need...these are 30 villages for godsakes, and the pakistani government as always is filling their pockets and neglecting the victims. Help the cause....give a starving child food and shelter, give a mother in hardship feed her children, help a father re-establish his household for his family, help rid the streets of dead corpses and also help rebuild the villages....

1. Rations must be sent immediatly

2. Houses must be rebuilt.</description>
  <mission>Send as much aid as we can to the victims of these flashfloods.</mission>
  <name>Help The people of Rain and Water storms In pakistan</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7035</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ji/qt/US/eN/Qy/1C/ErkS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
