<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Airport taxes (specially in the UK), are disgracefully high, and in some cases, for NO real reason.

The new doubling of APD is a tax that goes against its own point for example. Backgroud on this can be found in this article from the times: http://www.easyjet.com/common/img/Andy_Times_ban_old_aircraft.pdf

Basically what we want is to:
- Remove passenger duty
- Tax old and dirty aircrafts instead! (by taxing the airline directly, and not the general flying passenger)

As the article sais, charging the customer a flat rate tax, pushes airlines to operate older aircraft as they have to cut on their fares, whereas if you'd charge the aircraft carriers according on how efficient the aircrafts are, the more efficient aircraft carriers would directly reflect in lower fares.
In this way the customer can choose to FLY GREENER by simply paying less!

Moreover this tax should be to offset their CO2 emissions (more efficient = less CO2 = cheaper fares) which is also easyjet's policy.
An example is that flying easyjet rejects less CO2 per passenger-km than driving the supposed 'green' Toyota Prius.
(In numbers: last year, easyjet's average emissions were 95.7g of CO2 per pkm, against 104g per km of a Prius - Source for this the article stated above and www.hybridsynergydrive.com/en/prius_emissions.html)

More on easyjet's policy: http://www.easyjet.com/EN/About/Information/infopack_environmentalpolicy.html

1. Reduce Passenger's Airport taxes

2. Set a European carbon credit trading tax for all air carriers

3. Support EasyJet's policy on green flying with full aircrafts</description>
  <mission>Urge the EU to ban disgracefull and unfair (useless) airport taxes.</mission>
  <name>Excessive Airport Taxes</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7041</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8t/uU/aU/Al/M8/vC/GyOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
