<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There's a lot of bullshit involved with working for the Bertucci's corporation.  They're cheap basterds who don't give a shit about their employees, pay below-average low wages, violate several laws, offer no incentives or motivation to work, and demand your soul along with your absolute hardest work and devotion, and give back nothing in return.  They're constantly cutting back on hours to save money, which screws us over, and they've been postponing/denying so many raises who genuinely deserve them, and are  owed them according to company policy.  Bertucci's is oppressive and tyrranical. They don't even allow breaks unless you work for at least 6 hours, and even then you have to clock out.  I'm starting this cause from the Amherst bertucci's perspective, which suffers from one of the worst managers of all time, Robbo.  And there's just way too much bullshit constantly going on to list. The only reason why I'm still there is because I love and get along well with all of my coworkers, and the managers other than Robbo aren't too bad.  And I'm just too lazy to find another job.  Join our cause and help to get better conditions for all bertucci's employees everywhere!      

1. We demand that everyone who is owed a pay-raise recieve it.

2. We demand some minimal, inexpensive free food, and a 15 minute break after 4 hours(which is the law!)

3. We demand that Robbo get fired!

4. We demand that Tim stops keeping the back door locked all the time!(but otherwise he's really cool)

5. We demand at least little more steady hours!</description>
  <mission>Demand better conditions for bertucci's employees, mainly by getting rid of the infamous misfit manager, Robbo!</mission>
  <name>Robbo Must Get Fired!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7081</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/YV/bR/Z4/GS/f8/DR/axSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
