<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>So many people in the United States suffer from eating disorders, yet the amount of money that insurance companies are willing to pay is only a small fraction of the price. 
On average insurance companies are only willing to spend $500 a day for an in-patient treatment facility. That is only half. Most eating disorder in-patient treatment facilities, in the United States, charge upwards of $1000 a day. A day. That means the insurance company is only paying for half. While that may seem semi-okay... it really isn't. Since most in-patient treatment lasts for 3 months. That means the family must pay for 45 days of treatment on their own. Roughly 45 thousand dollars.
Then there's another issue with insurance, many people that suffer from eating disorders are in college, and in order to remain on their parents' insurance plans they must be enrolled as full time students. The insurance company will NOT pay for in-patient treatment if this is the case, because for that 3 months, the person seeking treatment is not considered a student by the insurance companies. 
This needs to be changed. Changed so that people who do want help can get it, without having to worry about burdening their families.
The beneficiary of this cause, Manna scholarship fund, provides scholarships to people wanting to get better, people that do not have the funds to do it on their own.


1. Financial aid should be provided for recovery to those suffering from eating disorders

2. Coverage should extend beyond treating medical side effects, into recovery, not just a few months after treatment but for a substantial amount of time</description>
  <mission>provide monetary support for those that cannot afford eating disorder treatment facilities.</mission>
  <name>Safe from Vanishing</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7097</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">147</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nh/FN/lS/AV/lb/nV/cfaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
