<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>You've probably heard this before: the U.S. produces enough food to feed the world 20 times over. This is probably true. However, just because we CAN doesn't mean we SHOULD. Because feeding the Third World is not as good as it sounds. Hunger is a useful tool, and provides the following benefits and more. 

VS. EVIL DICTATORSHIPS
Evil dictatorships like Zimbabwe and North Korea thrive on food aid. Do you honestly think your $5 donation feeds a starving African child. No, it feeds the dictator. By completely cutting off all aid to a country, we are putting the dictator's balls in a vice grip. With some creative sabotage, the dictator loses support of his base, and is overthrown/killed. Hunger is a wonderful tool in democratizing a country.

VS. ZOMBISM
Recent data has shown that an outbreak of Solanum is imminent. For those of you "in the dark," Solanum is proven to be the cause of zombism. Yes, zombies. Basically, with the majority of the world kept hungry and malnurished, the majority of the zombies will also be as malnurished. What's easier to fight? A hungry zombie that was a track star, or a hungry zombie that couldn't feed itself when it was alive?

[For those of you who are still skeptical of the zombie threat, please go to: http://www.wowomg.com]

Because of space, I could not list all of the benefits of keeping the world hungry has. But this cause is very easy to accomplish. All that needs to be done is this: don't donate to charities or organizations. 

In fact, you should eat all the food you can.


1. Hunger leads to change...in more ways than one.

2. Hunger isn't that bad.</description>
  <mission>keep the majority of the world hungry.</mission>
  <name>Keep the World Hungry</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7100</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yb/87/eA/E7/La/RK/ye1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
