<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>At Theological Horizons, we believe that Christians have a vital role to play in the forums of intellectual life.  With a vision for renewing Christian thinking and discipleship right at the heart of culture, we witness to the good news that all truth belongs to God.  

Theological Horizons is raising up a new generation of Christian thinkers, providing resources for their impact on our society.  After more than a decade and a half of ministry, Theological Horizons has mentored hundreds of young men and women who are now doing God's work in the world: teaching in colleges, serving in the church and witnessing in the marketplace, part of a new community of Christians engaged in ideas and discipleship.  Through lectures, bible studies, reading groups, writing prizes, first-rate publications, internships and gatherings, we hope to pilgrimage deeper into the mystery of God.  

Theological Horizons is centered at The Bonhoeffer House in Charlottesville, Virginia, less than half a mile from the Central Grounds of the University of Virginia.  The Bonhoeffer House is a home, as well, so family life provides a personal context for Horizons' hospitality.  Between discussions of ideas and theology there is a space for grace and for comfort, for a sense of belonging and Christian community.  

We invite you to be a part of our community.  If you, or someone you know, might be interested, contact us at info@theologicalhorizons.org and we will add you to our email list. Also, visit us online at www.theologicalhorizons.org, where our online reading group and discussion blogs provide enriching spaces for connecting and conversation.  

1. In a vast world of ideas, culture, and influence, it is through Christ that we discover life abundant.  

2. Theology, as the language of the church, speaks transformative possibility to the world.   

3. There is a great need for quality teaching, thinking and writing by Christians in our universities, churches &amp; communities</description>
  <mission>We support supports Christians in academia by advancing theological scholarship and by providing a welcoming home for engaging faith, thought and life.</mission>
  <name>Theological Horizons, centered at the Bonhoeffer House</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7110</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">52</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Z2/0Q/X2/5z/U4/ZB/gScS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
