<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For Two Cents We Can Change the World. Four thousand children die needlessly every day from drinking contaminated water. It's a tragedy that hundreds of millions of people obtain their drinking water from polluted sources such as muddy rivers, ponds, and streams. This public health crisis can be addressed today through an innovative and low-cost technology that effectively purifies and cleans water while removing bacteria, viruses, and parasites. Right now millions of people in Africa, Asia, and the Americas are being reached by a not-for-profit project, but millions more are in need. Help us reach a goal of providing 2 billion liters of safe drinking water. For only two pennies a day a child can have safe drinking water. We'd love to hear your thoughts. In fact, Give Us Your Two Cents Worth. Thank you.

Our website: &lt;a target="_new" href="http://www.csdw.org"&gt;http://www.csdw.org&lt;/a&gt;

Additional websites:
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target="_new" href="http://www.pg.com/company/our_commitment/drinking_water.jhtml"&gt;P&amp;G's Commitment to Children's Safe Drinking Water&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target="_new" href="http://www.pghsi.com/safewater"&gt;P&amp;G Health Sciences Institute &#8211; Safe Drinking Water&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target="_new" href="http://www.psi.org/our_programs/safewater.html"&gt;Population Services International &#8211; Safe Water&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a target="_new" href="https://secure.entango.com/donate/n3VxkZtj6kV"&gt;Make a Donation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;

1. More than 4000 children die every day from drinking contaminated water

2. We can prevent deaths caused by drinking contaminated water

3. 2 cents a day can provide a child safe drinking water</description>
  <mission>To prevent the sickness and death that occur in the developing world from drinking unsafe water.</mission>
  <name>Children&#8217;s Safe Drinking Water</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7117</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">364</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1007.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Wb/t0/FN/ky/R0/2s/6OWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
