<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> "So I close in saying that I may have had a tough break, but I have an awful lot to live for." 
-- Lou Gehrig in his farewell spech to baseball


"Lou Gehrig's Disease, also known as ALS, is a life robbing disease without any cure. With continued support, research and fundraising, a cure for this disease should be in the near future. It has to be.

Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), often referred to as "Lou Gehrig's disease," is a progressive neurodegenerative disease that affects nerve cells in the brain and the spinal cord. Motor neurons reach from the brain to the spinal cord and from the spinal cord to the muscles throughout the body. The progressive degeneration of the motor neurons in ALS eventually lead to their death. When the motor neurons die, the ability of the brain to initiate and control muscle movement is lost. With voluntary muscle action progressively affected, patients in the later stages of the disease may become totally paralyzed. Yet, through it all, for the vast majority of people, their minds remain unaffected.

The nerves that are affected when you have ALS are the motor neurons that provide voluntary movements and muscle power. Examples of voluntary movements are your making the effort to reach for the phone or step off a curb; these actions are controlled by the muscles in the arms and legs. The heart and digestive system are not involved in ALS. ALS eventually has an impact on breathing.

Most ALS patients die within 3-5 years after being diagnosed while 25% live after those first five years. In rare cases a patient can live into 20 and 30 years, but that is very rare.

Please let others know about this cause. Even if they do not personally know someone with ALS, it&#8217;s still a well-worthy cause."

http://alsa.org

&lt;object width="425" height="350"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/77HO49diVXM"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="wmode" value="transparent"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/77HO49diVXM" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" wmode="transparent" width="425" height="350"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

1. Find a cure for ALS

2. To improve the life of those affected by ALS

3. To make this a disease of the past</description>
  <mission>Find a cure for ALS</mission>
  <name>Strike Out ALS!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7118</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">267</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">110.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PH/1u/eV/Ht/eV/ru/tusS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
