<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>				&lt;p&gt;OneWebDay, Sept. 22 every year, is an Earth Day for the internet.

The first OneWebDay took place in 2006 - in 2008, it falls on a Monday.  It's always September 22.

It&#8217;s easy to take the web for granted.  But it&#8217;s worth taking a moment to reflect on what the web could mean to humankind in the future.  That&#8217;s the purpose of OneWebDay, held each September 22.

There are substantial threats to the free flow of information online, all over the world.  Many governments censor online content.  

Many people in developing nations can't get online at all. We need to ensure that the internet used by future generations will be open and empowering; access to the internet is central to the future of humanity.

The idea behind OneWebDay is to encourage people to think of themselves as responsible for the internet, and to take good and visible actions on Sept. 22 that (1) celebrate the positive impact of the internet on the world and (2) shed light on the problems of access and information flow. 

OneWebDay is a global, decentralized event. We're encouraging people around the world to meet up on Sept. 22 to talk about the threats to the net and how the web could change lives around the world in the future.  

In 2007, there were events in Colombia; Benin; Ethiopia; New York City, USA (with Jimmy Wales and others); Poland; Los Angeles, CA, USA; Bulgaria; Ecuador; Israel; Mauritius - Ebene Cybercity, Mauritius;      Chennai, India; Taiwan; Cambridge, MA, USA;      Chicago, IL, USA; Austin, TX;  St. Louis, MO, USA; UAE; PICISOC - Pacific Islands Chapter of ISOC; Naples, Italy; Berlin, Germany.

1. Access to the internet and the free flow of information online is threatened around the world.

2. The internet has changed human lives in many positive ways around the world.  We need to ensure that the internet used by future generations will be open and empowering.

3. Access to the internet is central to the future of humanity.</description>
  <mission>Support a global day to celebrate and protect the internet: Sept. 22</mission>
  <name>OneWebDay</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7123</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">775</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">300.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cx/a0/In/Uy/H5/Uv/zQ/m6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
