<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Serving Some 600 Christian and Humanitarian Organizations Through&#8230;

AVIATION

A fleet of 53 aircraft flying some 3 million miles each year in the remote regions of the world. More Info...

COMMUNICATIONS and INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Communications services to isolated areas worldwide: e-mail, HF/VHF radios, VSAT broadband internet access, and networking solutions. More Info...

LEARNING TECHNOLOGIES

Strategic distance learning tools and support to help meet the critical need for trained Christian leadership in developing countries. More Info...

Some 200 MAF missionary families raise ministry support for the privilege of serving God and helping people in need. In 26 countries throughout Africa, Asia, Eurasia, and Latin America, MAF overcomes barriers and transforms lives through the Gospel of Jesus Christ. MAF services enable and maximize...

EVANGELISM AND CHURCH NURTURE

    * Missionaries and local evangelists to unreached people
    * Indigenous church workers to isolated villages
    * Theological education by extension
    * JESUS film presentations
    * Scripture translation and distribution

More Info...
MEDICAL ASSISTANCE

    * Medical emergency evacuations
    * Medicines delivered safely
    * Flying-doctor services and
      other medical transport

More Info...
DISASTER RESPONSE

    * Food for the hungry
    * Relief supplies and agency
      personnel to disaster area

More Info...

NATIONAL TRAINING &amp; CAPACITY BUILDING

    * Discipleship
    * Skills training
    * Leadership development
    * Distance education

More Info...

COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT

    * Christian staff and supplies for health and community improvement projects
    * Village enhancements, including water wells


1. Overcoming barriers, transforming lives, building God's kingdom.

2. MAF is a faith-based, non-profit ministry. Teams of aviation, communications and technology specialists overcome barriers, transform lives, and enable the work of more than 600 organizations around the world.</description>
  <mission>Our passion is to see individuals, communities, and nations transformed by the Gospel of Jesus Christ.</mission>
  <name>Mission Aviation Fellowship</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7128</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">81</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">66.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ud/4q/hR/X4/4p/6P/PzXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
