<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our Vision
We see a world of abundance where people won&#8217;t go hungry.

Our Core Values
At Open Arms, the kitchen is the heart of who we are.

Open Arms of Minnesota delivers meals to people living with HIV/AIDS, breast cancer, ALS, MS, and other serious illnesses in the Twin Cities Metro Area.

Heritage
Open Arms is something good that has come from a terrible disease, HIV/AIDS. We honor our roots and remain committed to serving people who live with HIV/AIDS while sharing our experiences and resources to meet the evolving needs of those with other life threatening illnesses. At our kitchen&#8217;s table, there is always room for one more..

Food
We love food-it is the main ingredient that draws us together in the kitchen. We love to cook and bake, to serve meals and to eat. So many of life&#8217;s significant events involve food. Through food we celebrate life.

Connectedness
The stories we share in the kitchen where we work together are the same the world over-our community knows no boundaries. Open Arms brings diverse people together to share, learn, heal, grow, work towards a common goal and have fun.

Innovation
Different spices and experimentation in our kitchen keep Open Arms fresh and on the cutting edge of not-for-profit organizations. We take calculated risks that allow us to expand our thinking, programming and view of the world. We actively seek creative solutions to challenges, both locally and globally.

Responsibility
Open Arms makes the most of all of our resources: the time and talents of our volunteers and staff, our community relationships and partnerships, our reputation and the gifts entrusted to us. Social responsibility is the recipe that will sustain Open Arms now and into the future.

Hope
Hope is the secret ingredient in every meal we prepare and deliver-and in every interaction we have with each other and those around us.

More information can be found on our website at www.openarmsmn.org.


1. We hope that no person living with serious illness will go hungry.</description>
  <mission>With open arms we nourish body, mind and soul.</mission>
  <name>Open Arms of Minnesota</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7130</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">413</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">213.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/AF/L8/1V/TA/RC/Ly/Ve/QNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
