<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>//objective//
The Let&#8217;s Raise a Million Project is a student-led, nonprofit organization focused on introducing energy saving solutions to limited-income households. With the goal of reducing carbon emissions in target communities, college students go door-to-door and replace incandescent bulbs with energy efficient bulbs-- compact fluorescent lamps (CFLs) for FREE. During the installation, residents also get information on other ways to reduce energy consumption and bills as well as carbon emissions. Organized on the campus of Morehouse College as a program of SEeED (Students Endeavoring for Enlightened Environmental Decisions) in the fall of 2007, Let&#8217;s Raise a Million and its partners are committed to installing one million CFLs by 2013.

The simplest home improvement any household can make is to modernize its lighting strategy

// An Explanation: Why low-income households do not take advantage of CFLs? //
A highly probable explanation why low-income households do not utilize energy-saving, cost-minimizing CFL&#8217;s, is cost! 

Take for instance in India, a normal incandescent bulb costs $0.25 whereas a CFL; $2.00 (depending on its shape and power.)   So when an average person (and it should be assumed that the average person doesn&#8217;t thinks about the environment on a regular basis) goes to purchase a new bulb, to him or her the incandescent bulb appeals more. S/he isn&#8217;t far sighted enough to calculate the long-term benefit, even economic. S/he is more interested in today, and today $0.25 seems a lot less than $2.00.
 
Let&#8217;s Raise a Million shall attempts to short circuit this problem for low-income households.


1. Help us, Help Others, Help THEMSELVES

2. Climate Change is everyone's responsibility

3. CFLs are the first step of many of "Changing the Way we Live"</description>
  <mission>Introducing energy saving solutions to limited-income households. That is to say,  to Raise One Million (1,000,000) "CLEAN" bulbs!</mission>
  <name>The Let's Raise A Million Project...</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7131</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">169</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">184.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PZ/LM/zQ/co/jz/e5/2S/l8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
