<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>One of the main greenhouse gases is carbon 
dioxide, as trees grow they take in c02 from the air. When the wood dies the cO2 is returned to the air. Forest clearance and wood burning is increasing the latter half of the process, adding to cO2 in the atmosphere.The loss of the forests also means that there are fewer trees to absorb cO2.Methane is released during coal-mining,oil exploration and during land clearance. The main source of methane though is agricultural activity, The problem with methane is that as the world population increases, agricultural activity must increase and so emissions of methane will also increase.  A cfc molecule(found in fridges,air conditioners and areosols.) is 10,000 times more effective in trapping heat than a cO2 molecule, methane is about 30 times more effective.
If no action is taken the greenhouse effect could lead to a rise in average global temperatures of between 1.5 4.5 degrees celcius as early as the year 2030. Such increases will make the world hotter than it has been for more than 100,000 yrs.  By the end of next century temperatures could have reached those of the time of the dinosaurs and it is doubtful if humans could survive.  Storms and hurricanes will become more frequent and stronger as oceans heat up causing more water to evaporate. Floods,sea levels are already rising at a rate of 1 to 2mm each year due to expansion of the top layer of the oceans as they warm and the melting of the polar ice caps. The predicted rise by 2050 is between 20 and 50cm. It is important to slow the warming as much as possible. This means using less fossil fuel, eliminating cfc's altogether, and slowing down deforestation.This can be achieved best through energy conservation.

1. There are little things we can do everyday to minimize wasted energy.

2.  There are small investments we can make that will pay off for us and the environment

3. Tke action in reducing the amounts of green house gas emmissions.</description>
  <mission>  The mission is to stop global warming</mission>
  <name>Let's keep our environment clean!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7138</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Kf/Tr/0S/W8/N0/4b/tGJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
