<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Triangle Foundation is Michigan&#8217;s leading organization serving the gay, lesbian, bisexual, transgender (GLBT) and allied communities.

Triangle Foundation programs include...

Victim Services - Triangle Foundation is Michigan's only organization with full-time staff advocating for victims of harassment, violence or discrimination based on a person's actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity or gender expression.

Policy - Triangle Foundation is Michigan's leading organization working to pass GLBT friendly legislation and stop anti-GLBT legislation on a state, local and federal level.

Community Building - Triangle Foundation produces Michigan's largest events for the GLBT community.  These events are designed to help our community build a strong sense of community and provide safe and fun events to participate in.  These events include Reel Pride Michigan film festival, Motor City Pride, ComedyFest, Triangle Foundation Annual Dinner and the Women's Golf OUTing.

Public Education - Triangle Foundation facilitates trainings, discussions and lectures at organizations and venues across Michigan.  Media outlets, police departments, churches, K-12 schools, colleges, universities, health care systems and state government agencies are just some of the groups we train through this program.

Youth Initiatives - Triangle Foundation provides resources and programs designed to empower GLBT youth to be involved as leaders of their community.  These initiatives include Camping.OUT, Campus.OUT, the Michigan Consortium of Higher Education GLBT Centers, Schools.OUT, Generation.OUT Online and the Generation.OUT Scholarship Fund.

1. We envision a society characterized by a strong commitment to universal civil rights.

2. We envision safe communities, workplaces, and schools; stable families.

3. We envision self-reliant GLBT individuals.

4. Triangle Foundation opposes violence in all its forms.

5. Triangle Foundation supports full equality for all persons.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to promote equality and to secure freedom from violence, intimidation and discrimination for GLBT persons throughout Michigan.</mission>
  <name>Triangle Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/715</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1081</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1572.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wdy/flYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
