<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Fort Monmouth community is comprised of active duty Army, Navy, Air Force, Marines, Coast Guard, Reserve Components, retired military, Department of Defense appropriated and non-appropriated fund employees, contractors, and family members. 

Strategically located throughout Fort Monmouth, tenats include U.S. Army Communications-Electronics Command (CECOM), Program Executive Office Command, Control and Communications Systems, Program Executive Office Intelligence, Electronic Warfare and Sensors, and the U.S. Military Academy Preparatory School. Within this framework, is the Garrison&#8217;s responsibility for Base Operations/Contractor Support, Real Property that includes main post and the Charles Wood Area, as well as various programs and services to enhance the Well-Being for soldiers and civilians at Fort Monmouth. 

The mission of the US Army Communications-Electronics Command is to research, develop, acquire, field and sustain technologically superior integrated Communications, Command and Control, Computer, Intelligence, Electronic Warfare, and Sensor (C4IEWS) capabilities for America's Warfighter. CECOM provides the architectural framework and systems engineering to ensure joint interoperability and horizontal technology integration across the battlespace. CECOM executes its mission throughout the life cycle of warfighting systems and platforms through an integrated process of technology generation and application, acquisition excellence and logistics power projection. 

***updated***FEB 3, 2009****copy and paste to read the hypocrisy of the maryland base and its scam efforts to get ft. monmouth business.

http://www.app.com/article/20090203/OPINION01/902030307/1029/OPINION

1. Fight to keep Ft. Monmouth open in NJ!

2. Generate knowledge of the incompetence of the Maryland base

3. Inform the general public of the BRAC-scam

4. Begin a petition to our legislative leaders on the importance of saving Ft. Monmouth</description>
  <mission>reverse the BRAC-scam decision to close Ft. Monmouth and relocate its employees to Maryland</mission>
  <name>Save Ft. Monmouth, NJ!!!!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7153</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2976</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/do/Xi/LV/SX/1q/Xp/iUyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
