<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>To believe poverty can be eliminated through any economic means is not only na&#239;ve but rather an arrogant assumption; the likes of Malthus definitively highlight the problems of exponentially growing populations and the limited diminishing means by which to sustain it. Poverty is not the by-product of modern economics as suggested by socialists but rather an epidemic, perpetuated by global patronage to such nations by philanthropic nations, hence alleviating the need for any economic development through self-enforcing work ethics.

Sexual intercourse in poverty stricken nations has developed in to an almost allegorical right of passage as well as a means of leisure, the instincts of mankind naturally disallow abstinence, consequently leading to a multiplication of poverty stricken people, and as the rise of poverty becomes more evident, a natural solution emerges.

A solution? Very simple, a global agreement to deny any form of materialistic or physical patronage to such nations combined with an invasion to eliminate those in poverty through violent means as they naturally deplete their own resources. Such an alleviation of this burden upon humanity will prove beneficial to all, considering the wastage of food and resources on suffering nations. These dramatic decisions may appear unpalatable, however to prolong life in such nations is to perpetuate their suffering.

This cause is realistic, poverty cannot be alleviated through pathetic concerts or some measly economic aid to the nations, the people are uneducated and unwilling to embrace aid of western minds, the political situations are expected to remain dire, and a single solution prevails. The target is clear and can be eliminated by facilitating natural selection, alloweing such poverty to naturally disseminate without intervention.

The greater good must be served!

P.S Comments are welcome, however avoid pedantic condemnation and suggest &#8216;realistic&#8217; solutions instead


1. President</description>
  <mission>Eradicate Human Poverty</mission>
  <name>Make Poverty History 'Realistically'</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7154</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rz/BD/or/pU/1A/8O/eEGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
