<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Remember that scene from Lindsay Lohan's Mean Girls (2004).
Ms. Norbury asks the Grade 10 girls in the gym if they'd ever had a vicious rumour told about them.
THEN she asks if they had spread a rumour about another girl.
We're all guilty of it, don't argue.  Its time to stop it, here is how:

What is a Rumour: Any Negative story about anyone you consider a friend that you believe is UNTRUE, and potentially hurtfull.
Something you wouldn't want being spread about you FALSELY.

To Join this group you must agree to 10 Simple Rules in the event you hear a rumour:

1.  Do Not Just Ignore it
2.  Immediately Alibi (if possible &amp; if true) i.e. That's Bullshit, Samantha was in Seatle with me at the time
3.  Question the Rumour Teller:
  - "WHY would Samantha do that?"
  - "Do you REALLY think that's true"
4.  Defend the Victim: "That doesn't sound like anything Samantha has done before"
5.  Confirm the Rumour is  indeed false with the subject
6.  Tell the Victim of the Rumour:
   - What you heard
   - Who said it
   - Your advice on which course of action to take
   - Offer your additional help
7.  Encourage the Person Telling you the rumour to:
  i) Get their facts straight
8.  Do Not Purpetuate the rumour (Tell anyone else who isn't Immediately involved)
9. Finally, Attempt to take up a Live &amp; Let Live / Get Over It attitude towards life
10. Invite others to join this cause

Our mission is to change the world, one social cicle at a time

If we all stick together, the world will be a much better place, and leave more room for BUILDING friendships, and having fun!
Gone will be the days of Opening up your Highschool yearbook, and calling 20% of your graduating class bitches, whores and assholes.


In Memory of every friend anyone has lost or drifted away from before these rules could be written.

BTW. At the time I wrote this Creto, I do not know any Samanthas. If in the future I meet one, rest assured it was not written about you ;)


1. Do Not Just Ignore it

2. Immediately Alibi

3. Question the Rumour Teller

4. Defend the Victim

5. Confirm the Rumour is  indeed false

6. Tell the Victim of the Rumour

7. Get their facts straight

8. Do Not Purpetuate the rumour

9. Live &amp; Let Live / Get Over It

10. Invite others to join this cause</description>
  <mission>End the Rumour Cycle Now</mission>
  <name>Rumour-Free Credo</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7168</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ge/Z0/ch/Dq/pt/Fv/JxZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
