<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The coalition was organized in 1999 by a group which includes cancer survivors, women who&#8217;ve had abortions and others whose family members have had the disease. We came together because of our deep concern that women haven&#8217;t been informed about strong biological evidence and epidemiological research published since 1957 which provide overwhelming support for a cause and effect relationship between abortion and breast cancer. More than two dozen peer-reviewed studies conducted in different parts of the world report increased risk. Most of these studies were conducted by scientists describing themselves as abortion supporters. 

Only a few decades ago, breast cancer was known to be a grandmother&#8217;s disease. Because of abortion, it has become a young woman&#8217;s disease, and breast cancer rates have skyrocketed over 40% since the surgical procedure was legalized in the U.S. in 1973.

Our purpose is to educate women about abortion as a risk factor for breast cancer, help preserve their health and save lives. Women have the exclusive right to be decision makers where their own health care is concerned. 

It's important to note that the Coalition does NOT suggest that all women with breast cancer have had abortions, nor do all women with abortions in their medical history develop breast cancer.  It is ONE of the MANY risk factors for breast cancer, and women should be just as informed about it so they can begin early breast cancer screening.


1. Women who have had an abortion should begin getting mammograms earlier than other women.

2. Such women lose the protective effect of childbearing after a pregnancy termination.

3. The hormonally-altered breast tissue becomes more vulnerable to breast cancer after an abortion.

4. Regardless of one's opinion toward abortion, WOMEN HAVE A RIGHT TO BE NOTIFIED of their increased risk so they can take the necessary steps to protect themselves against potential risks with early and preventative measures and healthcare.</description>
  <mission>educate women about their increased risk of breast cancer if they have a medical history of abortion</mission>
  <name>Coalition on Abortion-Breast Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7191</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">27</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/rx/V7/tn/ft/Qe/a6/K5JS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
