<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.taintedblood.info/index.php

Latest News  http://www.taintedblood.info/news.php

During the late 1970s and early 1980s, haemophiliacs began using a revolutionary new product to treat their condition. 'Factor concentrates' were heralded as the way forward in haemophilia treatment, and profit-hungry pharmaceutical companies wasted little time in harvesting blood from the cheapest possible sources in order to make as much of the product as they could.

As haemophiliacs began using the products, it soon became apparent that something was wrong. People began dying. In their haste to push out as much factor VIII and IX as possible, the pharmaceutical companies had been sourcing donor blood from extremely dubious places. Donors with infectious diseases such as HIV and various strains of Hepatitis were routinely allowed, and in many cases paid, to give blood (see Kelly Duda's excellent film "Factor 8: The Arkansas Prison Blood Scandal"

http://www.factor8movie.com/

 The companies themselves would then pool the plasma together with hundreds of other donations, thus contaminating many thousands of units of factor concentrate. This product was then shipped around the world and given to thousands of haemophiliacs.

In Britain, more than 4,800 haemophiliacs were infected with Hepatitis C, and 1,200 of those with HIV. Many have already died from their infections. In the case of those given HIV, only 380 or so people are still alive.

Yet still the tragedy deepens, as the legacy of this disaster means that many spouses, partners and loved ones of those infected through blood have themselves become infected... many because people were not told that they had been infected until years after infection took place.

1. A call for a A public inquiry surrounding the events that led to thousands of British haemophiliacs' infections with HIV and Hepatitis C</description>
  <mission>Find answers to why "...the worst treatment disaster in the history of the NHS...", has killed, widowed and destroyed the lives of thousands. </mission>
  <name>TaintedBlood.info</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7202</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/x0/fG/u8/Ue/zS/32/DzZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
