<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The SUNYIT SAE Mini Baja team participated in its first SAE-sponsored competition in June 2007, making an impressive first-time showing overall and ranking in the top 25 in 2 individual competition categories.  SAE International, the premier society dedicated to advancing mobility engineering worldwide, promotes these student competitions.  (For official results go to http://students.sae.org/competitions/bajasae/ and select the RIT event.)

You can help the SUNYIT team:
1.  Show your support by "Joining" this cause.
2.  Let friends and family know about this cause.
3.  Funds are needed to prepare for the next competition, so the team is seeking corporate sponsors as well as donations from individuals and companies to make its next vehicle and competition a reality.

For more information on the SUNYIT SAE Mini Baja project, visit the SUNYIT student-club web site at: http://clubs.sunyit.edu/sae

Tax-deductible donations -- to the extent provided by the IRS -- can be made to support the SUNYIT SAE Mini Baja Fund by making gifts via credit-card using this web site, via credit-card by calling the SUNYIT Development Office at 315-792-7113, or making checks payable to &#8220;SUNYIT Foundation&#8221; and restricting the donation to the &#8220;SUNYIT SAE Mini Baja Fund&#8221; by writing the fund name on the memo line of the check and mailing directly to:
   SUNYIT Foundation
   PO Box 3050
   Utica, NY  13504-3050

Checks sent directly to the SUNYIT Foundation will be acknowledged by the SUNYIT Foundation, so be sure to include your name and mailing address so an acknowledgement letter/receipt for your gift can be sent to you.  Gifts via credit card can also be made by contacting the SUNYIT Development Office at 315-792-7113.

For more information about the SUNYIT Foundation and how donations can be used to support this or other education programs at SUNYIT, contact the SUNYIT Development Office, PO Box 3050, Utica, NY  13504-3050, Phone: 315-792-7113.



1. SUNYIT's SAE-Chapter is worthy of support in building all-terrain Mini Baja vehicles to learn about automotive and mobility engineering and showcase the talents of SUNYIT students in competitions against other colleges/universities.

2. One of the best ways to learn is "to do" and this project enables SUNYIT students to apply what they learn in the classroom to a real-world, engineering project from which they learn even more than can be covered in lectures or textbooks.</description>
  <mission>Support SUNYIT students in developing Mini Baja vehicles and competing with them against other colleges/universities at SAE-sponsored events.</mission>
  <name>SUNYIT SAE Mini Baja Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7206</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">135.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bk/uV/1b/Dp/BX/hC/HuMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
