<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This may come as a big surprise to you:  I'm training for the Honolulu AIDS Marathon, set to take place on December 9, 2007. That's right.... a marathon.... 26.2 miles!  For an ex-smoker who used to consume a pack a day for 12 years, this is a huge undertaking and a truly fulfilling experience.  I have logged nearly 100 miles of runs with the AIDS Marathon Training Program, running at least twice during the week and long group runs on Saturdays.  A month ago, running the marathon was an exercise in self-accomplishment and the thought of getting up at 6am every Saturday morning to run more than a mile was too daunting.  I now find myself humbled but fulfilled in ways I am unable to describe in words and look forward to finishing the marathon in December.

While logging 10 miles this past Saturday, I was hit by a sudden bout of panic at the realization that I needed to raise $3,500 by the end of August, or risk not fulfilling my commitment to the fundraising effort. 
 
The money I raise will benefit AIDS Project Los Angeles. APLA provides food banks, transportation, home health care and other vital services - to help keep people alive until there's a cure.
 
I have made a personal commitment to raise at least $3,500 by Saturday, August 25, 2007 - and I hope to raise even more. Any contribution you can make would mean a great deal to me. Contributions are tax-deductible.
 
To view my campaign page and make a contribution, please click on the link below:

http://www.aidsmarathon.com/participant.asp?runner=LA-5732&amp;EventCode=HN07
 
Thank you for your love and support.
 
Vikram.

1. To help keep people alive until there is a cure for AIDS.</description>
  <mission>Make a difference in the lives of thousands of people living with AIDS.</mission>
  <name>AIDS Marathon</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7213</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/rB/4t/ww/IR/rB/Tj/tdiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
