<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>From the Canadian Landmine Foundation:

If we all do a little, we can accomplish a lot!
In October 2006, 11 year old Ramy and his brother Khodor, 13 were picking pine cones near their home in southern Lebanon when they encountered a bomb from a past conflict.  Not knowing what it was they picked it up and before they could throw it away the bomb exploded, killing Ramy and seriously injuring Khodor.  This tragic incident highlights the plight of thousands of people who are having trouble rebuilding their lives after war.

Canada's Peacekeepers know too well the impact of landmines, and that the removal of these weapons is a necessary step in restoring peace.  During 2007 we will honour Canadian peacekeepers with the funds raised from Day of 1000 Lunches campaign: Colonel Don Ethell, by undertaking landmine clearance in Bosnia; RCMP Insp. Victor Josey, by training a mine detection dog for use in Afghanistan; and the sacrifice of peacekeepers' families, by undertaking a survivor assistance project in Lebanon. Every penny donated will be used to fund these projects. 

---

Landmines are left behind after conflicts, and are the cause of countless civilian deaths. In recent years, this issue has become very global. Treaties have been signed and many countries have altogether stopped landmine production. However, countries such as Burma, China, Cuba, India, Iran, North Korea, South Korea, Nepal, Pakistan, Russia, Singapore, United States and Vietnam are either still producing or hold the rights to continue to produce these weapons. 

It is my hope that one day landmines will be eradicated worldwide.

---

The Canadian Landmine Foundation is affiliated with the international organization, Adopt-A-Minefield.

For more information on Canadian Landmine Foundation:

http://www.canadianlandmine.org/


1. Eradicating landmines to aid people in the rebuilding process after war.

2. Supporting peacekeeping missions around the world. </description>
  <mission>To support the existing organizations, Canadian Landmine Foundation and Adopt-A-Minefield, in their goals to eradicate landmines in warzones worldwide.</mission>
  <name>Landmine Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7226</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">110</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">99.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pz/Ei/yo/Gs/XX/Hy/vuIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
