<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Especially in the Modern era, there has been an increasing hostility between philosophers and Christians.  The assumption among many Christians that all philosophers are atheists (or at least anti-Christian) is as unreasonable as the assumption among many philosophers that all Christians are unthinking slaves to orthodoxy.  It is the intent of this Cause to disprove both assumptions and to bridge the gap between philosophy and Christianity.
----------------------------------------------------------------
"Faith intervenes not to abolish reason's autonomy nor to reduce its scope for action, but solely to bring the human being to understand that in these events it is the God of Israel who acts." - John Paul II

The objects of philosophy, it is true, are upon the whole the same as those of religion. In both the object is Truth, in that supreme sense in which God and God only is the Truth. Both in like manner go on to treat of the finite worlds of Nature and the human Mind, with their relation to each other and to their truth in God. &#8211; Georg Hegel

"If those who are called philosophers, particularly the Platonists, have said anything which is true and consistent with our faith, we must not reject it, but claim it for our own use, in the knowledge that they possess it unlawfully." &#8211; St. Augustine

I do not feel obliged to believe that the same God who has endowed us with sense, reason, and intellect has intended us to forgo their use. &#8211; Galileo Galilei

1. Philosophy and Christianity can cooperate.

2. The intellectual pursuit of truth is not incompatible with the Christian claim to the truth of Scripture.

3. A healthy respect between philosophers and Christians will benefit both.</description>
  <mission>Repair the relationship between the philosophical and Christian communities.</mission>
  <name>Reconcile Philosophy and Christianity</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7236</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3R/20/4I/xB/2M/1D/AjfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
