<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>BEGINNING THE PROJECT:
Central Cranes Project was founded in 2005 by the cast of the Omaha Theater Company for Young People's production of "A Thousand Cranes." The story of "A Thousand Cranes" follows a young twelve-year-old girl named Sadako Sasaki as she struggles with her terminal illness caused by the Hiroshima bombings in 1945. When her good friend, Kenji, tells her that the gods grant one wish to anyone who can fold a thousand paper cranes, Sadako begins her collection. Sadly enough, she passes away before she can finish. But her friends, led by Kenji, are determined to make a thousand. After collecting over 2,000 cranes from all over Japan, the children erect a memorial in Sadako's name. This memorial still stands today, and thousands upon millions of cranes are sent to Sadako's resting place every year. We hope the children's wish is someday granted:

"This is our cry.
This is our prayer.
Peace to the world."


WHAT IS 'CENTRAL CRANES PROJECT?':
Every summer, CCP asks for donations of paper cranes from all over the nation. Everyone is asked to send in at least one crane with a simple wish written inside the folds. These cranes will be collected and, on September 21st, sent to Sadako's memorial in celebration of International Peace Day. It is such a simple project, but it leaves an everlasting effect on a world in need of tolerance and understanding. 

HOW CAN I DONATE MY CRANE?:
1. Fold one or more cranes with a simple wish folded inside. (To learn how to fold a crane, visit: http://monkey.org/~aidan/origami/crane/)
2. Mail all cranes to:
          J. Castello 
          2242 N. Halstead St., Apt. 2
          Chicago, IL 60614
          United States of America
3. Write your wish in a post on our cause page.


It only takes a small whisper in the world to start a cry. Become a part of this beautiful tradition, and spread the wish of peace to the world.
 

1. The world should take more steps to understand and accept peace on an international level

2. All citizens of the world should understand the severity of World War II and the Hiroshima bombings

3. Hiroshima must never happen again.</description>
  <mission>spread awareness of peace and international understanding through the story of Sadako Sasaki</mission>
  <name>Central Cranes Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7246</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/NV/DO/lp/iJ/0y/OX/PJJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
