<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Mission Statement

Africa Aid is a nonprofit organization that enhances the quality of life in underprivileged African communities through sustainable development initiatives, while enriching domestic communities by promoting awareness and cultivating international partnerships. 

Brief Summary

Africa Aid creates intimate partnerships between underdeveloped African communities and American sponsor cities. The Africa Aid model is unique in its ability to take the large-scale issues of extreme poverty such as: 

AIDS and Malaria 
Dehydration and Hunger 
Inadequate Sanitation and Irrigation 
High Child Mortality Rates and Low Literacy Levels 
and scale them down to a manageable community level. 


Network of Support

Rather than relying solely on our own aid programs, we develop a network of support and utilize valuable domestic resources: 


Universities and Research Institutions play a critical role in Africa Aid program design, with projects implemented into course curriculum. The development of aid programs in the classroom takes advantage of faculty experts and gives students real world experience. 


International Aid Organizations provide proven methods of humanitarian aid. In return, Africa Aid offers university designed programs and intimate knowledge of African communities. 


Public and Private Sectors team up with their local communities to tackle the problems of a third-world partner. 

By forging these essential community to community partnerships, Africa Aid works towards developing its own innovative style of nonprofit aid that benefits all who are involved. 



1. we must improve the situation in africa and that will consequently improve the situation in the world in different fields</description>
  <mission>Enhancing the quality of life in underprivileged African communities through sustainable development initiatives</mission>
  <name>Save africa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7257</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/hg/6t/CK/3a/Ox/aU/WPnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
