<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Mentor Foundation (Mentor) is a non-profit, non-government organization with a mission to prevent drug abuse and promote the health and well-being of children and young people. 

Mentor was established in 1994 in Geneva with Her Majesty the Queen of Sweden as President. Mentor has an international remit for drug prevention and is developing national organizations which operate as part of the Mentor Family. Currently these are: Mentor Arabia, Mentor Colombia, Mentor Germany, Mentor Lithuania, Mentor Sweden, Mentor UK and Mentor USA. Mentor Belgium is soon to be established and plans are in process for a Mentor presence in China, Italy and Venezuela. Mentor International is the central co-ordinating body of the Mentor Foundation. 

What does Mentor do? 

The focus of Mentor&#8217;s work is to undertake, develop, implement, evaluate and disseminate best or promising practice in drug prevention internationally. Mentor seeks to help those working with young people to find the best possible ways to implement the most effective drug prevention initiatives. In other words we:


&#8226; Create and undertake youth oriented drug prevention programmes that are scientifically sound to be implemented on a national or international basis. With its primary target group of young people, it undertakes projects and identifies promising and best practice. Mentor&#8217;s project work can be grouped into five key areas:
-Information and Policy Development 
-Schools 
-Families 
-Vulnerable Groups 
-Mentoring

&#8226; Research, evaluate and support prevention development projects in collaboration with or on behalf of other international agencies, NGO&#8217;s or governments to assist them in developing programmes that are of the highest calibre. 

&#8226; Act as a consultant in providing advice, training, evaluation and project management for international agencies and governments wishing to develop or improve their prevention policy and practice. 

1. We believe that there is a fundamental need to invest in preventing drug misuse and making drug misuse less likely. Prevention begins with the healthy development of the child in a positive family and a community environment that offers protection from ri

2. We believe that young people are able to make sensible, healthy choices and can take responsibility for their actions. We support activities that promote collaboration and involve young people in planning, delivering and/or evaluating activities. 

3. We believe in providing young people with the education and opportunity to gain competencies and skills that will support and enable them to make informed choices that avoid drug misuse. 

4. We believe that our mission is best achieved through actions and collaboration at various levels: global, national, community and individual. 

5. We believe in evaluation and sharing of effective practice. 

6. We believe in openness and honesty in all our work. 

7. We believe in a dynamic process of continuous improvement. 

8. We believe that political, economic and social circumstances have an impact on the ability for change to occur. We believe that poverty and disadvantage affect the development and application of life skills. 

9. We believe that spirituality, race, inequality, culture and tradition influence young people&#8217;s opportunities. 

10. We believe that there should be no discrimination in relation to race, gender or religion in the field of healthy development and prevention of drug misuse. </description>
  <mission>support the effective use of resources (human, financial and intellectual) to prevent drug-use and promote the well-being of children and youth.</mission>
  <name>The Mentor Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/726</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">46</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/D7g/HmqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
