<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The information listed below talks a little bit more about the Relay for Life I'll be doing on August 4th from 7pm until 7am.  There's a link at the bottom to donate to my actual fundraising home page, or if you choose to donate through here, profits go to the American Cancer Society, Inc., MN branch.
____________________________________________

Can you believe that more than 1.3 million new cancer cases are expected to be diagnosed in the United States this year? Those are staggering statistics, but there is hope. Each of us can do something to save lives and help those already fighting this disease. That&#8217;s why I&#8217;ve decided to take action against cancer by supporting the American Cancer Society Relay For Life&#174; event right here in our community.

Relay For Life is an overnight event that brings our community together to help support the American Cancer Society and its lifesaving mission to eliminate cancer as a major health problem. The Society works hard every day to prevent cancer and save lives by supporting groundbreaking research, affecting public policies that protect us from cancer, and educating people on how to prevent or detect cancer early. Our efforts at Relay For Life can help the American Cancer Society to keep working toward a cancer-free future. 

I want to invite you to show your support in the ongoing fight against cancer by joining us for this year&#8217;s event. Please click on the link below for more information. We hope to see you there! If you can&#8217;t join us, will you please visit the site and make a donation to support our efforts? Either way, you will make a real difference in the lives of people facing cancer &#8211; and in the lives of the people who love them. Thank you!

Follow http://www.acsevents.org/faf/r.asp?t=4&amp;i=190515&amp;u=190515-182216696
to visit my personal web page and help me in my efforts to support Relay For Life of St. Anthony Village

Best,
Terri Edington

1. Raise money to fight cancer</description>
  <mission>Fight cancer!</mission>
  <name>Relay for Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7262</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/PP/q0/oc/33/fm/Cq/qewS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
