<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Desten Zia Ray Smith was born emergancy C-section on May 16 2006 at 32 week due to cardiac arrest. he was 3 lb. 2 oz.  My placenta tore away from my uterus causing concield hemmoraging and Desten to be cut off from oxygen.  When the doctors got him out he was not alive, they resesitated him after 5 min.  Desten was then sent to B.C childrens hospital for 5 weeks, where we learned that he suffered major brain damage in the part of the brain that controlls motor functions, Causing messages to be disrupted, this results in sever cerebral pulsy.  This type of cerebral pulsy causes all musscles to be affected, we do not know if he will ever walk or talk, but we have hope! Desten was then tansferd to kelowna general hospital for 7 1/2 weeks.  At 3 1/2 months we took him home for the first time.  At  7 1/2 months Desten started having Infintile Spasms.  These are very severe seizures that cause complete mental regression. Over a 3 week time period he had 5000 of them.  We went to the childrens hospital  to administer a steroid called A.C.t.H, this would hopefully stop the seizures.  Desten spent over 3 months on steroids, and untill now it seemed like it worked. 2 weeks ago he had an EEG showing the same pattern of seizures.  Now he is back on drugs that so far are not working, we are waiting to see if we have to go back to vancouver.  Desten has a very complicated brain disorder that is very hard to controll. And there is no telling what will happen from here.  so please send good vibes to him, he really needs as much support and hope as possible. 

1. Desten need the love</description>
  <mission>Send good vibe to desten</mission>
  <name>good vibes to Desten</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7268</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">299</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.07</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7m/QH/ej/3B/UU/XN/h0pS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
