<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In December of 1980, the countries of the world met at the United Nations Headquarters in New York to develop a novel and creative solution to address the numerous threats to peace in the world at the time. Their goal was to create an elite training institution for future world leaders to come together and study peace in its many forms.   

Twenty seven years later, The United Nations mandated University for Peace is still the only institution in the United Nations system able to grant degrees at the master&#8217;s and doctoral levels in fields related peace and conflict resolution. The University currently enrolls around 140 students a year from over 50 countries on its campus in Costa Rica and in many ways, it is a small microcosm of what the world could be &#8211; a multiplicity of cultures coexisting and creating opportunities for a better world by studying sustainable development, gender, education, media, international law, environmental security and international relations. But what makes UPEACE really unique is that each of our masters programs is integrally linked to the study of peace and conflict resolution. 

Many of our graduates go on to work in the UN system and in various other international humanitarian capacities and all carry with them the relationships made at UPEACE. As the UN grows in importance so will institutions like this which train tomorrow&#8217;s leaders to handle emerging manifestations of peacelessness.

We hope you will join us in our mission to create lasting infrastructure for peace through education and I would encourage you to check out both the UPEACE website (www.upeace.org) and the UPEACE/US website (www.upeaceus.org) for more information. 

All donations go towards a scholarship fund to help students from developing countries study at UPEACE. The fund is managed by UPEACE/US and all contributions are tax-deductible. 

1. UPEACE is the only institution in the United Nations system able to grant degrees in peace and conflict studies

2. Tomorrows leaders must be trained to actively and systematically create peace in their communities

3. The Vision for UPEACE is to become a network of collaborating centers in different regions, guided from its headquarters in Costa Rica</description>
  <mission>To provide humanity with an international institution of higher education for peace with the aim of promoting among all human beings the spirit of understanding, tolerance and peaceful coexistence.</mission>
  <name>United Nations mandated University for Peace</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/728</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3433</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">362.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uot/rEiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
