<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Brain imaging studies have shown that music is linked to mathematical, memory as well as coordination controlling regions of the human brain.
Most sick children will spend their evenings in the hospital playing video games or watching TV. Instead, music can help when their sad, can help their pain and coping mechanism. From the sales of the albums we hope to raise enough funds to provide every hospitalized child with the opportunity to be exposed to music and its posotive effects.
Dr. Raffi Tacdjian is a third-year pediatric fellow in the division of allergy and immunology at Mattel Children's Hospital UCLA. He founded the nonprofit Children's Music Fund to help bring music to his patients. 
In order to help raise funds to provide new instruments and music therapy to chronically ill pediatric patients, Dr. Tachdjian has mastered a series of 3 CDs featuring his own tracks, as well as those of other international renowned artists who generously donated their music. Tachdjian is researching the effects of music in a study conducted through the Pediatric Pain Program at Mattel Children's Hospital. By interacting in a musical environment, hospitilized children can develop their overall mental processes while simultaneously improving their emotional well-being. 
Visit the website at 
http://childrensmusicfund.org/
(the series of "Reflectronic" cds can be purchased on the Childrens Music Fund website).
~donations (money or instrunments) can be made on the website
thanks : ) 


1. Music has the power to heal!</description>
  <mission>use the proceeds from album sales and donations to purchase musical instruments for hospitalized patients</mission>
  <name>Childrens Music Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7287</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1185</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">110.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cF/lU/a1/5G/xt/0z/ll4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
