<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hello, my name is Amanda and I was diagnosed with Multiple Sclerosis in November of 2006, exactly 3 months after my mother in law Grace passed away from the same disease. I had a feeling after her passing to push for reasons why I didn't feel good anymore and sure enough, I was diagnosed. I believe it was Grace who warned me about the seriousness of the disease. I currently take a daily shot like many others with this disease, and still do not feel like I once did. I am only 23 and now I can not work, and am surviving under the love and support of my United States Coast Guard husband who is also selling Avon on my behalf to help support our family and also to help make others aware. I am looking for others to join and share their stories, donate to finding a cure for MS, and making it world known. 
Multiple Sclerosis (abbreviated MS, also known as disseminated sclerosis or encephalomyelitis disseminata) is a chronic, inflammatory, demyelinating disease that affects the central nervous system (CNS). MS can cause a variety of symptoms, including changes in sensation, visual problems, muscle weakness, depression, difficulties with coordination and speech, severe fatigue, cognitive impairment, problems with balance, overheating, and pain. MS will cause impaired mobility and disability in more severe cases.
With this all being said, We do Avon fund raisers to try and help the best we can. go to www.youravon.com/joverdorf  and register. when ordering specify that you want to be part of the cure. Or if your just interested in helping my family out as well. Thanks, and God Bless!!

1. To Make the world aware of this progressive illness.

2. To donate to foundations that are currently searching for a cure or a cause.</description>
  <mission>Make people understand what this disease is and how to help those who suffer from it daily.</mission>
  <name>Making others aware of Multiple Sclerosis.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7305</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">356</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.3</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DK/hT/Es/C6/hz/yG/BolS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
