<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Anarchy" means more than just "no government," it means opposition to all forms of authoritarian organisation and hierarchy.

This group was created to bring together anarchists and revolutionaries. By doing this, we can create a network to promote anarchy and peace in the world. We can stop and disprove misconceptions about anarchy and help fund a great cause.

Just to state the obvious, anarchy does not mean chaos nor do anarchists seek to create chaos or disorder. Instead, we wish to create a society based upon individual freedom and voluntary co-operation. In other words, order from the bottom up, not disorder imposed from the top down by authorities. Such a society would be a true anarchy, a society without rulers. 

Anarchy is any social relationship that involves neither dominance nor submission. It is the absence of social hierarchy, with no one imposing their will on another by force or threat of punishment. Anarchy means "without a ruler", or "without government". Government here is meant in the sense of "governing over" and forcing compliance through coercion. Such order is violent order. Anarchy, by contrast, is inherently cooperative- people relating to one another as equals.

Anarchy is both a theory and practice of life. Philosophically, it aims for the maximum accord between the individual, society and nature. Practically, it aims for us to organise and live our lives in such a way as to make politicians, governments, states and their officials superfluous. In an anarchist society, mutually respectful sovereign individuals would be organised in non-coercive relationships within naturally defined communities in which the means of production and distribution are held in common. 

This group is against the domination by religious extremists, capitalists, and nationalists. When their rules ends, the earth and its inhabitants will be free.

Any suggestions are welcomed. Feel free to post on the wall or message me.

1. All people deserve to live a free life without outside domination.

2. Any type of religious, economic, government, or social domination should be abolished.

3. All people are created equal and should be treated equal. No hierarchies.</description>
  <mission>To promote freedom, peace, and anarchy without being controlled by any higher authorities other than ourselves.</mission>
  <name>Theres No Government Like No Government!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7325</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2497</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Sk/3z/kh/mn/r4/8g/KyWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
