<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 1967, World Wildlife Fund Canada has become one of the country's leading conservation organizations, enjoying the active support of more than 150,000 Canadians. As a member of the WWF International network, we actively contribute to the achievement of the organization's mission:

To stop the degradation of the planet's natural environment and to build a future in which humans live in harmony with nature, by:

    * conserving the world's biological diversity
    * ensuring that the use of renewable natural resources is sustainable
    * promoting the reduction of pollution and wasteful consumption

WWF Canada is tackling some of the most daunting conservation challenges facing the country, as well as the broader international community. Our energies are directed to completing a national network of marine protected areas, safeguarding the Arctic, supporting leading-edge research to protect Canadian wildlife and habitats, addressing priority conservation concerns for North America, and protecting Cuban wildlife and habitats.

WWF's conservation results include the protection of 96 million acres of Canadian wilderness through the Endangered Spaces Campaign; the development and implementation of recovery plans for a number of species, including the St. Lawrence beluga whale and the right whale; the banning of carbofuran, a grasshopper spray implicated in the decline of the burrowing owl; and the protection of thousands of acres of tropical forests throughout Latin America.

Information: 
http://www.wwf.ca/

DONATE ONLINE: 
https://secure.wwf.ca/HowYouCanHelp/Donate/Donate.asp

Stay informed by signing up for the WWF Canada newsletter: 
http://www.wwf.ca/newsletter/enewsletter.asp

1. Conserving the world's biological diversity

2. Ensuring that the use of renewable natural resources is sustainable

3. Promoting the reduction of pollution and wasteful consumption</description>
  <mission>To stop the degradation of the planet's natural environment and to build a future in which humans live in harmony with nature</mission>
  <name>World Wildlife Fund (Canada)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7334</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">464</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ae/Ex/bS/HU/kq/aW/BYDS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
