<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Please visit my personal fundraising page at the web address:
http://main.acsevents.org/site/TR/MakingStridesAgainstBreastCancer/MSABCFY08Eastern?px=1566568&amp;pg=personal&amp;fr_id=3404&amp;et=2r6Ko0Fo697lV0yaSV_iPw..&amp;s_tafId=73187

This year, hundreds of thousands of people will hear the words "you have breast cancer," and there's a good chance that some of them will be people we know and love. I have chosen to fight back against this disease and help make a difference by participating in the American Cancer Society Making Strides Against Breast Cancer walk ... and I hope you will join me.

Since 1993, 3.5 million walkers across the country have raised more than $230 million through Making Strides events to help fight breast cancer. Last year alone, the efforts of dedicated supporters raised more than $40 million nationwide to enable the American Cancer Society to continue fighting breast cancer every day.

Personal Statement:
As of this year's walk, and every following year I participate in the ACS Making Strides Against Breast Cancer, I will be walking in memory of my yia yia (grandmother) Kyriakoula Milona. Unfortunately, my grandmother of whom is also my namesake passed from Breast Cancer before I was born. I would like to think that participating in this walk and fundraising for it will help to prevent families across the country from having to go through the pain of losing or not even getting the chance to know their loved ones.

Please visit my personal fundraising page at the web address:
http://main.acsevents.org/site/TR/MakingStridesAgainstBreastCancer/MSABCFY08Eastern?px=1566568&amp;pg=personal&amp;fr_id=3404&amp;et=2r6Ko0Fo697lV0yaSV_iPw..&amp;s_tafId=73187 

1. We walk to celebrate all breast cancer survivors like Judy and to provide hope to every person affected by this disease.

2. We walk because we know that hope starts with us. Because we can make a difference. Because we want to help build a future where breast cancer no longer threatens those we love.

3. We walk because fewer women age 40 and older had their yearly mammograms last year and because many still do not have access to care. We want to change that. By walking, we will.

4. We walk because we know the American Cancer Society is the only organization available anytime, day or night, in 3,400 communities across the country to help all people touched by cancer &#8230; and we don&#8217;t ever want that to change.

5. We walk because of people like you patients, survivors, families, and friends. We walk so that you will continue to benefit from the American Cancer Society&#8217;s free breast cancer programs, such as transportation assistance to and from treatments and lodg

6. We walk because the American Cancer Society has been waging war against cancer for nearly a century, and our commitment to defeating the disease has never wavered. </description>
  <mission>To reauthorize and increase funding for the National Breast and Cervical Cancer Early Detection Program. </mission>
  <name>2008 Making Strides Against Breast Cancer of Buffalo, NY</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7340</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">417</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Uu/zC/WW/bV/7u/E7/B1JS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
