<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For the past fifty years, science has dominated the civilized world. If something is not demonstrated scientifically, it is claimed to be invalid and unworthy of our attention. 

Food manufacturers have exploited this phenomenon to their advantage. The markets are swamped with supposedly beneficial artificial foods. We have become a generation of gullible consumers.

We are beginning to understand and recognize that we are what we eat. We also realize that food does not nourish the physical body alone. It becomes clear then that there is no diet that is right for everyone all of the time. Neither are there miracle nutrients that will cure all ills. 

The quality of the food eaten affects the degree of well-being experienced. It is easy to comprehend that artificially created food, or food grown under sub-optimal conditions, cannot contribute the ingredients necessary to good health. 

Only natural, wholesome foods can produce the degree of health that brings peace of mind and enjoyment of life. In our society, this requires constant vigilance as to what we choose to eat.
The properties of natural nutrients are best described by these words: live, natural, and good quality.

  Live, meaning that it still contains live enzymes, such as fruit, vegetables, and sprouts. 
  Natural, as in unprocessed, unrefined foods, such as whole grains and legumes. 
 Good quality, meaning grown in soil rich in essential nutrients such as organically grown foods (pesticide free and grown without synthetic 

1. Eat what our bodies were designed to eat

2. Processed foods cause diseased bodies

3. Real Food should be our medicine </description>
  <mission>give our bodies the nutrients it needs to heal.

" Food should be our Medicine" - Hippocrates</mission>
  <name>Real Food Can Heal</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7353</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">82</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/T7/h4/jr/33/Bo/SH/MvCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
