<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our Vision: 

One day all artisans in the developing countries will earn a fair wage, be treated with dignity and respect and be able to live a life of quality.


More About Ten Thousand Villages:

Ten Thousand Villages works with artisans who would otherwise be unemployed or underemployed. This income artisans earn helps pay for food, education, health care and housing.

Since 1946 Ten Thousand Villages has supported the work of literally tens of thousands of artisans in over 30 countries in Asia, Africa, Latin America and the Middle East, making us one the largest fair trade organizations in North America. Working with more than 100 artisan groups, we purchase fine pieces from craftspeople with whom we have longstanding, nurturing relationships&#8230;helping to bring dignity to their lives.

Ten Thousand Villages is a founding member of the International Fair Trade Association, an organization that includes over 200 members in 55 countries, including many artisan groups in developing countries. We are part of a worldwide movement that is striving to improve the livelihood of disadvantaged people in developing countries through the expansion of fair trade.

We market quality products from diverse cultures around the world made by people that we know and care enough about to do business in a manner that together we consider fair. We strive to operate as a business with a compassionate mission so that we can provide vital, fair income to artisans. Our dream is to one day see that all artisans in developing countries will earn a fair wage, be treated with dignity and respect and be able to live a life of quality. 

www.tenthousandvillages.com

1. We honor the value of seeking to bring justice and hope to the poor. 

2. We trade with artisan groups who pay fair wages and demonstrate concern for their members welfare. 

3. We provide consistent purchases, advances and prompt final payments to artisans. 

4. We increase market share in North America for fairly traded handicrafts.

5. We market quality products that are crafted by underemployed artisans. 

6. We build sustainable operations using a variety of sales channels, including a network of stores with a common identity. 

7. We choose handicrafts that reflect and reinforce rich cultural traditions, that are environmentally sensitive, and which appeal to the North American consumer. 

8. We encourage North American customers to learn about fair trade and to appreciate artisans&#8217; cultural heritage and life circumstances with joy and respect. 

9. We use resources carefully and value volunteers who work in our North American operations. </description>
  <mission>Ten Thousand Villages provides vital, fair income to Third World people by marketing their handicrafts and telling their stories in North America.</mission>
  <name>Ten Thousand Villages</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7361</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">429</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/z8/Zn/8D/F6/sM/Hc/fpMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
