<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Help the Helpless is a non-profit organization dedicated to improving the life of extremely disabled Catholic children.

Poverty. Hunger. Disease. Abandonment. 
These words are all-too familiar to the handicapped children of India. These children are often seen as a curse on an already poor family, and frequently find themselves living on the streets. Help the Helpless is a nonprofit organization which provides a home for children like this, and an education, all in a loving, Catholic environment. 

St. Mary's School for the Handicapped, the Blind and the Deaf is solely dedicated to the care and education of the destitute handicapped orphans of India. 

Students must be medically certified to have a handicap of 65% or greater in order to be accepted into this school and orphanage. Many of the students are either missing one or more of their limbs or they have little or no use of their limbs. 
 
There are very few government programs to help these children, and there is no welfare system in India. Schools like St. Mary's are the hope for these children, but with no government funding, the school and orphanage are dependent upon the charity of their benefactors. There are presently more than 300 children on the waiting list seeking entrance into the school and orphanage, but there are not sufficient funds to support them. You can help! For as little as $10 per month, you can be a sponsor for one of God's precious children. Or, for $15 per month, you can sponsor an older child, or a special needs child who requires more care than the others.  


1. Abandoned children need loving support and education in the faith!</description>
  <mission>Help poor children in India</mission>
  <name>Help the Helpless</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7376</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">62</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">45.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mB/qB/sz/4r/q2/qZ/DQoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
