<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>THINK. ACT. LIVE.
BEYOND YOUR OWN BORDERS
http://www.oneworld.net

OneWorld.net publishes news and analysis of world events from a unique perspective, bringing to the fore the world&#8217;s &#8220;hidden voices&#8221;&#8212;those who have been overlooked or purposefully left out of the mainstream discussion of global issues. 

OneWorld.net helps individuals link up with the causes they believe in, and OneWorld helps non-profit organizations&#8212;those who work with the poor and other marginalized people around the globe&#8212;to improve the work they do.

OneWorld.net has always been independent, non-profit, and non-commercial but it is only through the support of committed OneWorlders like yourself that we can continue to deliver these high-quality services.

We compete daily with the likes of CNN and Fox News and do so with an annual budget less than what they probably spend on hair gel in a week.
________________________________________

WHY SUPPORT ONEWORLD?

o WE SAVE YOU TIME.
We do the hard work of scanning websites and bringing together diverse perspectives from individuals and groups worldwide.

o WE KEEP YOU CONNECTED GLOBALLY.
We publish the OneWorld Daily Headlines to bring you top stories from around the world.

o WE KEEP YOU CONNECTED LOCALLY.
We provide local lists where you can hear about events, jobs &amp; resources. We also co-host local networking events.

Every bit helps, and for $35 or more we&#8217;ll send you one of our coveted OneWorld tote bags.

Thank you so much for your continued support&#8212;together we can create a better world!

- The OneWorld Team 

1. Human rights should be nurtured and protected.

2. Resources should be shared fairly and sustainably.

3. OneWorld is dedicated to working in partnership with individuals and other organizations to bring about this vision.</description>
  <mission>OneWorld's mission is to harness the democratic potential of new media to promote human rights and sustainable development.</mission>
  <name>OneWorld.net: People's Media for a More Fair and Sustainable World</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7383</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">281</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/MW/M1/JZ/nr/7p/bL/DsLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
