<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The purpose of this cause is to educate people on the seriousness of HIV/AIDS

There are now over 34 million people living with HIV or AIDS worldwide. Most of them do not know they carry HIV and may be spreading the virus to others. Here in the U.S., nearly one million people have HIV infection or AIDS roughly one out of every 250 people. At least 40,000 Americans become newly infected with HIV each year, and it is estimated that half of all people with HIV in the U.S. have not been tested and do not know they are carrying the virus.
Since the beginning of the epidemic, AIDS has killed nearly 19 million people worldwide, including some 425,000 Americans. AIDS has replaced malaria and tuberculosis as the world's deadliest infectious disease among adults and is the fourth leading cause of death worldwide. Over 13 million children have been orphaned by the epidemic.

How HIV Is and Is Not Transmitted

The virus is not transmitted through day-to-day activities such as shaking hands, hugging, or a casual kiss. sitting on a toilet seat, using a drinking fountain, doorknob, eating with dishes,  or through drinking glasses, food, pets or mosquitos

 HIV is transmitted in 3 main ways:

1.  Having sex (anal, vaginal, or oral) with someone infected with HIV
2.  Sharing needles and syringes with someone infected with HIV
3.  Being exposed (fetus or infant) to HIV before or during birth or through breast feeding

Risk Factors for HIV Transmission if you:

Needle sharing--If you are injecting drugs of any type, including steroids, do not share syringes or other injection equipment with anyone else. (Disinfecting previously used needles and syringes with bleach can reduce the risk of HIV transmission.) If you are planning to have any part of your body pierced or to get a tattoo, be sure to see a qualified professional who uses sterile equipment. 

Had unprotected sex of any kind

Preventing Transmission:

Abstain from sex 

Learn as much as you can about each partner&#8217;s past behavior (sex and drug use), and consider the risks to your health before you have sex.

Use a latex condom every time you have sex.

Get tested


1. The largest estimated proportion of HIV/AIDS diagnoses were for women who have sex with infected men, followed by adults and adolescents infected through heterosexual contact.

2. Nearly half of the roughly 40,000 Americans newly infected with HIV each year are under the age of 25. Approximately two young Americans become infected with HIV every hour of every day, and about 25% of the people now living with HIV in this country beca

3.  In 2005, blacks accounted for almost half of the estimated number of HIV/AIDS cases in the US

4. All donations will go to AMFAR

5. Even if y'all aren't able to donate money, just be aware of the disease and try to educate others on the issue

6. In western countries, women are four times more likely to contract HIV through vaginal sex with infected males than vice versa. This biological vulnerability is worsened by social and cultural factors that often undermine women's ability to avoid sex with

7. You cannot tell by looking at someone whether he or she is infected with HIV or has AIDS. An infected person can appear completely healthy. But anyone infected with HIV can infect other people, even if no symptoms are present.

8. Immediately after infection, some people may develop mild, temporary flu-like symptoms or persistent swollen glands. Even if you look and feel healthy, you may be infected. The only way to know your HIV status for sure is to be tested for HIV antibodies p

9. Having HIV does not necessarily mean you will get AIDS.

10. Some people are afraid of others with HIV and AIDS. It's just like any other virus out there.  Be nice to them because there is nothing wrong with it.  One day it could happen to you! So always treat others kindly.</description>
  <mission>Help fight and raise awareness of the disease that is steadily infecting millions of people each year</mission>
  <name>HIV and AIDS Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/739</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">99355</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3507.87</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/b4X/v2tS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
