<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>so the world is getting hotter, wow, then in a few years it might get colder, oh my god lets panic! Temperatures change! We must think soo much of ourselves that we believe that our creations, our cars and planes can do damage to the earth, in light of such massive natural influences as the sun, which seems more likley to be responsible for climate change. Yes yes its all our doing, if the dinosaurs had driven hybrids maby they would be around today. the earth has been here a while now, most things on or in it are carbon based! has anyone ever seen any actuall proof, not of a heat rise ( this is obvious, heat will go up and down, climates will change) but of an effect of our carbon output? The reason behind this whole new 'carbon footprint' is that there are no products that can be made and sold, that will reduce the effects of weather! therefore, a cause for weather must be CREATED and sold to us (these pricks on the news droning on are the same scum as door to door direct salesmen. For those reading this in dissgust, if you really want to do your bit, DON'T BREED. apart from the world not needing any more closed minded, meek sheep who launch into a crusade without really understanding what is going on, possibly only to seem more considerate or sensetive to theire friends. If you think not flying or driving a smart car will put a dent in your so called carbon footprint, what do you think your child will do? and their children. If you really care about the environment, kill yourself and those around you!. Carbon is now a brand and a scam.

DO NOT DONATE TO THIS CAUSE. IT IS NOT NECESSARY.

1. a carbon footprint is purely marketing, dont be fooled.

2. Lets get a grasp of our insignificance.

3. doggie</description>
  <mission>to give a different angle.</mission>
  <name>Global Warming S M C</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7394</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/X0/Sh/Hg/tP/B3/cb/R8OS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
