<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Esphigmenou monks live a life of spiritual and monastic tranquility in the unbroken tradition of the brotherhood that has occupied the monastery for over a thousand years.  Mount Athos is the spiritual center of the Orthodox Church, where the monks are considered defenders of the faith. The Esphigmenou Monastery established in the first millennium, is where the great St. Gregory Palamas was abbot, and where St. Anthony left for Russia to establish Orthodox monasticism. Its remoteness and rugged natural beauty attracts pilgrims and tourists alike, who come to see the art and architecture of the Byzantine Empire.

The monks of Esphigmenou, the most populous monastery on the remote Greek peninsula Mount Athos, disagree with the politicizing of their faith by patriarch Bartholomew of Constantinople (Istanbul), and as a result, are once again under siege.  The patriarch, obsessed with quashing dissenting voices, has ordered the Greek police to enforce a blockade, to starve the monks into submission.

Items under embargo:

All food deliveries. 

Medical Supplies.  

Physician's visits prohibited (monastery has diabetic monks and heart patients). 

Fuel for heating, cooking etc. 

Monastery's telephone line has been cut. 

Electricity in Monastery's small dairy farm has been cut off. 

Monastery's Farm Tractor used to till the land has been seized by the Greek Police. 

Greek Police chief told Monastery to remove its last vehicle from Mount Athos which it uses, when necessary, to transport sick and  injured monks. 

Greek Police chief of Mount Athos has yet to arrest any of the well known, marauding band of men who have TWICE attacked the fathers of Esphigmenou Monastery, with crowbars and sledge hammers, sending seven fathers with serious injuries to the hospital and expelling two of them from Mount Athos. 

...and (unfortunately) MUCH more. 

www.esphigmenou.com

1. The Ecumenical Patriarchate and Greek government must end the sadistic embargo.

2. No setting up of pseudo-brotherhoods with the name Esphimgenou

3. Recognition that the monks have the right to basic human rights, and deserve to be treated with such.</description>
  <mission>Contribute your efforts to the cause of liberating Esphigmenou Monastery from the brutal attacks of both the Ecumenical Patriarchate and the Greek government. </mission>
  <name>Save Esphigmenou Monastery!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7395</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1198</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">120.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/e6/Im/vN/kl/Hc/y3/SRtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
