<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The NKF of Florida is one of 48 affiliates of the National Kidney Foundation, a not-for-profit, tax-exempt, national voluntary health agency. Its activities are governed by a volunteer board of trustees. All programs and services are made possible through the contributions of a generous public.

The mission of the NKF of Florida is to prevent kidney and urinary tract diseases, improve the health and well-being of individuals and families affected by these diseases, and increase the availability of all organs for transplantation.

The NKF of Florida is a vital resource for kidney patients and their families - helping them learn how to cope with the physical and psychological aspects of the disease and providing them with hope for the future.

      -- (www.kidneyfla.org)

&lt;b&gt;*DONATIONS CAN BE MADE AT:&lt;/b&gt; http://www.kidney.org/support/

1. Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is a public health problem affecting 20 million. 

2. Risk factors include:diabetes, high blood pressure, and family history.

3. 92,000 people are waiting for organ transplants.

4. 17 people die each day waiting for an organ transplant.

5. Organ transplant demand rises 5 times as fast as supply. 

6. Kidney disease results in 27 million physician visits, 6 million hospitalizations and 2.5 million surgical procedures each year. 

7. Early detection can help prevent the progression of kidney disease to kidney failure. 

8. African Americans, Hispanics, Pacific Islanders, Native Americans and Seniors are at increased risk. 

9. Three simple tests can detect CKD: blood pressure, urine and serum creatinine. </description>
  <mission>to prevent kidney and urinary tract diseases, improve the health and well-being of individuals and families affected by these diseases, and increase the availability of all organs for transplantation.</mission>
  <name>National Kidney Foundation of Florida</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7399</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">555</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Tp/e7/e5/Dh/xr/np/1B/vFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
