<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of the people who are serving in the armed forces are in life-changing situations. They face fear, home sickness, isolation, pain, and death.  Some of them are at the most strategic moments of their lives&#8212;moments of receptivity, of soul-searching, of discovery, and of life transformation.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their families, too, go through hardships, pain, and loss so that their loved ones can serve their country. It can be a horribly hard life.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Those in the military community need to know and rely on the hope of Jesus. They also deserve someone to come alongside them to help them cope, love, and carry on.&lt;/p&gt; 


&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cadence International&lt;/b&gt; - Cadence International's mission statement is to share the gospel and your life with the military community! &lt;a href="http://www.cadence.org"&gt;www.cadence.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cadence International is a Christian mission organization dedicated to reaching the military communities of the United States and of the world with the Good News of Jesus Christ. This is carried out through Bible studies, hospitality, evangelism, friendship, and discipleship. Cadence ministers not only to military personnel, but to their spouses and dependents as well. Malachi Ministries, the youth division of Cadence, reaches youth in the military community. Also through a partnership with CEF, Military Children's Ministry reaches out to the children of military personnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cadence serves all branches of the U.S. military in American and overseas locations. Cadence also serves and disciples military personnel of several foreign countries (including Ukraine, Russia, Belarus, Thailand, and Cambodia), sharing the message of salvation, hope, and love of Christ with this unique group of people.&lt;/p&gt;

1. People in the military community need to know Christ</description>
  <mission>To share the gospel of Jesus with the military communities around the world and show them love and support</mission>
  <name>Support our Troops with the love and hope of Christ</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7401</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">371</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Un/nx/wm/fx/t0/vV/8VrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
