<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Approximately 15.5 percent of adolescents (ages 12&#8211;19) were overweight in 2000. An additional 14.9 percent of adolescents were at risk for overweight (based on BMI / body mass index measures).

Overweight children and adolescents are more likely to become obese as adults. 

Being overweight or obese increases the risk of many diseases and health conditions, including the following:
Hypertension 
Dyslipidemia (for example, high total cholesterol or high levels of triglycerides) 
Type 2 diabetes 
Coronary heart disease 
Stroke 
Gallbladder disease 
Osteoarthritis 
Sleep apnea and respiratory problems 
Some cancers (endometrial, breast, and colon) 

About 25 percent of young people (ages 12&#8211;21 years) participate in light to moderate activity nearly every day. About 50 percent regularly engage in vigorous physical activity. Approximately 25 percent report no vigorous physical activity, and 14 percent report no recent vigorous or light to moderate physical activity.

Physical activity: Participating in physical activity is important for children and teens as it may have beneficial effects not only on body weight, but also on blood pressure and bone strength. Physically active children are also more likely to remain physically active throughout adolescence and possibly into adulthood.

Less than one-third (28%) of high school students meet currently recommended levels of physical activity.

NATFE (National Association on Teen Fitness and Exercise): http://www.natfe.org/
WE CAN (Ways to Enhance Children's Activity and Nutrition): http://www.nhlbi.nih.gov/health/public/heart/obesity/wecan_mats/parent_hb_en.pdf



1. Raise the awareness about the prevalence of obesity in young people

2. Develop innovative physical activity and nutrition education programs 

3. Raise the self esteem and self worth of youth so they can be productive citizens</description>
  <mission>improve the health status of young adults and their families by empowering them with opportunities to programs involving physical activity and nutrition education</mission>
  <name>Active Adolescents</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7402</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">12</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cV/D1/Qx/r3/Xg/tj/ttnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
