<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>President George W. Bush and Vice President Dick Cheney need to be impeach immediately. The two of them have led the American people into Iraq, which should not have occurred in the first place. It is now proven that Bush did not have any significant evidence to link Iraq with what occurred on 9/11. The main arguments for invading Iraq were weapons of mass destruction, some link to 9/11, &amp; hoarding terrorist organizations, of which are false. But it can be proven now that the invasion of Iraq has created a basis for recruiting other terrorists.

How has the war in Iraq created a safer America? To sum up the opinions of many people "IT HAS NOT MADE AMERICA SAFER!" Over 3,500 American troops have died in this war so far, and the Bush Administration praise these loyal service men/woman for doing a service for this country. What the media is not saying is how the Administration is using OUR troops for a cause that serves the special interest groups that have put them in the oval office. As most of the American people know, Bush/Cheney came from oil industry backgrounds. So it is not surprising the first area our troops secured in Iraq were the oil reserves. Cheney use to be a VP at Halliburton, and the Administration has used Halliburton to extract oil from Iraq. The problem is no oil has been extracted and billions of dollars are unaccounted for.

If over 3,500 American Troops have died as a cause of this war, think about how many Iraqis' have died. The answer is well over 200,000 people, but that is not a statistic that the media publishes because as Americans we do not care about any other nation except our own....right?

*Be part of the movement to bring America back in the spot-light of ethical behavior, and out of the red light of blood and world domination. $1 can make all the difference to spread the word, to lead Our country in a fresh direction.

1. Position #1</description>
  <mission>unite the citizens of the United States of America. The very citizens that have been lied to and manipulated.</mission>
  <name>Impeach Bush-Cheney</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7437</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">467</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/T0/7M/jN/iS/vf/6Y/5BES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
