<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I want to tell you what my friend Peter Van Stolk and the folks at Jones Soda are doing with Vitamin Angels, and ask you for your help to hopefully save 1,000,000 kids lives and sell some soda.  Here's the pitch to support Vitamin Angels from Jones Soda:
 
As you may or may not know traditional advertising is very expensive and it would cost Jones millions of dollars to place a television commercial with one the national media corporations. That money would be spent with no real way of measuring if it provided a benefit to us. 
 
So we had an idea: place our three-legged dog commercial on YouTube (just like everybody else and their dog) However just placing a video on YouTube means nothing if people don&#8217;t watch it. 
 
Then we thought about how we could make people feel good watching our clip and be motivated to send it to friends. 
 
Saving a child&#8217;s life should be the motivating factor in watching a commercial.  
 
So instead of giving money to Fox or NBC why not give the money to a charity?    Vitamin Angels
 
A crazy concept of using the money that we would spend with a media corporation and giving it to a charity for the same results! 
 
What if this idea takes off and companies copy us&#8230;&#8230;.. That would be awesome. 
 
Yes, Jones wants to pay you to watch this clip, and yes we want to you to be excited and proud about sending it to your friends.  
 
Save a life, send an email.
 
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wn3s2j33oEY

1. Every person has the right to vital nutrition

2. No one ever needs to go hungry

3. Vitamin A deficiency childhood blindness is preventable</description>
  <mission>Eliminate childhood blindness by the year 2020 through the systematic distribution of vitamin A to at-risk children. </mission>
  <name>Vitamin Angels</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7441</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Zw/X1/xe/PF/Yi/AH/Bx4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
