<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is straight from the humane society's e-mail news letter it said, 


" Soon after 'Baby' arrived at a puppy mill, her vocal cords were cut with scissors, without any anesthetic, so she couldn't bark. The puppy mill owner didn't want to be disturbed. Then, she was confined in a cramped cage with a chicken wire floor, so the owner did not have to clean it. Later, she broke her leg, and it was left untreated for years. Ultimately, the leg had to be amputated... 


As you may know, puppy mills are large-scale breeding facilities. They force mother and father dogs to produce litter after litter of puppies to support consumer demand for purebred and 'designer' dogs.


'Breeder dogs' are routinely kept in horrific conditions, enduring a lifetime of misery in tiny cages, deprived of exercise, decent food, or even basic veterinary care. As they age and their fertility wanes, these animals are often killed or abandoned. 


What most pet owners and animal lovers don't realize is that so many of the puppies sold through pet stores or Internet sites come from places just like these -- breeding operations filled with suffering, disease, and malnutrition. Puppy mills typically operate without oversight, sell puppies through third parties, and use deceptive practices to fool the public into believing they care about the puppies they breed. That is why it is crucial to shine a spotlight on this unseen industry."


When i read this it broke my heart. i had no idea this was happening!! and now that i do i want to raise the awareness of this cause. 


1. this is just sick and it needs to end. </description>
  <mission>stop them from continuing</mission>
  <name>Puppy Mills</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7446</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">347</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kN/xo/qT/lh/qK/Cz/s64S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
