<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>!!FACT!!   !!FACT!!    !!FACT!!    !!FACT!!   !!FACT!!
        !!FACT!!   !!FACT!!    !!FACT!!    !!FACT!!

1. Every two and a half minutes, somewhere in America, someone is sexually assaulted. 

2. One in six American women are victims of sexual assault, and one in 33 men. 

3. In 2004-2005, there were an average annual 200,780 victims of rape, attempted rape or sexual assault. 

4. About 44% of rape victims are under age 18, and 80% are under age 30.

5. Since 1993, rape/sexual assault has fallen by over 69%.



--Rapes Still Not Being Reported--
The National Crime Victimization Survey includes statistics on reported and unreported crimes in America. Sexual assault is one of the most underreported crimes, with more than half(59%) still being left unreported. Utilizing services such as The National Sexual Assault Hotline can help encourage victims to get help and report what has happened to them so that more perpetrators can be brought to justice.

Males are the least likely to report a sexual assault, though it is estimated they make up 10% of all victims. Young females are four times more likely than any other group to be a victim of sexual assault.




There's so much you can do without taking out your wallets.  Your voice is more powerful than any amount of money, and your actions could be the stepping stones to preventing another act of sexual violence.  Take a moment to think about what you could do to help the victims of sexual assault, and then act.


1. The prevention of all sexually related attacks/violence

2. Provide support for those who are victims of sexual violence

3. Educate the nation about different meanings of sexual violence</description>
  <mission>Support and Protect victims of sexual violence</mission>
  <name>Stop Sexual Violence/Rape</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7455</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">53464</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">848.14</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/q8/ll/O1/Yc/VX/R1/RRYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
