<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Millions of North Americans are prohibited by law from accessing personal records that pertain to their own identities, even when they reach adulthood.

Such records are held by governments in secret and without accountability, due solely to the fact that they were adopted. We advocate for the civil rights of these people.

MISSION STATEMENT:
Bastard Nation is dedicated to the recognition of the full human and civil rights of adult adoptees. Toward that end, we advocate the opening to adoptees, upon request at age of majority, of those government documents which pertain to the adoptee's historical, genetic, and legal identity, including the unaltered original birth certificate and adoption decree. Bastard Nation asserts that it is the right of people everywhere to have their official original birth records unaltered and free from falsification, and that the adoptive status of any person should not prohibit him or her from choosing to exercise that right. We have reclaimed the badge of bastardy placed on us by those who would attempt to shame us; we see nothing shameful in having been born out of wedlock or in being adopted. Bastard Nation does not support mandated mutual consent registries or intermediary systems in place of unconditional open records, nor any other system that is less than access on demand to the adult adoptee, without condition, and without qualification. 

BASTARD NATION'S NONPROFIT STATUS:
Bastard Nation is a 501(c)(4) non-profit organization. As a 501(c)(4), Bastard Nation does not retain all of the perks associated with being a 501(c)(3) non-profit (donations are not tax-deductible), but in return we have the freedom to support legislation and political campaigns, and in general to move beyond the arena of education into political advocacy. To this end, Bastard Nation accepts paid memberships and donations, sells merchandise, and holds annual conferences. 



1. Everyone has the right to know their own identity

2. Adoptees are NOT second-class citizens, and deserve the same rights, freedoms and liberties as everyone else!

3. It's MY BIRTH CERTIFICATE - NOT A GOVERNMENT SECRET!!!</description>
  <mission>To ensure that all adult adoptees have unrestricted access to their own original birth certificates</mission>
  <name>Bastard Nation - Open Adoption Records</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7456</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1399</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.65</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/lP/fl/Wo/et/pC/rU/oCpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
