<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our vision of America's public and community transportation future &#8212; the cause that we serve &#8212; is based upon fundamental values that are as old as the nation itself. Freedom, independence, dignity and choice are as much at the heart of the debate for building an accessible society as they have been in building a free society. There is never an end to the work to create a free society, and there will never be an end to our work to build a more mobile society. Both of these noble pursuits remain great works in progress.

Americans have been trying to build their mobile society for many years. Part of this mobility can be seen in the mass production of automobiles and highways that surround our nation, our cities and our neighborhoods. It can be seen in the proliferation of airports, regional air carriers and growing congestion in our skies. And although our values never grow old &#8212; our approach and technology do become outdated, as well as our thinking. 

For more information, go to http://www.ctaa.org.

1. Communities with staggering air quality problems and ground congestion need improved public and community transportation alternatives.

2. Areas and communities that have been abandoned or which are in decline need public and community transportation options as part of their renewal efforts.

3. A society that now includes a growing population of seniors needs new and expanded community transportation alternatives.  </description>
  <mission>Provide effective public and community transportation contributes mightily to the quality of life of the people living in the cities, towns and communities in which it operates. </mission>
  <name>CTAA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/746</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">28</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1c5/UOaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
