<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>-==NOTICE==--  
For those of you who don't know, when you click the "Donate" button from this cause, you are actually giving your donation to JustGive.org, who then passes your donation on to The Seed Company. Please do not send your donations through this organization. We have no doubt that they are a fine ministry with an honest purpose, but they do appropriate 4.5% of your donation for their own operating expenses. (This information can be found under their Terms of Use, at the bottom of the donations page.) Instead, let me urge you to go directly to The Seed Company website, www.theseedcompany.org or the OneVerse website, www.oneverse.org, and send your donations from there. You can be assured that when you donate directly to us, 100% of your gift will reach missionaries on the field.

OneVerse http://www.oneverse.org

Our Mission:
The Seed Company&#8217;s mission is to complete Bible translations in the heart languages of people without God&#8217;s Word through partnering with: 

-national colleagues 
-prayer supporters and investors 
-like-minded organizations 

Our Vision:
Creatively networking God's people around the world to translate the Bible into every language for his glory.

Our Core Values:
-Honoring God in all we do 
-Valuing individuals and relationships 
-Committed to effective partnerships 
-Encouraging creativity and innovation 
-Managing for quality results 

Doctrinal Statement:
-The divine inspiration and consequent authority of the whole canonical Scripture 
-The doctrine of the trinity 
-The fall of man, his consequent moral depravity and his need for regeneration 
-The atonement through the substitutionary death of Christ 
-The doctrine of justification by faith 
-The resurrection of the body, both of the just and the unjust 
-The eternal life of the saved and the eternal punishment of the lost 



1. To get a portion of scripture into everyone's  heart language by 2025.

2. To connect prayer and financial partners to translation projects</description>
  <mission>To complete Bible translations in the heart languages of people without God&#8217;s Word through partnering with national colleagues, prayer supporters and investors, and like-minded organizations</mission>
  <name>The Seed Company/OneVerse</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7464</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">691</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8a/mS/UN/6i/Va/mS/MttS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
