<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>AIDS is one of the largest and most complex threats to human health the world has ever known. Great stigma compounds already tragic physical consequences. And in the developing world, poverty itself is both a cause and an effect of a pandemic that is devastating the physical, social and economic health of entire regions.

People around the world continue to suffer and die from this disease, which often robs them of family, social networks and ways to make a living. Young women bear the greatest risk of infection and burden of caring for the ill. But many people have found ways to live with dignity despite their HIV-status, and Catholic Relief Services works to replicate that success. 

Central to our HIV and AIDS strategy is helping the local church and local agencies establish, expand and strengthen their own capacity to respond to the AIDS crisis.

Dignity and quality of life are at the heart of CRS' HIV and AIDS programming. We also work to reduce the spread of the disease by addressing its fundamental causes. 


1. Direct community-based assistance to people living with HIV and AIDS.

2. Ensure antiretroviral drugs that help reverse the virus' progression are avaialable to those that need them.

3. We must support orphans and other children made vulnerable by the effects of HIV and AIDS 

4. Prevention is key - complete information about HIV and AIDS, counseling and testing options, treatment of previous infections and prevention of mother-to-child transmission must be communicated.

5. Help families and individuals meet their own needs; empower self-sufficiency when appropriate.

6. Enlist advocacy efforts to give a voice both in the U.S. and in the developing world to those affected.</description>
  <mission>Facing AIDS with Dignity in the Developing World</mission>
  <name>Act on HIV and AIDS</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7471</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">250</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kd/2b/JP/EF/2Z/yF/Vx7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
