<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>UIFI is a 5-day journey, with each day building upon the one previous. UIFI offers participants the opportunity to explore, define, and enhance their leadership skills, personal awareness, commitment to their fraternity or sorority, and grow to expect values based action from themselves and those they lead.

The institute is interactive, fun, challenging, and intentional. During a session, you'll experience hands-on interaction, experiential activities, discussion time, and personal reflection time. There is considerable focus on the positive aspects of fraternities and sororities in addition to important discussions about issues that threaten our future. It really doesn't matter what session you attend, the curriculum is the same at all of them. 

Taking the ride means being willing to talk about how fraternity and sorority leaders live their ritual. It means having the courage, character, and commitment to do what is right and devise a plan to change the current direction of some fraternities and sororities. It means walking the talk. It means having a vision of positive change. 

Each UIFI participant is challenged to develop a personal plan of action and to make a commitment to leading their organizations through the change process. It is a unique challenge, one that each participant must be willing to undertake.



1. Fraternity &amp; sorority education must be values-based.

2. The values and rituals of our organizations should be seen daily in our actions.

3. Academic achievement and integrity are paramount.

4. Respect for all persons, including their health and safety and personal property, are essential.

5. Challanging others is the only way to bring about positive change.</description>
  <mission>To raise money for the UIFI program to provide more undergraduate Greek students the opportunity to attend the values-based educational program.</mission>
  <name>The Undergraduate Interfraternity Institute</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7473</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">461</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">525.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/RF/aX/T4/FD/1K/fq/gPZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
