<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Interact is Rotary International's service club for young people ages 14-18. Interact clubs are sponsored by individual Rotary clubs, which provide support and guidance, but Interact clubs are self-governing and self-supporting. 

Club membership varies greatly. Clubs can be single-gender or mixed, as well as large and small. The membership base can be drawn from the student body of a single school or from two or more schools from the same community. 

Each year, Interact clubs complete at least two community service projects, one of which furthers international understanding and goodwill. Through projects, Interactors develop a network of friendships with local and overseas clubs. And, in the process, Interactors develop leadership skills and learn the value of hard work.As one of the most significant and fastest-growing programs of Rotary service, with more than 10,700 clubs in 109 countries and geographical areas, Interact has become a worldwide phenomenon.

Interactors also often spearhead the formation of Rotaract clubs and participate in Rotary Youth Leadership Awards (RYLA). Interactors also often go on to become Youth Exchange students or Ambassadorial Scholars.

For more information about Interact in your area, contact your local Rotary club or your district Interact chair.

1. Developing leadership skills and personal integrity

2. .Demonstrating helpfulness and respect for others

3. Advancing international understanding and goodwill</description>
  <mission>INTERACT aims to have its members develop leadership skills and personal integrity, demonstrate helpfulness and respect for others, and advance international understanding and goodwill.</mission>
  <name>INTERACT</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7482</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3886</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">18.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2e/L4/Uy/RS/1k/iL/JK6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
