<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What we see in the world of killings in Iraq, Afghanistan and Palestine. What we saw already in Lebanon and what we'll see in the future is worse .We always cry foul of whats happening but we do nothing at all .In fact what we see of all those wars and killing is because we the ones who support  Zionism and USA.. Accept reality we hate them we criticize them but at the same time we support them by buying their products its an irony but reality. I know most will say its impossible to boycott all American products or Jewish. I would not disagree but we can still affect heavily on them .They call us terrorists and all that shit and we still support them! 
Victory comes when you make an effort to do something (don't expect it to come on its own) . Lets all boycott coca cola (if you wanna boycott more its even better) from this buy anything else ..come on i mean its not the only thing you have to buy...If we all boycott Coca cola for a month or a year imagine how bad we'll affect Americans economy which thru government supports Zionism. I'm not showing any hatred for the Americans but the hatred is there to that motherfucking government.
Don't dismiss this...
Unity to boycott Coca Cola
plz invite as much ppl as u can or pass this msg thru           

1. We still have a word in what happens today ,we don't decide but do affect the situation.

2. Encourage countries especially in the third world countries to stop buying overpriced, unnecessary goods and stop exporting huge portions of their natural resources when they can manufacture themselves.</description>
  <mission>Affect american and israeli goods &amp; economy by boycotting them or by any other means </mission>
  <name>Anti Zionism,USA,Coca Cola</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7493</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">112</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/OH/1J/Ri/Zi/Mb/Vu/VANS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
