<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We should try to limit pollution/ keep the environment safe to make our world a better place to live, not to prevent an over hyped potential apocalypse. We need to look past the scare tactics that many politicians, scientists, and entertainers use. We should be questioning what the &#8220;consensus&#8221; is telling us, and we should use pragmatic problem solving to study this type of global problem.  

The temperature of earth has been rising for the past 20,000 years. Very rarely has earth been cooler than the past 200 years; during those time periods, much of earth has been covered by ice. Over the past 650,000 years, earth&#8217;s temperature has gone through regular cycles of rise and fall. These cycles have to do with the gravitational pull between other planets and the sun with earth and the varying amounts of solar radiation that reach our planet, not with increasing CO2 levels.
        
Water levels have been rising for the past 18,000 years; about a 400 ft. increase total. Over the past few thousand years, the rate has actually slowed down. Ocean levels are only going up 1.8 millimeters a year; that&#8217;s less than the thickness of a nickel. Gore predicts sea levels to rise 18-20 feet in 100 years.  In actuality, it will take 3,500 years to get to that level.
	
The Kyoto Protocol, if actually followed by every member, would reduce global warming by .07 Celsius every 50 years. If we turned every kernel of American corn into ethanol, it would displace only 12% of our yearly gasoline consumption. That effect of &#8220;global warming&#8221; would also be too small to measure. Even if we Americans are able to decrease our carbon dioxide output, it would have no effect considering the rapidly increasing energy consumption of China and India. If we cut our emissions by half, we wouldn&#8217;t be able to measure the difference because of China and India&#8217;s increase. &#8220;Reversing&#8221; global warming would require cutting global emissions by 60-80%; an amount that would destroy the world&#8217;s economy. 


1. Position #1</description>
  <mission>spread awareness that global warming is NOT scientific fact.</mission>
  <name>Global Warming is Questionable</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7504</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">57</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yk/C3/Pr/vz/He/5I/PQrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
