<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>www.410bridge.org

&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;The Official Lowdown&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
The 410 Bridge began like most great movements do- as an idea in the head of one man, Lanny Donoho. Lanny founded BigStuf student camps and soon began a partnership with Compassion International to take several college students to Africa as part of their pre-camp training. It was on such a trip that the vision for The 410 Bridge was birthed. On a walk through the Kenyan slums, a place where God&#8217;s hope is so clear in the middle of such desperate conditions, the BigStuf team found their lives profoundly transformed, inspiring their founder to seek out a way to provide this life change to others, in both America and Kenya.

Thus, the vision was born: to provide the people of American churches, communities, and families a bridge to a nation in need, a way to answer the calling to serve and to give and to make adifference in God&#8217;s kingdom. As Lanny began to share this vision in April 2006, a number of people and organizations surfaced who felt such a calling and were looking for a way to fulfill it. With these people, we began to wonder what might happen if a new concept of missions was presented, one with a very clear and innovative direction that was captivating enough to capture thousands of people.

&lt;b&gt;Visit our BLOG!!&lt;b&gt;
http://410bridge.org/Blog/

&lt;b&gt;Follow us on Twitter!&lt;b&gt;
http://twitter.com/410Bridge


1. Education

2. Health

3. Micro-Enterprise

4. Spiritual Development

5. Water</description>
  <mission>The 410 Bridge partners churches with communities in Kenya, providing an outlet to serve one another and administer God's grace to a nation in need.</mission>
  <name>The 410 Bridge</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7509</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1891</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1301.45</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/O6/h2/df/qp/pG/xr/CW/qvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
