<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>If you would like to donate any money to a charity supporting this cause then I would suggest looking on Google or another search engine for a REGISTERED CHARITY.
***It is important that whatever charity you choose is legitimate and has its registered charity number clearly displayed on its website.***
You may also donate to Amnesty USA if you donate through this page.  Visit the Amnesty UK page to find out how to donate to them too.

www.amnesty.org.uk


PLEASE REFRAIN FROM BEING INTOLERANT AND IGNORANT WHEN POSTING ON THIS PAGE.  OFFENSIVE AND INNAPROPRIATE BEHAVIOR WILL RESULT IN YOU BEING BANNED FROM THIS CAUSE PERMANENTLY.


*******************************************


People often confuse Asylum Seekers with Illegal Immigrants.  There are many different catagories of immigration including Refugees and Economic Migrants.

To define them all:

ASYLUM SEEKER::
*has arrived in another country and has made themselves known to the authorities
*is fleeing from persecution in their homeland
*has applied for asylum, which is a legal right.

FAILED ASYLUM SEEKER::
*someone whose asylum application has been  turned down
*they are awaiting return to their country; if it is not safe to return, they may have to stay for the time being.

REFUGEE::
*they have proved they would face persecution back home
*someone whose asylum application has been successful and are allowed to stay in the country.

ECONOMIC MIGRANT:
*a person who has moved to another country to work.

ILLEGAL IMMIGRANT::
*a person that has arrived in another country and has intentionally not made themselves known to the authorities
*also can be someone who has stayed in a country longer than allowed
*someone who has no legal right to be there.


*******************************************


STATISTICS::
You'll probably be shocked to learn that 33% of refugees have a degree, post graduate and/or professional qualification. Only 15% of UK citizens have such qualifications.
As this is the case, why are so many people complaining about refugees "taking British citizens' jobs" rather than going out and getting their own qualifications that will enable them to get their own career?


65% of Asylum seekers can speak at least 2 additional languages, whereas only 18% of UK citizens can do so.
Why are we complaining about foregin people and their inhability to speak English when the majority of them can speak perfect English but we are too ignorant to listen to them properly?


People born outside the UK pay 10% more into the economy than they take out - &#163;2.5 billion in 1999 &#8211; 2000 (Home Office study)


60% of Asylum Seekers are under age of 30 years &#8211; UK desperately needs more people of working age to support population increasingly overloaded with pensioners.

***********************************

1. Asylum seekers and refugees must stop being persecuted and confused with illegal immigrants.</description>
  <mission>educate the public on issues surrounding seeking asylum in the UK.</mission>
  <name>Asylum Is A Human Right.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7515</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">122</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Br/P7/aS/C2/0M/O4/hauS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
