<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Every year nearly 200,000 children are born in India with congenital heart disease (CHD) adding to the existing millions suffering from the disease. Of these, only 6 to 8 percent of them receive medical treatment. The rest either don&#8217;t get timely treatment or their parents simply cannot afford the cost of surgery and treatment. Shockingly, in India each year about 121,000 cases of adult CHD cases reach the age of 15 years due to lack of health awareness, poverty and inadequate healthcare facilities. A new program to help such children was started by renowned cardiologist Dr.Gopichand, the Managing Trustee of Hrudaya Foundation, a non-profit charitable trust that does free treatment for underprivileged children afflicted by congenital heart disease.

Cure a Little Heart Foundation - a non-profit organization, in collaboration with the India based Hrudaya Foundation elaborates on the need for real community participation to get rid of the disease and this is possible only if socially conscious individuals and communities come together in this endeavour

Hrudaya regularly conducts free CHD screening camps and plans to take the screening camps to every part of India. Further, the charitable trust sponsors free surgeries for underprivileged children afflicted with the disease and bears all costs of surgery. In the last one year Dr. Gopichand has successfully conducted more than 400 free operations on poor children afflicted with CHD. The foundation is also open to provide health care to children all over the world. 

We know children are the future, and we don&#8217;t see what we do as charity. It is a necessity. If we don&#8217;t protect the children today, mankind will suffer tomorrow. The important thing is to act - and act now!





1. Putting the smile back to little children

2. Every penny you donate will contribute to save lives of children

3. Remember your donations will change the future of many children and their families

4. We hope this cause will have a positive effect on their little hearts

5. All the donations will directly goto the beneficiary and the accounts are audited by PriceWaterHouse Coopers for transparency.</description>
  <mission>To treat little children who are suffering from Congenital and Acquired Heart Diseases that has come upon through no cause of them and give them a better life in the society of mankind.

</mission>
  <name>Cure a Little Heart - Your Kind Heart can cure a Little Heart!!!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7517</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">898</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">715.08</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/TV/mf/4T/PJ/JF/tq/wgwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
