<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>
http://www.usask.ca/nativelaw/rs2.html

Native American and Alaska Native women in the United States suffer disproportionately high levels of rape and sexual violence, yet the federal government has created substantial barriers to accessing justice. 
 
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2PkSnXXQ1TQ


Much of the clinical and research literature on the consequences and treatment of sexual abuse assumes relative homogeneity in the abuse experience. Little differentiation is acknowledged on the basis of race, ethnicity, or class, despite the known salience of these variables in the construction and interpretation of human experience. A phenomenological examination of the experiences of six adult aboriginal women who were sexually abused as children identified six themes common to their experiences. These findings led to specific recommendations for working with aboriginal survivors of sexual abuse.

THE CANADIAN ABORIGINAL EXPERIENCE

Formal studies that examine the prevalence of child sexual abuse among native communities do not exist. However, clinical and anecdotal evidence suggests that the incidence of sexual abuse among Canada's native peoples are as high as 80% (The Nechi Institute, The Four Worlds Development Project, 1988). In one study, service providers in six Western Arctic communities estimated that in these native communities between 75% and 80% of all young girls under the age of 8 and at least 50% of the male children were sexually abused. While few statistics are available, child sexual abuse appears to be a serious problem within native communities; female children seem to be sexually victimized in greater numbers than male children, with both male and female native children apparently abused at a substantially higher rate than characteristically reported for non-native groups.
 

 This artical goes on for pages and pages  This is the Link. http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_qa3711/is_199508/ai_n8726838

1. Position #1</description>
  <mission>To make the public aware of what native children are faced with </mission>
  <name>Native youth .</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7522</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cV/kR/jk/5T/B8/YM/RV5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
