<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>NORD gives a voice to the rare disease community by serving as resource of information so that individuals can be a better health advocate for themselves. NORD provides rare disease information to the health care professionals so that they can become a better diagnostitian for their patients. NORD provides assistance for rare disease support groups so that they can be a better resource for their members and others who may be affected by that particular rare disease. NORD encourages the pharmaceutical and biotechnology industries to develop orphan drugs to treat these rare diseases. NORD educates our policy makers on the importance of creating legislation that will improve the lives of individuals affected by rare diseases through better drug and insurance coverage. And finally NORD provides to the general public a resource to tap into that will help them should they be diagnosed with a rare disease. 
Programs: NORD has three main components to its organization. Primarily there is Information Services that provides the reliable medical information on rare diseases. This includes a networking program for individuals wishing to be connected to others with the same disease; a newsletter, Orphan Disease Update,books such as NORD's Resource Guide and referrals to rare disease support groups. NORD's Patient Services Program administrates over 18 medication assistance programs for pharmaceutical companies primarily for orphan drugs. NORD's Advocacy Program assists individuals and support groups on getting the attention of their legislators so that they discuss with thier lawmakers their own concerns 


1. Encourgae research on rare disease

2. Provide information on rare disease

3. Educate policy makers about rare diseases</description>
  <mission>Cure Rare Diseases</mission>
  <name>National Organization for Rare Disorders</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7529</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">500</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">118.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fv/uh/dz/D0/SR/0u/wePS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
