<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Since 1977 City of Refuge has been actively involved in benevolent outreach to the Last, Lost and Least of inner-city Atlanta. We understand the need for programs that span multiple areas of need &#8211; from food, clothing, and shelter, to job training, placement, housing, life skills, and transportation. Our goal is to provide the best possible opportunities for success to those who are willing to work hard to change their lives.


MISSION:
City of Refuge offers both life saving resources and life building tools to individuals and families in Atlanta who are living on the margin. We understand the need for programs that span multiple areas of need &#8211; from food, clothing, and shelter, to job training, placement, housing, life skills, and transportation. Our goal is to provide the best possible opportunities for success to those who are willing to work hard to change their lives.

VISION:
Using the City of Refuge Warehouse as a base, we are committed to deploying men, women, and resources into environments where difficulty resides, bringing hope to those living there. The promise of a better life, along with the tools to build that life, is the passion of City of Refuge. 
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

The &#8220;Lifeline&#8221; is the initial entry point for exposure to the programs of City of Refuge. Our mission is to meet the initial needs of the last, the lost and the least of the city of Atlanta. This entry point gives the greatest opportunity for both volunteerism and charitable support. Our purpose is to take literally the words of Christ in Luke 14:23 to &#8220;go into the highways and byways and compel them to come in&#8221; to the Master&#8217;s banquet. 



1. Deep inside all of us there lives someone we were meant to be. There is within each of us a potential for goodness, beyond what may appear on the outside. All of us have the ability to give without seeking reward. All of us have the ability to listen (con

2. without judging and all of us have the ability to love unconditionally. It has been my experience that if you love people in spite of what they have done, you will eventually see change in them. If the love continues to flow into their life with no (cont)

3. expectation of repayment, you will see a life transformed. The needy hand, once extended to receive, will now be extended to give. You will witness a miracle and you will have played a part in it. - Vikki Scaffe</description>
  <mission>Mission: City of Refuge offers both life saving resources and life building tools to individuals and families in Atlanta who are living on the margin.....</mission>
  <name>CiTy Of ReFuGe ( Sharing hope with the Last, Lost and Least of Inner-city Atlanta)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7534</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">23</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/C2/fc/O4/l1/R2/1h/sxMS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
