<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The petition
Why sign this Petition? 

The Mainstream Media, some Politicians, intellectuals, even some Muslims want the world to think that the idea of an Islamic State is an extremist idea. We want to show the world...nothing can be more normal...then the just social order of Islam. 

Khilafah is the greatest legacy of the Prophet (saw). Khilafah will always be the historical mirror by which Muslims will see themselves. As the Prophet (saw) said, "For you is my sunnah and the way of the rightly guided khulafah". Therefore, Khilafah is the dream of very true believing Muslim. To learn more about "Why Khilafah Now?" goto 

http://khilafahtoday.wordpress.com/

Therefore, it is important to show the world that khilafah is in the heart of every Muslim, and we need to make sure that the idea to work for khilafah remains fresh in the minds of the Muslims and that it does not get tainted by the Mass Media Propaganda and evil politicians. 
___________________________________

Muslims are an Ummah (a civilization) whose unity is expressed through the Khilafah (Islamic Government). We believe that current leadership in the Muslim world is corrupt and corrupting; King Fahd, Musharaf, Mubarik &amp; thier likes need to be removed. The Muslim Lands, resources and armies need to be reunited. The Shariah needs to be established. The time for khilafah is NOW! We demand Muslims be given the right to self-determination and we demand we choose our own representatives. Muslims have a right to live by the Islamic lifestyle and culture. 

"We, Muslims of this Ummah, believe that it is our God given trust to establish the Islamic civlization &amp; to rediscover our own true selves, and there by begin the regeneration of the fabric of Islamic civilization and recapture the authentic spirit of Islam for the second time in history..."And then there will be Khilafah on the method of Prophethood"(hadih/Ahmed) 

A place in which Muslims can freely live in an Islamic astmosphere with out any fear and show to the world a place of justice and fair play. Finally and most importantly for us humans to stop playing God, and to give the authority to Rule back to Allah...Allah u Akbar. 

"Allah promises those who believe and take the right course of action that he will grant them khilafah..." (Quran) 

To learn more about how to end the Muslim Diaspora, what the Islamic State will look like and how to establish Khilafah go to 

http://khilafahtoday.wordpress.com/


To sign petition go to: 
http://www.khilafahtoday.com/

1. member</description>
  <mission>BRING ISLAM BACK</mission>
  <name>WE NEED KHILAFA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7540</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1245</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fF/3N/Ud/kx/lj/zy/oFcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
