<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>People have the right to smile, to live how they want to live, and to make their own decisions themselves without the influence and disruption of others.

The One Peace Initiative is a cause and initiative towards peace through not only big movements but also small ones in each person's life. Each small action towards peace brings us closer to true peace. One Peace can not happen just between nations, for it to come to pass it must happen between each and every single individual.

This Initiative isn't some extremely idealistic movement /organization that says people should love each other not matter what. Its more about tolerance. We all know that each individual is different and we can't hope to like each part of each person.

BUT it is our duty to bring happiness. Suffering, poverty, loss, sorrow, and hatred shouldn't exist. It only does because we allow it. We cause the pain of others and ourselves.

We are the only ones that can bring about our own Peace and the Peace of the world.

All that is asked of you is to try to remain tolerable. If you see something that would disrupt the Peace try to with hold peace in any way you can. Each of us is able. Although it is ideal to use words, I KNOW that there are people in the world that do not listen to reason and words, therefore they can only be taught in one other way. Unfortunately, I must admit that these people exist.

Don't get me wrong One Peace isn't absolute peace its peace for those that wish for it. If you don't wish for it then don't disrupt the peace of those who want peace. 

There are three types of people: those who live in peace, those who disrupt peace, and those who protect peace. This is the initiative for those who live in peace and want peace to become those who protect peace.



1. People have the right to have peace in the lives they live everyday.

2. Peace can not be brought and given by government or a higher power alone.

3. One true Peace could only be brought about by the people.

4. People must set aside their differences for any sort of peace to come.

5. It starts with the new generation, the children and teenagers are the hope that can bring about One Peace.

6. Education is the key to One Peace.

7. It is the job of the old generation to secure the future of not only themselves but also the future of the next generation and beyond.

8. Peace is only for those who wish for it and those who protect it.

9. People have the right to be free from suffering, poverty, loss, sorrow, and hatred.</description>
  <mission>bring peace, unity, and prosperity not only to the world but to ourselves in our daily lives.</mission>
  <name>One Peace Initiative</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7563</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">150.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/80/Ic/4s/Yd/RE/St/aV/ubS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
