<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>No Donations please, at least no through facebook . . . I WISH I HAD MORE ROOM TO EXPLAIN EVERYTHING BUT DON'T SO THIS IS ABOUT AS NUTSHELL AS IT GETS!! HAHA . . . 

There is little purity and love that compares to that of a child. Unfortunately, there are millions of children throughout the world who are stranded in orphanages, find themselves in severe poverty, and are unable to receive simple education. We are going to change that. We have the power and opportunity to be a hero to children throughout the world.

There will be two main parts of A Child's Wish [proposed name]: orphan/underprivileged support and education. For the most part, orphanages throughout the world offer children nothing. They are not loved, they are not nurtured, they are not educated, and they are malnourished. They have little to no opportunities opened to them. Through fundraisers and other means, we plan to provide financial support for the orphanages throughout the world, beginning with orphanages in Tskineti and Kodjori [Republic of Georgia] and moving into the world arena. We will provide an annual Christmas for the orphans as well as educational experience.

We also plan to provide education for children who don't receive it throughout the world, especially in Sub-Saharan Africa. Educating children is the key to peace and offering them the chances they currently do not have. We will bring them that education. 

Think about all of those children in your life whom you love and would do anything for. Now imagine them in the situation all of these young kids find themselves in. Please help me give them that opportunity at life that they deserve.

Please contact me if you have any questions or ideas PLEASE message me! The more inputs we have, the more successful we are going to be. 
We have the power to help. What are we waiting for! There is no feeling that compares to being a hero to these kids. I promise that! We can each be that hero. Thank you all for the support! Again, sorry this is so undescriptive and vague. More specifics will come as they are developed. Any ideas? Do share!

1. Everyone deserves a chance.

2. We have been blessed and have the opportunity to give back.

3. The love these kids portray is unfathomable!  They deserve better.</description>
  <mission>To help the poverished children of the world financially and educationally. [Please don't donate any money through facebook right now]</mission>
  <name>A CHILD'S WISH </name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7565</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">440</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/h1/NZ/IC/Ka/Hy/Pb/qVQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
