<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In the aftermath of the Second Congo War, also known as the African World War, the Democratic Republic of the Congo , situated in central Africa , is in a state of poverty and insecurity. Several armed militias are scattered across the land, and although a treaty has been signed and hostilities were formally ended on paper, violence continues to ravage the country particularly on the eastern side. 
 
Rape is being used as a tool of warfare. It was used during the war, and it is still being used to weaken the opponents' morale. Certain ethnic groups are targeted by others and EVERY side&#8212;which includes the armed forces of four governments and also the rebel militias&#8212;is using rape. Today, around a thousand women, children and even men are being raped every month, and annual totals are around 38,000. With only the extreme elite with access to adequate healthcare, most of these victims are left on their own. Most of the rape cases are accompanied by brutal mutilation. Although the rampant rape is known and obvious, very few have actually been tried for the crime.
 
"Many had been forcibly recruited and used as sex slaves by adult fighters. Many commanders and fighters&#8230; [consider] them as their sexual possessions&#8230;There was no systematic government effort to trace these missing girls or to offer them appropriate demobilization and reintegration support."
--From Amnesty International 2007 Report on the Democratic Republic of the Congo 

"Over the last eight years, some 4 million people have died in the Congo...Children as young as 3 years old getting raped...Women aren't just getting raped, and they're not just getting gang-raped; they're -- they're often being shot internally afterward, or people putting objects inside them."
--From Anderson Cooper 360 "Encore Presentation: The Killing Fields: Africa 's Misery, the World's Shame" Aired December 31, 2006 16:00 ET

1. Sex crimes must not go unrecognized nor unprosecuted.

2. Every human has the right to physical security.</description>
  <mission>Bring awareness of the atrocities underway in the Democratic Republic of the Congo</mission>
  <name>Stop Sexual Violence in the Democratic Republic of the Congo</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7579</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20844</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3220.42</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/k6/Y2/17/JG/tt/Xm/st0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
