<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is home to many girls. You can't just abolish something like this.

This is a poem, someone very special wrote. In this poem she describes Camp Occoneechee. It is where her heart is. It is her home. 
 

This is not my home.

These are not my things.

These four walls are not for me.

These pictures are not of me.

That is not my bed.

My home is far from here.

My home is where my dreams were built.

My home is where I discovered who i am.

My home is where my family and friends wait.

My home is surrounded by trees and meadows.

Deep within the mountains, near the lake.

Trails that wined, echos of songs that were sung.

Where memories drift softly in a breeze.

The sun lights the earth through holes in the branches high above.

My things are the mountains, the trees, and streams.

My things are the love, hope and memories overflowing from one place.

My bed is under the stars when they light up the night.

I was not meant to be contained by walls.

I was meant to roam free, farther than i can see.

My home is full of laughter and full of tears.

My home is a place where i can always go and love.

My home is where friends were made and friendships remain.

My home serves ice cream for breakfast and throws pancakes every Friday.

My home is a dance floor to square dance on.

My home is a pile of rocks to wish on.

my home is a hill to hike on.

my home is a guest book to sign and leave your mark.

My home is shared with fairies and magic and children.

My home is a landing area for space ships.

My home is a place where whispers, giggles, and song can be heard.

My home is where my heart is.

My home is not here, my home is there.

-- Cassidy King


1. Save Occoneechee!</description>
  <mission>Keep Camp Occoneechee Going on forever!</mission>
  <name>SAVE CAMP OCCONEECHEE</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7593</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">152</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GA/gp/RI/Ra/hQ/wn/Kk8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
