<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For the past few years, my good friend Sarah has leased, and then owned a wonderful Belgian x Morgan cross named Hippy. She was his best friend, and he was her's. When Hippy came down with Chronic Laminitis in February, everyone at our barn was devastated. We had no idea what was going to happen to him, and he was VERY sick. There was no light left in his eyes. I honestly thought that he had given up. But Sarah kept on loving him and enouraging him. He had done so much for her in the past few years, how could she not return the favor to her best friend? Through a long journey of different treatments, shoeings, and many days where Hippy's feet were in so much pain that he had to lie down for hours at a time,VERY gradually, the pain left his feet and the light returned to his eyes. Just recently, Linda, the owner of the barn, started free lunging him and working him in the round pen, slowly bringing him back into work to see if he could remain sound. He has been sound now for a couple months. Linda finally thought that Hippy would be ready to ride again, after 5 long months. And Sarah (of course) had that honor. It was amazing today. Hippy knew just what to do. Sarah climbed aboard, and they started out walking. Then they trotted. Then they cantered. Tears were in everybodys' eyes as we remembered the horse who Hippy was four months ago. There was no soul there, but now he was back. Sarah and Hippy were connected, two bodies, but one soul. She never gave up on him, even when other people did. She was just giving back to him, what he has always given to her. So to Sarah and Hippy, WELCOME BACK!!!!
This was written by my best friend Meg. She has seen everything. Thanks Meg for being there always. I hope every horselover is just like you.

1. It hurts so many horses every year.

2. There is no cure.

3. My gelding almost died from it.

4. I had many sleepless nights worrying.

5. I want to find a cure and the cause.</description>
  <mission>Help get out the word about laminitis and get information out.</mission>
  <name>Laminitis Hurts</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7632</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Qb/1H/Az/g5/uu/fx/3TNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
