<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>No more magnificent fish swims the world's oceans than the giant bluefin tuna, which can grow to 12 feet in length, weigh 1,500 pounds, and live for 30 years&#8230; 
The giant, or Atlantic, bluefin possesses another extraordinary attribute, one that may prove to be its undoing: Its buttery belly meat is considered the finest sushi in the world. Over the past decade&#8230; so many giant bluefin have been hauled out of the Mediterranean that the population is in danger of collapse&#8230;
The decimation of giant bluefin is emblematic of everything wrong with global fisheries today: the vastly increased killing power of new fishing technology, the shadowy network of international companies making huge profits from the trade, negligent fisheries management and enforcement, and consumers' indifference to the fate of the fish they choose to buy. 
"Cruel" may seem a harsh indictment of the age-old profession of fishing&#8212;and certainly does not apply to all who practice the trade&#8212;but how else to portray the world's shark fishermen, who kill tens of millions of sharks a year, large numbers finned alive for shark-fin soup and allowed to sink to the bottom to die? How else to characterize the incalculable number of fish and other sea creatures scooped up in nets, allowed to suffocate, and dumped overboard as useless bycatch? Or the longline fisheries, whose miles and miles of baited hooks attract&#8212;and drown&#8212;creatures such as the loggerhead turtle and wandering albatross? 
Do we countenance such loss because fish live in a world we cannot see? Would it be different if the fish wailed as we lifted them out of the water in nets? If the giant bluefin lived on land, its size, speed, and epic migrations would ensure its legendary status, with tourists flocking to photograph it in national parks. But because it lives in the sea, its majesty&#8212;comparable to that of a lion&#8212;lies largely beyond comprehension. 
Read the full NGM article at www.geocities.com/theonlybaboona/GlobalFisheriesCrisis.html

1. **What YOU can do to help:**

2. Look for the blue logo of the Marine Stewardship Council (see picture at www.geocities.com/theonlybaboona/MSC_logo.jpg) when buying seafood at your local supermarket. This nonprofit organization based in the United Kingdom has developed a standard 

3. for sustainable fishing using principles put forth by the Food &amp; Agriculture Organization of the United Nations. To receive permission to use the logo, a fishery must have sufficient numbers of fish and use methods that do not harm the marine environment

4. Today, hundreds of seafood display the council's blue oval. Products with the logo are sold in supermarkets in 27 countries worldwide. In 2006 Wal-Mart, the world's number-one retailer, pledged that within three to five years it would buy all of its fresh

5. and frozen seafood from MSC-approved fisheries. Also, Whole Foods Market has partnered with MSC and is committed to selling only fish caught in a sustainable manner. Check out www.msc.org for a full list of supermarkets that sell sustainable seafood.

6. Print out a Pocket Seafood Guide and carry it with you when you go shopping or eat at a restaurant. They can be found at mbayaq.org/cr/seafoodwatch.asp and seafood.audubon.org/seafood_wallet.pdf. We as consumers have the power to make a difference!

7. Visit OceanLegacy.org to sign a petition to the National Marine Fisheries Service, as well as other action ideas. Also visit the World Wildlife Fund website (http://www.wwf.org) for more information and ideas for how to help.</description>
  <mission>To raise awareness in consumers' minds about the types of fish they buy and how they are caught, and to begin to view the oceans and its creatures as things that deserve our respect and protection.</mission>
  <name>Help Save Our Precious Oceans and End Overfishing!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7634</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1426</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">242.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mU/oG/X2/YQ/w4/85/2MwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
