<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For a lot of kids in the Bay Area, nature and the environment seem like distant things that just aren't relevant in their busy lives. That's why there's Slide Ranch on the Marin coast.

Founded in 1970, Slide Ranch is a non-profit teaching farm located at a historic coastal dairy perched above the ocean in the Marin Headlands within the Golden Gate National Recreation Area (GGNRA). Slide Ranch staff operate the farm using a turn of the century farmhouse, old creamery and several outbuildings situated along a scenic coastal bluff. Organic gardens, goats, sheep, chickens and ducks, along with numerous coastal trails, tide-pools and pocket beaches, provide an ideal outdoor venue for teaching about healthy foods, healthy living and environmental awareness. 

Slide Ranch uses food, which we eat every day, as the organizing theme to teach about our connection to the sun, soil, water, air and people who work to feed us.

Annually over 6,000 Bay Area residents, many of them children, participate in three primary Slide Ranch programs: Family Programs, Group Programs and Summer Day Camp. Slide Ranch Programs bring learning to life with hands-on education activities on a working farm. Slide Ranch uses its organic gardens and animals to teach an appreciation of where fresh healthy food comes from, and to inspire a lifestyle that includes growing and preparing nutritious foods, getting plenty of exercise, and an appreciating the sustainable use of natural resources. 



1. Slide Ranch Programs bring learning to life with hands-on education activities on a working farm. 

2.  Slide Ranch uses its organic gardens and animals to teach an appreciation of where fresh healthy food comes from.

3. Slide ranch tries to inspire a lifestyle that includes growing and preparing nutritious foods, getting plenty of exercise, and an appreciating the sustainable use of natural resources. </description>
  <mission>inspire a lifestyle that includes growing and preparing nutritious foods, getting plenty of exercise, and an appreciating the sustainable use of natural resources. </mission>
  <name>Slide Ranch</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7639</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">23</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/iB/28/yP/5m/mp/Ua/l73S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
