<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The New River that runs from Mexicali, Baja California, Mexico, through Calexico, California is considered to be one of the most polluted waterways in North America. The source of the pollution is the refuse and waste from manufacturing plants operating in Mexico; agricultural chemical runoff from the area&#8217;s farm industry; and human waste form the ever-expanding population in Mexicali. The river contains a nightmare stew of about 100 biological contaminants, volatile organic compounds, heavy metals, and pesticides including: DDT, PCB, selenium, uranium, arsenic and mercury, all flowing from Mexico into the U.S. The river also holds the toxins that cause tuberculosis, encephalitis, polio, cholera, hepatitis and typhoid, all flowing untreated through our city; levels for many of these contaminants are in violation of U.S.EPA and Cal/EPA standards. The river&#8217;s environment is in a critical condition, its noxious odor keeps people from getting too close and its toxic foam blows into the parking lot of one of our supermarkets and our downtown area. Mexicali has a population of about 1.3 million, while Calexico has about 34,000 people. On the Mexican side of the border, the river has been encased in cement tubing, while it runs open through the center of Calexico, carrying the waste of the city of Mexicali and the entire industrial/agricultural industries of the area.

The work has begun, and things are in motion but people need to support this for it to maintain momentum.

Go to http://www.calexiconewriver.com/media.php

1. Clean the New River</description>
  <mission>Turn the most polluted river in North America into something a little closer to fresh water than what it currently is: 69.6% chemical runnoff, 29% raw sewage, and 1.4% industrial waste. </mission>
  <name>Clean the New River (California)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7649</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">21</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/LN/FR/XX/hB/kW/5s/mdKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
