<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Project Africa is more than a goal, it is a mission. The mission is to help eradicate extreme poverty and provide food, medicine, and shelter to those affected by AIDS. 
More than 38 million people around the world are infected by HIV/AIDS, 25 million in Africa alone. Globally, 15 million children have lost one or both parents to AIDS. 12 million of those live in Africa. Medication used to treat people living with HIV/AIDS costs as little as $140 per patient per year. We can make a true impact. If each American gave $0.50 a day we could raise $54,000,000,000. Thats over 10 times the amount necessary to treat everyone infected with AIDS for a full year. We would even have over $48 billion left over. Just giving up a soda everyday can treat an AIDS victim for over a year. 
More than 850 million people in the world are in extreme poverty and go hungry. The United Nations Development Program estimates that the basic health and nutrition needs of the world's poorest people could be met for an additional $13 billion a year. If you put that into the over $48 billion left after treating AIDS we still have over $ 35 billion left  over.

Private donations go further than governmental support. Maximize your impact through donations to non-profits, not just governments and the UN.

We have been blessed with so much, why can't we turn a portion of these blessings to those in need?  

$0.50 a day
365 days
$182.5 a year
Over $54 billion in relief.


Join our Facebook Group.
http://hs.facebook.com/group.php?gid=2361731903

1. Extreme poverty can and must be eradicated.

2. We have the means and power to help those affected by AIDS and other deadly diseases.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to raise money and awareness for those who suffer from disease and extreme poverty.</mission>
  <name>Project Africa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/765</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4946</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1275.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/IwF/Kc2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
