<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Vogt-Koyanagi-Harada (VKH) disease is a multisystem disorder characterized by granulomatous panuveitis with exudative retinal detachments that is often associated with neurologic and cutaneous manifestations. VKH disease occurs more commonly in patients with a genetic predisposition to the disease, including Asian, Middle Eastern, Hispanic, and Native American populations. Several human leukocyte antigen (HLA) associations have been found in patients with VKH disease, including HLA-DR4, HLA-DR53, and HLA-DQ4. 
Independently, Vogt, Koyanagi, and Harada described several patients during a 20-year period with bilateral uveitis, exudative retinal detachments, neurologic abnormalities, and disorders of the integument. Despite differences in their patients, the manifestations appeared to represent a spectrum of disease and several authors suggested that the disorder should be termed Vogt-Koyanagi-Harada syndrome. 

With such a wide spectrum of the disease, typical cases of VKH disease are uncommon. To help clarify the diagnostic features of VKH disease, an International Committee on Nomenclature established revised criteria for the diagnosis of VKH disease. The revised criteria defined 3 categories of disease: complete VKH, incomplete VKH, and probable VKH. Common to all forms of VKH disease are the requirements that: (1) patients have no prior history of ocular trauma or surgery, (2) patients have no evidence of another ocular disease based upon clinical or laboratory evidence, and (3) patients have bilateral ocular involvement. Additional criteria for each form of the disease are outlined below. 

IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO READ ON PLEASE FOLLOW THE LINK PROVIDED
WWW.WEBMD.COM AND SERCH FOR ' VKH '

1. VKH SHOULD NOT BE TAKEN LIGHTLY</description>
  <mission>NOTIFY PEOPLE OF THIS RARE BUT SERIOUS DISEASE </mission>
  <name>HELP VOGT - KOYANAGI - HARADA ( VKH ) DISEASE RESEARCH</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7663</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">90</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ox/MW/QB/Bb/Vd/w0/3xhS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
