<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Jewish Collegiate Learning Exchange (&lt;b&gt;theJCLE&lt;/b&gt;) was launched in July 2002 by Jewish professionals from the Miami area in an effort to reconnect college-age Jewish students with their heritage. They brought this exciting program to the University of Miami, Florida International University, and Florida Atlantic University campuses in an effort to fill the spiritual void that so pervades the lives of America's Jews.  Whether Reform, Conservative, or "just Jewish," all students are welcome and made to feel comfortable at a &lt;b&gt;JCLE&lt;/b&gt; event.

Rabbi Chaim Friedman lead the campus outreach effort at the University of Miami. Rabbi Saj Freiberg along with his wife Haddasah, lead the efforts at FIU; while Rabbi Daniel Bensoussan works with all campuses and NOVA. The focus revolves around the theme of students discovering the beauty, relevance, and fulfillment offered by the Torah lifestyle and learning about Judaism.  

In only a few years, the &lt;b&gt;JCLE&lt;/b&gt; has become one of the largest programs of its kind directed towards college students in the United States. The &lt;b&gt;JCLE&lt;/b&gt; have established a relationship with &lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;over 2000 Jewish students in South Florida&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;. The &lt;b&gt;JCLE&lt;/b&gt; programs include:
FREE Shabbat meals,
Social events,
Holiday programming,
Trips to Israel,
Networking with local Jewish professionals,
and MUCH MORE!


&lt;b&gt;Rabbi Freiberg (FIU)&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;a href="mailto:shabbatdad@gmail.com"&gt;Click here to email&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/sajfreiberg11111"&gt;Click Here to See My Facebook Profile&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Rabbi Friedman (UM)&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;a href="ocrabbi@gmail.com"&gt;Click here to email&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=577505650"&gt;Click Here to See My Facebook Profile&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Rabbi Bensoussan (NOVA)&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;a href="mailto:Donielbensoussan@gmail.com"&gt;Click here to email&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/collegerabbi"&gt;Click Here to See My Facebook Profile&lt;/a&gt;


1. Jewish students exploring their Heritage

2. Learning Torah

3. Learning about Israel</description>
  <mission>Engage as many students as possible in JEWISH study and to build vibrant Jewish communities on campus.</mission>
  <name>theJCLE - Jewish Collegiate Learning Exchange</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7671</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">221</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">425.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ob/l0/eW/KS/vX/HN/Br0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
