<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our Treasures... &lt;br&gt;
They are contemptuously called " the Scavengers ", because their work consists of scavenging through the filthy rubbish, collecting bits of plastic, cardboard, glass and metal waste... anything that could have some value... At the end of their fourteen hour work day they sell their findings for a few pennies. Harsh sun, pouring rain, sharp objects, infected garbage... it's all part of the normal work environment for our community. This is the Guatemala City garbage dump. &lt;br&gt;
But at Potter's House, we see the scavengers as God does: precious treasures. When they come to us, they find people that treat them with dignity. They find a place where Jesus lives... a place where they learn to see themselves as we do and as God does: as Treasures. &lt;br&gt;
Many people have looked at the garbage dump and said: &#8220;Why don&#8217;t they just fix it? Cover it up? Shut it down? Or Move it?&#8221; &lt;br&gt;
From an outside prospective, it seems so easy. But the garbage is not just around the people that live and work there; it has penetrated their hearts and minds. Many of the Scavengers believe that garbage is all that life has to offer. Others believe that they themselves are garbage, worthless and invaluable. Still others would rather work in the garbage than to beg in the streets, and to them, these are the only two options. &lt;br&gt;
Potter&#8217;s House Association works not only to remove the people from the garbage, but to remove the garbage from the people. Through five programs, we value the Scavengers as Treasures, and we teach them to value themselves. We have identified 8 types of poverty that keep the Treasures enslaved to the garbage. We work to liberate the Treasures from all types of poverty so that they can experience true freedom and fortune. &lt;br&gt; For more information visit: http://www.pottershouse.org.gt &lt;br&gt;

1. ASSIST: To offer humanitarian aid and assistance to those who cannot help themselves, especially the children and the elderly.

2. DEVELOP: To equip the Treasures to develop and become confident, competent, and self-sustaining.

3. EMPOWER: To provide resources for the Treasures to participate in the solution to their personal, familial, communal, and national problems.</description>
  <mission>To provide holistic opportunities for scavenger families by equipping them to be able to develop and transform their lives, families, and community.</mission>
  <name>Potter's House Association International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7686</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">28</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/KE/30/T8/s1/Z4/r0/rDbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
