<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In Santa Cruz, Boliva, Children as young as 7 years old living in sewer canals without any family or adult supervision. They were barefoot, filthy, diseased and sniffing glue to make it through the day. 

Most striking, however, was how similar they were to children and teenagers we see every day.

Facts:
- Bolivia is the poorest country in South America
- There are nearly 10,000 children in the streets in La Paz alone.
- 1 out of every 1,100 Bolivian children lives on the streets.
- 20% of children in Bolivia die before the age of three.
- Approximately 90% abuse drugs regularly (mostly improvised inhalants like glue).
- Most are subject to physical abuse.
- STD's run rampant amongst the street population.
- Disease (including tuberculosis, parasites and lice) are very common.

What can you do?
- Pray. As Christians, we believe that change begins and ends with prayer. Make a commitment to pray regularly or start a prayer group.
- Raise awareness. You can invite people to join this group, tell people in your community about the kids, or create your own organization. Be creative!
- Give. Follow the links below to provide resources to people already working in the field.

More information available here:
http://casaalfa.org
http://bolivianstreetchildren.org
http://street-children.org.uk/bolivia.htm


1. By helping these kids and showing them that they are loved we can start the founding of a new group of belivers who one day maybe able to walk the streets where they grew up and minister to others.

2. How would you feel if you were the father or Mother of one of these children? You would do anything and everything to help them.  By showing them that God is the Father they never had and that He loves them they might be able to return that love to other 

3. As Christians and human people it is our duty to be servants to everyone around us including those who live in smelly streets and to do everything we can to make them feel as if they really do belong in this world.

4. We CAN do this one child and one person at a time.</description>
  <mission>Help the Children of Boliva feel the love of the Savior</mission>
  <name>Street Children of Bolivia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7692</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9862</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">830.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gT/Lj/gL/xV/Bu/aD/UmaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
