<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In today&#8217;s conflicts 90% of the victims are civilians, of which 1/3 are children. Every year war destroys the lives of millions of people around the world.

EMERGENCY USA-Life Support for Civilian Victims of War and Poverty is an independent, non-profit corporation currently in the process of applying for 501(c)3 tax exempt status. Established in 2008 to raise awareness, promote peace and respect for human dignity, and to provide funding and community support for medical care, rehabilitation and relief efforts for victims of wars, land mines, poverty and natural disasters.

The programs we support provide free-of-charge, high-standard medical and surgical care in war-torn areas. EMERGENCY USA supports long-term sustainable interventions that help to develop local healthcare capacity and improve infrastructure. EMERGENCY USA emphasizes addressing the greatest inequalities in access to healthcare and, in particular, the provision of medical care to civilian victims of war.

Thank you for your show of support!  EMERGENCY USA CHAPTER has to close its Cause while a new U.S. organization establishes itself.  Don't worry, this effort is too important to close for long!  In the meantime, we hope you will remain a supporter, and until we come back and join you on Facebook Causes, we invite you to contact us directly for more information through our website:  www.emergencyusa.org


Ti ringraziamo tantissimo per il tuo sostegno e per la tua donazione. EMERGENCY USA provvisoriamente chiude il suo 'Cause', solo il tempo di finalizzare aspetti 'organizzativi/strutturali della nuova organizzazione EMERGENCY USA.  Le nostre attivita' sono troppo importanti, quindi ora i nostri sforzi sono concentrati nell'impegno di riattivare la nostra 'cause' al piu' presto.  Contiamo sul tuo continuo sostegno e, mentre ci auguriamo di vedere al piu' presto EMERGENCY USA su Facebook Causes, ti invitiamo a consultare il nostro sito www.emergencyusa.org per contattarci direttamente. 

1. Health care is the most basic of all human rights

2. Healthcare is not only a right, but it should also be high standard and completely free of charge.

3. Recognition of the inherent dignity and of the equal and inalienable rights of all members of the human family is the foundation of freedom, justice a</description>
  <mission>To provide free of charge, high standard medical, surgical and rehabilitative care in areas affected by war and poverty. www.emergencyusa.org</mission>
  <name>Emergency, USA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7721</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">191</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">40.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pU/ys/MM/5f/PE/pZ/duKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
