<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The William J. Clinton Foundation, started by former President Clinton, is a non-profit organization working towards strengthening the "capacity of people in the United States and throughout the world to meet the challenges of global interdependence." 

The organization concentrates on key areas of this issue such as "health security, economic empowerment,   leadership development and citizen service, and racial, ethnic and religious reconciliation." 

Recent victories for the Clinton Foundation include major price reductions for 16 medications critical to fighting AIDS/HIV, establishing guidelines for snack foods in schools, receiving a commitment from Virgin Group CEO Sir Richard Branson to invest $3 billion to combat global warming, and the creation of  a global Energy Efficiency Building Retrofit Program, which will "assist cities in reducing their greenhouse gas emissions".

The Alliance for a Healthier Generation is a joint initiative between the
American Heart Association and the William J. Clinton Foundation. It is
designed to ensure that the next generation of America&#8217;s youth grows up to be
one of the healthiest by coming together to fight one of our nation&#8217;s leading
health threats &#8211; childhood obesity.
Find out more at www.healthiergeneration.org and encourage the children
you love to take the Go Healthy Challenge at www.igohugo.org.

The Clinton Foundation is still in its early stages of development and financial as well as public support of the organization and its causes are crucial to its success. 

By joining this Cause, you are committing to the goals of the Clinton Foundation and are willing to allocate some of your time and possibly funds to promote a better political, economic, social, medicinal and ecological world for future generations to come. 

1. The United States and all of its citizens have a responsibility to assist in reducing the challenges of global interdependence.

2. Progress and advancement begins at the local level with small businesses, and small initiatives. 

3. Policies and laws must be passed to reflect the changing global climate and to assist those nations and individuals who struggle to adjust. </description>
  <mission>financially support and publicize the philanthropic efforts of the William J. Clinton Foundation. </mission>
  <name>William J. Clinton Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7728</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">219</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">325.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/En/wB/7l/Hp/Fl/tx/iVcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
