<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Tyler&#8217;s Story: The History of Tyler&#8217;s Hope for a Dystonia Cure

As a healthy and active 7-year-old boy, Tyler enjoyed playing basketball, soccer, tennis and golf. Just like most active 7-year-old boys, Tyler enjoys sports and playing outside.

In February of 2005 all of this changed. While practicing basketball with his father, Tyler could not bring his arm in without it shaking uncontrollably. His family decided to have this examined, the beginning of a long and disheartening journey. Tyler was in and out of Shands Teaching Hospital in Gainesville, Florida and many other nationally renowned hospitals. Tyler was examined by many specialists that performed numerous painful tests and treatments that resulted in dead ends and misdiagnosis. During one of Tyler&#8217;s inpatient stays at Shands, he was introduced to Dr. Michael Okun. This meeting resulted in his examining of Tyler and rendering a diagnosis of Primary Generalized Early-Onset Dystonia. 

Dystonia is a neurological movement disorder affecting the central nervous system characterized by involuntary and often painful spasms of the muscles. This disorder currently has no cure and progressively robs one of the ability to control voluntary movements and even the ability to walk, talk, and write -- while one's mind remains sharp and self-aware inside a twisting body.  Tyler will most likely be disabled before he reaches 12.

It is the mission of Tyler&#8217;s Hope Foundation to raise awareness of this horrible disorder so no other child has to experience what Tyler went through to be diagnosed. Tyler&#8217;s Hope Foundation was established to advance research for a cure, discover effective treatments and to promote awareness and education of this devastating disorder.

Learn more at http://www.tylershope.org and read Tyler's Progressional Diary at http://www.tylershope.org/diary.php


1. Raise awareness

2. Fund research

3. Find a cure</description>
  <mission>To promote awareness, fund research and find a cure for the neuromuscular disorder Dystonia.</mission>
  <name>Tyler's Hope</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7729</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3720</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">8028.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Wo/Or/3V/YW/7C/yl/xjNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
