<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is a type of cancer that many do not hear about.  It is known to begin as a mild stomach upset, constipation and nausea.  Most Doctors and medical professionals can not properly diagnose this due to the increased amount of stomach acid present.  As the disease progresses you are unable to enjoy a meal or even a light snack without discomfort and tremendous pain.  You eventually lose all bowel controll resulting in the reliance of a clostomy bag or more invasive procedures.  

Near the end stages of this terrible disease you are confined to a hospital where medical professionals make you as comfortable as possible.  The use of medications for comfort and pain controll and a I.V line in your arm for food and nurishment.  This is a life altering time not only for the ill individual but for the close family and friends whom are trying to be of help and support.

It is said that a female whom has children, mainly males aged 29 yrs of age and up could infact carry the same genes..... resulting in the chance of them repeating the same drastic illness.   This is not to be taken lightly.  We should all go for periodic colonscopies each year to remove the risk.  If the risk is in your family background then you should set up a plan including a well ballanced diet and plenty of exercise.

This article is in memory of a beloved mother of 3 grown men and her grandchildren today.  Help fight this cause so the number of casualties can be reduced.  Every dollar counts. 

1. Early treatment options.

2. Live life peacefully and lovingly.

3. Train family and friends for care giving roles.</description>
  <mission>warn others whom may be at risk</mission>
  <name>Gastrointestinal Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7730</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">76</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/h8/QD/wZ/bY/uy/Ui/aHKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
