<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Every job I've ever had, I've needed to pass a urine and drug test so as to prove something to the management of said job. I don't really see anything wrong with that. It's their company or corporation. They can do what they want.

And with every job, I receive a paycheck every two weeks. And every paycheck I've ever received has had some money taken out of it to go towards government programs such as welfare. Again, I do not have a problem with this. There are people in need and if my putting into the system something every two weeks helps them in their time of need, then that's great.

If I were to find myself without a job for an extended period of time because of some unforseen accident or incident, then I'd apply for welfare and take some money back out of the proverbial hat. Once again, I wouldn't have a problem with it.

Here's the thing: There's stringent testing policies in place for putting money INTO the system but not when taking money OUT of the system.

It all just seems strange to me.

It is my belief that the same testing that got you putting money INTO welfare should be in place for when you need to take money OUT of it. Why not? It's just a urine test. If you don't have a job but you're still smoking pot every day, something's missing.

Think of all the money the government would save from weeding out those that aren't truly in need. And think of how much more money we could give to those that ARE truly in need --- the mother of three whose husband died tragically in the factory, the man who was suddenly laid off not because his skills eroded but because the CEO wanted to save some money, etc...

Just think about it.

1. Those in need of welfare from society deserve it.

2. There needs to be more research done on the individual before a welfare check is given.

3. The same rules that apply for getting a job and putting money INTO the system should be applied to those asking for help and taking OUT of the system.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to change how welfare is distributed and who it's distributed to.</mission>
  <name>Change Welfare Now</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7737</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vD/B5/xQ/AG/pv/rU/vlbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
