<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Christian community, centred to Lebanon, and affiliated to the Roman Catholic Church as part of the Eastern Rite. There are also smaller groups in Palestine and Syria, as well as in Cyprus and the USA.
Their total number is about 1,5 million, of which about 800,000 live in Lebanon. This means that 60% of all Maronites live in Lebanon, and that they represent 25% of the country's population. According to the Lebanese constitution, the president of the country shall be a Maronite Christian.
In Syria about 40,000 Maronites live, headed by the archdioceses of Aleppo and Damascus, and the Diocese of Latakia.
Over centuries, the Maronites lived isolated in the mountains, where religion came to play an important part in all aspects of their lives. In modern times, they have become much more urban and represent an important part of the population in Lebanon's largest cities.
The spiritual head of the Maronites is the Patriarch of Antioch, who actually resides no longer in Antakya (now Turkey) but in Jounieh north of Beirut.
The liturgy was developed inside the Maronite Church prior to the affiliation to Rome in the 12th century, but Roman Catholic elements have been introduced. Even in modern times Syriac language is used for the services, even though the Maronites use Arabic as the vernacular tongue.
The Maronites claim to be within Orthodox theology, but this is not always true. From the 7th century, they became supporters of the doctrines of the patriarch of Constantinople Sergius, who claimed that Jesus had no human qualities, only divine (called Monothelite).
Celibacy is not a prerequisite for the Maronite clergy, but is regulated according to local traditions. 


1. lebanon is the country of the maronites.

2. maronites must stay in all the earth.

3. peace, love, help, beleive in god.</description>
  <mission>Publication the Maronite and help the Maronites.</mission>
  <name>Maronites</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7744</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">95</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rx/3W/SS/MI/ca/ip/aXCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
