<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Matthew Varagona was born on February 3, 1986 in St. Louis, MO as the youngest of three to Sharon and Charles (Buddy) Varagona. He was the younger brother of Sara and Jim.

Matthew turned 14 on Feb. 3, 2000. Five days later, he was admitted to PICU at STL Children's Hospital. Matthew had been experiencing difficulty breathing and had been coughing up blood. Doctors at Children's were not sure of Matthew's diagnosis, but they did know his condition was serious. He was kept in a chemically induced coma to allow machines to aid his lungs, heart, and kidneys in healing and functioning. Three days after admission, symptoms suggested Wegener's Granulomatosis. In order for treatment to be effective, he was kept in the coma and was unable to communicate with friends and family. The disease was in an advanced stage and Matthew's prognosis was not good. Family and friends stood by vigilantly for any sign of improvement each and everyday. During his stay, he received his acceptance letter to attend Bishop DuBourg High School, which he would never get to do. And on February 21, 2000, just thirteen days after Matthew had been admitted to the hospital, his battle with Wegener's was lost.

We raised $19000 at a benefit in March of 2001 in the hope that this young man's story will help raise awareness of this tragic disease and lead to progress in treating it.  Along with another $6000 from 2 golf tournaments, those funds were given to the Vasculitis Foundation to put towards research. The foundation then created The Matthew Thomas Varagona Memorial Grant, which was applied to a study that investigated the susceptibility of genes to lead to Wegener's in family members of patients. 

Since Matthew's death, we have worked tirelessly to raise awareness of WG in the hope that other people will not suffer as Matt did or experience the terrible grief of losing a loved one.

We ask that you give what you can and to spread the word.

1. Further research must be funded for Vasculitis to improve quality of life issues and aid in diagnosis.

2. People should know more about the Vasculitis disease classification, which includes: Behcet's Disease, Buerger&#8217;s Disease, Central Nervous System, Chur

3. This will be done in the name of MtV.</description>
  <mission>To memorialize Matthew Varagona of St. Louis, MO through awareness and fundraising campaigns for Wegener's Granulomatosis through the Vasculitis Foundation.</mission>
  <name>Matthew T. Varagona Memorial Vasculitis Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7759</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">336</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1647.5</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kX/Yf/3G/uy/HZ/tz/RACS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
