<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Friends of Rigby Foundation is a not-for-profit public charity in memory of Georgetown Student Daniel H. Rigby who passed away in a Georgetown House Fire in October 2004.

The Friends of Rigby Foundation has set out to keep alive not only the memory of Danny, but also Danny's devotion to public service. Not only has the the foundation established scholarships to both of Danny's Alma Maters (Bergen Catholic and Georgetown University), but is in a continuous effort to promote general student safety at Georgetown and other Universities around the country, especially as it pertains to housing and fire security.

The Charity was made an official tax free organizaion in fall of 2006 and welcomes the membership of all of those who knew and loved Danny, who know and love Georgetown, or who believe that the fire, housing and general safety of University Students across the country, if not the world, is a priority that needs devoted individuals to insure continued focus on it's effectiveness and betterment.

The Foundation does annual events to inform both of its previous successes and its future goals as well as to raise the money necessary to accomplish these goals. Every October, a Homecoming Event is done at Georgetown and every April, a formal evening is done in Washington DC and followed the next day by a 5k charity run. Many other regional events are done over the course of the year, including annual summer cocktail receptions in New York, etc. These events are the fuel off of which the foundation runs and are always a good time. 

By joining this group, you will be able to be kept up to date about the Rigby Events taking place across the country and will be welcomed as a new member of the Rigby Nation.

To find out more infomation regarding the charity, its goals, its officers, and its events, please visit it's official website at www.FriendsofRigby.org. We appreciate all of your continued support and interest in our worthwhile cause.

1. Keep the memory of Dan Rigby alive.

2. Establish Scholarships to Bergen Catholic and Georgetown University

3. Promote general student safety at Georgetown and other Universities around the country</description>
  <mission>The Friends of Rigby Foundation is a not-for-profit public charity in memory of Georgetown Student Daniel H. Rigby who passed away in a Georgetown House Fire in October 2004.</mission>
  <name>The Friends of Rigby Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7764</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">485</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">285.65</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/U8/kY/jz/ft/7t/Cd/zNuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
