<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There is NO WAY that Kurt Cobain could have killed himself in the method that is described in the autopsy. The coroner found that not only was Cobain shot, but he had 3 times the lethal dose of heroin in his system. Once "he" had injected the 1.53 milligrams per litre of heroin that was found in his blood stream, he should have become instantly incapacitated or died. After ell this, he would not have had the ability to put the drug parafinalia back into the cigar box in which it was found and then gone on to write a suicide letter and shoot himself. and not only was he shot, but he was found with the SHOTGUN on his chest, and not only that, but there were no fingerprints found on the weapon. If he had shot himself, there is absolutely no plausible way that he could have wiped off the gun after doing so. And for the icing on the cake, he was found 3 days after his death by the man who was to be installing an alarm system in his home. Why did Courtney not find him sooner? And if so, why did she not report her findings? After reading the above information, please follow the link below and sign the petition if you fully agree with what you have read.

http://www.petitiononline.com/q90x458/

1. Cobain was a god and he deserves closure.

2. Courtney Love is a murdering skank and deserves justice for the travesty she has commited.

3. Our justice system needs to be more diligent in its investigations and this is a perfect example of this.</description>
  <mission>convince the King County police force to re-open and further investigate the death of this legend. He is gone because he was taken, not because he left.</mission>
  <name>The MURDER of Kurt D. Cobain</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7767</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">561</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/No/6J/ty/8i/vv/B2/c4SS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
