<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Psychedelics have been a part of society for more than 2500 years and are proven to be far safer and healthier than any other drugs.  Psychedelics produce an awe-inspiring "religious" experience and bring the user closer to God and therefore should be protected under our first amendment rights.  Psychedelics are neither addictive nor harmful to the body. They have been proven to increase creative and logical thought, both of which are necessary for complex problem solving.  Users of psychedelic drugs include early computer developers, many famous artists, musicians, actors, authors, and countless other brilliant individuals.  I strongly urge anyone who feels that psychedelic drugs are bad or is afraid of the power they hold, to research them.  There's a lot of information on the internet which will help you understand the truth about these heavenly substances.  One website I truly love is The Vaults Of Erowid... www.Erowid.Org -- this site has information regarding effects, dose, law, chemistry, and various other articles and most importantly Erowid has a section called 'Experiences' this is a very large collection of detailed reports of users experiences.  This site is however not limited to psychedelic drugs, there is information about every drug imaginable.  Knowledge is power lol but remember Imagination is more important. 

'Imagination is more important than knowledge...'--Albert Einstein

This cause encourages not only the re-legaliZation of psychedelics but also encourages more focus being put on controlling truly dangerous and addictive drugs like methamphetamine, cocaine, heroin, ketamine, alcohol, and prescription pills. 

The government has scheduled all psychedelics schedule 1 which means 

A.)they are dangerous and harmful, 
B.)that they have a high potential for abuse, C.)that they are highly addictive and 
D.)that they have absolutely no use medically.  
It doesn't take a genius to realize that none of that is true about almost all of the psychedelics. 

The Truth 
A.)Psychedelics are not in any way physically harmful and if used correctly and in the right setting are also in no way psychologically harmful, people under the influence of psychedelics are no threat to others or themselves, and rarely disturb the peace like people on alcohol or other drugs, 
B.) Most people who use psychedelics do not abuse them and many use them strictly for spiritual enlightenment not for recreation 
C.) Psychedelics are neither psychologically nor physically addictive, the only exception to this is MDMA which can be psychologically addictive in rare cases. 
D.) This is the part that troubles me most; Psychedelics have many many uses in therapy as well as treatment for depression, anxiety, drug addiction, and there had been talk of use of LSD for people to cope with dieing, theres been study for use of MDMA for Post Traumatic Stress disorder.  I believe there should be a study done using LSD, where a low dose is given on a daily basis for depression, i believe this will work because after the first day the person will not even notice the effects of the drug however they will still be in a less depressed state.  Also because of the world-wide ban of these drugs there has been very little study into the possible uses of these drugs.  The pharmaceutical companies have far too much at stake to allow these wonder drugs into "their" market and they have billions of dollars to insure that their drugs get into your mouth.  Just think if LSD did cure depression, which it would, how many drugs would it get rid of--&gt; Prozac, Lexapro, Celexa, Zoloft, Paxil, Luvox, Welbutrin, Cymbalta, Elavil, Effexor, Remeron, Nardil, Parnate, Marplan, and how much do you think they make a year off these drugs alone, Its in the billions.

I purposefully left out marijuana from the list of drugs that this group supports mainly because there are a million marijuana legalization groups... 


</description>
  <mission>Influence the world to reform drug laws for psychedelics including LSD, Psilocybin, Mescaline/Peyote, MDMA and DMT/Ayahuasca, 2C-B.</mission>
  <name>legaliZe psychedelics</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7776</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2620</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">87.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rh/2R/KP/Tl/vJ/LI/WJ/fRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
