<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>To anyone who has ever given or would consider giving blood, Southern California's blood supply is extremely low right now and the American Red Cross is calling for blood donors.  They NEED people to give blood NOW!  This is a very real problem... you can check out the websites:

the press release on the LA red cross website:
http://www.redcrossla.org/media/index.php?pg=12&amp;sb=1&amp;id=514

or the red cross regional website for socal:
http://socalredcross.org

it was even in the 9/2/07 LA Times:
http://www.latimes.com/news/local/la-me-blood2sep02,1,5932697.story?ctrack=1&amp;cset=true

Maybe you hate needles or can't stand the sight of blood.  Many people have those phobias and still give blood.  It's really hardly even painful, FREE, doesn't take very much time, and unless you're anemic or something, in which case they probably won't accept you as a donor, it's highly unlikely you'll faint or anything.  If you've recently gotten tattoos or sketchy piercings or have spent an extended period of time in sketchy countries (like in Africa) you can't give, but otherwise, most normal and healthy ppl have greatly needed blood that will be regenerated by your body within a day so PLEASE GIVE BLOOD!

PLUS, there's all kinds of promotions and giveaways for donating, including a coupon for Chili's and a $500 gas card, so you won't walk away empty handed!
http://socalredcross.org/socal/content.php?Content=promos#events

Please find a blood drive site nearest you at either of the websites above or at www.givelife.org

You can also call 1.800.GIVE.LIFE (1.800.448.3543).

To sponsor a blood drive, please call 800.491.2113

To volunteer please call 800.498.9910



1. Southern California's threatened blood supply needs YOUR blood donation NOW!

2. Giving blood is safe and free and SAVES LIVES.

3. At any time, about 60% of SoCal residents are eligible to give blood, but only 3% do.  That needs to change.</description>
  <mission>Reinvigorate the SoCal blood supply.</mission>
  <name>SoCal Give Blood!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7779</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">50</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/H7/Kv/Ra/tN/ns/mU/tPfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
