<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>On the 25th of June 2006 Cpl. Gilad Shalit was abducted by Hamas terrorist inside the territorial borders of Israel.  17 days later IDF soldiers Udi Goldwasser and Eldad Regev were abducted by Hizbollah militants during a raid across the Israeli-Lebanon border.  These events proceeded the summers war between Hizbollah and the nation of Israel.  It has been over a year and all 3 still remain in captivity with little to no sign of life.  Soverign nations uphold to the highest standards in regard to the principles laid out in the Geneva Convention.  To have no contact with these prisoners either by the Israeli Government or the International Red Cross is a complete violation of such international agreements.  It is the responsibility for all human beings to stand up for such attrocities, for those who remain silent are just as guilty as those who perpetrate the crimes.  For over a year 3 families have endured pain that no mother, no father, no spouse, no family member should ever have to endure.  It is our time to stand up for these human rights violations that occur under our noses.  This is not just an Israeli issue, this is not just a Jewish issue, this is a world issue.

1. Help to free the captured Israeli soldiers by protesting their capture and their subsequent geneva convention right violations

2. Influence the USA, UNSC, and other nations of the world to aid this cause</description>
  <mission>Help influence the United States Government and the UN Security Council as well as other members of the international community to help free the 3 soldiers held captive by both Hamas and Hizbollah</mission>
  <name>Free Gilad Shalit</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7781</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">120235</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3128.06</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fP/PD/5K/kc/Ab/R6/tPES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
