<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What we do: 

State AIDS Hotline:
Volunteers staffing the Hotline responded to 1,455 phone calls. These calls included HIV/AIDS information and referrals throughout the state.


HIV Testing:
Staff and volunteers conducted 3024 HIV Test sessions in which 2,613 people received rapid testing and a total of 82 HIV-positive cases were identified.


HIV prevention services:
The staff of the education department distributed over 1.3 million condoms, engaged in risk reduction encounters with more than 2100 individuals, and partnered with over 40 community organizations to conduct HIV prevention activities. Services included street and community outreach efforts, condom distribution, health education, speaker&#8217;s bureau, and the community mobilization project (NO/AIDS Community Awareness Network &#8211; NO/AIDS CAN).


Case management:
NO/AIDS Task Force case managers helped more than 700 individuals meet their primary medical care, medications assistance, housing, transportation, mental health, substance abuse treatment, and other needs using an extensive referral network of more than 100 service providers.


Primary medical care:
NO/AIDS Task Force provided medical care to 373 individuals during the year. Fifty-three of these individuals were new to care during the year..

1. Founded in 1983 in response to the early devastating effects of the AIDS epidemic in the New Orleans area.

2. NO/AIDS Task Force serves all individuals, regardless of gender, sexual orientation or identity, race, ethnicity, religion, education, or socioeconomic status. The clients served by the agency over the past nineteen years have been those individuals and c

3. Our community is still at risk, and it is still up to us to change that! </description>
  <mission>To reduce the spread of HIV infection, provide services, advocate empowerment, safeguard the rights and dignity of HIV-affected individuals, and provide for an enlightened public. </mission>
  <name>NO AIDS TASKFORCE- Community Awareness Network</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7782</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">508</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">372.45</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ub/w2/WK/bD/hw/U8/NcfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
