<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It is a non profit organization whose mission includes:
&lt;center&gt;*Encouraging students to avoid drinking, gambling, smoking both on and off the property of the CEO facility and especially when out in any public areas.

&lt;center&gt;*Assist students to build relationships with United States students through correspondence and expose the students to higher technology 
education.

&lt;center&gt;*Help students in the district learn English and computer skills.

&lt;center&gt;*Practice self-discipline in school attendance and in study habits.

&lt;center&gt;*Teach youths to understand good advice, and to stay out of trouble.

&lt;center&gt;*Build new libraries for general public education.

&lt;center&gt;*Furnish teachers and students with school supplies, computers and textbooks used to study English and learn computer skills.

&lt;center&gt;*Provide meals before school, personal hygienes supplies, and basic medicine to students.

&lt;center&gt;*Offer humanitarian assistance to elderly, handicapped, widows, orphans, and malnourished infants.

&lt;center&gt;*Help people who face difficult situations who lack food or health screening.

&lt;center&gt;*Explain to parents the importance of improved hygiene in the family and advise them how to take care of their health.
 

More information at:
http://www.cambodiaeducation.org/

1. Everyone is entitled to an education.

2. Learning the universal language (English) will increase a wider understanding of one another.

3. A healthier lifestyle starts with learning hygiene.</description>
  <mission>Help students in the district learn English and computer skills.  Also to promote a healthier lifestyle.</mission>
  <name>Cambodia Education Organization</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7787</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">119</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wk/RL/He/Oz/TJ/Ei/JGSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
