<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>GICF will continue to grow Lulwanda Children&#8217;s Home (LCH) as we are blessed with future provisions and funding.  LCH, which opened its doors on December 1, 2004, is the first children&#8217;s home established by GICF. Lulwanda&#8217;s facilities include a kitchen, laundry room, boys&#8217; and girls&#8217; bathhouses, boys&#8217; and girls&#8217; dormitories, living areas, and a large garden which provides some of the food for the Home. The children&#8217;s home now houses 45 orphaned or abandoned children between the ages of 4 and 10.

Before coming to Lulwanda Children&#8217;s Home, these children had no one to care for them. Now they are thriving in a healthy environment. Children attend school at the home, learning basic life skills, English, math, and a variety of other subjects. Five classes (pre-school, kindergarten, and first, second and third grades) are held simultaneously for five hours daily, five days per week. The children also receive regular medical care, nutritious meals, and lots of outdoor play time &#8211; all in a warm family environment that promotes bonding between the children, their house mothers, and the rest of the staff members.

Presently the Lulwanda Children&#8217;s Home facilities are being expanded. This construction program is enhancing the functioning of the facility by adding an on site Administrator&#8217;s House and an additional dormitory, which will double the home&#8217;s capacity to 90 children. Recently completed construction also adds two blocks of three classrooms to allow expansion of the educational program from kindergarten through the primary grades. The Administrator's house was completed in December 2006, allowing Administrator Edwards Mukiibi to stay on the grounds.  The two classroom blocks were completed in April 2007, and the dormitory has just recently been completed as of July 2007.

For more information, visit the website at http://ugandaorphans.org/

1. Build and maintain children's homes in East Africa.

2. Add additional children at each children's home.

3. Give education to the children in English, math, science, computer, and life skills.

4. Reach out to those living in the same region of the children's homes through programs like the Good Neighbor Program.

5. Build and operate a small trade school to provide technical training for the teenage children of LCH to prepare them to enter the Ugandan workforce as productive citizens.

6. Build and support a medical clinic to serve not only the children's home but the surrounding area as well</description>
  <mission>Through God's grace and by His will, GICF will vividly extend and improve life quality of East African orphans with unwavering integrity and commitment abiding in Christian principles in all we do.</mission>
  <name>Grace International Children's Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7802</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">164</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dD/Zw/IB/NB/iU/4r/CVtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
