<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Each step brings hope. Every dollar promises care. You can make the difference. Take the next step!To join the fight against AIDS:
1. Register as an individual or start a team online.
2. Set a personal fundraising goal and then encourage friends, family, neighbors and colleagues to support your efforts.
3. Have supporters donate online or by check.
Steps for submitting donations:
1. Walker donations online must be received by Oct. 1, 2007, and mail-in donations must be postmarked by Sept. 28, 2007, in order to receive your incentive gifts on the day of the walk.All donations are tax-deductible.
For your TEAM to receive credit for walker supporting donations:
1. Put your team name on your 'Support a Walker' Form and in the memo line of each submitted check.
2. Mail-in support: Must be postmarked by Friday, Sept. 28, 2007 in order to be counted toward team totals. 
Event Location:AIDS Walk Washington will begin and end at Freedom Plaza (Pennsylvania Avenue and 14th Street, NW). The closest Metro stations are Federal Triangle (Blue / Orange lines) and Metro Center (Blue/Orange/Red lines).
Event Schedule: 
AIDS Walk Washington will take place on the morning of Saturday, October 6, 2007. An inspiring pre-Walk program of speakers and music begins at 9 a.m. The timed run will start promptly at 9:30 and the walk at 9:45 a.m. 10/6/2007  
Fees: 
General Registration: $25.00
Student Registration: $15.00

1. AIDS effects everyone</description>
  <mission>AIDS Walk Washington is a fundraiser benefiting Whitman-Walker Clinic, a non-profit health organization that provides accessible health care to those infected with HIV/AIDS.</mission>
  <name>AIDS Walk Washigton</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7807</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yu/0W/fS/a5/Vx/1t/x1eS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
