<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The 9/11 Truth Movement is a dedicated and important grassroots effort of 9/11 survivors and family members, firefighters, architects, engineers, scientists, professors, entertainers/filmmakers, media professionals, former military, former intelligence service, law enforcement, government officials and regular everyday citizens of America and the world who demand that unanswered questions be answered, and that the guilty parties be flushed out and held accountable.

If you are a truth seeker, or if you have the slightest bit of doubt regarding the official 9/11 story, you are not alone. A public opinion poll about 9/11 conducted by Zogby International in May 2006 indicated that:

42% of Americans more likely agree with people who "believe that the US government and its 9/11 Commission concealed or refused to investigate critical evidence that contradicts their official explanation of the September 11th attacks, saying there has been a cover-up."

Start asking questions, start listening to the alternative theories. If you are intrigued but skeptical, we urge you to keep an open mind and researching the movement's assertions.

All donations go to supporting Architects &amp; Engineers for 9/11 Truth, a non-partisan association of now more than 1,300 Architects, Engineers and affiliates demanding renewed investigation into the &#8220;collapses&#8221; of the three WTC high-rises on 9/11/01.

If you are new to these ideas, we suggest these links as a starting point for your own quest for 9/11 truth:

The Journal of 9/11 Studies Beginners' Guide to 9/11 Truth
http://www.journalof911studies.com/beginners.html 

The Top 40 Reasons to Doubt the Official Story of September 11th, 2001" by 911Truth.org
http://www.911truth.org/article.php?story=20041221155307646

Filmmaker Dylan Avery's documentary Loose Change: Final Cut (You can watch the full version online at Google video)
http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-3719259008768610598



ADDITIONAL RESOURCES:

911Truth.org
http://www.911truth.org

The International Truth Movement
http://www.truthmove.org

Patriots Question 9/11
http://www.Patriotsquestion911.com

History Commons Complete 9/11 Timeline
http://www.historycommons.org/project.jsp?project=911_project

9/11 Blogger
http://www.911blogger.com

Visibility 9/11
http://www.visibility911.com

9/11 Truth Europe
http://www.911Truth.eu

9-11 Research
http://911research.wtc7.net

9-11 Review
http://911review.com



Profession-Specific Information:

Architects &amp; Engineers for 9/11 Truth
http://www.ae911truth.org

Firefighters For 9/11 Truth
http://www.firefightersfor911truth.org

Scholars for 9/11 Truth &amp; Justice
http://www.stj911.org

Medical Professionals for 9/11 Truth
http://www.mp911truth.org

Religious Leaders for 9/11 Truth
http://www.rl911truth.org

Pilots for 9/11 Truth
http://www.pilotsfor911truth.org

Political Leaders for 9/11 Truth
http://www.pl911truth.com

Veterans for 9/11 Truth
http://www.v911t.org



GET INVOLVED!

NYC Coalition for Accountability Now
http://www.nyccan.org

9/11 TruthAction
http://www.truthaction.org

We Are Change
http://www.wearechange.org

2nd Responders
http://www.2ndresponders.org

Feal Good Foundation
http://www.fealgoodfoundation.org


"The truth about 9/11 is that we don&#8217;t know the truth about 9/11, and we should." - Lt. Col Robert M. Bowman, PhD (USAF, ret)</description>
  <mission>To educate the public on alternative media sources and the existence of independent scientific and scholarly investigations which question the official account of the events of September 11th, 2001.</mission>
  <name>The 9/11 Truth Movement</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/781</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5607</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">111.82</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/l7/6v/40/uN/Xb/xh/o0/0jS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
