<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Methodists United for Peace with Justice is a national association of laity and clergy. We are based in Washington, D.C. 

As our name "Methodists United" indicates, we seek the participation of all the Methodist family in the United States, including African Methodist Episcopal, African Methodist Episcopal Zion, Christian Methodist Episcopal, Free Methodist, United Methodist, and Wesleyan Churches. However, we are not an official part of any Methodist denomination.

Methodists United for Peace with Justice organized in 1987 in response to the foundation document and pastoral letter of the United Methodist Council of Bishops, In Defense of Creation: The Nuclear Crisis and a Just Peace. In this document the bishops called for greater witness and action for peace and justice. With this origin we have been faithful advocates of nuclear disarmament, but we have broadened our interests to other issues. We have also widened our scope to include all Methodist denominations in the United States.

1. Nuclear disarmament has been the central issue for Methodists United for Peace with Justice since our founding in 1987. This stems from our initial organizing in response to a call for prayer and action on this issue by the United Methodist Council of Bis

2. As a strong supporter of global non-proliferation of nuclear weapons, Methodists United for Peace with Justice believes that Iraq's capacity to develop, store, and potentially use weapons of mass destruction should be eliminated. We have favored UN inspec

3. Justice as a Foundation for Peace</description>
  <mission>Methodists United for Peace with Justice functions in three modes: Education, Public Policy Advocacy, and Ecclesial</mission>
  <name>Methodists United Peace/Justice Education Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7820</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">19</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Nt/ba/yx/Pa/Nr/Y0/Rn0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
