<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our Vision for the Future

At Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts, we envision a future where there is universal understanding and support for the right of each person to responsibly manage her/his sexual and reproductive health. Women's freedom, equality and health will be enhanced by access to a full range of family planning options. When the right to family planning is accepted as fundamental and mainstream, there is the potential for each woman to fulfill her own dreams.

We envision a future where laws will guarantee these rights and ensure access to quality health care, education and advocacy services. These services will be readily available in safe settings that preserve and protect the privacy and rights of each individual regardless of income, age, ability, marital status, race, ethnicity or sexual orientation.

PPLM will work collaboratively with a broad coalition of schools, organizations, parents, elected officials, and policy makers to encourage and promote strong families and communities. We will work with our partners to create a future where laws and funding will be based on the health needs of individuals and the desire to achieve positive health outcomes. In this climate, policy makers will embrace prevention initiatives, and there will be broad support for family planning, sexuality education, and freedom of choice. 

1. We believe in the right to sexual and reproductive self-determination that is non-coercive, non-exploitative, and responsible.

2. We believe in the responsible expression of one's own sexuality.

3. We believe in trusting individuals and providing them with the information they need to make well-informed decisions about sexuality, family planning, and childbearing.

4. We believe that women should have an equal place at life's table, and be respected as moral decision makers.

5. We believe that children flourish best in families and communities where they are nurtured, honored, and loved.

6. We believe in passion - for change, for justice, for easing the plight of others, for caring, for living our convictions, and for confronting inhumane acts.

7. We believe in inclusion and diversity - and the power and knowledge they confer.

8. We believe in leadership based upon collaboration rather than hierarchy.

9. We believe in action - to make things happen and to improve people's lives and circumstances.

10. We believe the future is global and that we are part of a global movement.

11. We believe in the urgency of creating a sustainable world and living in peace with our planet.

12. We believe in acting courageously, especially as allies with those who have little or no voice and little or no power.

13. We believe that every right is tied to responsibility and that taking responsibility is fulfilling in itself.</description>
  <mission>The mission of PPLM is to protect and promote sexual and reproductive health and freedom of choice by providing clinical services, education and advocacy.</mission>
  <name>Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7825</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">329</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">696.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zL/jk/Vr/YH/tA/IR/1LiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
