<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>About Us

Hungry for Justice formed in April 2007 as an ad hoc committee to organize local support for the federal trial of the Holy Land Foundation during the summer of 2007.

Mission

Hungry for Justice operates on the belief that the defendants will be found innocent of all charges and that truth will prevail. Its mission is to serve the community that supports the defendants and their lawyers during the trial.

Philosophy

Hungry for Justice adheres to non-violent principles and affirms the rights guaranteed by the U.S. Constitution and the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. 

Expression

Hungry for Justice carries out its services through a committee structure.

Committees

This structure is comprised of four committees: Outreach, Mobilization, Media, and Administration. 

Committee Objectives  

The Outreach Committee&#8217;s objective is to build community support by raising awareness about the trial and encouraging participation and action. This objective includes organizing: 

Speakers and presentations 
Fundraisers 
Coalition building 
 Literature   
The Mobilization Committee&#8217;s objective is to maintain a strong presence of support during the trial. This objective includes organizing: 

Court Watching 
Transportation/Parking 
Childcare 
Food Services 
 Noon vigil 
 The Media Committee&#8217;s objective is to distribute information about the trial to the public at-large. This objective includes organizing:  

Media Watching 
Press releases 
Letter Writing 
Blogging 
Art 
The Administration Committee&#8217;s objective is to provide oversight and funding to the committees. This objective includes organizing periodic meetings among the committee heads, representatives of the  defendants&#8217; families, and coalition partners. 




1. Hungry for Justice is a coalition that strongly believes that any hungry child should be fed, clothed and sheltered regardless of who his parents are.

2. Hungry for Justice is a coalition that strongly believes feeding hungry children, orphans, women, widows or men is NOT a crime.

3. Hungry for Justice is a coalition that strongly believes opposing the brutal Israeli Occupation of Palestine is NOT a crime

4. Hungry for Justice is a coalition that strongly believes in due process, 

5. Hungry for Justice is a coalition that strongly believes in first amendment and freedom of speech

6. Hungry for Justice is a coalition that strongly believes in first amendment and freedom of religion

7. Hungry for Justice is a coalition that strongly believes in first amendment and freedom of assembly</description>
  <mission>create a coalition of civil rights activists and advocates.</mission>
  <name>Hungry For Justice</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7846</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">43</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dX/61/zJ/KC/Um/o1/aSAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
