<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Institute on Religion and Public Policy is one of the world&#8217;s most effective and well-respected advocates for freedom of religion and belief.

An international, inter-religious non-profit organization, the Institute is dedicated to ensuring freedom of religion as the foundation for security, stability, and democracy.  Founded in 1999 and headquartered in Washington, DC, the Institute recognizes that religious freedom is more than just a church-state issue. As such, the Institute engages every segment of society to protect humankind&#8217;s most basic fundamental right: freedom of religion and belief.  Having received two nominations for the Nobel Peace Prize, the Institute&#8217;s programs reflect this multi-faceted approach, in national security, corporate social responsibility, interfaith dialogue and media engagement. 

Religious discrimination and persecution are not new issues.  They have been around as long as humanity.  But combating them does require new ideas and innovative solutions.  The Institute has developed creative and exciting methods of advancing fundamental rights, energizing new advocates and rolling back religious discrimination, persecution and tyranny.
 
Many religious freedom advocacy groups do an important service by highlighting individual cases of persecution, discrimination, imprisonment and abuse.  The Institute, however, has a more overarching goal: To create and strengthen legal, business, academic, media and other systems within countries&#8212;and internationally&#8212;to protect religious freedom so such abuses do not occur.

The Institute on Religion and Public Policy does not accept funding of any type from religions, religious institutions, or government agencies of any kind, unless government funds are specifically earmarked solely for the Interparliamentary Conference on Human Rights and Religious Freedom.



1. Religious Freedom is a basic and fundamental human right &#8211; it means we have the right to think and believe whatever we want 

2. Religious Freedom around the world leads to increased stability, security and democracy

3. The Institute on Religion and Public Policy promotes and ensures religious freedom around the world

4. The Institute is not connected to or funded by any one religion or government, enabling us to work to change policies without outside persuasion 

5. The Institute&#8217;s programs work to raise awareness, educate, inspire dialogue, engage and act so that one day religious freedom will apply to every ci</description>
  <mission>Promote Religious Freedom, Peace and Democracy Worldwide</mission>
  <name>Institute on Religion and Public Policy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7854</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1772</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">4889.49</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zc/KO/ce/cY/WZ/QS/Cw/zmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
