<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>PETA Senior Vice President Mary Beth Sweetland has diabetes she injects insulin. Insulin contains animal products and was developed with animal testing. 

"I don't see myself as a hypocrite. I need my life to fight for the rights of animals."

I guess Mary Beth's life is more valuable than yours. Think of anyone you know who's gotten sick, they would be dead if it wasn't for animal research. 

Anthrax, Chicken Pox, Cholera, Diptheria, Flu, INfluenza B, Hepatitis, Measles, Mumps, Polio, Rabies, Rubella, Smallpox, Tetanus, Whooping Cough, and Yellow Fever Vaccines wouldn't exist without animal testing. 

We also wouldn't have Insulin, Penicillin, Anti-inlfammatory Drugs, Pain Killers of any kind, chemotherapy, anticoagulants. artificail limbs like knees, hips or pacemakers. Organ transplants also wouldn't be viable without animal research. 

So if you support PETA, when you get Cancer or heart trouble or even a headache. Deny yourself treatment or be a hypocritical asshole. 

PETA has compared the holocaust to a live stock farms.  Morally identifying the humane termination of an animal for a meal to the extinction of 5 million Jews in a concentration camp is fucking evil.

Rod Coronado is a good friend of Ingrid Newkirk. He is a serial arsonist. PETA funded this shit head. Their income tax return is public record, look it up. He teaches and encourages people to commit acts of terror.

In the 1970s, Ingrid Newkirk worked for Montgomery County, Maryland, and then for the District of Columbia, as an animal protection officer and deputy sheriff, before becoming D.C.'s first female poundmaster in 1978. In 2003, talking about her job in Maryland, she said:

I would go to work early, before anyone got there, and I would just kill the animals myself. Because I couldn't stand to let them go through that. I must have killed a thousand of them, sometimes dozens every day. 

1. Animal cruelty is wrong

2. PETA are terrorists and bullies, not animal rights champions

3. Don't waste your money funding terrorism, fund the Humane Society. 

4. PETA funds terrorist group Animal Liberation Front who fire bomb animal testing labs. 

5. PETA would outlaw guide dogs for the blind, pets and honey. 

6.  2002 PETA euthanized 1325 animals at it's headquarters. They took in 2103 they killed almost 2/3's of the animals they rescued.

7. PETA opposes all animal testing regardless of the lives saved unless it's the vice president of PETA's life. 

8. PETA shoves veganism down your throat. Whatever happened to personal choice?</description>
  <mission>Wipe out hippie bullshit and hypocrisy</mission>
  <name>Screw Peta</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7868</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">76</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Z8/qM/3P/bH/nV/0Z/35dS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
