<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dicated to attempting to better humanity by trying to make life easy for everyone else. We take currency and use it only to help children, people, animals and locations that need it. We do as much as we can afford and never use it for the wrong reasons. Several Projects have already happened. Clean environments promote clean environments project is going somewhere people litter and cleaning it up. Monkey see monkey do... this also coincides with our you can recycle almost everything so why not theory, making it a game everyone wins. Our trip to Tijuana, Mexico where we handed out food to the hungry that we bartered from local merchants. And in Downtown Los Angeles we stood with over $500 dollars worth of groceries (which were healthy and practical) giving it to anyone who had "hungry eyes" i love that song. We are always planning a event so put in whatever you want or just go out and change the world yourself. wheres the decency and polite sincere minds? We don't support bad habits so we always promote kind words of encouragement for people to not rely on others but themselves to get better. The only money that is taken from your offering is what the pay-pal and or other creditors take on the transaction. 100% of what we receive eventually... (and we don't keep the legal 20% like other groups) goes to helping the forgotten we seek out. Bigger, Better, Thinking. The easier we make this for each other the easier it is.

1. Food for Everyone

2. Clean Environments

3. Recycle

4. World Happiness

5. Healthy Liftstyles

6. Global Pop Culture Information Intergration</description>
  <mission>Make life easy</mission>
  <name>EyeLAshout Philanthropy</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7876</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/24/bF/Vg/ml/WD/Ui/U4LS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
