<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>With today's costs of medical treatment, many families face serious financial complications when caring for a family member with cancer or autism. Just this year (2007), the Centers for Disease Control reported that autism affects 1 of 150 children in the U.S. (http://www.autism.com/). Cancer, affected over 10 million people in 2002 in the U.S. alone, and that number continues to grow (http://cancercontrol.cancer.gov/). This foundation is unique because it takes the time to personally make a difference in peoples lives by providing them with the financial aid they need to survive as a family, without restrictions based on middlemen, geographical features, or nature of the illness. Much of the financial aid is personally delivered to a family's home by the founder of the Smile Forever Foundation, Patrick Gonnelli. Pat Gonnelli started this foundation in dedication to his wife, Barbara Gonnelli, who passed away from breast cancer after a struggle of 13 years. The foundation is called "Smile Forever" because of Barbara's constant smile and dedication to help others, even when she was battling cancer. This foundation allows us the opportunity to help people in our own communities (NY/NJ) who are financially unstable after caring for a loved one with cancer or autism. In doing this, we carry on Barbara's spirit of helping others, which makes a real difference in both our and their lives - every day is another opportunity to smile.

For more information on the foundation, its events, testimonials, photos, published articles and ways to donate go to: http://www.smile-forever.org/

To see an album I have composed of pictures of the Foundation, go on my profile, to my photos, to "the Smile Forever Foundation Photos" or to this link: http://www.facebook.com/album.php?aid=36843&amp;l=81fcf&amp;id=676380073

                           -Danielle Harris :)




1. Families made financially unstable after caring for a loved one with cancer or autism deserve our help and support.</description>
  <mission>Helping to personally provide financial aid to families affected by cancer and autism</mission>
  <name>The Smile Forever Foundation - Helping People Smile</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7878</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">61</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/EM/Jy/du/qv/Un/h8/rZCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
