<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Equality is a fundamental human right and so is freedom to not be arbitrarily discriminated against. Sadly, too many countries persecute gays, lesbians, bisexuals and transgendered people, and this is unacceptable. Unity for LBGT Rights Worldwide aims to try to unite all people, and to attempt to educate people who hold irrational beliefs of hatred for the LBGT community to like their fellow human beings and to treat them with dignity and equality. We would like every single person in the world to be on an equal footing both legally, and insofar as it is possible, socially. The latter is much harder to achieve than the former, yet this does not make it worth trying for. Unity for all people.

1. Equality before the law for all LBGT communities worldwide.

2. Unity in terms of societal acceptance for all LBGT communities worldwide.

3. To persuade officials who perpetrate discrimination against the LBGT communities throughout the world to alter their stances and to dissuade them from beliefs of hatred.

4. Offer solidarity and unity for our persecuted brothers and sisters from around the world, trying to help by exerting pressure on governments and by campaigning on their behalf for equality, because human rights and equality are universal norms.

5. Russia is experiencing LBGT rights abuses at the moment, as Sunday May 27th's actions proved; help by signing the following petition urging world leaders to condemn Russia's homophobic stance: http://www.petitiononline.com/RusLBGT/petition.html</description>
  <mission>support our brothers and sisters throughout the world in their struggles to gain equality and to wipe out discrimination they may face because they are part of the LBGT community.</mission>
  <name>Unity for LBGT Rights Worldwide</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/790</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">120</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sI8/dLaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
