<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Waqfeyat Al Maadi Community Foundation is the first established Community Foundation  in its real sense, in Egypt.

A Foundation per definition is based on the concept of ENDOWMENT (Waqf in its traditional sense), where funds are allocated in a financial vessel bearing interest to sustain operational costs of the organization for centuries and centuries to come. A Community Foundation is one that focuses its effort for the upgrading of a certain geographic area.

The foundation mainly aims at reviving and modernizing El Waqf as a traditional tool for organized social giving embedded in Egyptian history. 

It provides an innovative sustainable model of Community Foundations that employ modern applications of El Waqf Endowments
as a sustainable channel for mobilizing and channeling local resources towards sustainable local development of a given community. 

In our case Waqfeyat Al Maadi is devising a number of Waqfs (Endowmnets) to serve specific needs of our targeted underprivilaged community in Al Maadi outskirts (El Bassateen, El Maasara, Torah, etc .

The Foundation also acts as a hub, pioneer, facilitator and catalyst for civil society organizations in adopting innovative and financially sustainable, participatory Models of
Endowments or Waqfs. 

SUPPORT OUR ENDOWMENT AND GIVE LIFE BACK TO A MODERN WAQF for Development. 

Contact Al Waqfeya at 018 - 1722224, 25255549, or myself at 010 - 1697187 
Email: waqfeyatalmaadi@yahoo.com


1. Revive and promote El Waqf (Endowment) system in funding development</description>
  <mission>Revive El Waqf  (Endowment ) mechanism for development</mission>
  <name>Endowment Building for Waqfeyat El Maadi Community Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7906</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">116</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0j/nr/V1/iY/PT/hI/IDcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
