<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Auto-mobility, the combination of autonomy and mobility, is not a right.  In fact, there are many people who cannot, and choose not to drive.  The elderly, the young, those with disabilities, and others.  Further, automobiles harm our health, our communities, and the the environment.  

In the United States, and to a lesser extent in most other industrialized countries, the transportation -system is heavily dependent on, and catering to, the private automobile.  This causes suburban sprawl, 'necessitating' more highway construction.  However, more highways brings more traffic, as it makes travel more attractive and available.  

The form of a transportation system affects the outlay of the society.  That is, if travel over long distances is easier, businesses, homes, and amenities will become further and further apart.  This can be seen as local businesses have shut down, and have been centralized into much-abhorred 'box stores'.

This is fine, of course.  A society should be able to choose how it wants to live, should it not?  Isn't that democracy at work?

-Well, this model is dependent on cheap foreign oil.  Of course, we'll never see gasoline dip below $3.00 a gallon again.
-We also need cheap construction costs of highways.  Of course, the industrialization of India and China has driven up the costs of building materials ranging from steel to cement.
-This is also dependent on an economic accounting system which does not include the costs of pollution.

It is becoming painfully obvious that automobiles and the United States Highway System are not sustainable, in either an environmental nor an economic standpoint.  

Every day, it is becoming more and more difficult to live in a 'modern' society without the use and ownership of a personal vehicle.  Communities are being slowly driven apart.
  
There's a lot you can do.  But first, PARK YOUR CAR.

1. The Automobile is not economically or environmentally sustainable.

2. The Automobile harms communities and democracy.

3. The Automobile distorts our perceptions of the importance of time and space.</description>
  <mission>Education and Advocacy for a smarter transportation system, today.</mission>
  <name>Park Your Car</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7907</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">27</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Uu/Kw/rX/Yw/wP/wt/SVzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
