<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There is a rise in the number of sexually active youths ages 14 and under in the united states today. Some of these youths are as young as 8 years old. I have interview 4 adolescents in regards to the situation at hand. One adolescent {Student A} is only 13 and she is not only experience as far as vaginal intercourse goes, but she participates in anal and oral intercourse as well. The five people I interview all said they know atleast 4 girls who are exactly like Student A. Student B is 15 years old and she says became sexually active after dating a guy that is 2 years older than her. It was said by a NSFG survey that 81% of females that have been sexually active from age 14 where in a relationship with a older guy. Student C is 16 years old and he said became sexually active because of peer pressure and because it brought him popularity, he was 11 at the time. Student D is 12 years old says she has not experiment with any form of sexual intercourse but she knows atleast 20 students her age that are sexually active Student E is 19 now and he has been sexually active since the age of 10. He said he did it because he wanted to feel older. But he hardly ever shared that information because he was afraid of how people would have reacted. Now of days he feels that for some reason youths think it's cool to have sex and that is the reason why we have so many sexually active teens as well as teen pregnancies, teen abortions, and teens that are affected with STDs. You don't have to take my word for it but it's best if you are aware and research the situation for yourself. check out this website for starters: http://www.teenpregnancy.org/resources/reading/pdf/14summary.pdf

1. nearly 1/5 adolescents have had sex before the age of 15

2. Boys are most likely to have had sexual intercourse than girls

3. in general parents claim to speak to thir children often about sex but their children recall these communications less than the parents claim.

4. a respectable net source say 1/3 of parents actually know that their 14 and under child(ren) are sexually active

5. we have to take a stand as parents, brothers, sisters, and friends. I remember when children represented innocence. Where has those days gone?</description>
  <mission>deminish and spread awareness of this situation </mission>
  <name>awarness of the rise in sexually active youths ages 14 &amp; younger</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7915</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">389</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">120.65</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/N4/vD/q4/Bt/4E/ql/vp3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
