<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Bush Administration has just issued a disastrous "License to Kill" plan that could trigger the extermination of half the gray wolves in Wyoming and Idaho, starting as early as October -- unless we stop it now. 

The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service is accepting public comments on this cruel proposal only until August 6. Please register your opposition right now by GOING TO THIS WEBSITE AND FILLING OUT  FORM: http://www.nrdconline.org/ct/J1_OOdn1DuhS/

Our best hope for blocking this "open fire" order is to generate a tidal wave of public outrage and protest...so please sign your Citizen Comment immediately. 

The Bush Administration wants to treat wolves like vermin, instead of an endangered species that has staged a welcome and dramatic comeback from the brink of extinction. 

In preparation for these mass killings, the government has already purchased planes and helicopters capable of gunning down entire packs of wolves in minutes. 

Their goal: To immediately kill up to 700 wolves in Greater Yellowstone and central Idaho. 

Our goal: To stop this horrific proposal in its tracks -- by generating 200,000 pro-wolf Citizen Comments by the August 6 deadline.

Can we do it? I'm certain of it. Only three months ago, online activists like you sent more than 137,000 Citizen Comments protesting the Bush Administration's plan to remove Greater Yellowstone's wolves from the endangered species list. 

Simply put, they will allow the slaughter to begin while wolves are still on the Endangered Species list! 

Please block this new License to Kill by expressing your personal opposition while the Bush Administration is still taking public input. 

Submit your Official Citizen Comment now -- and shield the wolves of Greater Yellowstone and Idaho from the coming crossfire. 



1. The endangered species of wolves should not be killed.

2. The killing of these wolves needs to be stopped NOW.</description>
  <mission>get as many people to fill out and send petition to our government!</mission>
  <name>Stop Bush From killing the ENDANGERED Wolves!!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7946</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">302</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Uv/7z/vQ/Zn/rM/me/lMbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
