<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I want to start an advocacy group related to non-profit canvassing organizations.  Though I am no longer employed by PIRG, I feel that there has got to be an efficient yet spiritually balanced method of fundraising that doesn't stress it's directors (and other employees) with unpaid overtime and expectations that are clearly required yet not determined as requiring as much time as they actually take.  I feel this is absurd.  Now that I'm working for the AFL-CIO I'm realizing how unsatisfactory PIRG can be to the collective mental health of it's employees.

I propose that instead of using funding to develop more offices, that we should maximize the potential of each individual office and campaign, hire more directors as necessary, and pay everyone who does campaign work, and works overtime.  WIth this, it will recruit more educated and serious canvassers who will rise to positions where they will be less weary of directing an office. This inturn will actually expand PIRG while fortifying the basis of grassroots organizing, which involves prioritizing and maximizing local involvment and should take into consideration workers rights, not merely acquiring more capital from the expansion of new offices.  

Please message me with any positive or negative feedback.  (-:

1. All workers deserve to be paid for their work.

2. The mental health of employees should be considered.

3. PIRG should maximize local campaign effectiveness and employee satisfaction at the expense of growing exponentially.</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness of and develop a union of individuals that believe in workers rights for the Public Interest Research Group</mission>
  <name>PIRG workers advocacy awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7950</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3s/Rg/mc/en/3Z/RV/LjOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
