<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) is an anxiety disorder arising as a delayed and protracted response after experiencing or witnessing a traumatic event involving actual or threatened death or serious injury to self or others. There are three categories for the types of traumatic experience that can result in PTSD. These are (in order of the severity of the disorder they cause from low to high):

1) Catastrophic - A catastrophic natural event that the sufferer or another individual was directly involved in, such as a hurricane or flooding.

2) Non-deliberate human - An accident that impacts upon the sufferer or another individual but no harm was meant to be caused, such as car, train or plane crashes.

3) Deliberate human - An intentional attack upon the sufferer or another individual, such as a violent attack or sexual abuse.

There are many outcomes of this:

- The sufferer can has a severe mistrust in any aspect of the event, which leads to avoidance of any situation which could cause distress, and can be addressed by therapy such as systematic desensitization.

- The sufferer is constantly hypervigilant, they are always in the fight, flight mindset, always on edge and ready to atack or run, especially in situations reminiscent of the traumatic experience.

- The sufferer can experience flashbacks in which they relive the experience that traumatised them in their brain and can manifest itself as a body memory. They can go through the traumatic experience months, years or decades later and it is as real as the time it actually happened.

1. Awareness of PTSD must be raised

2. A greater understanding of PTSD must be conveyed to prevent stigma and stereotypes associated with mental illnesses

3. Sufficient and ongoing support for sufferers must be put in place</description>
  <mission>To raise awareness of PTSD</mission>
  <name>PTSD Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7962</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">975</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">20.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ac/Da/l1/Xx/wN/8C/NuZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
