<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In South Africa there are many townships and areas mainly supplied by government. There is a lack of adequate therapists for the children there. I personally come from South Africa, my cousin Lara runs the Thusanani children's foundation. The Thusanani Children&#8217;s Foundation is usually the only source mentally challenged children have for therapy and education. Many of these children come from abusive starving families. Many are also orphans whose parents have died as a result of AIDS. I have helped out with the children I have seen the starvation; I have seen these children&#8217;s eyes light up at the sight of us coming for they want to learn. They are always sad when we leave. It breaks the heart. These people need help. All money goes to these children some mentally retarded some were not given the right treatments at birth. This simply gives them a chance no matter how small they have it. Simply spreading the word and offering your love means more than you can possibly imagine. Please if you join invite some people, ask them to do likewise. This problem is not going away without help. Thank you all especially to the recruits keep it up!!!

To donate please do NOT send money to the economy organization. Send all money directly to Thusanani at: P O Box 92117

Norwood

2117

in South Africa

Or to:

2034 Old Forge Way Marietta GA 30068 and I will then forward the money directly to Thusanani



1.  Support the Thusanani Childrens Foundation with love hope and prayers.

2. give hope

3. spread the word to the world

4. NOTE: ALL DONATIONS MUST BE SENT DIRECTLY TO THE THUSANANI FOUNDATION IN SOUTH AFRICA OR A LOCATION THAT WILL SEND IT TO THEM.</description>
  <mission>Help the Thusanani children's foundation through donations and moral support. To offer what we can even from far away. </mission>
  <name>Thusanani Childrens Foundation of South Africa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/797</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">152</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dcc/WMNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
