<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Thus the empire of our Redeemer embraces all men. To use the words of Our immortal predecessor, Pope Leo XIII: "His empire includes not only Catholic nations, not only baptized persons who, though of right belonging to the Church, have been led astray by error, or have been cut off from her by schism, but also all those who are outside the Christian faith; so that truly the whole of mankind is subject to the power of Jesus Christ." Nor is there any difference in this matter between the individual and the family or the State; for all men, whether collectively or individually, are under the dominion of Christ. In him is the salvation of the individual, in him is the salvation of society. "Neither is there salvation in any other, for there is no other name under heaven given to men whereby we must be saved." He is the author of happiness and true prosperity for every man and for every nation. "For a nation is happy when its citizens are happy. What else is a nation but a number of men living in concord?" If, therefore, the rulers of nations wish to preserve their authority, to promote and increase the prosperity of their countries, they will not neglect the public duty of reverence and obedience to the rule of Christ. What We said at the beginning of Our Pontificate concerning the decline of public authority, and the lack of respect for the same, is equally true at the present day. "With God and Jesus Christ," we said, "excluded from political life, with authority derived not from God but from man, the very basis of that authority has been taken away, because the chief reason of the distinction between ruler and subject has been eliminated. The result is that human society is tottering to its fall, because it has no longer a secure and solid foundation."

Pope Pius XI, Quas Primas

1. All men must render public worship and obedience to Christ the King</description>
  <mission>To bring all governments and nations into submission to Christ the King for in Him alone is true peace, happiness and freedom found.</mission>
  <name>The Social Reign of Christ the King</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7976</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1225</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/et/xn/QC/vF/Fw/00/LaQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
