<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>His story:
Travis Brent Fortson, "Good Samaritan," was severely injured on July 9, 2007 in a traffic accident while trying to assist another motorist who was involved in a traffic accident. Travis, his wife Heather, his daughters Belle (5) and Amelia (3), his parents and extended family covet your prayers for his speedy recovery.

On July 9, 2007 at approximately 9:45am, Travis and several other motorists had pulled over to help another vehicle that had been cut off in traffic on I-85 and spun off the road. While walking to the accident site a semi-tractor trailor approached the site, locked down its brakes, jack-knifed and struck Travis and the other two men. Travis was air-lifted to Spartanburg Regional Hospital since his injuries were the most life threatening. By the grace of God, Travis is surviving! Unfortunately, his injuries are significant: the doctors amputated his right leg about mid-thigh, he sustained multiple injuies to his right shoulder and right side of his face, and additional surgery will be necessary to repair his crushed pelvis. Travis will also need extensive skin grafting on his right leg to prepare for a prosthesis.

Travis is a 1997 graduate of The Citadel. He is the son of Jeanne and Don Whilden and Brent and Helen Fortson. His twin brother and his wife are Drew and Julie Fortson. His sister Whitney and her husband Steve Balzer are also attending to Travis.

Travis' wife is Heather and they have two lovely daughters, Belle who is five (5) years of age and Amelia who is three (3). Travis is on the board of stewards and a member of the Western Carolina Sailing Club. He is a lover of yacht racing, being with friends and family, camping and playing with his dog, Ella.

Please pray for healing of his injuries, his strength and will to heal himself and for his family and friends. The Lord IS with him and is already working His miracles and it is a miracle Travis is with us!!





1. Travis Fortson to recover.

2. Fortson to recover

3. Family to reunite</description>
  <mission>Help Travis Fortson</mission>
  <name>The Travis Fortson Cause</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7980</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/VL/7j/P7/rL/Vk/lx/BEIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
