<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Are aims are to show that big business has to act fairly. A good exaple of the public winning over the extortions of big business is the bank charge extortions. With an average of 1,500 paid back to each customer claiming as the charges they administer for late payments are unfair. This has been a good step forward, but much more should be done.

Insurance companies for example not paying out on many occations because they hope / know they will not be challanged in court. For example, you did not report the offence within 12 hours. Even though the customer was not him self aware of the event for 36 hours. These loop holes in the law should not be allowed.

On all cases like these I call for a jury of normal people to decide what is fair, not people whose job it is and work on profit.

I call for a trade union of customers against the big immoral business, as "Trading Standards" are know where to be seen.

A name and shame list should be drawn up and bill-boarded around major cities. Why complain to the company when you can complain about the immoral actions of big business on the net and publicly on the side of their buildings.

I am also currently in talks with a "no win no fee" company into droping it rates if they are affiliated with this cause. But we need the numbers first. Please join and give any suggestions and name and shame with your own cases. I personally name and shame "Carphone Warehouse 02" and their "Life Line" assurence policy. 

1. Bring a moral code to Big Business.

2. Ban profit at all cost procedures.

3. Raise money to publicly name and shame the companies that have been morally, even if not "legally", unfair to you.</description>
  <mission>make big businesses rely on a moral code and not legal loop holes.</mission>
  <name>Big Business needs Big Ethics.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/7986</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DS/rq/Nk/qU/CV/ZY/ep2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
