<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>DO NOT CLICK THE "DONATE" BUTTON! INSTEAD, READ THE NOTICE BELOW:


St. James's Summer Shelter is a student-run 8-week transitional program that provides 10 to 12 homeless individuals with a place to stay, 3 meals a day, internet access, and individualized case management. We work one-on-one with our clients to help them obtain employment and housing. The shelter has a communal feel, and is often described by the shelter guests as something like a "family."

St. James's is under the auspices of Harvard University's Phillips Brooks House Association, Inc. PBHA is a student-led independent 501(c)(3) nonprofit public service organization.

***All Donations are tax deductible!***

You can DONATE in one of two ways:

***ONLINE: Go to http://www.pbha.org/donate. Be sure to designate &#8220;St. James&#8217;s Summer Homeless Shelter&#8221; in the Specific Needs box.

***BY MAIL: Send a check made payable to &#8220;St. James&#8217;s Homeless Shelter&#8221; to 
St. James&#8217;s Homeless Shelter
Phillips Brooks House
Harvard Yard
Cambridge MA, 02138

***Do NOT donate through the "donate" option here because, as it turns out, such donations will go to PBHA in general, and not the Shelter specifically! BUT please do donate in one of the two ways described above!***


1. Individuals living in a shelter deserve to be treated with dignity and respect in an environment that is safe, secure, and friendly.

2. Homeless persons have the right to case management that takes into account their specific needs. 

3. Students have the ability to affect change through their dedication, hard work, research, and advocacy on the behalf of their shelter clients.</description>
  <mission>To provide homeless persons with the resources and individual case management needed to help them achieve financial stability and permanent housing.</mission>
  <name>St James's Summer Shelter</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8011</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">42</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">78.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ZS/Ah/LC/cQ/GE/52/3HxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
