<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>As part of the Cradles to Crayons mission, we also set a foundation for lasting change through the meaningful, tangible volunteer opportunities we provide to thousands of youth and adults each year.

The organization is dedicated to ending child poverty. Living in poverty means no books, shoes that don't fit properly, a worn-out winter coat etc. There is a great need for our services. Almost 500,000 Massachusetts kids (one out of three) live in poor or low-income households. C2C provides year-round support for children in these situations.

C2C recycles childrens toys and clothing to provide over 30,000 kids each year with the necessities they need on a daily basis.  We hope to double that number this year.  We currently serve Massachusetts and Pennsylvania, but we want to be nationwide in the near future.

An important element to the eradication of child poverty is creating awareness within our communities and motivating a call to action.  To do that we need your help. 

HOW TO HELP:
1. Volunteer in our warehouse, The Giving Factory.
2. Join our Teen Leadership Council. Summer and Fall applications are now available on Cradles to Crayons&#8217; homepage.
3. Donate money: every bit counts!
4. Clean out your closets and donate any clothes, toys, or books that you no longer need
5.Create awareness in your town. Invite friends on Facebook by taking the pledge or simply spread the word.

10 MOST NEEDED ITEMS:
   1. Kids' clothing sizes newborn to 14/16 
   2. New socks/underwear (all sizes)
   3. Sneakers &amp; sandals
   4. Strollers
   5. Playards, cribs, &amp; bedding
   6. Safety gates
   7. Car seats
   8. Outlet covers &amp; cabinet locks
   9. Diaper bags
  10. Sports balls


CONTACT INFO:
82 Myrtle Street
Quincy, MA 02171
www.cradlestocrayons.org
Office #: 617.471.8417
Fax #: 866.841.9995

1. Building a foundation for LASTING change by showing today's youth they can already make a difference.</description>
  <mission>To provide, free of charge, low-income and homeless children from birth to pre-teen the basic essentials they need to be safe, warm, ready to learn, and valued. </mission>
  <name>Cradles to Crayons</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8013</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">975</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">885.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bP/wp/7u/KJ/iP/de/zceS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
