<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>WE WANT 1 MILLION FRIENDS OF NEW ORLEANS!!!

Friends of New Orleans is a private, nonprofit, nonpartisan, membership organization for people in the U.S. and abroad who care about this region. We want to:

   1. Mobilize those who believe that that the region needs a hand-up, not a hand-out;
   2. Urge all Americans to band together to ensure that this historical and strategically important part of the nation not be forgotten; and
   3. Remind decision-makers about the economic and quality of life impact this region of southern Louisiana has across the nation.

By becoming a Friend of New Orleans, you will:

    * Send a message to those who don&#8217;t think the U.S. federal government should fund the rebuilding effort, because they don&#8217;t understand that failing to do so hurts the entire country.
    * Show the residents of southern Louisiana that you care and that they have not been forgotten.
    * Learn about the big picture issues that are shaping the national debate around the rebuilding effort.
    * Become aware of the challenges and opportunities that exist in the devastated areas, and how you &#8212; one person &#8212; can get involved and help.


1. A Presidential debate should take place in New Orleans in order to shine a light on the urgent issues there.

2. Local residents and nonprofits should have a major role in decision-making during the rebuild.

3. New Orleans needs the support of friends from outside the region. This is an opportunity to demonstrate our collective concern. </description>
  <mission>Help New Orleans rebuild after Hurricane Katrina, the worst natural disaster in US history.</mission>
  <name>Rebuild New Orleans with Friends of New Orleans)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8015</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2710</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">360.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/lX/ag/47/gG/2i/zf/P2rS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
