<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our strategy is to Educate, Empower, and Employ non-English speaking residents whose heritage is rich in family and cultural traditions, but whose lives have been economically impoverished and educationally deprived.

Neighbors Link was founded to meet the needs of 3,000 Latino immigrants who represent 26% of Mount Kisco's total population. When problems at many levels became apparent, concerned members of the community raised private funds to convert a masonry warehouse into a community center for low-income working people. That was in the year 2000, and it signaled the remarkable transformation of a whole community. Today, Neighbors Link offers a fully staffed center with comprehensive programs for:

&#8226; Adult Education
&#8226; Employment and Economic Development 
&#8226; Computer Skill Training 
&#8226; Leadership Training 
&#8226; Entrepreneurial Development 
&#8226; Recreation and Community-Building 
&#8226; Personal and vocational enhancement
&#8226; On-site help and referrals for personal and family issues such as housing and homelessness, medical and mental health, family budgeting, tax payer identification, non-payment of wages, alcoholism, domestic violence, immigration issues and other critical concerns.

Neighbors Link offers a collaboration of community efforts under one roof. These include Head Start, BOCES educational systems, Casa de Lengua (Greeley High School Tutors), Lexington Center for Recovery, Open Door Medical Clinic, Grupo Fenix (Alcoholics Anonymous), ESL tutorial program, The Westchester Library System, Westchester Family Services, as well as caring people from towns throughout the community who volunteer their time, talent and personal resources.

1. Employ

2. Empower

3. Educate</description>
  <mission>strengthen our community by actively enhancing the healthy integration of recent Latino immigrants</mission>
  <name>Neighbor's Link</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8026</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">13</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qh/PV/oR/0w/15/hr/vabS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
