<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Using the best available scientific knowledge and advancing that knowledge where we can, we work to preserve the diversity and abundance of life on Earth and the health of ecological systems by:

* protecting natural areas and wild populations of plants and animals, including endangered species;

* promoting sustainable approaches to the use of renewable natural resources; and

* promoting more efficient use of resources and energy and the maximum reduction of pollution.

We are committed to reversing the degradation of our planet's natural environment and to building a future in which human needs are met in harmony with nature.

We recognize the critical relevance of human numbers, poverty and consumption patterns to meeting these goals.
Programs: 	WWF has a unique way of working: global reach, action at every level, and innovative solutions that meet the needs of both people and nature.

With a 45-year history of results, our foundation in solid science, and our global network, we are capable of saving nature on a grand scale.

Our singular method of linking on-the-ground conservation work with policy and private sector involvement produces lasting change by altering the forces that devastate nature.

And our understanding of and concern for the lives of indigenous peoples keep us focused on building a sustainable balance between humans and nature.

By many measures, WWF is the most broad-reaching and effective conservation organization in the world. 

1. To save the earth 

2. To help animals in need 

3. To reser vegatation</description>
  <mission>WWF's mission is the conservation of nature</mission>
  <name>WWF (World Wildlife Fund)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8028</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">74</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/AB/Jv/OF/Pb/Gk/4Q/NN2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
