<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Children of Ethiopia Education Fund (COEEF) is a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization that matches needy children, mostly girls, with sponsors in the US who are willing to spend $225 ($20/month) per year to provide tuition, uniform, and supplies for one student in private school for one year. Lasting relationships are built through becoming a pen pals with sponsor students, while you watch them grow in their education and life.

Why girls? In most families in Ethiopia, if there is a choice of who to send to school, the son will go before the daughter. In fact, while 64 percent of boys attend school in Ethiopia, only 36 percent of girls do so. Even girls who do attend school are often forced to drop out around age 12. Studies have shown that in sub-Saharan Africa, girls who stay in school are less likely to get AIDS, will marry at an older age (and thus be better prepared for the responsibilities of being a mother, rather than passing poverty on to a child with a teenage mother), and are more likely to improve the lives of their children than comparably educated men.

Thanks to our ever-growing family of sponsors here and around the world, hundreds of girls are enrolled in modest private schools throughout Ethiopia, where they receive the kind of education that Americans take for granted.

1. If you educate a child, you educate a nation - By them, our future can be brighter.

2. Girls are educated up through high school are less likely to marry young and less likely to contract HIV/AIDS.

3. Girls who are educated are more likely to improve the lives of their children, families and country.</description>
  <mission>COEEF seeks to provide a quality, private education for children in Ethiopia, mainly females, through a network of sponsors in America and other developed countries.</mission>
  <name>Children of Ethiopia Education Fund - COEEF - Mesgana Dancers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8038</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">86</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yi/Mf/kB/3A/xY/1r/Ye/TgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
