<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>    Children's Miracle Network is an amazing organization that helps save the lives of millions of children every year. It suports 170 Children's Hospitals around the US, each of which are open 24 hours a day and offer the best, most advanced care. Whether the patient is simply sick or injured, or if they have a life threating diesease or condition, these hospitals provide them with the best care possible no matter the age, race, insurance, or ability to pay. 
    In order to provide this care free of cost to those families who cannot afford to pay, Children's Miracle Network puts on tons of fundraisers including one large annual televised fundraiser the "Children's Miracle Network Celebration" and many others such as the corporate sponsors selling of paper ballons, which I am sure you have seen at Wal-Mart!! 
   The best way for us as college students to get involved would be through our schools dance marathons (or Knight-Thon for those of you at UCF!). These events are not simply a marathon but a fundraiser, contestants raise money in teams, and then come to the event to celebrate what they have done! Last year UCF students raised $30,000 for Children's Miracle Network and this year we hope to raise even more!!! 
    If you want any more information about our Knight-Thon (knight-thon.com) or any information at all about how to get involved don't hesitate to contact me. Through facebook for now will be best, but as soon as I get my new e-mail account I will post that as well! Love you guys!!

1. Give children the medical attention they need when they need it, not when they can pay.</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness and funds for this amazing cause.</mission>
  <name>CMN Hospitals</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/804</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26921</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2720.99</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7q/Fx/yH/1D/z1/U5/Vb/ArS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
