<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There was a period when Indian diamonds were very famous the world over. These included the Koh-i-noor, Orlov, the Great Moghul, Darya-i-noor, Indore pears, Shah and Arcots. These were all part of the treasure houses of the great emperors of India. Today, they are all in the hands of outsiders.

In 1853, it was mounted on a magnificent tiara for the Queen, which contained more than two thousand diamonds. Five years later, Queen Victoria ordered a new regal circlet for the diamond. In 1911, Garrards made a new crown that Queen Mary wore for the coronation - it contained, among them the Koh-i-noor. In 1937, this was transferred to the crown made for Queen Elizabeth the Queen Mother, based on Queen Victoria's regal circlet and is set in a Maltese Cross at the front of the crown.
The 20th century saw a war of words over Koh-i-noor and its rightful ownership. In 1947, the government of India asked for the return of the diamond. 
The Koh-i-Noor left the shores of India on April 6, 1850, and on reaching London on July 2, 1850, it was handed over to the Board of Directors of the East India Company. Sir J.W. Logg, the Deputy Chairman of the East India Company, presented it to Queen Victoria. The queen recorded in her journal: "The jewels are truly magnificent. They had also belonged to Ranjit Singh and had been found in the treasury of Lahore.... I am very happy that the British Crown will possess these jewels for I shall certainly make them Crown Jewels".
Many still await the many treasures which were &#8220;stolen&#8221; by the British Raj, and no one knows how long the wait will be. Today, if you happen to visit London, look at the Crown Jewels for the Queen and the Koh-i-noor placed in her crown up front inside a Maltese cross.

By Harpreet Kaur: http://www.dancewithshadows.com/society/kohinoor-diamond-india.asp


1. The Kohinoor's Legitimate ownership belongs to the Indian People

2. The Kohinoor was mined in India, therefore belongs in India </description>
  <mission>Persuade the Queen of England to handover the Kohinoor Diamond to the Indian Government so it can be returned the People of India!</mission>
  <name>Bring The Kohinoor Diamond Back To India</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8040</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">680</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kL/GM/yA/Za/88/K0/O5BS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
