<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We will make a difference in the lives of children, 
one child at a time 

VISION
South Delhi, India has seen tremendous growth in recent years. However, much of the economic, social and educational benefits have eluded the slum dwellers and the homeless. Manav Kalyan Kendra wants to make a qualitative difference in the lives of these people, especially children. Its primary vision is to create self-sustaining communities. 

MISSION
The mission of MKK-USA is to support programs and projects geared towards children, especially education, humanitarian aid, preventive medicine, disaster relief and sanitation. MKK-USA will also support similar humane activities in other parts of the world.

1. Support programs for the education of slum children through scholarships, tuition reimbursements, books and supplies, and after-school tutoring. By year 2005, assist 50 needy and bright children. By year 2020, assist 200 slum children with education needs

2. Provide educational support and humanitarian aid to children, and to children&#8217;s programs, in the U.S. and other countries. 

3. Provide emergency disaster relief for floods, storms, earthquakes, and fires.

4. Provide preventive medical care and medical supplies, including immunizations, inoculation, flu shots, first aid supplies, and OTC medicines.

5. Provide adult reading and writing classes, and high school equivalency classes. The goal is that by year 2020, half the population of men and women above 20 will have reading and writing skills in Hindi and/or English. 

6. Work with government and non-government entities to ensure the supply of safe drinking water, electricity, sewer lines, storm water management, garbage disposal and street lights in all targeted communities. 

7. Educate slum children about hygiene and sanitation. Encourage monthly &#8220;clean sweep&#8221;drives.

8. Recruit volunteer doctors, nurses, educators, social workers, and community leaders to accomplish the above goals and objectives. 

9. Conduct seminars and meetings, and work with other organizations in the furtherance of our mission, goals and objectives. </description>
  <mission>support programs and projects geared towards children, especially education, humanitarian aid, preventive medicine, disaster relief and sanitation.</mission>
  <name>Manav Kalyan Kendra (MKK) - USA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8044</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/AQ/A6/SV/Xq/vC/hr/Fj0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
