<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Anti-Racist Action is an international movement of people dedicated to stopping racism, sexism, homophobia and other forms of bigotry from harming our communities. We work hard to "expose, oppose, and confront" hate in whatever form threatens the diversity and safety of the places we live in and the people we live with. We also firmly believe in building a fun, diverse, liberated and explicitly anti-racist, anti-sexist and anti-homophobic youth culture.

1. We go where they go: Whenever fascists are organizing or active in public, we're there. We don't believe in ignoring them or staying away from them. Never let the nazis have the street!

2. We don't rely on the cops or courts to do our work for us: This doesn't mean we never go to court. But we must rely on ourselves to protect ourselves and stop the fascists

3. Non-Sectarian defense of other Anti-Fascists: In ARA, we have lots of different groups and individuals. We don't agree about everything and we have a right to differ openly. But in this movement an attack on one is an attack on us all. We stand behind eac

4. We support abortion rights and reproductive freedom. ARA intends to do the hard work necessary to build a broad, strong movement against racism, sexism, anti-Semitism, homophobia, discrimination against the disabled, the oldest, the youngest and the most 

5. Educate all people about how systemic racism functions

6. Challenge institutional policies and actions which benefit whites at the expense of others</description>
  <mission>promote racial justice and equity by challenging systemic racism and acting as a catalyst for antiracist action and learning</mission>
  <name>Anti-Racist Action!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8052</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">922</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.04</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oj/2J/VU/dn/Hx/2G/fNPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
