<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"BE A DIVA -- DEMAND HE WEAR PROTECTION" 

The Candie's Foundation

"BE STRONG -- DON'T BE A STATISTIC"

~ facts ~

4 in 10 girls will experience at least one pregnancy before reaching age 20.

Only 41% of teenage mothers graduate from high school and only 1.5% will earn a college degree by age 30.

Nearly 80% of unmarried teen mothers end up on welfare.

Nearly 80% of fathers of babies born to teen mothers do not marry their babies mothers.

If you have unprotected sex, you have an 85% chance of becoming pregnant within one year.

Almost one million teenage girls will become pregnant this year.

"BE FOCUSED -- DON'T GIVE UP ON YOUR EDUCATION" 

~ tips for teens ~ 
visit http://www.teenpregnancy.org/default.asp 

How to Avoid Pregnancy
&gt; everything from abstinence to different forms of contraception. 

Facts &amp; Stats 
&gt; The latest data on teen sexual activity, pregnancy and childbearing (lots of answers here). 

Test Your Knowledge
&gt; Think you know it all when it comes to teen pregnancy? Prove it.

Teens Tell All
&gt; What do teens think about sex, pregnancy, contraception, parents, the media, and religion? 

Teen Resource Guide
&gt; A list of web sites where teens can find further information.
 
"BE SMART -- THINK TWICE" 

For the TEDDY GEIGER &amp; CIARA Candies Foundation Commercial visit
http://myspacetv.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.individual&amp;videoid=4179784

"BE VOCAL -- SAY NO WAY" 

For more information and/or to get your very own 'Be Sexy Tee' visit www.candiesfoundation.org

"BE SEXY -- IT DOESN'T MEAN YOU HAVE TO HAVE SEX"  




1. "I'm Sexy Enough... To Keep You Waiting"</description>
  <mission>help reduce teen pregnancy by raising awareness of this serious problem and the consequences.</mission>
  <name>PAUSE Before You Play</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8055</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">136</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4N/lD/iZ/VE/xA/mX/P5hS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
