<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The CCO partners with colleges, churches and organizations to develop men and women who live out their Christian faith in every area of life. Our ministry is transformational. We challenge the students we serve to submit every area of their lives to Jesus Christ. Some of our staff people serve as an arm of the local church on campus, while others work as residence hall directors, coaches or student activities directors.  

Even young people who were raised in the church often forget about it during their college years. It can take them years to come back&#8212;often they leave the church forever. At the same time, churches located near college campuses often want to reach out to students but don&#8217;t know how. We help the church by doing college ministry with them. We help students by connecting them with the people of the church. We show them how the church can still be relevant to their lives.  

Since we are partnering with the school, we are on campus all the time, and we get to know students in a context in which we wouldn&#8217;t otherwise. We have a chance to develop relationships with students and model the Christian life by showing what it means to do our jobs as Christians. 

No two CCO ministries look exactly alike. We do contextual ministry, meaning that our staff adjust to the needs of the particular campus at which they serve. We cooperate with other ministries because want to enhance the environment in which we are serving, not to compete with good things already happening. 

Each college, church or cooperating organization pays for half of a CCO staff worker&#8217;s salary. The CCO staff worker needs to raise the other half of his or her salary from others who also see the strategic importance of college ministry. Would you be willing to partner with us in our mission?

Want to know more, who we are, what we believe, our leadership, our history, where we serve? Visit ... us online at

www.ccojubilee.org

1. All things belong to God.

2. Jesus changes people's lives.

3. We love college students.

4. Faithfulness is pursued together.

5. We celebrate life.</description>
  <mission>Transforming College Students to Transform the World</mission>
  <name>CCO - Coalition for Christian Outreach</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8057</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2489</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">873.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5t/F0/xY/QN/Er/uE/4xQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
