<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Sumatran, a.k.a. the hairy rhino, Dicerorhinus sumatrensis, is probably the most endangered of all rhinoceros species. Numbers have declined over 50% due to poaching over the last 15 years. Fewer than 300 Sumatran Rhino survive in very small and highly fragmented populations in Southeast Asia with Indonesia and Malaysia being the only significant range states. Furthermore, there is no indication that the situation is showing any signs of stabilizing. 

Common Names:
-Sumatran Rhinoceros 
-Asian Two-Horned Rhinoceros: the only two-horned rhino in the Asian region. 
-Hairy Rhinoceros: refers to the long, shaggy hair found on the species in contrast to the other species which appear hairless. 

Scientific Name and Origin:
-Dicerorhinus sumatrensis 
-Dicerorhinus: from the Greek di, meaning "two"; cero, meaning "horn" and rhinus, meaning "nose" 
sumatrensis: referring to Sumatra (with the Latin -ensis, meaning locality)

Size:
-Weight: 1,300 - 2,000 lbs (600 - 950 kg) 
-Height: 3 - 5 ft (1.0 -1.5m) tall at shoulder 
-Length: 6.5 - 9.5 ft (2.0 - 3.0m) length of body

Longevity:
Life span approximately 35-40 years

Gestation:
Gestation period is approximately 15-16 months. 
Interbirth intervals of a single calf, every 3 years.

Habitat:
The Sumatran Rhino lives in dense tropical forest, both lowland and highland, mainly in the Malay Peninsula, on the Indonesian island of Sumatra and on Borneo. 

Ecology:
The Sumatran Rhino is a browser with a very varied diet consisting of the great diversity of the plant species in tropical forest.



1. The Sumatran is near extinct.</description>
  <mission>Save the Sumatran Rhino from near extinction.</mission>
  <name>Save the Sumatran Rhino</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8062</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">732</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">280.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uq/fk/xi/1X/Nq/0O/LphS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
