<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.etcgroup.org

ETC Group is dedicated to the conservation and sustainable advancement of cultural and ecological diversity and human rights. To this end, ETC Group supports socially responsible developments of technologies useful to the poor and marginalized and it addresses international governance issues and corporate power.

ETC Group works in partnership with civil society organizations (CSOs) for cooperative and sustainable self-reliance within disadvantaged societies, by providing information and analysis of socioeconomic and technological trends and alternatives. This work requires joint actions in community, regional, and global fora.

ETC Group's strength is in the research and analysis of technological information (particularly but not exclusively plant genetic resources, biotechnologies, and [in general] biological diversity), and in the development of strategic options related to the socioeconomic ramifications of new technologies.

ETC Group works primarily at the global and regional (continental or sub-continental) levels. ETC Group does not undertake grassroots, community, or national work. ETC Group supports partnerships with community, national, or regional CSOs but ETC does not make grants or funds available to other organizations. We do not have members.

1. We address the socioeconomic and ecological issues surrounding new technologies that could have an impact on the world&#8217;s poorest and most vulnerable.

2. We investigate ecological erosion (including the erosion of cultures and human rights); the development of new technologies (especially agricultural but also new technologies that work with genomics and matter).

3. We monitor global governance issues including corporate concentration and trade in technologies.

4. We operate at the global political level.

5. We work closely with partner civil society organizations (CSOs) and social movements, especially in Africa, Asia and Latin America. </description>
  <mission>monitor power, track technology and strengthen diversity</mission>
  <name>ETC Group-or Action Group on Erosion, Technology and Concentration</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8074</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">31</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ov/wi/5z/Dc/yt/7T/mRKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
