<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The goal of this cause on facebook is threefold:

1.  Raise awareness about this organization.
2.  Recruit volunteers and establish additional PCRF chapters worldwide.
3.  Raise additional funds. 

The PCRF is a registered 501c3 organization in the U.S.  Donations are tax deductible.  

At a time when conditions in Palestine and other parts of the Middle East seem hopeless, the PCRF is affecting real change for those most in need.  The organization is run in an extremely lean and efficient manner - through in kind donations and heavy volunteer involvement each $1 donated is turned into $50 of value.  

Objectives and results:

The main objective of the PCRF is to identify and treat every child in the Middle East in need of specialized surgery not available to them locally. We locate, sponsor and run volunteer medical missions to the Middle East in adult and pediatric cardiac surgery, pediatric cardiology, plastic and reconstructive surgery, maxillofacial surgery, pediatric urology, ophthalmology, vascular surgery, pediatric orthopedic surgery, occupational therapy, and other specialties. We also locate abroad free medical care for children who cannot be adequately treated in the Middle East. The PCRF is the main organization regularly sending injured and sick Arab children to North America, the Middle East and Europe for free care that is not available to them there. Since 1991 over 750 children have been or currently are being treated outside of the Middle East through the PCRF

The PCRF currently has several injured or sick Arab children in the U.S., the Middle East or Europe being treated for free. We are also working to locate free medical care for many more injured and sick children from Palestine, Lebanon and Iraq. We rely on the kindness of many volunteers throughout the U.S. who act as host families, volunteers and donors, enabling us to continue our humanitarian relief work.

1. Healthcare is a universal human right

2. Children affected by war are most in need of healthcare services</description>
  <mission>Provide medical &amp; humanitarian relief to Palestinian and other children in the Middle East by locating free medical care for those who are unable to get the necessary treatment in their homeland.</mission>
  <name>Palestine Children's Relief Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8077</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">520</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">430.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Un/Gm/Ek/M7/6n/sZ/dMeS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
