<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Vision:
Through advocacy, service provision and capacity building, the Galilee Society empowers Palestinian citizens and strengthens civil society in Israel. The Galilee Society has a history of collaboration with Jewish, Arab and international organizations, both governmental and non-governmental. As the largest and longest-standing Palestinian NGO in Israel, the Galilee Society is known and trusted by the Palestinian community as an organization that strives to protect minority rights, thus promoting and strengthening democratic principles of pluralism and equality in Israel.

Approach:
Established by four health care professionals in 1981, the Galilee Society has long been committed to a rights-based approach to development. This approach, formalized in 2004, eliminates the separation between human rights and development as distinct spheres. It creates a dynamic in which development is seen as a component of human rights and human rights provide the framework to guide development agendas. Through its rights-based development programs, the Galilee Society advocates for the Palestinian minority's right to equality, right to health, right to a healthy environment, and right to a decent standard of living.

The Galilee Society focuses on the Palestinian minority in Israel as an indigenous people, and, in particular, on Palestinian women and children. Our programs strive to eliminate discrimination against the Palestinian minority living in Israel, in the spheres of health, environmental, educational and socio-economic status. Important elements of this approach are accountability, empowerment and participation. The concerned communities are provided with access to information, procedures, and policy making processes, thus ensuring feedback mechanisms are in place and accessible. Development projects, as implemented by the Galilee Society and other NGOs, are conceived and built with the community and not outside it.

1. Equitable health, environmental and socio-economic conditions are a human right

2. Protection of minority rights in Israel is key to maintaining democracy</description>
  <mission>The Galilee Society &#8722; The Arab National Society for Health Research and Services &#8722; strives to achieve equitable health, environmental and socio-economic conditions for Palestinian Arabs in Israel. </mission>
  <name>The Galilee Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8080</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/HO/f1/6P/Xk/Dz/KR/ZYjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
