<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Shopping in the Grocery Store, Supermarket or Corner Shop is fraught with ethical dilemmas. Typical shoppers have no concept of how their food is made, where it comes from and who touches it along the way.

The average food item travels more than 1200mi. There are only 4 days worth of food in a typical Grocery Store. These facts bear witness to the oil dependent, Corporate AgriBusiness model of shipping foods around the land from central depots.

As more food scares and contamination cases reach the news we must arm ourselves with knowledge about the wheres, hows and whys of our food system in order to assure we have Food Security.

Food security is all about having a local, secure, non-tamperable, sustainable food source. It is not--as Corporate Agribusiness would have you believe--about the ability to ship huge amounts of food items from central warehouses within a matter of days anywhere on the planet. Unless we take control of local food systems the Multinational Corporate Agribusinesses--Cargill, Monsanto, ADM, Nestle, etc--will control even more of what we eat, and how we can purchase it. 

If we don't protect our rights to eat what we want, when we want it, and purchase it from who we want to we may very well have no choice at all. Our food system  is wholly controlled by 3 or 4 large corporations who have no concern for consumer health and welfare beyond their own bottom line.

Caveat Emptor means "Buyer Beware". So look into how much of your food Cargill handles; Just what Monsanto has poisoned with GM crops and Round Up; How much Organic food you buy is imported from China, fertilized with human poo.

The Caveat Emptor Campaign is about empowering consumers with the knowledge to make the right, ethical choices about their food maintaining everyone's right to healthy, safe, nutritional foods without unnecessary regulations.

Find out more on The Kitchen Garden Network: http://kitchengardens.net

1. Consumers have the right to know about the production of Groceries.

2. Government control of the food system should favor consumers not Multinationals.

3. Local, Sustainable, Organic Agriculture needs more support.</description>
  <mission>Create Consumer Awareness about Groceries</mission>
  <name>Caveat Emptor</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8082</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1g/SL/Ar/dk/We/Jw/886S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
