<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In the year 2000, it was realized there was a need for families that had a child with Positional Plagiocephaly to obtain support and information.  Thus, in the year 2001, with the addition of a mother whose child had Positional Plagiocephaly, Craniosynostosis And Parent Support, Inc. became Craniosynostosis And Positional Plagiocephaly Support, Inc.  Headquartered in Fredericksburg, VA, Craniosynostosis And Positional Plagiocephaly Support, better known as CAPPS, is dedicated to offering support and providing information to families who have a child with either condition.

Of our many our many objectives, our primary goal is to raise awareness through education.  Although these two conditions are very different in cause, in many cases they have a similar outward appearance, which causes many mis-diagnoses.  By educating the HealthCare community and general public, we will be able to reduce the amount of mis-diagnoses and children will get the appropriate treatment for their condition without losing valuable time.  It is imperative that parents know the symptoms and signs of both disorders so that infants can obtain treatment without delay.  Positional Plagiocephaly, is most often a preventable condition, therefore parents and childcare providers need to know what steps to take in order to prevent this condition from occurring.

Our secondary goal is to offer support to families that have a child with either condition.  The staff of CAPPS is always available to help families with information and emotional support.  We are also able to put families in contact with each other, so they can share information and their experiences and offer emotional support to one another.



1. Raise awareness through education.

2. Offer support to families that have a child with either condition.</description>
  <mission>Offer support and information to other families who had a child with Craniosynostosis &amp; Positional Plagiocephaly </mission>
  <name>CAPPS Kids</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8097</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">489</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Cv/zl/ZJ/L3/Fi/lw/KSYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
