<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>HOW WE BEGAN

A diving          in 1967 left Joni Eareckson Tada a quadriplegic in a wheelchair, unable to use her hands. During two years of rehabilitation, she spent long months learning how to paint with a brush between her teeth. Her high detail fine art paintings and prints, best-selling books, beginning with her autobiography, as well as her visits to 35 countries, has made Joni recognized around the world. 

Mrs. Tada's role as a disability advocate led to a presidential appointment to the National Council on Disability for three and a half years, during which time the Americans with Disabilities Act became law. Mrs. Tada began the Joni and Friends organization, which continues to help those affected by disability.
                                                          
WHAT WE DO

For nearly a quarter of a century, Joni and Friends has been dedicated to extending the love and message of Christ to people who are affected by disability, whether it is the disabled person, a family member, or friend. Our objective is to meet the physical, emotional, and spiritual needs of this group of people in practical ways.
                                                    
GET INVOLVED

Joni and Friends exists because of the hundreds of dedicated volunteers and staff. Without your support and participation, Joni and Friends could not continue the excellent and vital work that they do, every day, with so much love and dedication.

We invite you to join us and get involved. Volunteer your time, join the Circle of Friends, write a Prayer Letter, be one of the Friends of People with Disabilities &#8211; there is so much to be done. 


http://www.joniandfriends.org/index.php

1. Present the clear and concise Gospel of Jesus Christ to all people with disabilities and their families served through our programs.

2. Train, disciple, and mentor people affected by disability to exercise their gifts of leadership and service in the church and their communities.

3. Energize the church to move from lack of awareness to including disabled persons into the fabric of worship, fellowship, and outreach. </description>
  <mission>To communicate the Gospel and equip Christ-honoring Churches worldwide to evangelize and disciple people affected by disabilities.</mission>
  <name>Joni and Friends</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8109</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1778</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">745.6</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Hh/Ta/Oq/rw/2A/M2/h5sS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
