<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For the first time in history we got what it takes. To beat poverty. "Beat Poverty? I doubt it, not in my life time. Poverty has been around forever, you will never beat it. Sure maybe we can beat it in a thousand years or a million years but not now. We dont have what it takes". So you really don't think we have what it takes? LISTEN UP!
Cash: We got it, we got LOADS of it. The United Nation say by 2015 we can cut poverty in half! For the poor to have food, health care, education, and safe water. that only cost 150 billion dollars a year. Think that sounds a lot? Then think about this. North American Teens spend 155 billion dollars on cloths junk food dvds, and other stuff. And world leaders spend more. A lot more. 1 trillion dollars on war weaponds and training. We Have The Cash
Food: We grow it, we grow tones of it. We grow enough food to feed each person on earth 4.3 lbs a day. Enough to make everyone feel satisfy. Full, stuffed! enough to feed everyone, and some more. But yet 850 million people go to bed ungrey everyday. We have the FOOD!
Drugs: We make them, we make a lot of them. For AIDS we make Antiretrofiber. They don't cure, but they prolong life. In developing countries only, 8% of people get the drugs that they need. For the other 92% AIDS is a death sentence. It doesn't have to be. We have the drugs.
We Have The Cash
We Have The Food
We Have The Drugs
" We Are The First Generation That Can Look Poverty In The Eye And Say This And Mean It- We Have The Cash, We Have The Drugs, We Have The Science. Do We Have The Will To Make Poverty History?!" Bono, U2.
For the first time in history we got what it takes.
Do You? Hungrey For Change?

1. People Shouldn't Be Put To Bed HUNGREY!

2. People Shouldn't Be Dying In Groups Every Day!

3. Change Is Not BAD!</description>
  <mission>Raise 1000$ by spring of 2008!</mission>
  <name>30 Hour Famine</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8126</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/JO/Dc/Hf/k0/ab/xL/RChS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
