<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Today, islands are home to the greatest number of endangered species on the planet.  For the last 500 years, 62 percent of all mammal and 88 percent of all bird extinctions have been island species. Currently, the top ten hotspots for species extinctions worldwide are all on islands.  When islands species die, islands become uninhabitable causing the demise of ancient island cultures. Seacology addresses this crisis.  

Seacology searches for solutions that protect island wildlife and ecosystems while supporting local island communities.  At present, islands host some of the most economically and environmentally fragile communities on earth. Seacology works directly with local NGOs and village leaders to conserve marine and terrestrial island habitat, promote ecotourism, and find sustainable ways to improve the quality of life for developing island communities.  

Seacology has over 200 projects on 114 islands around the world. We have protected over 1 million acres of island ecosystems, while supporting island communities with much-needed schools, waste management equipment, fresh water delivery systems, and ecotourism programs. Visit www.seacology.org to learn more about how we save the world&#8217;s islands!


1. Marine and terrestrial island environments need to be conserved.

2. Islanders across the world deserve better opportunities.

3. Environment and culture go hand in hand.</description>
  <mission>To preserve island cultures and ecosystems around the world, and to reverse the trend of plant life, marine life and wildlife extinctions, safeguarding biodiversity on islands globally.</mission>
  <name>Seacology - Saving Island Environments</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/813</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1377</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">210.56</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/61/Xm/rM/7P/yB/GI/1j/ChS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
