<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Have you ever envisioned a world where there are no nations, no lines of separation between homo sapiens? This earth belongs to all of us; we were born into it, we live on it, and we have separated ourselves over such silly differences: skin color, creed, religion, even sexual preference.
The "New Earth" cause is about changing all of that. We must form a planet, a gestalt whole of a species. This factional lifestyle we lead must end. No more Americans, Russians, or Koreans, but humans from the various regions around the planet.
The argument has been made that nations instill a sense of pride in their people, and that removal of such nations would demoralize the people and make them feel inferior. Why should it matter so much, when you can feel pride in the world society rather than a smaller corner of it? True, uniqueness is important, but humans are already unique. Very few planets we have seen are actually capable of supporting human life. This Earth Planet is. As the "oddballs" of the galaxy, we should be proud of that.
Furthermore, unification as a planetary society is important for our survival. An "earth alliance" of sorts is the only way to travel in space. Without such 
unity, various nations will engage in space races and battles for supremacy in the dark vacuum of the universe, and will seek to dominate all in space. If we stand together, this will never, for who can claim himself to be bigger than his planet?
Now, we do not make the claim that the society has a greater say than the individual. But when the individual has so much power, and abuse of this power becomes unbearable, we must do all in our power to bring him down.
Believe, ladies and gentleman, that you can make a difference.
The biggest way to make this difference is to support education. That is why all proceeds will go to the World Learning, Inc. These people promote leaders through their education, and through this education, people will begin to understand how to run their planet.

1. All national borders must cease to exist.

2. Various currencies, and the current economic standard, which favours the wealthy, must come to an end.

3. The people of Earth must realize that their only chance for survival amongst the stars is to unite as one species.

4. Space travel must reach a position of higher importance.

5. Research must be promoted vastly, to improve not only our physical quality, but to send us to the stars.</description>
  <mission>Change the world as we know it</mission>
  <name>The "New Earth" Cause</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8133</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6n/eB/Mq/UQ/XL/ai/AQuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
