<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Every year in the U.S., millions of perfectly healthy and loveable dogs, cats, puppies, and kittens must be destroyed - simply because there are not enough homes to go around and not enough money for the shelters to take care of them.

Here are the cold hard facts:

Of the estimated 8-12 million animals that enter shelters each year, 60% of dogs and 70% of the cats are killed.

That's one about every six and one half seconds.  

Millions more are abandoned, only to suffer from illness or injury before dying.

It costs U.S. taxpayers an estimated $2 billion each year to round up, house, kill, and dispose of homeless animals.

Each day 10,000 humans are born in the U.S. and each day 70,000 puppies and kittens are born.  As long as these birth rates exist, there will never be enough homes for all the animals.

The public acquires only 14% of its pets from shelters; 48% get their pets as strays, from friends, from animal rescuers, 38% get their pets from breeders or pet stores.

Only 30% of dog guardians are aware of the pet-overpopulation problem.

SO HERE IS WHAT YOU CAN DO TO HELP...
 - Spread the facts about pet overpopulation
 - Adopt from a shelter
 - Get your pets spayed or neutered
 - Volunteer at your local animal shelter
 - Donate today!

--------------------------------------------

Your Gift to the Kansas Humane Society Helps.

DID YOU KNOW THAT A DONATION OF...

$15 vaccinates seven animals? 
$25 provides educational materials for a classroom of local school children? 
$50 provides special foods for animals with special dietary needs? 
$100 provides veterinary care and medicine for a sick or injured animal? 
$500 heats or cools ten of our dog and cat kennels for a season? 

To learn more about us please go to...
http://kshumane.org/index.html

1. TO PROMOTE AND ENSURE THE WELFARE OF ANIMALS, SHELTER AND ADOPT UNWANTED ANIMALS, PROVIDE HUMANE EDUCATION, AND PROTECT ANIMALS BY ENFORCEMENT OF CRUELTY AND ANIMAL WELFARE LAWS. </description>
  <mission>SHELTER AND ADOPT UNWANTED ANIMALS</mission>
  <name>Help Support the Kansas Humane Society</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8134</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2439</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">615.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Sl/wq/hC/Oy/6C/gU/OSLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
