<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This group is designed to bring about a greater understanding of the character of man and how it is of a different kind from the character of the beasts as explained by the Philosopher in his work "De Anima"

Those who join this group ought to recognize that in doing so they are asserting the goodness of animals, while also recognizing the superiority of man, considered only from the vantage-point of their natures.

It is the express hope of this cause that by coming to a greater understanding of the distinction between man and the beasts many foolish ideas - like "animals are people too" and "animals should have all the same rights as men" - might cease to waste the time and efforts of those who are ignorant of this distinction.  Further, this understanding might lead to an acceptance of the animal's role as a thing whose life may be taken for the good of human life - such as animal testing and animal meals.  Thus, ignorant people might not feel bad for the natural assertion of man's superiority and the ordering of the good of the beast to the man which is signified by the act of taking the life of the beast in a well-ordered manner.

It is also to be wished that man recognize that though the beast is lower than the man still the nature of the beast is good and to be appropriately treated and respected.

1. Man is of a different, higher order than the beasts

2. Beasts are intrinsically good, according to the order of nature

3. Man acts excellently when he treats the beasts as good things</description>
  <mission>To bring about a greater awareness of the distinction between man and the beasts</mission>
  <name>The Hierarchy in Nature</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8136</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/WP/cD/DO/sN/MT/OE/1TcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
