<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> APBD is a  neurodegenerative disease that attacks nerve cells and pathways in the brain. Our mission is to improve the diagnosis and treatment of APBD, support individuals and families affected by the disease, increase awareness of APBD among health professionals and the public. Our ultimate goal, and the heart of our program is to find the underlying cause as well as a cure for APBD and its complications through the support of research, education, and patient services.

The Adult Polyglucosan Body Disease Research Foundation (APBDRF) is a not-for-profit organization that was founded by the individuals affected by Adult Polyglucosan Body Disease (APBD) and their friends. Having witnessed the devastating effects of this disease, the founders pledged to work to increase awareness so others would not have to suffer similarly. 
 The Foundation's mission is to help prevent APBD through education and to support research efforts, which have yet to find an effective therapy. 

The APBD Foundation's board of directors is dedicated to increasing public awareness and understanding of the disease. Outreach is critical to at-risk populations, such as Ashkenazi Jews, as well as to the medical community, which still remains largely unaware of the disorder. Please provide us with your e-mail address so we can keep you updated about new developments.

 This Foundation needs donations to support research, and other public education materials and efforts; but more importantly, the Foundation needs your help to spread the word to those who are potentially at risk. 

 Contact us about contacting your local synagogues, Jewish organizations, friends and the media about increasing awareness and encouraging screening and research. 

 Remember, your support in vital until a treatment is developed or a cure of APBD has been found

www.apbdrf.org

1. Finding treatment and eventually a cure for APBD

2. spreading awareness to the medical community and public

3. support for patients and families affected by this disease</description>
  <mission>to improve the diagnosis and treatment of APBD, support individuals and families affected by the disease and increase awareness of APBD among health professionals and the public.</mission>
  <name>APBD Research Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8148</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Mj/tQ/0v/Q1/WN/G0/TX/z6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
