<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> Hospice &amp; HomeCare By The Sea has been serving the community of Palm Beach and Broward counties since 1979. We are an organization dedicated to providing compassionate care for patients living with a life-limiting condition and as well as their families. Hospice services are available to people who choose not to continue aggressive medical treatment, such as chemotherapy, radiation, or dialysis. Controlling patients&#8217; pain and other symptoms, as well as providing emotional and spiritual support for patients and their families, is known as palliative care. This is why hospice exists: to help patients live life comfortably and to the fullest for as long as they live. 
  
  
Hospice By The Sea utilizes highly-skilled professional Care Teams that provide individualized plans of care to meet each patient&#8217;s needs. Each team consists of physicians, nurses, nurses&#8217; aides, social workers, trained volunteers, and if desired, spiritual care advisors. Abriendo Puertas (Opening Doors) is our Spanish-speaking Care Team, knowledgeable and sensitive to traditions and customs, meeting the special needs of our Hispanic population.

Most patients receive hospice services in the home, or wherever they may be, including a long-term care facility, hospital, or private residence. Hospice Inpatient Care Centers &#8211;located in Boca Raton, West Palm Beach, and Hollywood &#8211;are also available for acute care and pain/symptom management. 

Reimbursement for hospice services may come from: Hospice Medicare, Hospice Medicaid, private insurance, donations, fundraising events, grants, and private pay, when possible. In any event, hospice care is provided regardless of ability to pay.

Hospice By The Sea relies heavily on the support of the community to make up the shortfall of what insurance programs do not cover.

1. to help patients live life comfortably and to the fullest for as long as they live. 

2. Hospice By The Sea utilizes highly-skilled professional Care Teams that provide individualized plans of care to meet each patient&#8217;s needs

3. Hospice Inpatient Care Centers &#8211;located in Boca Raton, West Palm Beach, and Hollywood &#8211;are also available for acute care and pain/symptom management. </description>
  <mission>to help patients live life comfortably and to the fullest for as long as they live</mission>
  <name>Hospice by the sea</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8158</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">38</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">75.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Cw/Ox/OH/WM/Ba/O5/RruS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
