<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Imagine-Life is a 501(c)(3) innovative non-political, non-profit organization which produces educational media campaigns to increase the awareness of the American public on and inspire balanced discussion about underrepresented human rights violations around the world. The organization&#8217;s initiatives give voice to populations that are oppressed in the U.S. media, and are designed to raise awareness, educate, provide a conduit for understanding, activate, and incite change in subjective and biased news reporting in the U.S. media.

The charity organization is a pioneer&#8212;focused on utilizing the power of the American media to educate millions of people about underlying human rights catastrophes that are too often unheard in the U.S. media.  Genocide in Rwanda, the Holocaust, Bosnia and Herzegovina&#8217;s interethnic civil dissension, the apartheid in South Africa&#8212;the cycle of violence keeps turning as long as inequality, injustices, and ignorance are accepted. Education and awareness are key in hopes of avoiding such catastrophes.  

In an unbalanced media forum, Imagine-Life is tilting the scales.  Opening the hearts and minds of Americans to a people(s), a region(s), and a crisis(s) by utilizing the power of the American media, such as: television public service announcements (PSAs), magazine article ads, theater releases, cable television programming, home videos and the internet. 


Imagine-Life seeks to give a voice to the oppressed in order for the American public to see the scope of injustices and demand that American policies be a reflection of American values and freedoms.  Empowering communities to create environments where peace can prosper.

Join us in planting today's seeds of hope for a better tomorrow. 


1. Giving a voice to the oppressed in American media.

2. Ensuring that American values are a reflection of American foreign policy.

3. To end human suffering and help create environments where peace can prosper.</description>
  <mission>Our misstion is to utilize the power of the U.S. media to alleviate human suffering by leading educational campaigns focusing on underrepresented human rights violations around the world.</mission>
  <name>Imagine-Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/817</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">354</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5KI/6kWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
