<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Human trafficking unfortunately takes place throughout the world, and will continue in its cyclical path of destruction and abuse if we, as conscientious individuals do not protest against its presence. These acts of evil have total disgard for age, race and gender. One of the greatest atrocities that was committed against the female gender occured during WWII, by the Japanese military and government.  

Approximately 200,000 women between the ages of 9-40 were abducted from their countries, families, schools and homes during World War II.  These women were transferred to the Japanese front lines of war, and were forced to endure rape and other sexual acts by the soldiers and military personnel-- an average of 10-50 TIMES PER DAY.  100,000 of these women are believed to have been taken from Korea.  

These women were called "Comfort Women" by the Japanese military, but in reality, they were military sexual slaves.  Lines of soldiers stood outside the temporary barracks of these prisoners-- where they would have a set amount of time to rape and depredate these women, seconds before the next soldier entered in his stead.  

Medical experimentation was administered to these women and girls-- rendering them sterile.  The pregnant, diseased or escapees were slaughtered and discarded in unmarked graves.
When the war ended, the Japanese government and military attempted to hide all evidence of this atrocity, killing as many survivors as possible.  To this day, the Japanese government refuses to admit its guilt in the organization and execution of such a dispicable operation.  The surviving women are all in their late 70's and 80's-- they tell their story, but the world does not hear their cries of truth, of justice, nor for the calls of morality.

Read their testimonies in the public libraries, watch the documentaries, and see with your own eyes how evil can be hidden in our day and age.


1. Rape is an act of violence, and cannot go unforgiven.

2. War gives no excuse for this ungodly mistreatment towards women and young adolescents of the surrounding countries.

3. An apology is simple, yet it is a beginning.  So, also is awareness.

4. Although we are students, aspiring to succeed in a free and wealthy society-- we must question our own position of morality.

5. Respect the survivors: visit The Sharing House in Seoul, Korea where they cohabitate-- see their paintings, listen to their songs, protest along with them every Wednesday, at the Japanese Embassy.</description>
  <mission>to spread awareness, demand justice, and support the surviving victims of this example of human trafficking.</mission>
  <name>in Respect and Remembrance of the 200,000 Japanese Military Sexual Slaves of WWII</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8175</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">175</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/He/Ou/Px/jR/HI/WL/BD2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
