<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>*What is Secularism?

Secularism is generally the assertion or belief that certain practices or institutions should exist separately from religion or religious belief.  In one sense, secularism may assert the freedom of religion, and freedom from the government imposition of religion upon the people, within a state that is neutral on matters of belief, and gives no state privileges or subsidies to religions.In another sense, it refers to a belief that human activities and decisions, especially political ones, should be based on evidence and fact rather than religious influence.
It is the independence of human values such as freedom, justice, equality, democracy, peace and ethnic background. Considering it a humanitarian value no matter about its historical background; to activate for the person and only the person   

*Results of complete Secularism: 

-The equality that comes from the law without any civil, religious or group as mediums.
-Patriotism that makes each individual a national person.
-The government will have total authority if it declines from religion so there will no longer be states within a state. It extracts the fact that any religious image, without considering Christian or Muslim, or if the president is Christian or Muslim; in spite of the fact if the people are Muslims or Christians. Furthermore, the army will become more attached to one another, because they no longer are afraid of being divided; as a result of religion and therefore will gain strength in order to protect and participate in building a better country.  
- The concept of isolation and coldness in the Lebanese will lessen, and the conflict towards Arabian and Arab so Lebanon can become a pioneer country on the bases of nationalism and Arab secularism, that has not been implemented in any other Arab country. 
-Complete secularism helps in building a fair and active society for everyone; Restores to all the people their rights without any discrimination.


1. Differentiate between religion and politics.

2. Divide religious education from official institutional education. 

3. Employment secularism: total governmental independence not to associate any job to the amount of religions and not to discriminate between employees according to religion but to treat each one fairly. 

4. To delete all the subjects in the constitution, laws and documents that are written; especially elections and army; updating the civil rights, especially the bends chosen with respect to religious beliefs building civil courts that is responsible for impl

5. Support Civil Marriage in Lebanon .

6. reinforce political activities of the political parties especially after adjusting certain laws in relation to elections and that the parties present its candidate without any religious favors. 

7. Many other Ideas should be discussed on the wall</description>
  <mission>Make the Idea of Secularism clearer and encourage the Lebanese People to suport it ! </mission>
  <name>Support Secularism (el 3almeniyyeh) in Lebanon (for a stronger Country)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8186</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">359</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/NL/pz/kQ/CX/it/EX/nRmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
