<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dog fighting is an international problem and one that is close to many hearts. It is commonly described as a blood sport; the ''sport'' has many links to organised crime groups and drug trafficking. The matches can last for hours and other than the fact they take place in a pit 2 to 3 feet deep the rules are much the same as boxing. The dogs are matched by weight then provoked by their owners, standing safely behind a scratch wall, until the referee calls for the owners to &#8216;let go&#8217; upon which time the match will only finish when one of the competitors kills or is killed. Owners of fighting dogs who classify themselves as &#8220;professionals&#8221; have considerable knowledge of the blood lines, offspring of the more infamous blood lines can sell for 1000USD each. Once these dogs become champions in this underground colosseum of coerced aggression and barbarity, scars and wounds replace the normal glory and spoils of a conventional boxing match. The following extract is from an article describing the state of a Pit Bull after a bout in the New Orleans dog fighting circuit; &#8220;Her ears are chewed down to nubs, her skin is scarred and raw-looking, and she's got a baseball-sized abscess on her back, the result of her last bout. She slumps on the kennel's cement floor among piles of feces and scattered kibble crawling with ants.&#8221; The people who claim ownership of these poor creatures cannot receive punishment to even begin to parallel the incomprehensible savagery they commit. 

1. Increase policing of underground dog fighting

2. Bring more awareness to the cause

3. Increase penalties of captured owners</description>
  <mission>stop blood sports involving any breed dog.</mission>
  <name>Mates, not Gladiators.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8188</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7I/Mh/6O/P6/ca/2K/sE0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
