<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We all know that swim practices can get long and boring.  They are especially hard when you go through a whole set (or maybe the marathon) with a song stuck in your head...and its not usually a whole song either, usually its just a few lines from a song.  Although swimming is a great sport, it is times like these that I know everyone questions their commitment.  As a part of my campaign for student council secretary, my platform is that we need underwater speakers installed in the big pool at the YWCA.  A fellow member of student council (CJ: the elf) has researched these speakers and they are not too expensive.  Since they would probably only be used by the senior/platinum groups, those would be the groups that would have to fund the speakers.  I do not know how much everyone would have to pitch in, that is an issue for our treasurer/scientist (Maureen) to figure out.  So I am asking all of you to imagine a world where we could listen to our own music during sets (not Pete's easy listening, Oz's reggae, or Seth's indie-rock...unless we wanted to of course), a world where instead of humping each other during warm up with no beat, we will be accompanied by the sweet tunes of T.I. or my man Luda, instead of wallowing in self-pity because thats all there really is to do during endless sets, we can let Dierks Bentley or Keith Urban do it for us.  Join me, Peter Raffel: Student Council secretary, in my quest to make the Y, and your life, a better place. JOIN UWSY TODAY AND MAKE A DIFFERENCE IN YOUR LIFE AND THE LIVES OF OTHERS!!!

note: i am thinking about getting UWSY t-shirts and bumper stickers made...let me know if you are interested!!!

1. The boredom of swimming must end immediately.

2. Entertainment during practice is a universal right.</description>
  <mission>to convince the establishment that we need underwater speakers at the YWCA.</mission>
  <name>UWSY (Under Water Speakers at the Y)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8209</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vo/qj/1P/Ou/H5/5p/JojS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
