<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>During the last six years, my nation -The United States of America- has seen her status as the shining city on the hill fade away.  The rights of the average American are now jeopardized by things such as warrantless wiretaps, the USAPATRIOT act, as well as legal precedents being established in the treatment of accused American citizens such as Jose Padilla.  He might be guilty but we have denuded him of his 1sr, 4th, 5th, 6th, 8th, 10th, and 14th amendment rights.  We have a president who is on record as saying "don't throw the constitution in my face its just a goddamn piece of paper."  It is vital that we rediscover and return to our constitutional heritage.  

Our economy is on the brink of collapse as we have a national debt of nearly 10 trillion (in six years it has more than doubled) and we consistently have budget deficits.  Our trade deficits are terrible and the pitiful condition of our energy infrastructure and reliance on foreign oil is terrifying.  Furthermore illegal immigration remains a problem that will continue to harm both the immigrants and the working poor in America for years to come.

Our troops are sacrificed for wars that do not concern our national security.  They are misused for get rich quick schemes in Iraq instead of finding the bastards in Afghanistan responsible for 9/11.  What is worse is that according to an article on the AP yesterday they may be dying in Iraq fifty years from now.

So now we must decide as Americans if we want eternal and senseless war abroad and tyranny at home, or do we want something better.  Something that is our birthright as Americans.  Something sacred and true.  If you are like me then you want a restoration of the constitution as the supreme law of the land, you want a government that serves the people, a government that will focus on balancing the budget, and a government that will never ever send troops into harms way unless it is absolutely clear that America is under attack.  

1. Restore the Authority of the Constitution and Bill of Rights

2. End Government intrusion into the affairs of its private citizens

3. Stop torturing terror suspects because torture doesn't work and is absolutely un-American

4. Quit trying to be the world's policeman and only commit troops to battle when America is threatened

5. Do not use the War on Terror as an excuse to create despotism at home and imperialism abroad</description>
  <mission>save the republic from tyranny </mission>
  <name>Save the Republic</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/822</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">19</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DkK/fR7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
