<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>www.benamarbenatta.com

Mr. Benatta is a 33 year old Algerian citizen who trained as an aeronautical engineer. He came to North America to flee political persecution and threats to his life while serving in the Algerian Armed Forces. On September 5, 2001 Mr. Benatta crossed the border into Canada and claimed political asylum. His biggest fear was being returned to Algeria where he was certain to be tortured or killed for deserting the military. Canadian authorities put Mr. Benatta into immigration detention while they tried to ascertain his identity. 

While in Canadian custody and unbeknownst to Mr. Benatta, terrorists attacked the World Trade Centre in New York City and other targets on September 11, 2001. Without a hearing, without counsel and without conducting proceedings in his first language (French), Mr. Benatta was unceremoniously driven over the border in the back of a car by Canadian officials and handed over to U.S. officials on September 12, 2001. This was an illegal transfer and the beginning of a long nightmare for Mr. Benatta. Mr. Benatta was held in the Metropolitan Detention Centre in Brooklyn, New York, where he was treated as a suspect in the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks. He was beaten. He was abused. He was held in conditions that the United Nations described as torture. He was forgotten. Mr. Benatta was actually cleared of any terrorist activity by the FBI in November 2001; however, he was never told that he was cleared because he was being held incommunicado and did not have access to a lawyer. 

In all, Mr. Benatta, an innocent man, spent nearly FIVE years of his life in American prisons where he suffered serious abuse at the hands of his prison guards, which is documented by the U.S. Department of Justice. On July 20, 2006, Mr. Benatta was allowed to return to Canada to resume his claim for refugee status. His application is pending. He is trying to get his life back. 

1. We need answers. Who made the decision to put Mr. Benatta in the back of a car and illegally transfer Mr. Benatta to U.S. Officials on September 12, 2001? Mr. Benatta and Canadians alike need the truth.

2. We need change. The laws must change to protect vulnerable people like Mr. Benatta from this happening in the future. We are calling on the Government, as a first step, to implement the oversight recommendations from the Arar Commission.

3. Write to Public Safety Minister Stockwell Day demanding a public review at Sir Wilfrid Laurier Building, 13th Floor 340 Laurier Avenue West Ottawa, Ontario, K1A 0P8. 

4. Sign the Benatta petition here: http://www.thepetitionsite.com/1/canadians-need-the-truth-about-benatta </description>
  <mission>To demand a public review into the actions of Canadian officials in illegally transferring Benamar Benatta to U.S. officials on September 12, 2001.</mission>
  <name>Benatta Coalition for a Public Review</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8228</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">88</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/S3/Pm/iz/EV/HZ/st/vbaS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
