<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>  Acts of Violence or Neglect perpetrated against animals are considered animal cruelty. Some examples are overt abuse, dog fighting, cockfighting, and denying a companion animals the basic nessities of care, such as food,water,shelter, and love.
Animal Hoarding or Collecting!
  obessive/compulsive disorder in which an individualkeeps a large number of animals sometimes more than 100-in his/her home and neglectsto care for the animals and the homeenviroment "COLLECTORS" are usually in denial about this situationhoarding can be considered a crime...form of neglect.
Animal Welfare Act!
  This Act passed into law in 1966 that ensures that pets and animals used in research and for exhibition purposes are provided humanecare and treatment. This Act also assures the humane care and treatmentof animals during transportation in commence and outlaws the sale or use of animals who have been stolen.
Backyard Breeders!
  Dog owners who's pet either gets bred by accident, or who breeds on purposes to make extra money or example let children witness "the miracle of birth". The animals involved are usually not tested for genetic or health problems, and there usuallyis no thought to where pups will go.
Battery Cage!
  A wire cage , measuring no more than at time sixteen inches wide, in which four or five hens/cats or dogs are housed. These cages are lined in rows and stacked several times. This system has been outlawed by Countries in the European Union.
    This list of Animal Cruelty goes on:
debeaking/ declawing/ ear cropping/ tail docking/ and sooo much more. for more info see Animal Cruelty / glossary  canada

1. canada's animal cruelty must end now

2. Animal Rights

3. animals have feelings aswel</description>
  <mission>Help Save Our Fury Friends</mission>
  <name>Stop Animal Cruelty</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8243</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">88</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/mu/ZG/oR/kt/ow/Zc/zU5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
