<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Waukesha County Department of Health and Human Services is under pressure from the State of Wisconsin to reduce their budget in the 2007-2008 year. 

The Association for the Rights of Citizen's with handicaps (ARCh) is an organization that is supported by Waukesha County to spread the message of acceptance and tolerance. ARCh empowers children and adults with disabilities to realize their full potential in the community. "Prevention Awareness and Community Education" (PACE) is a program within ARCh that educates the Waukesha County residents on preventable causes of disabilities. Shaken Baby Syndrome, Fetal Alcohol Syndrome, Toxoplasmosis, and Lead Poisoning are all PREVENTABLE causes of disabilities among children.  ARCh spreads the message of these child safety issues so that they don't happen. 

In the budget cut ARCh would loose $19,000 of its crucial income, disabling the education that ARCh provides for its constituents.

ARCh provides pivotal education and makes an amazing difference in the community. By preventing a problem before it happens, lives are saved.

"For every $1 spent on prevention, $100 is saved somewhere else."

Please help ARCh by writing to your County Board Member encouraging them to continue their funding for the PACE program. 

This is the link to the County Board Members. Please find your region and write! Also you can send a letter to Dave Vrakas the County Executive, he's the head honcho-

http://www.waukeshacounty.gov/page.aspx?SetupMetaId=9822&amp;id=7514



1. Help ARCh make a difference, please write a letter.</description>
  <mission>Keep funding from the County to help make a difference in the community.</mission>
  <name>Save ARCh!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8245</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">128</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">65.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bg/E8/G5/HX/ix/rn/aiJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
