<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Old cultures die out as new cultures are born. The problem is we are being farmed for the next culture.  Cultures are not time tested, they are timed to expire.  Strategic planning goes in to making you believe that YOU have decided what you will do today.  Who decided you NEED to buy a house when you're 30?  Why do you NEED a $300 pair of pants? Where is it written that you NEED a brand new luxury edition SUV?

Lets take a minute to understand the links between corporations and their connecting companies.  Where the synergy begins and what kind of corporate wool covers consumer eyes.

We've heard about Old Navy, Gap, and Banana Republic.  Same with Coke, Sprite, and Fanta.  Corporate ties don't end there.  It's a pyramid of corporate ownership.

When Apple, Converse, Emporio Armaniv, Motorola, Gap Inc, and American Express started "(RED)" some thoughtlessly bought in, thinking they were truly contributing to the world.  That $199 iPod, where $10 went to help a cause was simple a tax deduction for the previously mentioned corporations. It is a donation from THEM, and not from you. "Designed to Help Eliminate AIDS in Africa" and fuel the idea that this group of corporations care, spreading the word that these corporation "help," stamping them with approval for future purchases. 

Wake up. Stop biting. Support small business. Make that tax deduction yours and donate DIRECTLY to causes or charity!

Our beneficiary is Mobilize.org, a group dedicated to educating the young on how public policy affects our lives.  Public policy is of course what regulates corporations and marketing.  Currently, most all media regulation is out-dated and in a preventative manor, those corporations have self-censored in order to avoid government regulation.

1. End excessively-profitable influence on culture.

2. End the buying of excessive amounts of unnecessary purchases.

3. Cultivate an awareness of the pervading influence of American culture on the globalized world

4. Stop relying on mainstream sources of information and media. The options are endless, the choice is yours.</description>
  <mission>End cultures being centered around corporate profits and a materialistic worldview that reduces us to mere consumers.</mission>
  <name>End the Commercialization of Culture!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8252</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">141</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/KI/8U/Ei/UW/Ww/2M/wy/L7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
