<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We Are the Revolution -W.A.R.-

-W.A.R. focuses on the younger voting blocs, mainly people between 18 and 30 years of age. 
-W.A.R.- This is a serious name for a serious cause. Being the future of this nation and being the main body which serves in our military, we are the ones who should bring about change. A revolution is defined in Webster's as 'a total change of conditions, or to effect an extreme change.' In 2008 there will be political conflict at home, and the revolution will be about young voters taking a large part in this.
-This is meant to be an unbiased information resource for people to learn about the Presidential Election of 2008. You may not agree with every party featured in this cause, but its necessary to provide the voter with information about all options
-It is aimed at boosting the political involvement of the younger voting generations. 
-This is not a means to promote a particular party, but to provide basic information about any and all parties involved in the election. 
-Remember, we are the future, we can bring change, We Are the Revolution

Some websites with Political information 
(these aren't in any specific order)
Voter Registration
https://www.govote.org
Do Something- voting website, helpful information
http://www.dosomething.org/
Guide to American Political Parties
http://www.politics1.com/parties.htm
Democratic Party
http://www.democrats.org/
Republican National Committee
http://www.gop.com/
Green Party of the United States 
http://www.gp.org/
Libertarian National Committee
http://www.lp.org/
America First Party
http://www.americafirstparty.org/
American Nazi Party
http://www.americannaziparty.com/
Communist Party USA 
http://www.cpusa.org/
Democratic Socialists of America 
http://www.dsausa.org/dsa.html
The Labor Party
http://www.thelaborparty.org/
U.S. Marijuana Party
http://www.usmjparty.com/
Libertarian National Socialist Green Party
http://www.nazi.org/

1. Increase voter turnout among young voters. 

2. Provide an unbiased source of political information.</description>
  <mission>To promote the politcal awareness of our generation in preparation for the 2008 Election</mission>
  <name>We Are the Revolution</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8255</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tt/LF/rB/tu/3w/zb/2PgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
