<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Smiles from Nicholas Foundation was started in remembrance of Nicholas Rydzynski, and his struggles with Cerebral Palsy and Pediatric Cancer. In his 4 short years, Nicholas endured so much, but endured with dignity, grace, courage and persistence that any would envy. His struggle ended on September 11th, 2006, after a 4 year struggle with Cerebral Palsy, and a 10 month battle with Neuroblastoma (Pediatric Cancer).
As parents, we hoped that everything that could be done to help Nicholas through his struggles, and save his life, was being done. We found out something very different during the struggles: the reality was we are in crisis mode. Not enough funding, not enough support, and not enough awareness is leaving CP and Pediatric Cancers behind. Little is being done to help kids with CP and Pediatric Cancer.
Smiles from Nicholas Foundation is growing into a national organization representing Cerebral Palsy and all Pediatric Cancers. One little boy brought these two issues to the forefront of our lives and the countless he touched in a very special way. Now it&#8217;s time to share his story, identify the problems, and do something about it for those that have been down the path as we have, those currently on their own journey, and those that will be touched by these journeys, and don&#8217;t even know it yet. In the name of one, in honor of thousands.



1. CP and Pediatric Cancer are two of the least funded challenges facing our kids! The result is limited advancements. CP has not had a significant advancement in decades. Pediatric Cancer has seen some improvements, but MORE is needed.

2. Pediatric Cancer is the number 1 disease killer of children in the United States. Only accidents cause more deaths. 

3. Currently, 800,000 Americans live with some form of Cerebral Palsy. That&#8217;s more than Multiple Sclerosis, Cystic Fibrosis, and Muscular Dystrophy COMBINED. </description>
  <mission>Provide knowledge, comfort and hope to families currently living through their Cerebral Palsy and Pediatric Cancer journeys as well as find cures.
www.smilesfromnicholas.org</mission>
  <name>Smiles From Nicholas</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8256</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">373</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oV/TL/YA/mS/Il/Ch/S5/K1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
