<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What the Memory Walk Does:     
    Memory walk, the national signature event of the Association, is the only national fundraising even for Alzheimer&#8217;s disease. Since its inception in 1989, Memory walk has raise more than $225 million for Alzheimer programs and services for individuals with Alzheimer's, their families and caregivers.
    Teams are our leading fundraisers. by joining forces with Memory Walk, your Team will join thousands of others across the country increasing the amount of funds available to fight Alzheimer's disease. Today more than 5.1 million Americans have Alzheimer's disease and this number is expected to grow to 16 million by the middle of this century. for most of them, the process that will destroy their memories. Their lives and their savings- has already begun.
    This is why your team&#8217;s support is so important. Funds raised through Memory Walk will remain in the local community and are used to create and maintain vital programs and services. The Alzheimer's Association is the premier source of information and support for the 5.1 million Americans with Alzheimer's disease, and through our national network of chapters, we offer a broad range of programs and services for people with the disease, their families and caregivers.

Why We Walk:
     Alzheimer's disease affects more than 5 million Americans and costs our nation more than $148 billion a year. Unless we find a way to change the course, as many as 16 million Americans could have the disease by 2050.

Join a Walk and Help Make a Difference in 2007:
    Because of people like you, the Alzheimer's Association memory Walk nationally raised 30.5 million dollars in 2006. Locally, we raised $455,000. Help us reach our local goal of $500,000 this year. 


1. I believe that a cure can be found within my life time.

2. It's a terriable disease that will effect more americans as the baby boomers age.

3. This disease robs the individual of their dignity.</description>
  <mission>TO eliminate Alzheimer's Disease through the advancemetn of resarch and to enhance care and support for individuals, their families and caregivers.</mission>
  <name>Alzheimer's association memory walk of 2007</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8259</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">76</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bF/jE/Vn/Gb/nQ/LL/JxeS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
