<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society is the world's largest voluntary health organization dedicated to funding blood cancer research, education, and patient services. 

I am training to participate in the Dublin Marathon in October 2007 as a member of The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society's Team In Training. All of us on Team In Training are raising funds to help stop leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin lymphoma and myeloma from taking more lives.

I'm completing this event in honor of my late grandfather, Irving Silverstein, who I lost to Lymphoma in 2001, as well as for all individuals who are battling blood cancers. These people are the real heroes on our team, and we need your support to cross the ultimate finish line - a cure!

Research is the key to finding a cure, and funding for this research is essential. I have set a personal goal to raise $5600 toward this effort.

As I run the 26.2 mile marathon, you will be with me in spirit, and your sponsorship will inspire me to run stronger and faster to the finish line. Suggested donation amounts are listed on this site, but whatever you can do to contribute matters&#8230;it all adds up! With over 75% of your donation going directly to research, you truly can make a difference.

Thank you so much for your support and generosity!

Please visit my website to make a donation to support my participation in Team In Training and help advance the Society's mission.

http://www.active.com/donate/tntepa/tntepaATwedda 

Also, please invite your friends to join this cause.



1. The Society has dedicated itself to being one of the top-rated voluntary health agencies in terms of dollars that directly fund our mission.</description>
  <mission>Cure leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin's disease and myeloma, and improve the quality of life of patients and their families.</mission>
  <name>The Leukemia and Lymphoma Society -- Team in Training</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8274</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/UV/Yb/3Q/Iq/8G/GU/rhHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
