<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Foundation will support:

The rebuilding of Marial Bai: This summer, Valentino will travel back to Marial Bai and begin work on a large complex there which will feature a school, a library, a women's center, a youth activity center, a community gathering center, and a sports program. 
College educations for Sudanese immigrants in America: As can be seen in Valentino's life, even with support networks, it's very difficult for Sudanese in America to attain college educations. The Foundation will help provide scholarships to aid the educational pursuits of Sudanese immigrants, and will assist programs that serve the Sudanase diaspora. 

THE REBUILDING OF MARIAL BAI

Valentino's hometown of Marial Bai, in the Northern Bahr al-Ghazal State of southern Sudan, was burned to the ground many times during the 20-year civil war between the government of Sudan and the Sudan People's Liberation Army. The perpetrators were the militiamen known as the murahaleen&#8212;the same militias (now called janjaweed) who currently terrorize Darfur. Since the signing of the peace accord between the government of Sudan (GOS) and the SPLA/M, there has been peace in southern Sudan, and this has allowed southerners to begin rebuilding. Valentino's hometown of Marial Bai is a regional trading center which attracts visitors from hundreds of miles around, and he seeks to make this town a center of learning as well. This summer, he will lay the groundwork for constructing a complex of buildings with the following components:

A Community Gathering Center

A Youth Resource Center

A Women's Educational Center

A Library

Sports Program

Make a donation!

Every purchase of What Is the What constitutes a donation to Valentino's foundation. Additional gifts can be made online:www.valentinoachakdeng.com

If you would like to mail your donation, tax-deductible checks can be sent to: 

The VAD Foundation
849 Valencia St.
San Francisco, CA 94110


1. Famine affects three million Sudanese</description>
  <mission>development of Marial Bai, Sudan</mission>
  <name>Valentino Achak Deng Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8283</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">69</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">192.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7h/ux/Md/1V/TX/iB/D5RS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
