<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>www.arizonamethproject.org/

Methamphetamine is a real and growing problem in Arizona. According to the 2006 Arizona Youth Survey, 4.3% of our state's youth ages 13-17, have tried Meth.

The ARIZONA METH PROJECT is a large-scale exercise in prevention, aimed at significantly reducing Meth use in Arizona. The integrated program consists of an ongoing, research-based marketing campaign, supported by community outreach and public policy initiatives, that realistically and graphically communicates the risks of methamphetamine to the youth of Arizona.

For more information about the ARIZONA METH PROJECT, please click here or dial:

Maricopa County: 602-372-METH
Outside Maricopa County: 1-866-773-8999

The prevention program, which was designed by the Meth Project, combines advertising with community-based programs and was started in Montana as the Montana Meth Project. The Montana Meth Project has demonstrated significant results in changing attitudes and behaviors towards Meth since its inception in 2005 and was recently cited as a model for the nation by the White House Office of National Drug Control Policy. The Meth Project is working with states across the nation interested in replicating the program as part of their efforts to reduce the prevalence of methamphetamine use.

For information about the Meth Project, please contact:

The Meth Project Foundation
Nitsa Zuppas, Executive Director
270 University Avenue
Palo Alto, CA 94301

Phone: 650-752-1000
Email: info@methproject.org

1. Significantly reducing Meth use in Arizona.

2. The hazardous and life-threatening consequences of methamphetamine use are clear, compelling, and undeniable.</description>
  <mission>To significantly reduce Meth use in Arizona.</mission>
  <name>The Arizona Meth Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8298</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">241</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Zo/PY/Rc/Cw/Ks/HK/cjES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
