<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>KFC suppliers cram birds into huge waste-filled factories, breed and drug them to grow so large that they can&#8217;t even walk, and often break their wings and legs. At slaughter, the birds&#8217; throats are slit and they are dropped into tanks of scalding-hot water&#8212;often while they are still conscious. It would be illegal for KFC to abuse dogs, cats, pigs, or cows in these ways.

KFC&#8217;s own animal welfare advisors have asked the company to take steps to eliminate these abuses, but KFC refuses to do so. Many advisors have now resigned in frustration.


Fill out the form below to request our pack of Kentucky Fried Cruelty campaign materials, which also includes general peta2 stickers and leaflets. If you have already requested campaign materials from PETA, please wait until you have received them and used them up before requesting more supplies. peta2's other packs include plenty of Kentucky Fried Cruelty campaign materials already. 

If you need campaign materials immediately, we suggest using our printer friendly "Kentucky Fried Cruelty" leaflets and our "Chicken Chumps" fliers. Also, if you just need some materials for yourself instead of materials to hand out to others, please request them here, and we can send you a more personalized pack. 


http://www.peta2.com/TAKECHARGE/t-kfccampaignlit.asp



Here's a video!

http://www.kfccruelty.com/

http://www.peta2.com/TAKECHARGE/undercover-georges/index.asp

http://www.covancecruelty.com/





Please Sign this petition, it takes only seconds

http://www.starconsultants.com/Alt/form2.html






1. STOP EATING AT KFC

2. SIGN A PETITION - GET ACTIVE- JOIN THE MAILING LIST ON PETA2.COM

3. MAKE A DIFFERENCE!</description>
  <mission>STOP THE CRUELTY AND TORTURE!!!!</mission>
  <name>STOP KFC!!!!!!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8302</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">74</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ke/Tt/t8/Fm/La/tQ/n2XS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
