<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Scientists have proven that moral emotions arise in a person before he is exposed to any sort of religious &#8220;handbook&#8221;. Thus, we find that in order for a person to be moral, he does not need a scripture for guidance. Compassion stems from non-believers everywhere. Doctors save lives in underdeveloped countries. Scientists dedicate their lives to finding cures for diseases. The majority of these people are secular; it seems they are helping people out of concern for their suffering, not because they believe God will reward them for it. Everyone can contribute in the nobly selfless ways in which these people, who recognize that we are both capable of and responsible for relieving humans of suffering, do. We should take the time to imagine living someone else&#8217;s life. Then we can understand that the problems in this world will more likely be cured through our faith in humanity, not in God. 
Put aside every racial, ethnic, and religious difference we have. We can all hate, hurt, and destroy. Thankfully, we can all also love, save, and nurture.  
 &#8220;Of the 25 most dangerous cities, 76% are in red states [dominated by conservative Christians], 24 % in blue states. In fact, 3 of the 5 most dangerous cities in the United States are in the pious state of Texas. The 12 states with the highest rates of burglary are red. 24 of the 29 states with the highest rates of theft are red&#8221; &#8211; Sam Harris, demonstrating the intimidating correlation between violence and religion
The existence of such dominant and intolerant religious doctrines has created a globally competitive atmosphere which continues to divide people who, at their cores, are remarkably similar. The clash of religions, which has negatively affected the world from a time before the Crusades to today, will only hinder the possibility for us to create a viable future for ourselves. The possibility that the world may change rests in our hands, not those of a supreme being.

1. Scientific rationality and religious faith are incompatible, and the denial of this certainty will continue to obstruct the progress of human civilization. 

2. We are blessed with the ability to communicate through words. Once humans learn to speak to each other about religion in an open, honest, and rational way, one of civilization&#8217;s greatest challenges will be overcome. 

3. This may be a step toward a universal appreciation of the supremacy of humanity and its power to beget positive change. 

4. We cannot only be &#8220;against&#8221; something. We need to be &#8220;for&#8221; something. Until we are &#8220;for&#8221; something, nothing can be accomplished.

5. In order to relieve our world of religious war, faith in reason and humanity must be strengthened.

6. &#8220;In all this vastness, who will come and save us? God? ..We have it within us to stop the destruction, preserve our environment, and cherish..the only home we&#8217;ve ever known&#8221; - inspired by the words of Carl Sagan 

7. (Donations will go to the Institute for Humanist Studies, which Richard Dawkins cites in his book The God Delusion as an organization in need of support)</description>
  <mission>To show that staunch religious believers express a dangerous intolerance of criticism and others&#8217; beliefs. To foster trust in the potential of the human race and fellow members of our global community</mission>
  <name>Faith in Humanity</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8305</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1512</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">235.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/T8/Lq/DF/4K/nX/j8/qosS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
