<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Animals have the right to a decent quality of life because they too share our planet with us.  

In George a local woman allegedly bribed two youths to hang her dog by offering these youths a packet of chips.  &#8220;The Police and the SPCA found the dead dog in a bushy area outside Zone 3, Thembalethu on Tuesday. 
The bitch had a rope around her neck and was swinging from a branch in the strong wind. 
Her paws were apparently hardly 10cm from the ground. 
An autopsy performed by the local vet, Dr Elke Schwellnus, showed the dog had sustained at least two skull fractures. 
She was allegedly beaten with a stick. 
Dog 'suffered terribly' according to Winnie Swanepoel, SPCA inspector and senior manager at the Garden Route SPCA in George, the dog suffered terribly. 
"It would seem as if she was strangled to death and that she died slowly. Her neck did not break with the hanging," she said. 
An elderly resident of Zone 3 told the SPCA and police on Tuesday the woman was punishing the dog for having killed her chickens. 
According to the elderly resident the woman used a packet of chips to bribe two boys to hang the dog for her. 

"The dog apparently did not want to go with the children, so the woman told them to hit her (the dog) across the back with an object like a stick," said Swanepoel. 
She said an elderly man tried to stop the children at a certain stage. 
Swanepoel added the bitch had probably given birth to a litter recently, as her breasts were swollen. 
Police spokesperson Captain Malcolm Pojie said nobody had been arrested in connection with the viciously cruel incident at the time Cape S*n went to press.&#8221; &#8221;

&#8220;The greatness of a nation and its moral progress can be judged by the way its animals are treated.&#8221;
Mahatma Ghandi.


1. South African laws need to recognise animals as beings.

2. Animals deserve to be treated with dignity and to live happy lives; it is within every human to give this to an animal.

3. Abusers need to stop living behind the face of our less than humane laws.</description>
  <mission>To make sure that South African animals are protected by the South African laws from abuse.</mission>
  <name>Stop Animal Cruelty in SA by Changing Our Laws.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8308</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1535</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Iq/WK/WH/j5/TU/g5/ERWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
