<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Amnesty International (AI) is a worldwide movement of people who campaign for internationally recognized human rights. 

AI&#8217;s vision is of a world in which every person enjoys all of the human rights enshrined in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and other international human rights standards.

In pursuit of this vision, AI&#8217;s mission is to undertake research and action focused on preventing and ending grave abuses of the rights to physical and mental integrity, freedom of conscience and expression, and freedom from discrimination, within the context of its work to promote all human rights.

AI is independent of any government, political ideology, economic interest or religion. It does not support or oppose any government or political system, nor does it support or oppose the views of the victims whose rights it seeks to protect. It is concerned solely with the impartial protection of human rights.

AI has a varied network of members and supporters around the world. At the latest count, there were more than 2.2 million members, supporters and subscribers in over 150 countries and territories in every region of the world. Although they come from many different backgrounds and have widely different political and religious beliefs, they are united by a determination to work for a world where everyone enjoys human rights.

AI is a democratic, self-governing movement. Major policy decisions are taken by an International Council made up of representatives from all national sections.

AI's national sections, members and supporters are primarily responsible for funding the movement. No funds are sought or accepted from governments for AI&#8217;s work investigating and campaigning against human rights violations. 

1. We need to protect the rights of the people</description>
  <mission>bring the world together</mission>
  <name>Amnesty International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8331</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">53</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2K/Zk/g0/bT/6v/US/RTyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
