<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This year, I have the honor and pleasure of participating in MDA's 2007 Utica Lock-Up to help "Jerry's Kids&#174;". To reach my goal I need your help! 

I'd like to include you or your company on my list of contributors who are helping me reach my goal. Your donation would help MDA continue the important fight against muscular dystrophy. Check out my web page by copying the link below. There you'll find all kinds of information about MDA, and be able to make your tax-deductible donation on-line using your credit card. 

MDA serves people in our community with neuromuscular disease by providing clinics, support groups, assistance with the purchase and repair of wheelchairs, braces and communication devices, and summer camp for kids. MDA also funds research grants to help find treatments and cures for some 43 neuromuscular diseases that affect people of all ages, right here in our community. 

I sincerely hope that you'll take the opportunity to support MDA. If you have any questions, please don't hesitate to call or e-mail me. 

On behalf of the families MDA serves, thank you! 

Warmest Regards, 

Andrew Bick

Copy and paste the address below into the address bar of your internet browser.

https://www.mdaevent.org/ParticipantInfo.aspx?j=a69c99a4-a1ae-4e22-8c41-eaa27ac2b99b

1. Researching Musculary Dystrophy can help develop effective treatments.

2. Treatment of Muscular Dystrophy can help prolong life.

3. Muscular Dystrophy Camp is a great place for kids with Muscular Dystrophy to enjoy life.</description>
  <mission>To raise money and awareness for Muscular Dystrophy Research.</mission>
  <name>Muscular Dystrophy Association 2007 Utica Lock-Up</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8347</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/z2/2q/ex/je/xO/FN/okfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
