<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Imperialism is the forceful extension of a nation's authority by territorial gain or by the establishment of economic and/or political dominance over other nations.

What would be of Africa, a once intellectually thriving continent,  if it wasn't for European colonization and destruction?

What would be of the Native Americans if it wasn't for European domination and genocide?

Civilization is subjective. Our understanding of civilization cannot be forced on other nations. What can now be referred to as the American Empire is doing just that:
Puerto Rico.
American Samoa.
Guam.
U.S. Virgin Islands.
Cuba.
South Africa.
Nicaragua.
East Timor.
Haiti.
Panama.
Afghanistan.

Iraq.

We must end America's imperialistic movements throughout the world and allow others to develop and grow without forceful intervention.

*Anyone may join the cause regardless of your nationality.

**Please take the time to read this essay (rather abstract) on historical and modern imperialism here, if you can:
http://docs.google.com/Doc?id=dcp7gknm_10d5qbbh


***All donations are received by the National Peace Institute Foundation.
From their website:
"NPFs programs are designed to support the development of a climate of understanding that the US has many options other than the use of its armed capacity in international conflict, and to promote international peace and the resolution of conflicts among nations without recourse to violence. " 







1. Imperialism is a violation of human rights and has historically led to mass genocide and destruction.

2. America must end its occupation and control over other nations.

3. Our idea of government, religion, culture, and way of life is not necessarily that of other nations, and it should not be forced on an unwilling people.</description>
  <mission>End Modern Imperialism</mission>
  <name>Americans Against American Imperialism</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8349</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">198</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/r3/RS/Zo/G2/oo/Ue/lscS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
