<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In 1999, the Phillips family of Atlanta formed the Nu&#231;i Phillips Memorial Foundation in memory of their 22-year-old son and brother Nu&#231;i, who in 1996 killed himself after a long battle with major depression. Nu&#231;i was a talented musician and a promising student at the University of Georgia in Athens. After his death, the family recognized the need for obstacle-free, user-friendly ways of treating and supporting those who suffer from depression and other such disorders. With a focus on Nu&#231;i's fellow musicians, the nonprofit Foundation created Nu&#231;i's Space.

It is a resource/support center dedicated to promoting the emotional, physical and occupational well-being of the music community. With a staff of four musicians, under the guidance of founder Linda Phillips, the center provides a stable, caring environment. For many, such an environment is all that is required to impart a sense of worth and validity. For others, additional help is needed. 

Nu&#231;i's Space is unique because of its simplicity and effectiveness. The musician is viewed as a whole entity to be nurtured. The physical benefits of the building itself are never separated from the emotional benefits. The supportive, accepting environment is key to the well-being of those who use the Space. Since opening its doors in September 2000, Nu&#231;i's Space has helped over 320 musicians receive professional counseling. But that number does not tell the complete story. For every one who has been helped in this manner, many others including family, friends, and community have benefited. 

Nu&#231;i's Space provides:

&#8226; Low cost mental health counseling referral service
&#8226; Inexpensive rehearsal facilities
&#8226; Performance area
&#8226; Coffee lounge
&#8226; Music/self-help library
&#8226; Music and health related workshops
&#8226; Support groups
&#8226; Volunteer physicians to treat minor illnesses of uninsured musicians
&#8226; Opportunities to educate and destigmatize mental illness not only in the music    community but in the community as a whole


1. Suicide Prevention 

2. Promoting the emotional, physical and occupational well-being of the music community.

3. Creating a positive environment for community health</description>
  <mission>Nuci&#8217;s Space aims to prevent suicide by providing free treatment for musicians suffering from depression as well as to assist in the emotional, physical and professional well-being of musicians.</mission>
  <name>Nuci's Space</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/835</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">107</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.2</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/dS0/75cS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
