<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A woman was telling coworkers about having breast cancer; the chemotherapy was beginning to make her lose her hair. She decided to have a laugh at the disease and get a Mohawk before all her hair fell out. They decided she didn't need to go through this alone and would get Mohawks with her. And also decided to see how much money people would give to see them punked out. In just a few days 33 people got Mohawks raising over $15,000 to find a cure for breast cancer!

And so began Hawk-A-Thon: Mohawks for a Breast Cancer Cure!

Join today in support of finding a cure for breast cancer. Recruit your friends, donate, and spread the word!

HERE'S HOW IT WORKS:
1. Add this Cause to your Facebook profile.
2. Set a goal -- say $500 or even $1,000!
3. Invite all your friends to make donations. 
4. Once you reach your goal, get a Mohawk
  and add your photo so everyone can see!
5. Then challenge one of your friends to a Hawk-a-Thon of their own!

All the money raised goes to the OHSU Cancer Institute, an international leader in cancers research, for finding a cure for breast cancer.

For more information visit www.Hawk-a-Thon.org, and join the Hawk-a-Thon Facebook group.

1. A cure for breast cancer is attainable. 

2. Medical breakthroughs at OHSU Cancer Institute have brought us closer to a cure for breast cancer than ever before.

3. When someone empathetically goes through the breast cancer treatment with a patient, it is as helpful in the healing as the medicine.

4. "Having her friends go on this journey with her will help as much as chemotheraphy - maybe even more," said a supporter of the first Hawk-a-Thon.

5. Hawk-a-Thon is rad fun!</description>
  <mission>Fund Research to Find a Cure for Breast Cancer</mission>
  <name>Hawk-a-Thon: Mohawks for a Breast Cancer Cure!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8385</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">306</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">471.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ox/13/Ws/3x/Zp/ZQ/3u6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
