<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our Firefighters

The Bolinas Volunteer Fire Department was founded in 1946. In 1954 it became a &#8220;special district&#8221;.  The Bolinas Fire Protection District firefighters provide fire, rescue, and emergency services to the 2,500 residents and visitors to Bolinas, a 10.5 square-mile territory spanning coastal Marin from Volunteer Canyon north to Dogtown. Our team of 16 first responders (six are staff and ten are volunteers) handle about 250 incidents a year.

The vast majority, a full 70% of the incidents, are medical emergencies, boat emergencies or automobile accidents, 10% are fires and the remaining 18% are trees or wires down, storm damage, citizen assists and false alarms. We average just about two fires per month. They call the helicopter in to transport a critically ill or hurt person about 6 times per year.

 

Our Clinic Team

Founded in 1983, the Bolinas Family Practice was already in existence before the Coastal Health Alliance was formed. The Bolinas Family Practice merged with Coastal Health Alliance (CHA) in 1992. CHA operates the Point Reyes Medical Clinic and the Stinson Beach Medical Clinic in addition to the Bolinas Family Practice Medical Center.

Our team of three part-time physicians, physician assistants, lab technicians and office staff work hard to keep Bolinas healthy.

In any given month the clinic has over 200 patients visits, with about 40% paying through private insurance, 34% paying a sliding scale, 16% through Medical, 8% paying through Medicare or a combination of Medicare and Private insurance

1. we live in a beautiful place

2. we're on our own in a big storm or fire, and we're miles from any hospitals

3. we need to provide necessary services to help in case of emergencies.</description>
  <mission>help ensure the safety of our town</mission>
  <name>Bolinas Firehouse and Clinic</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8386</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1F/FO/AU/oO/Ct/dy/Y4OS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
