<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Ishimwe" means "Give Him Praise and Thanks" in Kinyarwanda, the language of Rwanda.

The inspiration and vision for the Ishimwe Center started when Faith Shaw returned to her native land of Rwanda in 2000. She was broken-hearted by the sight of countless small children living in cardboard boxes on the street and fending for themselves. Faith and her husband Roger established the first Ishimwe Center home in 2004, the N'iwacu Rescue Home at Ruhengeri. Their vision has been to provide a place in which children rescued from desperate circumstances can grow in a safe and loving environment, attend school, and have a bright future. 

Please join the Ishimwe Center group on Facebook to learn about specific children who need your sponsorship: 
http://facebook.com/group.php?gid=2480876644

1. Child and baby care - many babies are thrown in the trash at birth or abandoned near hospitals. The police pick them up and take them to places like I

2. Youth supervision - our small children become teenagers and we will continue to look after them until they are ready to leave as adults.

3. Geriatric care for widows - since the Rwandan genocide, many widows are worse off when they find themselves without work or family to care for them. W

4. Education - school fees for desperately impoverished children such as those in the Kabuga Parish, just outside of Kigali</description>
  <mission>The aim of the Ishimwe Center is to create real and lasting hope for some of the most needy children and widows in Rwanda by the provision of family homes and by educational sponsorship programs.</mission>
  <name>Ishimwe Center - Rescue Home for Rwandan Orphans</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8391</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">371</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">536.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yD/s1/O2/6d/Cc/vP/ow/cnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
