<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Statement of Principles

     The International Society for Individual Liberty is an association of individuals and organizations dedicated to building a free and peaceful world, respect for individual rights and liberties, and an open and competitive economic system based on voluntary exchange and free trade. Members and affiliated organizations pursue these goals through independent action, using their freely chosen strategies. The association exists to promote the exchange of information and ideas, to study diverse strategies and to foster fellowship.

Freedom Through Education

     ISIL is a non-partisan educational foundation which is dedicated to building a worldwide grassroots movement for liberty. We realize that the principles of liberty must be understood and cherished by large numbers of ordinary people before any significant or lasting political change can occur.

     We provide support (contacts, books, literature) for libertarian activists in America and all around the world &#8211; with special sponsorship programs for individuals engaged in building new liberty movements in Third World countries and the former communist bloc. We also have sponsored many of these individuals to our world conferences, where they have gained contacts, ideas and inspiration.

1. To build a free and peaceful world through the ideals of free markets, social tolerance and individual responsibility.

2. To educate on the philosophy of libertarianism.</description>
  <mission>To build a free and peaceful world through the ideals of free markets, social tolerance and individual responsibility.</mission>
  <name>International Society for Individual Liberty</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8397</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">50</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">18.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eC/NA/eD/eZ/gI/ax/Uw8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
