<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>RESULTS is a nonprofit grassroots advocacy organization committed to creating the political will to end hunger and the worst aspects of poverty. RESULTS is committed to individuals exercising their personal and political power by lobbying elected officials for effective solutions and key policies that affect hunger and poverty.

RESULTS Educational Fund is committed to educating the public, the media, and leaders about issues related to poverty and hunger in the United States and abroad. We hold public forums, train citizens in democracy, hold media conference calls to share the latest information, and produce quality oversight research to determine the effectiveness of programs for the poor. RESULTS Educational Fund is a 501(c)(3), tax-exempt nonprofit organization.

The National Conference Call is held at 11:00am on the second Saturday of the month.  The location of the National Conference Call changes as different folks host the call.

In Seattle, the Education &amp; Action meeting is always held at 7:00pm on the Wednesday following the conference call (the Wednesday falling between the 12th and 18th of the month).  Meetings are held at Wallingford United Methodist Church (2115 N. 42nd Seattle, at 42nd and Bagley) because they generously make the space available to a secular (non-religious) organization like us.  In March and October, there is an optional potluck which begins at 6:15pm.

For more information:

Call Bob Dickerson at 206-285-0375. 



1. we can lobby officials for key policies that affect hunger and poverty.

2. we can affect the public thru media, such as editorials and forums.</description>
  <mission>Creating the public and political will to end hunger and the worst aspects of poverty.</mission>
  <name>RESULTS - Seattle Chapter</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8399</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/H0/jN/b7/OL/S5/vS/NO3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
