<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>   Especially during times of war, Israel has mercilessly abducted tens of thousands of innocent civilians, holding them without trial, particularly Palestinians and South Lebanese. These people are not aware of what crime they committed, and families are protesting to no avail to find out the fate of their loved ones.

    Groups like Hizbollah have formed through disaffected Lebanese whos families have been captured, property seized or destroyed, and lives ruined. The only thing they had in common with anyone were fellow Lebanese in this situation. If you want these people to stop fighting Israel, then give them a reason to.

  Recently, 256 Palestinians out of the thousands were released as a 'gift' to support the Fatah administration. What kind of sick joke is this? The fact that they were released proves their innocence, but now Israel is holding these people as bargaining chips despite their innocence? Get a clue, these people have lives of their own, families of their own. The blood of a Palestinian is equal to the blood of an Israeli. End this disgusting tactic, especially on the massive scale Israel has employed it.

UPA is a humanitarian non-political organization with a mission to alleviate the suffering of Palestinians. United Palestinian Appeal does not endorse this cause and is in no way responsible for its content.

1. Extradite Lebanese civilians abducted without trial since the first Israeli-Lebanese war.

2. Either charge the prisoners with their alleged crimes or release them posthaste.

3. End the policy of mass abduction justified by times of war.</description>
  <mission>Release the Innocent Palestinian and Lebanese Civilians Abducted by Israel in the last 20 years.</mission>
  <name>Free the Innocents Locked Away in Israeli Dungeons</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8402</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">244</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/w2/mO/uX/nq/0t/FZ/4QtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
