<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>American Friends of Magen David Adom- AFMDA is celebrating its 70th year of supporting Magen David Adom, Israel's equivalent to the Red Cross.

Today, MDA and its team of trained volunteer and professional medical responders depend on AFMDA support to provide the entire nation&#8217;s pre-hospital emergency needs, including medical, disaster, ambulance and blood services. The MDA National Blood Services Center, located in Ramat Gan, provides 100% of the blood requirements of the IDF and 95% of the blood needs for Israeli hospitals and the general population.

* Magen David Adom (MDA) and its team of trained volunteer and professional medical responders provides the entire nation's pre-hospital emergency medical needs, including disaster, ambulance and blood services.

* AFMDA raised over $32 million to build the MDA National Blood Services Center in Ramat Gan. This institution ensures that Israel's healthcare providers have enough blood to save lives: MDA provides 100% of the blood requirements of the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) and 95% of the blood needs of Israeli hospitals and the general population.

* In the past five years, AFMDA raised over $90 million to purchase medical supplies and ambulance for MDA in Israel.

* AFMDA provided 110 ambulances to MDA Israel in 2004, of which 49 were specially equipped MICU's (Mobile Intensive Care Units).

* In 2003, AFMDA sent 99 ambulances to MDA Israel, including 22 MICU's and 7 Blood Mobiles.

* Thanks to AFMDA supporters, 700 MDA ambulances travel over 5.25 million miles a year taking care of more than 325,000 patients annually.

* MDA answers calls for all types of accidents, medical emergencies and terror attacks.

* MDA has over 100 Emergency Medical Stations and 11 dispatch stations in communities throughout Israel. Many of these have been built or upgraded by American Friends of Magen David Adom.

Contact us at:
352 Seventh Avenue,
 Suite 400, NY, NY 10001


1. AFMDA is a tax exempt organization under Section 501 (C) (3) under the Internal Revenue Code. Our Federal tax ID number is 13-1790719. AFMDA is the on

2. WWW.AFMDA.ORG</description>
  <mission>SUPPORT MAGEN DAVID ADOM</mission>
  <name>American Friends of Magen David Adom (AFMDA)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8403</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">435</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">628.32</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Am/DO/sr/ey/Qs/jU/iR/6uS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
