<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For the past year all of us have been working to make Little Full Cry a great place for NVTRP &#8211; painting fences and sheds, moving and organizing equipment, renovating and furnishing the office. The amount of love and sweat equity that the staff and volunteers have poured into Little Full Cry is immeasurable! Our horses know its home too &#8211; each time one of them lays in the field fronting Clifton Road, basking in the noonday sun, we&#8217;re reminded how much each enjoys the expanse of the open pastures at Little Full Cry.  It&#8217;s Home!

So now the journey continues. No time to rest on our laurels. Our goal now is to raise funds in the next 2-3 years to buy the remaining 11.5 acres of the farm and build andindoor. The Board had developed a wonderful vision for what NVTRP can be once the program owns the entire farm. One day:

 - NVTRP will offer not only therapeutic riding and hippotherapy, but also aquatic therapy with an office and therapy room for a full time physical and occupational therapist

 - There will be an indoor arena so that lessons can be provided throughout the year

 - Siblings will be able to play on playground equipped for use by children with disabilities

 - Some of our teen riders may be able to have an internship with NVTRP to gain valuable work experience in a supportive environment

 - Parents will have an indoor sitting room to share conversation, have a coffee or just a quiet moment

 - NVTRP will host special workshops and conferences on issues of interest to our rider families, our staff and volunteers

1. NVTRP has been serving the community for 29 years but has never had a permanent home.

2. By purchasing Full Cry Farm, NVTRP will be able to serve people with disabilities in the community for years to come.

3. It&#8217;s Peaches 30th Birthday Wish! (she&#8217;s turning 30 in 2010)</description>
  <mission>Donate to her forever farm for Peaches and her Pony Pals at Northern Virginia Therapeutic Riding Program in Clifton, Virginia</mission>
  <name>Peaches 30th Birthday Wish!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8420</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">131</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">267.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pN/3O/ZU/ly/Yr/pT/Ld/dES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
