<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Being diagnosed with heart disease can be a difficult time for you and your family.Your heart is a muscle that gets energy from blood carrying oxygen and nutrients. Having a constant supply of blood keeps your heart working properly. Most people think of heart disease as one condition. But in fact, heart disease is a group of conditions affecting the structure and functions of the heart and has many root causes. Coronary artery disease, for example, develops when a combination of fatty materials, calcium and scar tissue (called plaque) builds up in the arteries that supply blood to your heart (coronary arteries). The plaque buildup narrows the arteries and prevents the heart from getting enough blood. Stroke is the fourth leading cause of death in Canada. Each year, about 16,000 Canadians die from stroke. Each year, more women than men die from stroke.There are between 40,000 to 50,000 strokes in Canada each year. For every 10,000 Canadian children under the age of 19, there are 6.7 strokes. About 300,000 Canadians are living with the effects of stroke. After age 55, the risk of stroke doubles every 10 years. A stroke survivor has a 20% chance of having another stroke within 2 years. Of every 100 people who have a stroke 
15 die (15%) 10 recover completely (10%) 
25 recover with a minor impairment or disability (25%) 40 are left with a moderate to severe impairment (40%) 10 are so severely disabled they require long-term care (10%)
Stroke costs the Canadian economy $2.7 billion a year. The average acute care costs is about $27,500 per stroke Canadians spend a total of 3 million days in hospital because of stroke.




1. we need 2 help out anyway we can</description>
  <mission>Help people with  heart disease </mission>
  <name>Heart Disease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8422</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">81</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7N/1g/L1/QK/NW/rE/ZUAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
