<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Ask any young person in Cameroon if they could have one wish, and there is only one answer: &#8220;To go to school.&#8221; 

&lt;P&gt;Unfortunately, so many things get in the way of this wish. A boy&#8217;s mother dies of AIDS and his grandmother, who is now taking care of him, can&#8217;t afford the books and uniforms to send him to primary school. A young woman who wants nothing more than to become a nurse knows that her widowed mother does not have the means to put her through school. A young man forced to drop out of college to support his family when his father died, dreams of getting his Master&#8217;s degree in environmental science in order to engineer solutions to address malnutrition in Cameroon.

&lt;P&gt;These are just some of the intelligent, motivated young people Opportunity Africa has been able to help achieve their dreams. Opportunity Africa knows that the education of an individual in a developing country creates a ripple effect. An educated individual provides increased economic opportunities for their family. A family that doesn&#8217;t have to worry where they are going to get their next meal can work harder at their jobs with fewer days off from illness and children can concentrate and succeed in school. Stable families create stable communities. It starts with one, but the education of an individual benefits their family, their village, and eventually, their country.

1. Education is a basic human right for everyone, regardless of a person's race, gender, or socioeconomic status.

2. Education reduces poverty and improves health outcomes for individuals and their families.

3. Education creates stronger communities with the resources to end hunger, conflict, and poverty in Africa.</description>
  <mission>To enable Cameroonian students to achieve their educational dreams in order to overcome poverty and improve health outcomes for the whole country.</mission>
  <name>Opportunity Africa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8427</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">393</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1A/G1/42/IB/SJ/2Q/62/eoS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
