<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is a "restorative practice"?  In general, it is a way of approaching breaches of covenant,community and relationship that emphasizes restoration of:
     *dignity
     *productive membership
     *power
     *safety
     *relationship

Restorative practices are used in criminal justice to assist offenders in making amends to their victims, victims in confronting their offenders and all parties in moving past the event toward places of dignity, safety, power and constructive roles in their communities and families.

In schools, restorative practices are employed to combat bullying, hate-based harrassment and other breakdowns in student relations.

In families, restorative practices are used to help families work with public systems who are overseeing the care and protection of their children, such as the child welfare, juvenile justice and mental health systems.

Restorative practices run the gamut from the small scale (e.g., a family with a child in the child welfare system) to the very large (e.g., the Truth and Reconciliation Commission of South Africa).

At CFRP, we offer family group conferencing, victim-offender conferencing, dialogue and reconciliation, wraparound and other collaborative and restorative alternatives to traditional and institutional services.

While some methods may appear, on their face, as therapy or mediation, restorative practices are at their core political.  Individuals are treated as citizens with rights and responsibilities.  Peace and justice are sought by engaging those persons and groups most directly concerned, rather than relying on experts and enforcers.

We are dedicated to developing these sorts of methods and advocating for social justice for all.  

Our office is based in San Rafael CA and work primarily in Marin County, but offer services, training and consultation regionally and nationally.

1. Justice is relational, between people and comes when harms are amended and people are restored to healthy, productive roles in their community, family, society.</description>
  <mission>"...to develop, implement and study collaborative and restorative processes for use by families, communities and organizations in the service of social justice.&#8221;</mission>
  <name>"...in the service of social justice"</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8446</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">22</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">60.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kY/kO/ig/TH/nR/0K/DGOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
