<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> There are many terrifying realities that force countless children onto the streets: domestic violence, being orphaned or abandoned, or simply belonging to dysfunctional families.

For most, there is no way back.

Task Brasil Trust was established in the UK in 1992 in response to the situation of the street children of Brazil. Its projects improve the lives and support the needs of children and pregnant girls living on the streets.

Since its establishment as a charity in the UK in 1993, Task Brasil Trust has come a long way in helping the street children of Rio de Janeiro. In the early days, Ligia Da Silva (Founding Trustee) and her supporters began by trying to make contact with children on the streets, assisting poor families who were not able to provide for their children and helping young people, against all the odds, to receive a reasonable education.

Task Brasil was given an enormous boost in 1997 with a very generous donation by Jimmy Page, the Led Zeppelin rock icon, who witnessed first hand the deprivation of the children and troubles in the favelas whilst playing in Rio de Janeiro. The money donated was used to buy a plot of land in Santa Teresa with a house, Casa Jimmy, to provide a safe and happy home for a lucky few of the abandoned children.

Casa Jimmy has now been running for over 8 years, helped by a talented team of childcarers, psychologists, administrative staff and volunteers from both Brazil and around the world. Over 340 children, teenage mothers and their babies and their families have benefited from the facilities funded partly by the Prefeitura of Rio de Janeiro and largely by private donations. More recent donations have funded the purchase of land neighbouring Casa Jimmy providing housing for volunteers and land for a future project "Casa Charlotte" which will provide a home for teenage mothers and their babies independent from Casa Jimmy. 

1. Improving the lives and supporting the needs of children and pregnant teenage girls living on the streets of Brazil.

2. Helping young people, in Brazil, against the odds to receive a reasonable education.

3. Facilitating development and increasgin self confidence in children living on the streets in Rio centre.</description>
  <mission> Task Brasil acts to advance the education and well-being of impoverished children in Brasil."</mission>
  <name>Task Brasil</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8465</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">104</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">183.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kg/Hs/zx/D4/B0/Ly/Z43S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
