<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Crohn's and Colitis Foundation of America is a non-profit, volunteer-driven organization dedicated to finding the cure for Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis. CCFA was founded in 1967 by Irwin M. and Suzanne Rosenthal, William D. and Shelby Modell, and Henry D. Janowitz, M.D. 

Four decades ago, CCFA created the field of IBD research. Today, the foundation funds cutting-edge studies at major medical institutions, nurtures investigators at the early stages of their careers, and finances underdeveloped areas of research. Educational workshops and symposia, together with our scientific journal, Inflammatory Bowel Diseases, enable medical professionals to keep pace with this rapidly growing field. No wonder the National Institutes of Health has commended CCFA for "uniting the research community and strengthening IBD research."

1. Working with the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to examine the coverage standards of Medicare and Medicaid for therapies that IBD patients need to maintain their health, as well as the challenges IBD patients encounter when applying for Social Sec

2. Testifying before the House Health and Human Services Appropriations Subcommittee in support of annual increases in funding for IBD research at the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the CDC.

3. Collaboration with other organizations such as the National Colorectal Cancer Roundtable and the Digestive Disease National Coalition (DDNC) to increase awareness of the importance of screening for colon cancer and to advocate for the rights to specialty </description>
  <mission>To cure and prevent Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis through research, and to improve the quality of life of people affected by these digestive diseases.</mission>
  <name>Crohn's and Colitis Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/847</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2802</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1257.21</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/KsR/URwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
