<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>North Shore Animal League America is the world's largest no-kill animal rescue and adoption shelter.  Here's a quote from their mission statement: "Across the country, we rescue, nurture and restore pets to happy and healthy lives in loving homes. To date, we have rescued close to 1 million dogs, cats, kittens and puppies."

A big part of NSALA is their "Help Me Heal" program, which asks for donations from charitable people to help fund life-saving operations and other medical care for hurt, sick, and abused animals.  Pictured to the right is a kitten named Sweet William that was recently rescued by the NSALA after apparently being hit by a car; he's suffering from head trauma, eye problems, lung bruises, a pelvic fracture, and two broken legs, as well as anemia, an upper respiratory infection, internal parasites and fleas.  Because of NSALA's Help Me Heal program and it's generous supporters, he will probably be able to live a normal life.  Visit &lt;a href="http://www.nsalamerica.org/campaigns/sweet-william/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.nsalamerica.org/campaigns/sweet-william/&lt;/a&gt; to read his story.  He is just the latest animal spotlighted in this program, and he's certainly not the only one benefited by it.  Please support this fantastic organization by donating, spreading the word, adopting a new pet, volunteering, or any other way you can think of to help!

1. No-kill shelters give every animal a second chance.

2. Every animal deserves a second (and a third, and a fourth...) chance.

3. It's up to us to help these poor, suffering animals to live a happy and healthy life.</description>
  <mission>raise awareness and, more importantly, funds for NSALA, the world's largest no-kill animal rescue and adoption center. </mission>
  <name>Help Them Heal!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8471</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">30.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Un/5c/7b/fO/VP/Xy/5F7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
