<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Let's assume that 20% of Canadians give blood. That's 6,000,000 people. Of those 6,000,000, approximately 10% will be gay or lesbian. That's 600,000.

One blood donation can save up to four lives. In an absolute extreme situation, 600,000 donations could save 2,400,000 lives. Donating twice a year, that total doubles to 4,800,000 lives.

That's almost 5 million people that could have been saved, if only the gay and lesbian population of Canada were able to donate blood. Let's bring it a little closer to home, shall we?

A baby, improperly strapped into a carseat, is in a severe accident, and requires blood.

A young girl is being treated for Leukemia, and requires blood.

A young man in highschool is injured in sports, and urgently needs blood.

A mother is experiencing complications while giving birth. She needs blood.

A blue-collar dad is injured in the workplace. He needs blood.

An aunt or uncle is undergoing a transplant due to a genetic illness. Guess what? They need blood.

A grandmother slips in the winter in her driveway and suffers internal trauma. She could very well need blood.

How many of these accidents and terrible circumstances have you seen happen? How many people do you know have died because of accidents like this? Because of blood shortages?

Why can't gays donate? Because they -MIGHT- have HIV or AIDS.

First off, ANYONE can have HIV, male or female, gay or straight. So, logically, that should elimate the entire population from donating blood. Fair is fair, right?

HIV and AIDS are no longer "gay" diseases. The entire population is at risk. It's time Canadian Blood Services acknowledges this fact and stops discriminating, and yes, this is in fact discrimination.

How many people have to die before something changes? 

1. Equality in the healthcare system

2. The end of sexual discrimination

3. Pure and simple, saving lives.</description>
  <mission>Save lives no matter who you are</mission>
  <name>Support Gay Blood Donation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8489</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">103</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zH/Ks/ev/v4/Zc/Ia/ubNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
