<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> 

Scleroderma, or systemic sclerosis, is a chronic connective tissue disease generally classified as one of the autoimmune rheumatic diseases.
View scleroderma images

The word &#8220;scleroderma&#8221; comes from two Greek words: &#8220;sclero&#8221; meaning hard, and &#8220;derma&#8221; meaning skin. Hardening of the skin is one of the most visible manifestations of the disease. The disease has been called &#8220;progressive systemic sclerosis,&#8221; but the use of that term has been discouraged since it has been found that scleroderma is not necessarily progressive. The disease may take several forms which will be explained later. There is also much variability among patients.

What scleroderma is not

Scleroderma is not contagious, it is not infectious, it is not cancerous or malignant.

How serious is scleroderma?

Any chronic disease can be serious. The symptoms of scleroderma vary greatly from individual to individual, and the effects of scleroderma can range from very mild to life-threatening. The seriousness will depend on what parts of the body are affected and the extent to which they are affected. A mild case can become more serious if not properly treated. Prompt and proper diagnosis and treatment by qualified physicians may minimize the symptoms of scleroderma and lessen the chance for irreversible damage.

How is scleroderma diagnosed?

The diagnostic process may require consultation with rheumatologists (arthritis specialists), and/or dermatologists (skin specialists) and require blood studies and numerous other specialized tests depending upon which organs are affected.

My father has scleroderma so I decided to do the walk to find a cure. If you would like to donate to my site directly. the link is : http://www.firstgiving.com/Loveandhopeforall

1. The disease is uncommon and not many people are aware of what it is.  

2. People suffer everyday and the cause goes unknown.

3. Together we can make a difference and find a cure. </description>
  <mission>help to find a cure and raise awareness about scleroderma</mission>
  <name>Scleroderma</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/849</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">474</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">474.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2Ba/EBWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
