<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In countries across Asia, thousands of bears live a life of torture on bear farms, so that their bile can be extracted and used in Traditional Medicine to cure ailments ranging from headaches to haemorrhoids. Bears are confined in cages which vary from agonisingly tiny "crush" cages to larger pens, all of which cause terrible physical and mental suffering. But their torment does not end there.....the bears are subjected to painful methods of bile extraction which involve crude surgery to implant a steel catheter into the abdomen or the creation of a permanent hole in the abdomen known as the "free-dripping" technique. Many bears die as a result of the unsanitary surgery and those that survive spend the rest of their lives suffering in pain and deprivation. Whilst the methods of farming bears for their bile vary across Asia and are continually 'evolving', ALL of them are incredibly cruel and totally unacceptable. 


Since 1993, the Animals Asia team have been working with dedication on projects to end bear farming. The Foundation will continue to work with government departments and local communities in Asia on programmes helping to reduce the suffering of captive bears. They will continue negotiations to rescue and rehabilitate bears from farms, and to keep their wild counterparts where they belong - in the wild. To this end, AAF is co-sponsoring the first comprehensive, scientific bear population density survey in Sichuan Province in order to determine the true number of bears in the wild in Sichuan.

1. Bear bile farms are extremely cruel and must end</description>
  <mission>Help spread awareness about bear bile farms and raise money for 'Animals Asia Foundation'.who rescue and rehabilitate the bears </mission>
  <name>HELP END BEAR BILE FARMS</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8502</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">22091</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">4115.43</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/rs/M6/Zg/gS/d1/EJ/IOwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
