<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A BRIEFING...
Lineup: 
Johnny Rotten (John Lydon) &#8211; vocals 
Steve Jones &#8211; guitar 
Glen Matlock &#8211; bass (1975-1977, 1996-) 
Sid Vicious (John Simon Ritchie) &#8211; bass (1977-1978) 
Paul Cook &#8211; drums
The Early Days: 
Although the foundations of the Sex Pistols began in 1972, when Steve Jones and Paul Cook started playing together, and later with Glen Matlock, it was a fateful day in 1975 when Johnny Rotten walked into Malcolm McLaren's clothing boutique, SEX. Rotten was wearing a homemade "I Hate Pink Floyd" t-shirt. 

He was asked to audition by singing along to "Eighteen" by Alice Cooper. He passed the audition, and the band was formed.

Hello EMI: 
After just a handful of live performances, the band was signed to the major label EMI for a very large advance. The Sex Pistols released their first single, Anarchy in the UK, and began to command the attention of England. 
The attention was rarely positive. It was during this time that the band caused a massive public uproar after uttering obscenities on a live television talk show, which lead to the show's eventual cancellation.

It's good to see that the "cultured elite" are starting to recognize the contribution that punk has made to culture. On the cultural front, punk has always about making a stand. Whether it's music, art or literature, punk is being invited into places it formerly wasn't welcome. 



1. TO BE INDIVIDUAL AND NEVER CONFORM

2. fight for your rights, speak your mind but betrue to yourself

3. ALWAYS OPPOSE ALL THAT U BELIEVE TO BE WRONG</description>
  <mission>KEEP THEIR MEMORY ALIVE</mission>
  <name>REMEMBER THE SEX PISTOLS?</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8508</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">297</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/CC/Ui/1e/44/6R/rX/GHsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
