<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> Recently, a very serious problem has been brought to the attention of several members of cafemom. It is a very heinous website called www.puellula.com. This website is a safe haven for pedophiles. The heading on their main page reads, "A Celebration of the Splendor of Little Girls". This website includes links to pictures, or "art" as they call it, of little girls, confessional blogs, a directory of resources for pedophiles (for "both boylovers and girl lovers, as well as anybody else looking for information about pedophilia and consensual child love"), as well as many other links. This site has a manifesto, stating demands to the government to legalize pedophilia.

The most disturbing, though, is a link to a page title Sugar and Spice that is specifically for little girls who have "fallen in love" with a pedophile. This site is set up to draw in little girls. It looks like any other fun little girly page. It tells girls that it is okay to be "in love" with an adult, and it is okay to have sex with an adult. A quote from the page: "Remember that information helps you to make the choices that are right for YOU. Don't let other people think for you, YOU know yourself better than anybody else, so YOU should be the one to decide whom to love and how to use your mind and your body." It has a questions and answers section, downloads, and a page to links for more information.

If you agree that things like this should be outlawed, stopped, and shutdown with serious penalties (I'm thinking execution) please sign your name below and pass this on. People from all over the world can sign this petition, so now is our chance to make a change and do something that is right and good for all of the planet. This cannot be allowed to continue.



Please sign here:

http://www.thepetitionsite.com/takeaction/968550862

Thanks!


PLEASE MAKE SURE YOU SIGN THE PETITION!

1. These type of sites encourage pedophilia.

2. Do you think it's ok for adults to have intimate relations with a child?</description>
  <mission>shut down "legal" pedophile websites</mission>
  <name>Save Our Children</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8511</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">28</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gF/2F/7u/7Y/Xm/Dx/h2YS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
