<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Fighting for a Cure!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

For the past two years I have participated as a Crew member for the Avon Walk for Breast Cancer. This year I decided to become a Walker. This coming October I will commit to walk 39 miles in two days to raise money and awareness for this important cause. However, in order to become a walker, I have to raise a minimum of $1800. I am reaching out to you for your support.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Your donations, whether it be $15 or $50, will help make such a difference in the lives of those who are battling this disease. Your contribution will help to support medical research, education and early detection programs, and clinical care and support services for women with breast cancer in communities across the country.  There is a special focus on helping medically underserved women, the poor, minorities, the elderly, or those with inadequate health insurance.  And much of the money granted by the Foundation goes back to the communities where it was raised, supporting everything from local grassroots programs to national organizations.   
&lt;br&gt;
It is faster and easier than ever to support - you can make a donation online by simply clicking on the link at the bottom of this message.  Whatever you can give will help! 
&lt;br&gt;
Thank you for your support!
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;font color=fushcia&gt;To donate online directly through the Avon Walk Foundation,&lt;A HREF="http://info.avonfoundation.org/site/TR?px=1651534&amp;pg=personal&amp;fr_id=1285&amp;s_tafId=192473 "&gt;click here&lt;/A&gt;


1. To find a cure for breast cancer

2. To help those suffering from breast cancer</description>
  <mission>Raise money to increase awareness of and fund research for breast cancer</mission>
  <name>New York Avon Walk for Breast Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8531</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">75.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6Z/yr/HF/Q7/PX/IT/BH1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
