<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hi Friends

It is with great sadness that Doctors For Life International (DFL) notes the tenth anniversary of the legalization of abortion-on-demand. The current count of victims of this law amounts to more than 550 000 babies dead, thousands of women suffering from Post Abortion Syndrome and the intimidation of countless health workers refusing to participate in the atrocity of abortion.

Despite the growing amount of medical evidence supporting the humanity of the unborn child, the Department of Health continues its policy in support of abortion-on-demand. Abortion is the destruction of those who cannot defend themselves, an extreme manifestation of the strong victimizing the weak.

Apart from the destruction of human life, abortion also poses some serious health risks to the mother of the unborn child. Studies show that 25% of women suffer from Post Abortion Syndrome - a serious condition marked by sleep disorders, flashbacks and chronic depression, which can lead to suicide. Inherent in abortion are also the increased risks of contracting breast cancer and having problems with future pregnancies and childbearing

In 2006 DFL successfully challenged an amendment to the Abortion Law in the Constitutional Court. As a result Parliament must now consult with the public when reconsidering the legislation. It is expected that public hearings will be held throughout South Africa before the end of the year.

In the light of the grave consequences of abortion, DFL calls on government to reconsider its position on abortion DFL also calls on Parliament to recognize ethical dilemmas surrounding abortion when it amends the law later this year.

DFL is an association of more than 1300 medical doctors and professors. Since 1991 DFL has been active in emphasizing the scientifically proven humanity of the unborn child, as well as providing assistance to women with unwanted pregnancies.

www.doctorsforlifeinternational.com
and
www.p4life.co.za


1. Stop all forms of abortion.

2. a Fetus is a baby and has life!

3. We say "Save Mother Earth" but we kill our babies. Join us to raise a Voice!</description>
  <mission>Stop the sensless killing of innocent little babies! The question is: do we have the right to decide who lives and who not? Sorry, the role GOD is already taken up.</mission>
  <name>Stop Abortion!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8541</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9529</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wd/x5/XB/eG/LR/TG/z2/r5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
