<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Rotary is a worldwide organization of business and professional leaders that provides humanitarian service, encourages high ethical standards in all vocations, and helps build goodwill and peace in the world. Approximately 1.2 million Rotarians belong to more than 32,000 clubs in more than 200 countries and geographical areas.

The main objective of Rotary is service &#8212; in the community, in the workplace, and throughout the world. Rotarians develop community service projects that address many of today's most critical issues, such as children at risk, poverty and hunger, the environment, illiteracy, and violence. They also support programs for youth, educational opportunities and international exchanges for students, teachers, and other professionals, and vocational and career development. The Rotary motto is Service Above Self.

Although Rotary clubs develop autonomous service programs, all Rotarians worldwide are united in a campaign for the global eradication of polio. In the 1980s, Rotarians raised US$240 million to immunize the children of the world; by 2005, Rotary's centenary year and the target date for the certification of a polio-free world, the PolioPlus program will have contributed US$500 million to this cause. In addition, Rotary has provided an army of volunteers to promote and assist at national immunization days in polio-endemic countries around the world.

1. FIRST. The development of acquaintance as an opportunity for service;

2. SECOND. High ethical standards in business and professions, the recognition of the worthiness of all useful occupations, and the dignifying of each Ro

3. THIRD. The application of the ideal of service in each Rotarian's personal, business, and community life;

4. FOURTH. The advancement of international understanding, goodwill, and peace through a world fellowship of business and professional persons united in </description>
  <mission>The mission of Rotary International is to support its member clubs in fulfilling the Object of Rotary</mission>
  <name>Rotary International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8549</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8627</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">688.07</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/IH/kY/h0/nM/nE/7f/CrkS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
