<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> What if you witnessed your neighbor killing her child,  or your best friend just had her sixth  female fetus aborted.  Would you stand up and say something?

 Lakshmi already had one daughter, so when she gave birth to a second girl, she killed her. For the three days of her second child's short life, Lakshmi admits, she refused to nurse her. To silence the infant's famished cries, the impoverished village woman squeezed the milky sap from an oleander shrub, mixed it with castor oil, and forced the poisonous potion down the newborn's throat. The baby bled from the nose, then died soon afterward. Female neighbors buried her in a small hole near Lakshmi's square thatched hut of sunbaked mud. They sympathized with Lakshmi, and in the same circumstances, some would probably have done what she did. For despite the risk of execution by hanging and about 16 months of a much-ballyhooed government scheme to assist families with daughters, in some hamlets of ... Tamil Nadu, murdering girls is still sometimes believed to be a wiser course than raising them. "A daughter is always liabilities. How can I bring up a second?" Lakshmi, 28, answered firmly when asked by a visitor how she could have taken her own child's life eight years ago. "Instead of her suffering the way I do, I thought it was better to get rid of her." (All quotes from Dahlburg, "Where killing baby girls 'is no big sin'.")

Female infanticide is the intentional killing of baby girls due to the preference for male babies and from the low value associated with the birth of females." (Marina Porras, "Female Infanticide and Foeticide".)

How can you help:


www.worldvison.ca


www.gendercide.org

Prayer,  for these women and their baby girls that often never see the light of day.


1. We need to educate eachother and bring awareness 

2. You can sponsor young girl from one of these countries,  such as India.  This would educate them,  that one day if they are faced with this decision she will know she has a choice</description>
  <mission>To raise awarness of sex selection and killings of baby girls</mission>
  <name>Stop Sex selection in India</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8552</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">862</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/HG/4m/m3/tG/tE/h1/310S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
