<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>United For Uganda is a group that works towards awareness, education, and fundraising on campuses and in the global arena, with the end to alleviate some of the problems plaguing Ugandan communities. By using direct action models, we work to create a better a better society by supporting and engaging in immediate local initatives with an eye to visionary global goals. We are currently part of the Invisible Children's campaign - Schools For Schools program. We are currently helping fund Layibi Secondary School in the Gulu area of Northern Uganda.

 The LRA is agreeing to peace talks, and that is great news! Although this is not at all a straightforward and simple process, it seems that all sides are indeed putting effort into making something work. This is great, but only raises even more questions and an extreme need for effective and comprehensive reconstruction efforts. 

Before, our role in the struggle was very confused. With the new development, we really no longer have an excuse not to act (to the extent, of course, that we can and should) to try to aid reconstruction efforts in every way that we can. 

History has shown us over and over again that the reconstruction period after a deciding point in a conflict is one of the most crucial time periods, and often one of the most overlooked. 

The conclusion: now is the time to really start getting involved, because now is a time when our actions will more realistically and positively affect the people we are concerned about (the first and clearest example is the thousands of children who will now be "released" from the LRA, without homes, family, or education, but with enough traumatizing experiences under their belt to affect them for the rest of their lives). 

1. awareness

2. education

3. funding</description>
  <mission>Our goal is to spread awareness and aid to help resolve the ongoing conflict in northern Uganda.  Please get involved!</mission>
  <name>United For Uganda</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8562</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">67</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Z7/hu/S2/bP/e6/yZ/KinS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
