<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What do the RIAA and the Mafia have in common?

A hit list.

That's right, the RIAA has singled out not only individual users but entire ISPs and university campuses!

If you are a university or college student, beware, every year the RIAA adds more schools to this list.

However, the crooks at the RIAA don't even have have the guts to find out who to subpoena. Every year schools on the "hit list" are sent eseentially blank forms which the school's administration or IT department fills out with file sharer's names, IP address, and various other slots of information. 

Schools feel obligated to fill these out and many students will face a minimum of $3,000 plus legal fees if caught. 

I urge all members to talk with their administration and fellow students. If the administration does not care or will not listen, organize! Rally the troops, get students together and speak as one to the administration. Tell them we will not be intimidated by those teaching us! 

Harvard University has repeatedly told the RIAA to shove off, if one of the top schools in the nation can  do this, then so can your school! 

Again, I urge each and everyone to take a stand, approach those in charge and make your voice heard, and if it requires persistence and numbers, then we must all do our part to keep the RIAA off our campuses!

For those who want to take an even greater step towards fighting the RIAA I urge you to share as many public and open source files as possible. Share your free anti-spyware program, share your game demos, share movie trailers, share music that independent artists have created for sharing. 
In France a major P2P organization has formed doing just this, sharing completely legal goods, overloading bandwidth and frustrating the goons.      

Tell your school, tell your friends, write your congressmen! 

1. Keep the RIAA off campus!

2. Stand together

3. Share legal goods!</description>
  <mission>Take a stand against the RIAA's tyranny of music!</mission>
  <name>RIAA- Take a Stand!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8565</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">34</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pB/0N/17/tD/Jr/yH/326S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
