<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In 2008, Convoy of Hope assisted nearly 6 million people in the United States and around the world by providing them with food, clothing, medical aid, and other needed resources through our community outreaches and disaster response arms.

The mission of Convoy of Hope is simple - we exist to feed millions of people in need in the United States and around the world through children&#8217;s nutrition initiatives, citywide outreaches and disaster response.

Hal Donaldson, president of Convoy of Hope, knows how powerful compassion can be. On August 25, 1969, his parents, Harold and Betty Donaldson, were hit head-on by a drunk driver. Harold was killed; Betty survived but was immobile for some time, unable to work or cook. Hal and his younger siblings quickly learned what it was like to live without many of life&#8217;s basic necessities.

However the Donaldsons were more fortunate than many others. People from local churches and the community stepped up to help them by providing food and shelter. Those generous acts gave the Donaldson kids a sense of hope and also a determination to one day help others who were in need.

In 1994 Convoy of Hope was formed. The idea was to network churches within communities to help people. Over the years that morphed into a global movement where honored guests receive groceries, medical and dental screenings, haircuts, help finding jobs, and prayer.

The response has been phenomenal!

In 15 years Convoy of Hope has helped nearly 30 million people in more than 103 countries. In that time we have also given away more than $150 million worth of food and supplies to people in need.

1.  www.convoyofhope.org

2. www.facebook.com/convoyofhope

3. www.twitter.com/convoyofhope</description>
  <mission>Convoy of Hope provides help and hope to millions of people in the United States and around the world through children's nutrition initiatives, citywide outreaches and disaster response.</mission>
  <name>Convoy of Hope</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8581</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7381</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3661.38</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sp/Qw/sg/VF/Zv/y7/Go/J0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
