<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The genocide in Darfur is absolutely appalling. This ethnic cleansing is remeniscent of the Holocaust, Rwanda, and Cambodia. This inhumanity to man (which believe it or not is fueled by religious fundementalism, not suprisingly muslims murdering christians) needs to be stopped and the perpetrators brought to justice. 

Many organizations around the world have responded to the crisis in Darfur by donating money. This money is used to purchase food, water, medical supplies, etc, for the people in Darfur. However, these supplies are more often than not seized by the militias commiting the genocide. This money is essentially being thrown down the drain as very little aid is reaching the people of Darfur. 

I propose a different method. We take part of the money that is being collected, and hire hundreds, possibly thousands of mercenaries.

Why mercenaries? Well, it is apparent that the United Nations has little backbone. The U.N. cannot intervene in Darfur because a few nations have not condoned the effort (mainly China). It seems with all likely hood, that no nation or international peace keeping organization is going to come to the aid of the people of Darfur.

Mercenaries will provide us with the ability to get results. First, we could use the mercenaries to protect the convoys of supplies being sent into Darfur. We could use the mercenaries to maintain routes for these convoys. We could use mercenaries to protect the very people who are being massacred. Finally, we could use the mercenaries to kill the human garbage responsible for this atrocity.

1. The ethnic cleansing occuring in Darfur must be stopped.

2. The militias and men responsible for this genocide should be killed, captured, and executed.</description>
  <mission>Stop the genocide in Darfur in a more pro-active way. </mission>
  <name>End the Genocide in Darfur by Hiring Mercenaries.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8593</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/XH/yn/7J/42/zH/cu/JPqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
