<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>      Voting may not seem like the first thing in mind when we turn 18.  There&#8217;s always college, strip clubs, clubs and  cars. Not to forget freedom from your parents. Getting that tattoo that mom did not want you to get. Well register for voting why? Cause believe it or not, We are America. We are the next generation, the generation that can  come together and accomplish incredible things. Unlike in the past generations we have a voice. Our parents and grad parents have fought adversity to give us that freedom to have a choice. So when you turn 18 register to vote. Because  we should choice who governs us.&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;Let me see&#8230; well your going to have these excuses.
 &lt;br&gt;
Well I don&#8217;t know anything about politics.? Well lets see, that&#8217;s not true. We all take government in high school. 
 &lt;br&gt;Another excuse:  well what&#8217;s a democrat? What&#8217;s a republican? What the hell is a liberal? The Nazi party of America? What the hell right. There&#8217;s a bunch of parties. But don&#8217;t freak out. It&#8217;s easy, just ask your self  questions:
&lt;br&gt;Like do I want the war in Iraq to end? Yes or no, or this is just something that we need to end ASAP
&lt;br&gt;Should gay marriage be legalize? Yes or no, or maybe just a civil union
&lt;br&gt;I like to be conservative? Yes or no, or maybe I&#8217;m somewhere in the middle 
&lt;br&gt;Hell I love to be liberal? Yes or no, or maybe I&#8217;m somewhere in the middle
&lt;br&gt;Does bush suck? Yeah, no, well maybe a little
&lt;br&gt;Well lets see how can explain that with out putting you to sleep. At the end when your in that little booth . You are so important that you can even  cost a recount.
&lt;br&gt;Well if any of you want any help finding out who you may vote for you can always go on www.youtube.com 
Or other type of media. The news seems to work. 

1. New generation, New revolution.

2. Would you let someone else tell you what you should say?</description>
  <mission>Encourage  young people to vote.</mission>
  <name>Voting is just not for old people.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8604</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">43</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xs/4H/qU/WE/Su/2e/UW2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
