<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Kwe is a Haitian Creole word which means "Believe" in english. At first glance, Kwe is a small company run by a group of high school and college students. The company uses original designs created by artists and students to create t-shirts, tote bags, buttons and other apparel. The entirety of money generated by the sale of these items then goes back to supporting various orphanages around the world (Not a single penny of the money goes back to those who run the company).

However, Kwe has come to be known as more than an apparel company... to many Kwe is an ethos, a paradigm, a way of life. It is the idea that every individual has the power to make a difference in the lives of those around them. 

This idea has become quite infectious and has even led to the creation of school clubs. The Kwe club aims to help foster a sense of global awareness by introducing students to issues which confront individuals all around the world, and by giving students the ability to respond to these issues with their own individual skills and talents. 

So together... Kwe the business, Kwe the belief, and  Kwe the club have bonded together to form a sort of movement. A perpetual effort to put an end to apathy and indifference, and to band together to help overcome the issues which affect people all around the world. 


1. To provide support for disadvantaged children around the world

2. To raise awareness about different issues around the world

3. To inspire and equip people to make a positive impact on the world</description>
  <mission>Provide support for disadvantaged children around the world while developing awareness of global issues</mission>
  <name>Kwe::Believe</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8605</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">365</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">30.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Z6/Nw/8p/uJ/Lj/sB/7quS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
