<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>On September 21st, International Peace Day, 10 people from 5 continents will climb Mt. Kilimanjaro to raise money for the Roots &amp; Shoots/UNHCR Lugufu Program.  For each of the 5,895 meters up to Mt. Kilmanjaro&#8217;s summit, we hope to raise $5, adding up to a total of nearly $30,000 that will support the R&amp;S Lugufu program.    
*About the Lugufu Project*
Over 35,000 refugees from the Democratic Republic of the Congo live in Tanzania&#8217;s Kigoma Region including thousands of youth whose lives have been filled with instability and fear.  The R&amp;S/UNHCR program in Lugufu (run by the Jane Goodall Institute) is designed empower these children through hands-on service learning projects that emphasize care and compassion for all living things.  
The main projects undertaken in the past five years have been: 
*income generating schemes like beekeeping, chicken rearing and barbershops
*service projects such as assisting the disabled
*environmental education 
*sporting events
*workshops such as art therapy to build capacity and personal development  
In addition, the Lugufu R&amp;S program has begun a scholarship for exceptional students who are can't afford to continue their schooling.  Besides providing immediate benefits such as food and education, these projects have allowed youth in and around Lugufu to realize their power to make a difference in their community.  
Like all R&amp;S efforts, the Lugufu program is run with a grassroots philosophy, supported by dedicated teachers and creative students.  One staff member and one local volunteer coordinate the entire 1800-student-large program. The program needs your help to survive and expand!   

[however, we prefer that you DON'T donate through facebook.  Write a check instead, and your money will go directly to Kigoma rather than to JGI-USA]

For more information about the climb email me at peaceclimb2007@gmail.com 

also see:
www.rootsandshoots.org
www.janegoodall.org
www.unhcr.org

1. We believe in The power of informed and compassionate youth to effect change

2. the benefits of self-confidence building service-learning projects for refugee youth

3. there is a need to raise awareness of the effects of war, especially those that are no longer headline news  </description>
  <mission>Support the program which gives children in Lugufu Refugee Camp a sense of empowerment, connection to each other and self-esteem</mission>
  <name>Roots &amp; Shoots/UNHCR Lugufu Program</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8624</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">183</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tZ/Ep/Zw/TE/1V/xD/4ArS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
