<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Colleges Curing Cancer has made a commitment to build a team for The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society&#8217;s Light The Night&#174; Walk. This is an opportunity for our company to do something good in our community. It is an opportunity for you to help fight cancer by:
&#8226;  Joining the Light The Night team
&#8226;  Making a personal contribution
&#8226;  Raising funds for the Society to use for critical cancer research and 
services for patients and their families 

Light The Night is an evening walk to celebrate and commemorate the lives of people touched by cancer. Walkers hold illuminated balloons&#8212;white for survivors, red for supporters&#8212;and light the night with hope. The Walk culminates in a community celebration with music, refreshments and 
entertainment&#8212;where friends, family members, neighbors, co-workers and others come together 
to demonstrate their support for cancer patients.  

Team members raise funds by encouraging others to contribute. As Team Captain, I encourage you to become involved in this worthwhile endeavor, and to give 
yourself the experience of helping others. You will be glad you joined us. Call me at (518-265-4059) or register online! 
REGISTER TO WALK AND JOIN MY TEAM 
Colleges against Cancer

Who: Anyone who wants to fight cancer is invited to join. No particular level of fitness is required.  
How: We encourage every walker to beat the national average amount ($200) by setting their 
individual goal to at least $250. I&#8217;ll give you information on how to go about it. Our team goal is $1000.

Fundraising Rewards: All participants raising $100 or more will receive an illuminated balloon and a T-shirt to wear during the Walk. Walkers raising $300, $500, $1,000, $2,500 or more can receive other exciting gifts. 

Please join us for this very special evening. Be a part of our team. You&#8217;ll enjoy yourself. And you&#8217;ll make an important difference in the lives of others.

1. Every five minutes, someone in this country is diagnosed with blood cancer: Every ten minutes, someone loses the fight. 

2. Leukemia causes more deaths than any other cancer among children

3. The myeloma survival rate is only 32 percent. 

4. Light The Night and brighten the future for millions touched by cancer.</description>
  <mission>walk to raise awareness and funds to cure leukemia, lymphoma and myeloma, and improve the quality of life of patients and their families.</mission>
  <name>Colleges Against Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8631</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tW/dE/k8/5G/kq/MZ/YTzS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
