<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Pemphigus is a group of rare potentially life-threatening autoimmune disorders that cause blistering of the skin and/or mucous membranes. 

In a person with pemphigus, the immune system mistakenly perceives the cells in skin and/or mucous membrane as foreign, and attacks them. When auto-antibodies attack, the skin virtually becomes unglued. This causes burn-like lesions or blisters that do not heal. In some cases, these blisters can cover a significant area of the skin.

Although pemphigus affects people of all races and cultures, and men and women develop pemphigus equally, it is very rare. It is estimated that only one in every million people will develop pemphigus. Because of the rarity of the disease, it is not possible to say who will get one of the several types of pemphigus, but it is never contagious in any way.

Too little is known about possible triggers such as environmental toxins, medications and diet. Pemphigus is best controlled by early diagnosis and treatment. Too often, patients are misdiagnosed by health care providers who lack knowledge, resulting in unnecessary pain and suffering for patients.

While the emergence of corticosteroids in the last 40 years has notably reduced the mortality rate associated with the disorder, it may still be as high as 25% - usually due to complications associated with treatment. All existing treatment options are accompanied by severe side effects which have a significant impact on patients' quality of life. Pemphigus has also been noted to occur in domestic animals such as dogs, cats and horses.

More research is necessary now into the causes, diagnoses, treatments and a cure!

Please help! 

1. Patients should not have to suffer because of misdiagnosis due to ingorance of healthcare providers.

2. Research will lead to safer and more effective treatment options.

3. Increased awareness will improve patient quality of life.</description>
  <mission>To increase awareness of the rare autoimmune disorders pemphigus/pemphigoid and to advocate research into treatments, diagnoses and a cure.</mission>
  <name>Support Pemphigus &amp; Pemphigoid Awareness and Research</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8639</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1109</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1350.02</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/md/w7/fK/H4/bs/Gy/s00S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
