<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The first ever 24 hour, no sitting, no sleeping, University of Kentucky Dance Marathon, DanceBlue, took place February 10-11th, 2006. More than 30 student organization and over 180 dancers flooded into Memorial Coliseum to kick off the event at 9pm. With the help of over 100 UK students, faculty, staff and administration, DanceBlue was able to become the most successful student run philanthropy event in UK.s history. In the first year, DanceBlue raised for $123, 323.16 for the UK Pediatric Oncology Clinic! In its second year, DanceBlue raised an unbelievable $241,514.64. We are extremely excited about DanceBlue 2008!


The Golden Matrix Fund was created to benefit the University of Kentucky Pediatric Oncology Clinic patients and families. Childhood cancer not only affects the child physically, but also creates may emotional and financial difficulties for the entire family. Children who have cancer make routine visits to the hospital and have to undergo countless tests and procedures regularly, all the while trying to fit in with their peers. Families affected by childhood cancer are faced with countless added stressors to their daily lives: paying medical bills, obtaining transportation to and from hospital visits, taking time off work to care for their children and the emotional affects on other siblings. The Golden Matrix Fund is used to alleviate some of these issues that childhood cancer can create. The fund will help the families of the UK Pediatric Oncology Clinic receive better care, better support, less financial burden and give the children back to their childhood. As the fund grows over the years, it will also support pediatric cancer research and specialized clinic staff.




1. To Raise money for the University of Kentucky Pediatric Oncology Clinic Patients and Families

2. To allow for better care, better support,less financial burden, and give the children back to their childhood.

3. Eventually help fund pediatric cancer research and specialized staff.</description>
  <mission>To enhances the lives of children and families suffering from childhood cancer through the Golden Matrix Fund. </mission>
  <name>DanceBlue 2008</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8649</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">511</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">135.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ag/xH/Sv/Ue/HK/qQ/LERS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
