<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The World Health Organization says that in order for c-section to be used in such a way that it creates a safe outcome for both mother and baby, no country should have a c-section rate that is higher than 10-15% of all births.

Despite this, many countries around the world have c-section rates which far exceed this, meaning that the lives and future health of both Mothers and Babies are being put at risk.

Many healthcare providers do not give women the full details in order to make an informed decision, and when women educate themselves they are pressured to give up their right to an informed refusal.

http://www.ican-online.org/

http://www.childbirthconnection.org/

http://www.radmid.demon.co.uk/

http://www.internationalmidwives.org

http://www.vbac.com/

PLEASE NOTE: This group is not about demonizing c-sections, which is a life-saving surgery when used appropriately. There is no question that we are both lucky to have such a medical technique at our disposal, but that it has made a positive change in our society in saving the lives of many women and their babies. However, as with any major surgery it carries great risks and women have a right to know about these *especially* when the c/s is to be done without any medical necessity.

1. Provide support for organisations that do research into the safety and correct use of c-section

2. Provide information so that women can understand all the aspects of c-section

3. Provide resources so that women may make informed refusals

4. Put pressure on healthcare providers to give women all the facts

5. Support VBAC</description>
  <mission>Provide advocacy for the safe use of c-section as tool in creating safe births</mission>
  <name>Cesarean Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8651</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1331</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5O/pd/6v/j6/0Y/Xj/HtxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
