<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>RMHC provides stability and resources to families so they can get and keep their child healthy and happy, and we have been doing this for 37 years. 

By creating, finding and supporting programs that directly improve the health and well-being of children, Ronald McDonald House Charities (RMHC) is working to improve the lives of children and their families around the world. 

The three core programs of RMHC - the Ronald McDonald House, Ronald McDonald Family Room and Ronald McDonald Care Mobile - are focused on helping families in need. 

Our cornerstone Ronald McDonald House program began in 1974 based on a simple idea: Provide a "home away from home" for families of seriously ill children receiving treatment at nearby hospitals. Since that time, more than 10 million families around the world have benefited from the comfort provided by a Ronald McDonald House.

The Ronald McDonald Family Room program extends the comfort of a Ronald McDonald House to a hospital setting. Typically located just steps from neonatal or pediatric intensive care units, the Family Room provides a place to escape the stress and tension of the hospital.

Through relationships with local health care providers, the Ronald McDonald Care Mobile program brings cost-effective medical, dental and health education services directly to underserved children in both rural and urban areas around the world.

Together with support from hundreds of thousands of passionate and caring volunteers, donors and RMHC staff, we are able to carry out our mission. It is supporters like you, on this Cause page, that enable us to further our mission, expand our reach, and serve more families in need. Thank you!



1. RMHC provides stability and resources to families so they can keep their children healthy and happy.

2. RMHC has a network of 297 Chapters who operate 306 Ronald McDonald Houses, 169 Ronald McDonald Family Rooms and 44 Ronald McDonald Care Mobiles.</description>
  <mission>Create, find and support programs that directly improve the health and well being of children. </mission>
  <name>Ronald McDonald House Charities </name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/866</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">130319</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10179.33</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/x0/tL/ex/Y3/a7/pz/zI/F3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
