<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>My background, experience and record enable me to bridge gaps, achieve political solutions, restore America's moral leadership abroad, heal partisan divisions and solve problems at home. 


1. The Iraq War is costing Americans $8 billion each month.  By implementing my plan to de-authorize the war and withdraw ALL troops in six months, we can start redirecting these funds toward what matters most for Americans: improving education, expanding ac

2. We must "Act Boldly and Act Now" in order to make America a Clean Energy Nation like I made New Mexico a Clean Energy State. Consider this a call to action, for Congress, the energy industry, and the public. I am calling for a New American Revolution -- a

3. Affordable and secure health insurance for every American should be our national goal. A system that denies people health care because they can't afford it flies in the face of America's core values of opportunity and security. Americans are demanding act

4. As Congressman, Ambassador, Secretary and Governor of New Mexico, Bill Richardson has been a champion of civil rights, equality, freedom and the rule of law. As President, Bill Richardson will continue to fight for and protect the rights and freedoms that

5. Throughout my career in public service, I have been fighting for conservation because I understand the importance of protecting our most valuable natural resources. I have been honored to be recognized as an Environmental Leader of the Year by the Nationa

6. Since I took office as Governor of New Mexico, we have jump-started the state's economy after 8 years of a Republican administration mired in gridlock and inactivity. In what is being called "The New Mexico Turnaround", we've created over 80,000 new jobs 

7. Improving our schools has been central to my work turning around New Mexico. As Governor, I worked hard on behalf of teachers, investing in higher salaries and expanded benefits for those who have given our communities so much. We raised New  Mexico teach

8. I am committed to implementing comprehensive reforms that secure our borders and our ports and provide for an effective and humane immigration policy 

9. This administration&#8217;s lack of realism has led us to a dangerous place. We need to take a different path. A path based on reality, not unilateralist illusions.  A path that understands that the gravest dangers that threaten us today do not threaten only </description>
  <mission>Elect Bill Richardson for President</mission>
  <name>Richardson for President</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8677</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ZZ/pS/z1/DQ/7Z/ph/puES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
