<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>staytough.fightHARD. inc. is a grass roots non-profit organization, formed to aid in the campaign to &#8220;battle against Lou Gehrig&#8217;s disease&#8221;.

staytough.fightHARD. originated at Bucknell University in Lewisburg, PA. Created as a surprise benefit by Timothy M. O&#8217;Neill Jr. and fellow classmates, the April event was held in honor of Timothy M. O&#8217;Neill Sr., who had been diagnosed with ALS the previous August. The tremendous support and success of the benefit raised the idea of expanding staytough.fightHARD. into a larger scale non-profit organization with goals of education, fundraising, and aid.

In an effort to educate the public, our hope is to be invited to corporate campuses, college campuses, golf outings, business events, sporting events, beach parties, pool parties, or any other function; in order to spread the word about Lou Gehrig&#8217;s disease.

Our methods of fundraising include; the solicitation of corporate and private donors, parties, merchandise sales, raffles, and games of chance. As other opportunities arise, we will certainly entertain them.

Based on the amount of funds we generate, we will attempt to assist all those we are able, with the financial help being used for mobility equipment, augmentative devices, or aiding in the installation of handicap apparatus.

1. Assist financially, wherever possible, those families affected by ALS

2. Raise funds in order to aid research centers as they develop treatments for PALS (people with ALS).

3. Educate the public about the devastating effects of ALS</description>
  <mission>battle against Lou Gehrig's disease</mission>
  <name>staytough. fightHARD.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8686</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">449</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">719.34</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/41/su/Z6/TX/Xd/5K/drlS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
