<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The campaign is a part of Nalgene's efforts in natural resource preservation and conservation.

While Nalgene does sell a 'Refill Not Landfill' bottle, the campaign in itself isn't about business. It's truly about the conservation that can be increased by using reusable containers instead of buying bottled water.

-8 out of 10 plastic water bottles used in the United States become garbage or end up in a landfill. (Container Recycling Institute) 
 
-The energy we waste using bottled water would be enough to power 190,000 homes. But refilling your water bottle from the tap requires no expenditure of energy, and zero waste of resources. (PBS Point of View 2004)
 
-Making all of the bottles for the US requires more than 1.5 million barrels of oil annually. That's enough to fuel 100,000 cars. (Earth Policy Institute) 

-In the United States in 2006, bottled water consumption reached a record 8.3 billion gallons, 185 million gallons of which was imported. The total amount spent on bottled water was over $11 billion. (Beverage Marketing Corp.) 

-In contrast to tap water, which is distributed through an energy-efficient infrastructure, transporting bottled water long distances involves burning massive quantities of fossil fuels. Nearly a quarter of all bottled water crosses national borders to reach consumers, transported by boat, train, and truck. (Earth Policy Institute) 

-It costs more money to drink bottled water than to put gas in your car--up to five time more--due mainly to its packaging and transportation.(Earth Policy Institute) 

-Bottled water companies do not have to release their water-testing results to the public, whereas municipalities do. (Natural Resources Defense Council) 



Join the cause, invite a friend, and buy yourself a reusable bottle.. it's a cheap and easy way you can do your small part in preserving the natural resources we still have.

Visit http://www.refillnotlandfill.org/ for more information.

1. Bottled water comsumption is at an all-time high and is becoming a national, wasteful problem.</description>
  <mission>to reduce the amount of waste disposable water bottles contribute to landfills each year.</mission>
  <name>Refill Not Landfill</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8702</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">439</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2Q/ad/Vo/87/Cn/MX/FyjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
