<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Imagine it is the year 2012.  In the past five years, a remarkable thing happened &#8211; the world contained the spread of HIV.  Not with a vaccine or any new technology that is still being developed, but with a change in hearts and minds that enabled all people from all walks of life to get tested without fear or shame.  The world became more compassionate and accepting of all people, more educated about HIV, and less fearful, to the point that people are now getting tested regardless of their risks, and people with HIV/AIDS are seeing hope and options, not rejection and scorn.  

Does it sound unrealistic?  Believe it or not, we are actually seeing the seeds of this happening in Wheaton, IL and Buchifi, Kenya.  We are engaging people in education and testing throuhgout the regions we work, and we want to do all we can to help spread it. 

By supporting our work, and by encouraging all people to get tested for HIV and then talk about the issues, we can become the kind of world where people living with and at-risk for HIV need not live in fear.  In the process, we increase our ability to hold ourselves and others accountable for doing what it takes to not spread and not get HIV.  

Check out www.mosaicinitiative.org to find out more.



1. We have all the information we need to end the spread of HIV

2. Until we learn to embrace and honor all humanity, we will not be successful

3. Getting tested for HIV doesn't change the truth, it exposes it.

4. For every person who gets into an HIV treatment program, six people are infected.  It's a trend we can change.

5. HIV is a virus that has no regards for borders and boundaries.  

6. The work to end the HIV/AIDS pandemic willl succeed when the world becomes whole, or will fail because we cannot come together.</description>
  <mission>THE MOSAIC INITIATIVE IS A GRASSROOTS NON-PROFIT ORGANIZATION COMMITTED TO PREVENTING THE SPREAD OF HIV BY BUILDING PARTNERSHIPS AND COALITIONS WITH THE VISION OF CREATING HEALTHY COMMUNITIES. </mission>
  <name>The Mosaic Initiative</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8707</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">9</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">186.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/re/Oy/Fo/Av/Td/Vv/oa0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
