<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Up 'til Dawn is currently accepting applications for the Fall 2008-Spring 2009 Executive Board. For an application, please visit our UNI Up 'til Dawn website and click on How can I help? : http://unistjude.googlepages.com/ 

"Fight the yawn &#8211; stay awake to cure childhood cancer."  That&#8217;s the motto of Up &#8216;til Dawn&#174;, the coolest philanthropic program to hit college campuses across the nation. We stay Up Till Dawn because cancer never sleeps and there should be no child who dies in the dawn of life. Up &#8216;til Dawn unites students, staff and their local communities with a goal to help the children of St. Jude Children&#8217;s Research Hospital. Students who lead Up &#8216;til Dawn on their campuses educate the community about St. Jude while raising money through a variety of activities.  At the end of the program, campuses host a Finale Event and stay &#8220;Up &#8216;til Dawn&#8221; celebrating their achievements and honoring the patients at St. Jude. Students &#8220;fight the yawn&#8221; so that St. Jude patients can grow up and go to college, too.

For more information about St. Jude or Up 'til Dawn please visit http://unistjude.googlepages.com/  OR e-mail our Executive Directors at unistjude@gmail.com

*ALSAC, or the American Lebanese Syrian Associated Charities, Inc is the fundraising wing of St. Jude.

1. St. Jude Children's Research Hospital provides all patients FREE healthcare along with housing, food and necessities for their family so they can focu

2. St. Jude Children's Research Hospital leads the nation in childhood cancer research along with sickle cell anemia and AIDS.

3. In the last 40 years St. Jude have increased the chances of surviving ALL (Acute Lymphoblastic Luekemia) from 4% to 96%. This trend is seen through ma

4. St. Jude research benefits not only American children, but children throughout the world.

5. The strain for the flu vaccination that everyone in the USA recieves each year is decided at St. Jude Hospital.</description>
  <mission>Help St. Jude Find a Cure to Childhood Cancer so the Children Can Someday attend College Too</mission>
  <name>Up 'til Dawn  and the St. Jude Children's Research Hospital at the University of Northern Iowa</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8724</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">211</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ot/H0/v3/hZ/5U/hp/41/iWS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
