<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>ENVY is a Environment protection organization, Founded in Bogota - Colombia.

The main purpose of ENVY is to improve the environment, and bring people knowledge about the environmental damage we are causing, and how do we stop it.

ENVY is a registered organization, That invests in recycling projects, and projects to reduce gas discharge ... we receive donations to invest in campaigns of atmosphere improvement.

We are looking for help ATM. We currently work in Colombia and our close countries, But we need some help to reach other countries, and help their people.


Remember we won't have a society if we destroy the environment. 



----------------------------------------------------------

ENVY es una organizacion de proteccion ambiental, Fundada en Bogota, Colombia.

El proposito principal de ENVY es mejorar el ambiente, y llevar informacion a la gente sobre el da&#241;o ambiental que estamos causando, y como prevenirlo.

ENVY es una organizacion registrada, Que invierte en proyectos de reciclaje y proyectos que ayudan a reducir la emision de gases ... Recibimos donaciones para invertir en campa&#241;as de mejoramiento atmosferico.

En este momento estamos buscando ayuda, Por el momento trabajamos en colombia y en paises cercanos, pero necesitamos ayuda para llegar a mas pases y ayudar a su gente.

Recuerda nunca vamos a tener una sociedad, si no cuidamos el ambiente.



1. Atmosphere improvement is necessary to live

2. Environmental and natural resources need care

3. Contamination Must End</description>
  <mission>Improve The Environment, And Make The Planet A Cleaner, Greener and Safer Place</mission>
  <name>ENVY - Organizacion Ambiental</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8747</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">31</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0K/cv/vd/6P/r3/al/cZ/KmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
