<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In July of 2007, fifteen of us embarked on a journey across the world. Basically, it turned out to be way more than a "student travel" trip. This group exists because we care.

SPEAKcambodia is where it's at. This is how we're going to make change. By collecting your babysitting money, taking up your time to watch our presentations, and cluttering up your closet space with our (really sick) t-shirts, we're giving kids in Cambodia the opportunity we've all been given.

So, where is your money going?
1. Cambodian Living Arts:
Founded 8 years ago, CLA has been working to preserve Khmer cultural traditions nearly lost during the Pol Pot regime. As recently as 4 years ago, several master artisans were found living in squatter communities, still hiding in fear from the Khmer Rouge. These remaining artisans are the last living connections to Cambodia's cultural past. CLA supports these masters in teaching the youth of Cambodia the traditional art, music and dance forms in an attempt to provide the artistic rituals that were nearly lost. Today more than 300 students attend various classes at CLA locations scattered about Cambodia. www.cambodianlivingarts.org

2. Global Children
Global Children is a NGO dedicated to provide impoverished children with a sufficient education. Global Children representatives visit provinces and orphanages all over Cambodia, observing the most devoted and motivated students. These students are chosen from the different provinces and are given scholarships to attend universities. Unfortunately, as this organization is still growing, Global Children can only afford to give out seven scholarships per year. 
www.global-children.org


1. Education plays a fundamental role in the world

2. Everyone deserves a chance</description>
  <mission>Promote Educational Access for Kids in Cambodia</mission>
  <name>SPEAKcambodia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8750</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">457</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/JD/xS/Cb/Tz/hU/Xh/lp7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
