<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>ERI is a nonprofit group of activists, organizers, and lawyers with expertise in human rights, the environment, and corporate and government accountability. We focus our work at the intersection of human rights and the environment, which we define as earth rights.  We specialize in fact-finding, legal actions against perpetrators of earth rights abuses, training for grassroots and community leaders and advocacy campaigns.  Through these strategies, ERI seeks to end earth rights abuses, and to promote and protect earth rights.

ERI was founded in 1995 along the Thai-Burma border, with a focus on using innovative legal strategies and mechanisms in order to bring justice to indigenous Burmese communities abused by the Burmese military regime and its corporate partners in the name of development.  That year, ERI's three co-founders - a human rights campaigner from Burma and two recently graduated American law students - brought the landmark case Doe v. Unocal on behalf of 15 villagers from the jungles of Burma against the Unocal Oil Corporation for human rights abuses related to the construction of the now infamous Yadana gas pipeline.  Today from our offices in Washington DC and northern Thailand, ERI both represents and partners with individuals and communities around the world who are victims, survivors, or at risk of human rights and environmental abuses which occur during natural resource extraction projects such as oil and gas development, water diversion projects, logging, and mining.  

1. Litigating in U.S. courts on behalf of people around the world whose earth rights have been violated by governments and transnational corporations.

2. Exposing and publicizing earth rights abuses through campaigns, reports and articles.

3. Training the next generation of locally-rooted earth rights activists and defenders.</description>
  <mission>EarthRights International (ERI) combines the power of law and the power of people in defense of human rights and the environment.  </mission>
  <name>EarthRights International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8766</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">860</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1094.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/8e/Ui/vU/aX/tM/em/E7/hrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
