<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hello,

I'm on a quest!!!

I've known Katherine Gortnar for almost 7 years. And during this time I had the honor of becoming a good friend of Katherine's. She was one of the most amazing women I've known. Katherine always had this way of making you feel so comfortable, she was just an amazing person! Just beautiful inside and out. Katherine keeps me inspired beyond belief.
 
Katherine's courageous fight with cancer ended last year and I believe it is things like this that makes life so unfair. With so many bad people (monsters) in the world, who in my mind deserve this kind of fate, that such a beautiful person should have her life end when she was so young is tragic!

I know I can't find a cure for cancer, if you know me you know I'm no scientist to say the least. But I am sick and tired of good people, family and friends, losing to this terrible disease that I have to do something.

So I'm on a quest to try and raise money to fight cancer. This is the best way I know how I can contribute to defeating this disease.

On September 7-9, 2007 I'll be participating in a very special event called The Weekend to End Breast Cancer.

I'll walk 60 kilometers over the course of one weekend with thousands of other women and men. The net proceeds will support breast cancer research, treatment, and services through the Princess Margaret Hospital.

I've agreed to raise at least $2,000. So I need your help, please sponsor me with even the smallest amount as every little bit helps. Use the link at the bottom of this email, and go visit my site - and please take the time to support me. Please keep in mind how far I'm walking - and how hard I'll have to train.

Just cut and paste this URL below in a new Internet Browser:
http://www.endcancer.ca/site/TR?pg=pfind&amp;fr_id=1202&amp;JServSessionIdr010=voadzt5y72.app25b
 
Thank you in advance for your generosity!

Sincerely,

Michael



1. To end Cancer!!!</description>
  <mission>Waise over $2,000/</mission>
  <name>The Weekend to End Breast Cancer</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8769</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7g/qZ/QV/bU/lR/Px/KgiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
