<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Global Warming is the current issue for politicians. They are creating solutions to the so called "problem" in order to win votes, when in reality there is no problem.

The Earth's climate has been going up and down for millions of years, ice ages are undeniable proof of this.  In order for the planet to thaw from it's most recent ice age, there must have been a significant rise in temperature.  This certainly wasn't due to cavemen boarding too many jumbo jets.  It was due to an entirely natural process, something that global warming enthusiasts refuse to acknowledge.

Other facts that argue against global warming:

Ice core records from the last 650,000 years show that rises in temperature have come BEFORE rises in CO2, not after. 

Evidence that we are experiencing natural fluctuations in climate are supported by some historic British facts. 

1) Almost 2000 years ago it was warm enough in Britain for the Roman's to grow grapes.

2) At around 1100 A.D the Vikings settled and harvested crops in 
Greenland, a continent now almost entirely covered with ice.

3) Between 1400 and 1850 A.D, Britain suffered from an extremely cold period, with harsh winters and cold summers causing starvation and disease.

100 million years ago, there was six times as much carbon dioxide in the atmosphere as there is now, yet the temperature then was marginally cooler than it is today. Many scientists have concluded that carbon dioxide doesn't even affect climate.

As a dominant greenhouse gas, water vapour is far more important that CO2.

Remove all the CO2 from the atmosphere, and the temperature would drop by just 0.3%.  Remove all the water vapour, and the temperature would drop by 99.6%.

If I were a politician I'd probably be making a video about the dangers of water vapour. I'd be Prime Minister by next Tuesday. 

1. To question the current political stance on global warming</description>
  <mission>To prevent the world diverting unspeakable amounts of money from it's economy into a problem that doesn't exist.</mission>
  <name>Global Warming Is A Load Of Old Nonsense</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8770</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">47</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2K/LU/Za/FI/HC/n2/YUbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
