<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>An obstetric fistula develops when blood supply to the tissues of the vagina and the bladder (and/or rectum) is cut off during prolonged obstructed labor. The tissues die and a hole forms through which urine and/or feces pass uncontrollably. Women who develop fistulas are often abandoned by their husbands, rejected by their communities, and forced to live an isolated existence.
Eradicated in western countries at the end of the 19th century when cesarean section became widely available, obstetric fistula continues to plague women throughout the developing world. It is estimated that there are 100,000 new fistula cases each year, but the international capacity to treat fistula remains at only 6,500 per year. The United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) estimates the world's population of fistula sufferers at more than two million.
Why does Fistula occur?
Poverty, malnutrition, poor health services, early childbearing and gender discrimination are interlinked root causes of obstetric fistula. Poverty is the main social risk factor because it is associated with early marriage and malnutrition and because poverty reduces a woman's chances of getting timely obstetric care. Because of their low status in many communities, women often lack the power to choose when to start bearing children or where to give birth. Childbearing before the pelvis is fully developed, as well as malnutrition, small stature and general poor health, are contributing physiological factors to obstructed labour. Older women who have delivered many children are at risk as well.
 
This purpose of this campaign is to create awareness in the minds of people about the reality of Fistula in hope that the information presented will bring action. Let us join forces with organizations such as Light of Africa and the UNFPA to eradicate Fistula. 


1. No woman should live in hiding.

2. Promote education for marginalized women in poorer countries.

3. Campaign against sexual violence as a weapon in conflict torn countries.</description>
  <mission>Beauty for Ashes is a campaign to create awareness of Obstetric Fistula and raise efforts to fight the disease. </mission>
  <name>Beauty for Ashes</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8775</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">235</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/LW/Sf/3y/2F/Qk/Jq/6WmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
