<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>ONE is Americans of all beliefs and every walk of life &#8211; united as ONE &#8211; to help make poverty history. We are a campaign of over 2.4 million people and growing from all 50 states and over 150 of America&#8217;s most well-known and respected non-profit, advocacy and humanitarian organizations. As ONE, we are asking our leaders to do more to fight the emergency of global AIDS and extreme poverty. ONE believes that allocating more of the U.S. budget toward providing basic needs like health, education, clean water and food would transform the futures and hopes of an entire generation in the world's poorest countries.

ONE is nonpartisan; there&#8217;s only ONE side in the fight against global AIDS and extreme poverty. Working on the ground in communities, colleges and churches across the United States, ONE members ask America&#8217;s leaders to increase efforts to fight global AIDS and extreme poverty, from the U.S. budget and presidential elections to specific legislation on debt cancellation, increasing effective international assistance, making trade fair, and fighting corruption. Everyone can join the fight.

The goal of ending poverty may seem lofty, but it is within our reach if we take action together as ONE.

1. More than 38 million people around the world are infected by HIV/AIDS, 25 million in Africa alone. Left untreated, AIDS leads to an early death for people in their most productive years who are needed to raise crops and families, teach school and care for

2. We Believe we can beat: AIDS, starvation, extreme poverty.

3. We Recognize ONE billion people live on less than ONE dollar a day.

4. We Commit ourselves - ONE person - ONE voice - ONE vote at a time - to make a better, safer world for all.</description>
  <mission>The Campaign To Make Poverty History.</mission>
  <name>The ONE Campaign</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8780</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">677</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/NZ/ue/sN/AT/YN/5V/O7pS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
