<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In almost four years contributions made through the Yellow Ribbon Fund have provided the following for injured service members and their families: 

*More than 900 free rental cars,
*More than 11,000 free taxi rides,
*More than 4,000 free hotel room nights,
*38 families have used our five apartments for more than 4,000 nights,
*Hundreds of free tickets to sporting event, concerts and plays, and hundreds of lunches, dinners, golf games, duck and goose hunts, fishing trips, and other activities.

$25&#8212;buys a taxi ride for an injured service member to go from Walter Reed or Bethesda Naval Hospital anywhere in D.C. or Silver Spring, freeing that young man or woman from the hospital for the evening. 

$50&#8212;gives a family a free rental car for a week. This is probably the most &#8220;liberating&#8221; gift that the Yellow Ribbon Fund provides to families living at Walter Reed or Bethesda Naval.  

$150&#8212;buys a free night in a local hotel for a family while they are visiting their injured service member who at Walter Reed or Bethesda Naval.

$350&#8212;gives a family a free week in one of our five apartments. This enables us to assist families who do not otherwise have housing in our area. 

$1200&#8212;enables us to rent a bus to take 40 to 50 injured soldiers, Marines and their families to a local event, such as the circus, a play, or a similar opportunity where generous community members have donated free tickets for the troops.

For more information please visit us at our Web site: http://www.yellowribbonfund.org/


1. Supporting injured service members and their families</description>
  <mission>Assisting our injured service members while they recuperate at the Walter Reed Army Medical Center and the National Naval Medical Center.</mission>
  <name>Yellow Ribbon Fund - Supporting injured service members</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8787</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2545</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1549.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/UW/6f/Nx/8w/54/Dm/dLqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
