<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Statement of Faith 

We believe in God the Father Almighty, Maker of heaven and earth; And in Jesus Christ, His only begotten Son, our Lord, who was conceived by the Holy Spirit, born of the Virgin Mary, suffered under Pontius Pilate, was crucified, dead and buried; He descended into hell; the third day He rose again from the dead; He ascended into heaven, and sits at the right hand of God the Father Almighty; from thence He shall come to judge the living and the dead. 

We believe in the Holy Spirit, the holy Christian church, the communion of saints, the forgiveness of sins, the resurrection of the body, and the life everlasting. 

Vision statement 

The vision of Open Doors is to strengthen and equip the Body of Christ living under or facing restriction or persecution because of their faith in Jesus Christ, and to encourage their involvement in world evangelism by: 

    *

      Providing Bibles and literature, media, leadership training, socio-economic
    *

      development and through intercessory prayer; 
    *

      Preparing the Body of Christ living in threatened or unstable areas to face 
    *

      persecution and suffering; and  
    *

      Educating and mobilizing the Body of Christ living in the free world to identify with
    *

      threatened and persecuted Christians and be actively involved in assisting them.  

We do so because we believe when one member suffers, all members suffer with it (1 Corinthians 12:26), all doors are open and God enables His Body to go into all the world and preach the Gospel. 

How we limit ourselves 

We are dependent on prayer support for our ministry as well as asking for prayer for the persecuted Church. 

1. Providing Bibles and literature, media, leadership training, socio-economic

2. evelopment and through intercessory prayer

3. Preparing the Body of Christ living in threatened or unstable areas to face </description>
  <mission>To strengthen and equip the Body of Christ living under or facing restriction or persecution because of their faith in Jesus Christ, and to encourage their involvement in world evangelism</mission>
  <name>Opened Doors</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8788</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">31</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ya/4w/wc/Cg/ak/CN/PsuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
