<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Sderot is a small city with a population of 25,000 people. It is nearly on the border of Israel and Gaza. The houses and schools, streets and hospitals of Sderot are constantly being hit with "Kassam" rockets. 
Right now the situation in the city is simply tragic. The timeframe from when a rocket is sent from Gaza to when it explodes on the streets of Sderot, is fifteen seconds. That's not a misprint- FIFTEEN SECONDS! That means that people, who have just heard the sirens, have only fifteen seconds to flee to the shelter. There is a catastrophic lack of shelters, and some schools and houses don't even have them at all. Some of the schools are closed because of that. That's how Sderot, has been living for the past five years - on the edge, not knowing when the next rocket will fall. Obviously, those that suffer the most because of this are the children. They are forced to live in an atmosphere where they are not sure of anything. They have to fear for their lives. Many refuse to go to school and stay home where it's not as scary. Teenagers are scared to sleep alone and fall asleep only in bed with their parents. And little children, when asked the innocent question of "why do snails have their own little homes on their backs?" answer without thinking &#8220;so they can hide from the &#8220;Kassams". In the city there's absolutely no work being done with the children. They have been abandoned to figure things out on their own. "

"In the past month we have helped these children and done something for them. 10 children were given a summer rest free of the sound of siren signaling an imminent bombing. We have given these children, even if for a short time, something they don't have at home: happiness, safety, and care."

we just want to bring awareness to this very very serious problem/issue that the city of Sderot is facing.
And just know, we CAN and WILL make a difference with your support.

1. Let these kids have a safer life</description>
  <mission>Raise money for after school programs for these kis</mission>
  <name>Children of Sderot</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8795</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">628</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">18.02</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/wY/a3/Bp/Wk/Cn/kb/gcLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
