<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our names are Amberly and Kelly. We live in New Jersey and are both recovering from Anorexia Nervosa. We met in a treatment center, Avalon Hills in Utah, and have been inseparable ever since. We both have had a long hard battle with this disease, but now are both 100% set on recovery and are doing well. Each and everyday we are choosing health! We invite you to choose health with us! Unfortunately, eating disorders are becoming more and more common everyday. Over 5 million women and 1 million men struggle with an eating disorder in the United States alone. Our goal is to have more people pledge to choose health, then people who are diagnosed with eating disorders. We encourage everyone, recovering from an eating disorder or not, to see the importance of health and choose it! Help us spread the word! Our plan is to start small, by selling &#8220;i choose health&#8221; tee-shirts to raise money. We have designed tank tops that symbolize how the importance of health over societal standards of beauty. On the front is the outline of a skeleton with a superimposed purple heart, to symbolize recovery and how one&#8217;s health should be more important, and ,more highly valued, than thinness. On the back is the message &#8220;I choose health&#8221;. These shirts are available in sizes M-2XL. All of our money will go to men and women who have struggled with an eating disorder, and now are recovering, but are unable to fulfill their dreams of college, graduate school, law school, or whatever it may because of finacial problems due to the prices we must pay for treatment. Our philosophy is... So many people get rewarded for being unhealthy, why not reward those who are fought hard, and now have choosen to have their health back.  email us at ichoosehealth@hotmail.com 

1. People who have fought eating disorders and won the battle deserve rewards

2. Eating Disorders are becomming more and more common every day and we must know more about them</description>
  <mission>make eating disorders more aware and stress the importance of choosing health</mission>
  <name>I CHOOSE HEALTH</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8796</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">116</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yb/WO/r4/n2/W7/YS/0zRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
