<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Equality Maryland is Maryland's largest LGBT civil rights group, with thousands of members across the entire state. Equality Maryland includes:

    * a 501(c)(4) advocacy organization that lobbies in Annapolis and across the state to create equal protection under the law for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender (LGBT) Marylanders and their families;
    * a 501(c)(3) educational foundation that works to eliminate prejudice and discrimination based upon sexual orientation and gender identity through outreach, education, research, community organizing, training and coalition building; and
    * Equality Maryland PAC, which exists to influence elections.

Equality Maryland works to secure and protect the rights of LGBT Marylanders by promoting legislative initiatives on the state, county and municipal levels. Our professional lobbyists and legislative team work with our allies in the General Assembly to shape and pass positive legislation in Annapolis and to beat back discriminatory legislation.

Equality Maryland's sister arm, the Equality Maryland Foundation, works to eliminate prejudice and discrimination against LGBT Marylanders through outreach, education, research, community organizing, training and coalition building.

    * We act as an advocate for LGBT Marylanders.
    * We aim to empower ordinary citizens to become extraordinary activists.
    * We work to provide a strong and unified voice for LGBT concerns in the media.
    * We will tirelessly toil until equal protection under the law has been achieved for all members of our diverse community.

1. LGBT Marylanders and their families deserve equal protection under the law.</description>
  <mission>To eliminate prejudice and discrimination based upon sexual orientation and gender identity in Maryland.</mission>
  <name>Equality Maryland</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8809</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">587</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/CS/lB/ul/1j/H1/AA/MJyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
