<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The National Indian Child Welfare Association (NICWA) is a national voice for American Indian children and families. We are the most comprehensive source of information on American Indian child welfare and the only national American Indian organization focused specifically on the tribal capacity to prevent child abuse and neglect. 

NICWA is a private, non-profit, membership organization based in Portland, Oregon. Our members include tribes, individuals&#8212;both Indian and non-Indian&#8212;and private organizations from around the United States concerned with American Indian child and family issues. Our board of directors is made up of 19 American Indians, and we have a staff of 24, most of whom are American Indians. Together, our partners, board, and staff work to protect the most vital resource of American Indian people&#8212;our children.

Our Vision
Every Indian child must have access to community-based, culturally appropriate services that help them grow up safe, healthy, and spiritually strong - free from abuse, neglect, sexual exploitation, and the damaging effects of substance abuse.

NICWA is unique. It is the only Native American organization focused specifically on issues of child abuse and neglect and tribal capacity to prevent and respond effectively to these problems. Together, our members, board, and staff work to ensure that the most vital resource of Indian people-our children-are protected.

1. To protect the most valuable resource of Indian people - Indian children. 

2. To promote the spiritual strength of Indian children and a positive cultural identity. 

3. To be a strong voice for the needs of Indian children and Indian child welfare programs nationwide.</description>
  <mission>The National Indian Child Welfare Association (NICWA) is dedicated to the well-being of American Indian children and families.</mission>
  <name>Protect Our Children &#8226; Preserve Our Culture</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8816</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5952</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">783.06</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/XA/JC/T1/NI/Wt/cP/DE/igS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
