<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>First launched in 1987, the cost-effective YVC model has since been established in communities nationwide. Programs are sponsored locally by such diverse community-based organizations as Volunteer Centers, the YMCA, United Way, school districts, RSVP offices, and municipalities. Funding is provided by foundations, corporations, individuals, United Ways, and local and federal government. While each local community's YVC program is tailored to meet unique community needs, the program consists of two fundamental components: 

Summer Component 
In the summer, young people volunteer on teams supervised by trained Team Leaders, who are generally of college age. Volunteers work on their projects full time Monday through Friday for two or four weeks at a time. The intensive design of the summer component reinforces teamwork skills, appreciation for diversity and civic responsibility. 


School-Year Component 
During the school year, YVC Program Directors and staff work closely with teachers to design and implement age-appropriate service projects that tie school curriculum to community service. In addition, young people from throughout the community work together on service projects after school, on weekends and during school breaks.

1. To engage young people in service projects that are challenging, rewarding and educational. 

2. To serve the unmet needs of the community and its residents. 

3. To promote among young people a greater understanding and appreciation for the diversity of their community. 

4. To promote a lifetime ethic of service among young people. </description>
  <mission>To create and increase volunteer opportunities to enrich America's youth, address community needs and develop a lifetime commitment to service.</mission>
  <name>Youth Volunteer Corps of America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8824</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">79</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DP/MR/Dw/bi/e8/Dh/v02S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
