<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It is quite evident that poverty is one of the most paramount issues facing our world today. The nation of Guatemala located in Central America is one of many countries that lay victim to poverty, due mainly to unequal land distribution and years of civil war spurred on by racial discrimination against those Guatemalans of Mayan descent. Guatemala has also experienced natural disasters such as floods and earthquakes, which have also contributed to the extremity of the nation's poverty.

Today, poverty in Guatemala is made manifest by  the following statistics:
50,000 people live in a ditch since the earthquake of 1976.
11,000 squatters live at the city dump and live off its trash.
5,000 homeless children live in the streets of Guatemala City.

It is the mission and purpose of Christian Cultural Center in Brooklyn, New York to provide food and clothing to these people. We will also be building homes for the homeless as well as assist in building churches. But most importantly we desire to give those who are homeless and without money something greater than material things. We desire to present to them the gift of reconciliation through our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ. 

But we can by no means fulfill these dreams without your help in donations. So I ask you to put your own desires beside, and help a person in Guatemala escape out of that prison we call poverty by extending a helping hand towards them.






1. Poverty is a problem that can be cured, because there are 3 people in the world who have more money than 48 Third World Countries

2. There are 7 wealthy people in the world that can by themselves bring an end to poverty

3. The main cause of the perpetuation of poverty is the pursuits of the rich</description>
  <mission>Put smiles on the faces of poor, helpless children and adults in Guatemala</mission>
  <name>Help put an end to poverty in Guatemala</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8827</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">114</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0T/HB/oG/lJ/f2/48/qJmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
