<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>NORML Canada is a non-profit, public interest, member operated and funded group, chartered at the federal level in Canada since 1978. The organization aims to eliminate all civil and criminal penalties for private marijuana use &#8211; through government lobbying, public education, research, and legislative and judicial challenges. NORML Canada believes that the present policy of discouraging marijuana use through the use of criminal and/or civil law has been excessively costly and harmful to both society and the individual. 

1. That it is the right of every adult to use, possess, produce, and distribute cannabis &#8211; whether for recreational, medicinal or industrial purposes.

2. That in Canada, a constitutional democracy governed by the Charter of Rights and Freedoms, there is a consensus that governments should not interfere with the liberty of the citizen, unless the conduct in question presents a serious, substantial, or signi

3. That cannabis is a relatively benign substance that has been used safely by many millions of Canadians. Nonetheless, it is recognized and accepted that the criminal law prohibits driving a vehicle while one's ability to do so is impaired by any psychoacti

4. That the continued application of the stigmatizing label of &#8220;criminal&#8221; to a voluntary and informed choice made by over 3,000,000 Canadians can only serve to foster widespread disrespect for the administration of the law, and of criminal justice in par

5. That cannabis should be fully legalized, and that its use, production, and distribution be properly regulated and taxed by provincial and local governments, much like alcohol and gambling.

6. That an acceptable interim step in moving towards full "legalization" would be the "decriminalization" of possession and small-scale production of cannabis sativa, where decriminalization is defined as the removal of all criminal or civil sanctions &#8211; in

7. That the production of cannabis is not inherently dangerous and that both medical and recreational users should have the right to grow their own cannabis, subject only to zoning by-laws and building permit requirements. However, patients who use cannabis </description>
  <mission>eliminate all civil and criminal penalties for private marijuana use &#8211; through government lobbying, public education, research, and legislative and judicial challenges</mission>
  <name>NORML Canada</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8829</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">304</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2r/E5/b7/3b/J4/N6/aRUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
