<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Please sign if you want open captioning in movie theaters.. if you support the hard of hearing and deaf community. Send the link to your friends if you want this.  I want to see this at all movie theaters, not just certain ones on certain days at certain times.  Equal access for the deaf needs to happen!

Why should the deaf be segregated from the hearing?  People don't realize that we have civil rights too, just like the African Americans fought for their liberties.. The deaf culture is doing the same thing.  So step on board..

Speak up, share your opinion..  Are you for it or against it?  Tell us why.  There are over 50 million people that are deaf and hard of hearing in the United States...  That is 50 million people that aren't getting to enjoy the movies at the theaters like a hearing person is.

NOT ONLY ARE MOVIE THEATERS AN ISSUE, BUT EDUCATIONAL VIDEOS IN SCHOOL/COLLEGE STILL DON'T HAVE CLOSED CAPTIONING, AND DVD SPECIAL FEATURES DON'T HAVE CLOSED CAPTIONING.  WHAT IS GOING ON?  HAVEN'T THESE PEOPLE EVER HEARD OF ADA?!!?!?

Also, we need to realize that this is a baby booming age.. People are aging and are losing their hearing.  AND things such as IPODS, concerts, etc.. are causing people to lose hearing everyday.. and they could reap the benefit of having captions mandated in all theaters one day too.  LISTEN UP POLITICIANS AND MOVIE THEATER OWNERS!

http://www.petitiononline.com/92284/petition.html

Watch this video if you want to learn more.

http://youtube.com/watch?v=hKnF9CCYQPQ


1. The deaf and hard of hearing are still discriminated against in every country in the world.

2. We are people too, and like to watch movies and tv just like everyone else.

3. ADA hasn't been enforcing this.</description>
  <mission>To provide equal access for the deaf and hard of hearing.... AND KILL REAR WINDOW CAPTIONING (Most theaters don't have this anyways, but it SUCKS.. :)!!!  </mission>
  <name>OPEN CAPTIONING IN MOVIE THEATERS (VIDEOS SHOWN IN SCHOOL, AND ON DVD SPECIAL FEATURES)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8830</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20969</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.38</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/i0/oe/yK/Ml/vZ/DG/VGnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
