<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>People in other countries are literally dying for what we throw away.

IMAGINE going to the hospital and being unable to receive treatment because basic materials-bandages, needles, suture, syringes, blood pressure units-are unavailable. In the United States this situation is unthinkable. However, in many developing countries this happens every day. People around the world are literally dying for lack of even the most basic medical supplies.

At the same time, every year U.S. hospitals throw away an estimated 2,000 tons of unused surgical supplies worth over $200 million. This still useful material often ends up being landfilled or incinerated&#8212;needlessly adding to the pollution problem and the cost of healthcare in the United States.

Global Links is a registered 501(c)3 not-for-profit organization that recovers surplus medical materials from U.S. hospitals and makes it available to hospitals that serve the poorest members of society in less developed countries.

Because poorly planned donations can be worse than no aid at all, each donation is carefully tailored to meet the needs of the recipient institution. Dedicated volunteers help Global Links to maintain high quality standards and low costs. Global Links spends less than 3% on overhead costs. 

1. To reduce the amount of still useful surplus medical supplies that are needlessly thrown away in the United States.

2. To provide targeted hospitals in developing countries with the ability to better treat their patients, and expand services.</description>
  <mission>donate surplus medical supplies to targeted hospitals in developing countries.</mission>
  <name>Global Links</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8833</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">14</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1E/RE/QA/Vs/Qr/cH/mf7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
