<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hope is a hypnotic word. It rises in the midst of death and despair, when everything else is stinking of moulds and ashes. Hope creates ripples in stagnant thoughts, static mindsets. At a time when life holds no charm, Charles Jackson is of the opinion that hope comes about as a comforting factor which at first stays dormant, yet manacing and finally engulfs the excruciating pain that the harrowing experiences have caused. Above all, HOPE IS A VISION.

And Hertz Helpers Foundation is one such organisation that dreams of this vision. We are a team of young aspiring people who want to help mankind by making a discernible difference in our poverty-stricken society. We want to eradicate hunger and replace drooping attitudes with smiling faces resulting from the traumatic experiences suffered by the earthquake victims. We are going to promote primary education, instil in the minds of the younger generation that life has a world to offer ahead.

We know we cannot win overnight. Success will require sustained action over decades. It takes time to train quality teachers, nurses and engineers; to build roads, schools and hospitals; to grow our small and large integrated networks which are able to create the jobs and income needed. So we must start now. And we must struggle through it until we achieve our goal. This goal of serving humanity , of building lives from scratch.

1. To create job opportunities for poor men and women who became the victims of the devasting disasters that took place in Pakistan in the past

2. To support and groom poor children intellectually by providing them the primary education.

3. To build houses for the people who had lost their homes in any of the  disasters that took place in the past.</description>
  <mission>To help mankind by making a discernible difference in our poverty-stricken society.</mission>
  <name>Hertz Helpers Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8837</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">13</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yu/mM/Ee/ut/gS/qM/FCiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
