<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Organizaci&#243;n Chico Mendez was founded in honor of the Brazilian activist by a man named Jorge Armando Lopez in the town of Cantel, Quetzaltenango, Guatemala. Organizacion Chico Mendez strives to educate the community about the importance of reforestation, and the interconnectedness of all life and the natural environment. The organization plants trees because it believes in renewing oxygen for future generations and wants to ensure that the water that runs from the mountains remains pure for everyone to enjoy. In addition, Organizacion Chico Mendez is working to prevent the privatization of water in the region. In order to make the organization a self-sustaining project, they have partnered with the most highly respected language school in Guatemala: Proyecto
Linguistico, which offered to build the classrooms and train the teachers for a language school with an ecological focus. Organizacion Chico Mendez must only come up with the money to purchase the land. Lopez has located a piece of suitable piece of land at a reasonable price and we have decided to help him raise the funds to purchase it. We have until the end of August to raise the money.
Please consider making a tax deductible donation to so that Organizacion Chico Mendez can purchase the land for the language school. If you are interested in
making a donation online, please visit globalyouthconnect.org/donate and click on "make a donation." Under item, type "Chico Mendez"; under unit price, type the amount you wish to donate; click update totals; then, click "continue" or log into paypal. You can also make out a check to Global Youth Connect, write Chico Mendez in the memo,
and send it to:
Global Youth Connect
15 Gage Street
Kingston, NY 12401

1. Save the environment!</description>
  <mission>fundraise enough money so this wonderful organization from Guatemala can start a language shool and obtain self sustainability</mission>
  <name>Chico Mendes fundraiser!!!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8847</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">34</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yt/BK/gT/eO/31/Rk/rypS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
