<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Denielle  has crohns and colitis since she was 7 she has 3 brothers and none of them have it .. it suppose to be genitic so lets hope that we help  find a cure before there children have it . ... here is some info on the disease 

Crohn's Disease and Ulcerative Colitis are inflammatory bowel diseases that are characterized by inflamation of the gastrointestinal tracts (anywhere for Crohn's and specifically the colon for people with colitis). The main gastrointestinal symptoms are abdominal pain and weight loss.While ulcerative colitis is curable through the removal of part of all of a patients colon, Crohn's is not. Instead, a number of medical treatments are utilized with the goal of putting and keeping the disease in remission. These include steroid medications &amp; immunomodulators. Crohn's disease affects between 400,000 and 600,000 people in North America. Although the cause of Crohn's disease is not known, it is widely believed to be an autoimmune disease. Crohn's disease often develops in the teenage years, though individuals in their 60s and 70s are also at increased risk. Ulcerative colitis is a rare disease, with an incidence of about one person per 10,000 in North America. There is no known cause for these two diseases though it is thought to be genetic. 

There more kids in cape Breton with crhons then any where else in the world....lets try to help them find  a cure for this disease 
I started this cause for my Daughter Denielle who has crhons and knows the pain that it causes... At sixteen she already has osteoporosis because of the disease, has broke her spine, and suffers daily ..from either the drugs to maintain the disease,, or the disease its self.. 

1. drugs that will help keep this desease in remission </description>
  <mission>help find a cure </mission>
  <name>crohns Disease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8855</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1940</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/JH/mj/fo/hq/PB/nv/e2qS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
