<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;http://www.fremont-education.org
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
The Fremont Education Foundation is a non-profit, tax-exempt, public charity, established in 1991, to encourage increased community involvement and investment in our schools.  Our members include parents, educators, school administrators, business people, and others from our community.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
We are an independent foundation that works closely with, but is separate from, the Fremont Unified School District.  

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 

Our Achievements
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
The Fremont Education Foundation has:   
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
    * Awarded over 97 classroom grants over the past 12 years.  Students at 38 elementary, junior high and high schools have benefited from these grants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
    * Established after-school band programs at all 27 elementary schools in Fremont, beginning with the 2000-2001 academic year.   This program represents the first time Fremont's elementary students have been able to participate in band instruction on their campuses in over 10 years. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
    * Launched a major new program to provide sports equipment and sports wear scholarships to FUSD high school students, starting with the 2003-2004 academic year.   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 

Our Fundraising&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 

We rely on the following sources for funds:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 

    * Personal donations&lt;br /&gt;
    * Corporate donations&lt;br /&gt;
    * Foundation grants&lt;br /&gt;
    * Annual Telethon&lt;br /&gt;
    * Annual &#8220;Excellence in Education&#8221; gala&lt;br /&gt;
    * Other fundraising events 

1. Program 1:  After-School Band

2. Program 2:  Innovative Education Grants

3. Program 3:  Guy Emanuele Sports Fund</description>
  <mission>encourage increased community involvement and investment in our schools.</mission>
  <name>Support Fremont Education Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8857</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">203</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">40.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/y5/1v/Wc/NH/2i/ka/aKJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
