<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Beh&#231;et's disease is common in the Middle East, Asia, and Japan. It is rare in the United States. In Middle Eastern and Asian countries, the disease affects more men than women. In the United States, it affects more women than men. Beh&#231;et's disease tends to develop in people in their 20's or 30's, but people of all ages can develop this disease. Beh&#231;et's disease is an autoimmune disease that results from damage to blood vessels throughout the body, particularly veins. In an autoimmune disease, the immune system attacks and harms the bodies' own tissues. The exact cause of Beh&#231;et's disease is unknown.  Beh&#231;et's disease is not contagious; it is not spread from one person to another. Beh&#231;et's disease affects each person differently. The four most common symptoms (as listed) are mouth sores, genital sores, inflammation inside of the eye, and skin problems. Inflammation inside of the eye occurs in more that half of those with Beh&#231;et's disease and can cause blurred vision, pain, and redness. Other symptoms may include arthritis, blood clots, and inflammation in the central nervous system and digestive organs. "
Prepared by NINDS. Credit goes to the NINDS and the NIH. Pictures courtesy of Johns Hopkins University on behalf of its Division of Rheumatology &amp; ABDA. Copyrights reserved.

Please visit The American Behcet's Disease Association's website for more information. http://www.behcets.com/site/pp.asp?c=bhJIJSOCJrH&amp;b=260521

Other sites that may be helpful:

http://www.behcets.org.uk

1. Bring information to people

2. Help raise money for research</description>
  <mission>Bring information to people who have never heard of this, and give those who have it a support system</mission>
  <name>Behcets - The unknown disease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8870</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">935</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">308.35</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/zC/Z3/ok/cH/X1/za/wjYS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
