<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A little about Michael Bloomberg:
He is currently the Mayor of New York City and the founder of the Bloomberg media company. Though a lifelong democrat, he ran on the republican ticket in 2001 for mayor. In June 2007 he left the republican party and is currently an independent and an ideal candidate for a third party. 

Bloomberg's stances and accomplishments as mayor:

Gay Marriage-

"My personal opinion is that anybody should be allowed to marry anybody. I don't happen to think we should put restrictions on who you should marry"

Public Health- 

Bloomberg extended New York City's smoking ban to all commercial establishments, including bars and nightclubs. 
On 5 December 2006, New York became the first city in the United States to ban trans-fat from all restaurants. It will go into effect in July of 2008

Enviroment-

Bloomberg is transforming all city cabs and buses into hybrids

Immigration-

He argues that deportation breaks up families and scares illegal immigrants away from cooperating with law enforcement or accessing vital social services.

Gun Control-

Bloomberg is a strong advocate of gun control and made it a major issue of his administration in his second inaugural address. "I don't know why people carry guns. Guns kill people..." 

Death Penalty- (watch)
http://youtube.com/watch?v=O3dIJfaqSHc



1. Bloomberg for President</description>
  <mission>draft Michael Bloomberg as a Presidential Candidate through Unity08.com
It would be nice to have "more voices and more choices" in 2008, especially if it is some republican vs Hillary. 

</mission>
  <name>Michael Bloomberg for President '08 (official)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8871</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">28</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/L7/El/he/Kl/i0/OF/w2lS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
