<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is Dance Marathon you ask? Dance Marathon is the largest student-run philanthropic organization at Iowa State. We are students working together with the Iowa community, reaching out to promote awareness of the Children's Miracle Network and &amp; University of Iowa Children's Hospital. Since 1998, students have come to Dance Marathon to celebrate the children survivors &amp; remember the children who have passed away throughout the year. 

We give financial and emotional support to local Iowa families with children that have life threatening illnesses.  All the donations raised go directly to the University of Iowa Children&#8217;s Hospital through the Children&#8217;s Miracle Network.  

Last year, 537 students packed the Memorial Union, standing on their feet for 15 hours helping to raise $160,664.19 for Children&#8217;s Miracle Network, benefiting children &amp; families right here in Iowa. This year's event will be held on January 26th, 2008, &amp; promises to be even bigger &amp; better than before!

How do you get involved? SIGN UP TO BE A DANCER! If you decide to become a dancer, there is a $25 registration fee &amp; you are asked to raise $200. But don't worry, you're not on your own here. We hold letter writing sessions, organized canning events, &amp; give you the option of allowing people to donate online. Raising the money is easy. Now the best part: the day of. The day of Dance Marathon is a 15 hour bonanza of fun, games, &amp; dancing. But don't be fooled by the name, you don't need to dance for 15 hours...you can go the whole day not dancing at all. We just ask that you stay on your feet the entire time. Plus, all of the children the money is helping will be there to play with &amp; tell you face to face how much they appreciate all that you do. So go ahead, register, raise the money, &amp; change the life of a child forever.

Register online @ www.dm.stuorg.iastate.edu

1. Kickin' it for the kids!

2. Give a day - change a life.

3. Many hearts, one beat.</description>
  <mission>provide financial and emotional support to local Iowa families with children that have life threatening illnesses.  </mission>
  <name>Iowa State University Dance Marathon</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8872</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">304</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Z6/Ik/1r/qa/J5/1Q/GRxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
