<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Bush administration has continued to place the National forests of Missouri in the "For Sale" ads to pay for underfunded rural school systems across America. This is the most flagrant assault on Missouri's Mark Twain National Forest by the Bush administraion and it's cronies, but most certainly will not be the last. The PERMANANT selling of about 
21, 500 acres of Missouri's forest to pay for a TEMPORARY lack of funding seems to be rather silly, and, a short term solution to a long term problem. If this is allowed, every time a government funded program is under funded (perish the thought), we'll sell off another hunk of natural beauty to compensate for the PRESIDENT'S misuse of OUR tax dollars. And, if things continue to go the way this administration would like, after all of the forests are gone they'll sell our houses to pay for a new solid gold toilet seat for Air Force One (Halliburton would definitely be paid six figures to install it). Since the Presidents actions (and speeches) have proven that he is not capable of listening to reason (and all coherent thought) we must let congress thwart his current evil efforts (there will certainly be more during the rest of his term) with political pressure from the only people he seems to care about.....wealthy politicians. If any of you know an oil executive who'd join the cause, our forests would be safe until Bush and friends are out of public (dis)service for good. This is a non-partisan cause, if a different party is in office (hopefully in 09') we must still fight for what we COULD SOON lose....and CAN'T EVER get back.

There is currently a proposal to establish 49,323 acres of designated wilderness areas, but we need a political sponsor....we seem to have anti-environment politicians in Missouri as well as sitting idly by in the white house.

"If people in general could be got out into the woods, even for once, to hear the trees speak for themselves, all difficulties in the way of forest preservation would vanish."....John Muir

Show them what they're missing.

1. Stop the destruction of Missouri's forests.

2. Make Missouri people aware of our forest's peril.

3. Act Now.</description>
  <mission>Ensure that our children have the same access to beautiful forests in Missouri as our ancestors did.</mission>
  <name>Protect Missouri's Forests</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8878</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">91</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/S8/o0/RO/yC/0C/rw/j3kS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
