<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Operation H2O was founded and is led by a group of students dedicated to making clean water accessible to those in need around the world. When they read the chapter in The Revolution: A Field Manual for Changing Your World (check this book out, it's amazing) about the lack of clean water in some parts in the world, they decided that they could not just sit back and do nothing.

It is estimated that about 1.1 BILLION PEOPLE in our world have no access to clean water. The water that they do have access to is infested with parasites and deadly bacteria, causing illnesses and diseases that are unimaginable to us in the United States. These people have only two options: 1) don't drink the water and suffer from dehydration and eventually die OR 2) drink the parasite infested water and die of a water-borne illness. (Wikipedia "Guinea Worm" and be prepared to be grossed out.)

This is not a way to live.

Team Operation H2O is currently working on holding fundraisers in different high schools and churches in their county. They recently hosted a benefit concert for the cause and are planning to host a coffee shop later this year to raise more money and awareness of this social injustice.  All the money that is collected will go to Blood:Water Mission (check out www.bloodwatermission.com) and their 1000 Wells Project (check out www.1000wells.com).

1. Clean water should be accessible to EVERYONE in the world.

2. In an age that is so technologically advanced, humans should not be suffering or dying from treatable conditions, such as diarrhea or worms.</description>
  <mission>help people around the world gain access to clean water.</mission>
  <name>Operation H2O</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8892</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">70</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/YB/GE/qh/Bj/r4/F6/G0QS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
