<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Each year about 65,000 U.S.-raised students who would qualify for the DREAM Act&#8217;s benefits graduate from high school. These include honor roll students, star athletes, talented artists, homecoming queens, and aspiring teachers, doctors, and U.S. soldiers. They are young people who have lived in the U.S. for most of their lives and desire only an opportunity. Even though they were brought to the U.S. years ago as children, they face unique barriers to higher education, are unable to work legally in the U.S., and often live in constant fear of detection by immigration authorities.


The &#8220;DREAM Act&#8221; and &#8220;American Dream Act&#8221; provide an opportunity for U.S.-raised
students to earn U.S. citizenship. The &#8220;DREAM Act&#8221; would allow certain immigrant
students to adjust their status to that of a legal permanent resident on a conditional
basis for six years based on the following requirements:
&#9687; Age. Immigrant students must have entered the U.S. before age 16.
&#9687; Academic requirement. Students must have been accepted for admission into a twoor
four-year institution of higher education or have earned a high school diploma or a
general educational development (GED) certificate at the time of application for relief. or served in the U.S. armed forces for at least 2 years.
&#9687; Long-term U.S. residence. Students must reside in the U.S. when the law is
enacted. In addition, those eligible must have lived in the U.S. for at least five years
preceding the date of enactment of the Act.
&#9687; Good moral character. Immigrant students must demonstrate good moral character, a
defined term in immigration law. In general, students must have no criminal record.

1. Education (at any level) is a universal right.

2. Not helping students' attend college results in much greater costs to the state and contributes to an uneducated workforce</description>
  <mission>Lobby our senators and representatives to pass the Development, Relief and Education for Alien Minors Act. </mission>
  <name>Passage of the DREAM Act.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8894</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">18167</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">240.24</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/6X/wT/ix/WF/AF/N6/Bd/1CS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
