<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Transcendentalism was a group of new ideas in literature, religion, culture, and philosophy that emerged in New England in the early to middle 19th century. It is sometimes called American Transcendentalism to distinguish it from other uses of the word transcendental.

Transcendentalism began as a protest against the general state of culture and society at the time, and in particular, the state of intellectualism at Harvard and the doctrine of the Unitarian church which was taught at Harvard Divinity School. Among Transcendentalists' core beliefs was an ideal spiritual state that 'transcends' the physical and empirical and is only realized through the individual's intuition, rather than through the doctrines of established religions.

Prominent Transcendentalists included Ralph Waldo Emerson, Henry David Thoreau, Margaret Fuller, as well as Bronson Alcott, Orestes Brownson, William Ellery Channing, Frederick Henry Hedge, Theodore Parker, George Putnam, and Sophia Peabody, the wife of Nathaniel Hawthorne. For a time, Peabody and Hawthorne lived at the Brook Farm Transcendentalist utopian commune."

http://www.walden.org/
http://www.suntomoon.com/pages/waldenwoods.html



Intuition is a person's most precious gift, I firmly believe that the world needs to get in touch with them selves and nature, keep and remain in a state of complete concentration. Going off of one's quick keen inisight will only insure one's ablity to tune into not only the world but the sub-conscience of the mind.

1. Nature

2. Be you

3. Self-enlightenment

4. Power of the mind

5. The art of walking</description>
  <mission>to enlight the general public to the power of nature</mission>
  <name>The Spread of Transcendentalism</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8897</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">77</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/XV/Sd/CP/gA/AF/ah/BFGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
