<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our mission statement:
The RSPCA as a charity will, by all lawful means, prevent cruelty, promote kindness to and alleviate suffering of animals.

The RSPCA intends to achieve its mission by:

effecting strong branch, regional, national and international organisations dedicated to providing a public service, delivering effective relief of animal suffering and enforcing the law


working tirelessly to reduce the harmful impact of human activities on animals through education, campaigning and the application of ethics, science and law


striving for the highest levels of efficiency, effectiveness and integrity


urging that, save where the public benefit requires, humankind should not intentionally cause suffering to any animal when it is not for its own benefit, or cause suffering by neglect. This applies whatever the animal, or the situation in which it finds itself.

Charitable status: 
The RSPCA is a registered charity (no. 219099) that receives no lottery or state aid. Its &#163;82 million annual running costs are funded exclusively by voluntary donations and legacies. 

To read the RSPCA Acts and the Society's current rules click here. Please note that this content will open in a new browser window.

How YOU can help: 
- If you know about an animal that is injured or being treated cruelly, call the RSPCA's national 24-hour cruelty and advice line on 0870 55 55 999. 
- Campaign for new animal welfare laws. 
- Make a donation to the RSPCA to help the Society achieve even more for animals. 
- Become a member of the RSPCA and support its work. 
- Become a volunteer at your local RSPCA branch and help out with practical animal welfare work, or fundraising.

To find out more about how charities use your money, how fundraising is regulated and what to do if you have a complaint visit www.charityfacts.org 

1. Effecting

2. Working

3. Striving

4. Urging</description>
  <mission>The RSPCA's vision is to work for a world in which all humans respect and live in harmony with all other members of the animal kingdom.</mission>
  <name>RSPCA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8898</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">14657</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">192.39</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qv/6K/nH/Ax/b0/vf/oIOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
