<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Why MS?

Having multiple sclerosis means that you may suddenly have blurry vision. Or that your memory will fail you for no apparent reason. Or that you may not always be able to walk, let alone ride a bike. The symptoms of MS are different, and devastating, for everyone - the only certainty is that it will affect yet another person every hour of every day.

Why I Ride.

This is my 7th year riding in the City to Shore MS150. I began riding in 7th grade, but now I have even more of a reason to ride. I ride on the Jessters, a team made for my friend who was diagnosed with MS in college. I ride to help her keep "living strong" and to raise money to fight MS. 

Why You Should Sponsor Me!

The National Multiple Sclerosis Society will use funds collected from the MS Bike Tour to not only support research for a cure tomorrow, but also to provide programs which address the needs of people living with MS today. Because we can fight this disease by simply riding a bike, because we have chosen to help thousands of people through a contribution to the MS Bike Tour, we are now getting closer to the hour when no one will have to hear the words, "You have MS." I will ride the whole race to support this cause. 

TO SPONSOR ME, PLEASE CLICK ON MY PERSONAL PAGE!!!

"My Personal Page"
http://www.nationalmssociety.org/site/TR?px=1869835&amp;pg=personal&amp;fr_id=2750&amp;s_tafId=4211 

"The Jessters Team Page"
http://www.nationalmssociety.org/site/TR?team_id=4001&amp;pg=team&amp;fr_id=2750&amp;s_tafId=4211


1. We ride to support a future free of MS.</description>
  <mission>help find a cure for MS, and to help those inflicted with the disease.</mission>
  <name>MS 150 City to Shore Bike Tour</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8911</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">36</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">120.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Dn/B6/ui/JR/XE/ud/AkPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
