<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Anti-Nazi League (ANL) was an organisation set up on the initiative of the Socialist Workers' Party with some sponsorship (and a few small financial donations) from some trade unions and the endorsement of a list of prominent people in 1977 to oppose the rise of what they deemed to be far-right groups in Britain. It was at its height between 1977 and 1981. The initial sponsors included Peter Hain (a former Young Liberal leader; then the communications officer of the postal workers' union UCW, more recently Secretary of State for Northern Ireland), Ernie Roberts (deputy general secretary of the engineering union AUEW) and Paul Holborow (of the Socialist Workers Party (SWP))Most of the ANL's activities in the 1970s were in opposition to the National Front, an organisation led by John Tyndall who had a long history of involvement with openly fascist and Nazi groups. The ANL also campaigned against the British Movement which was a more openly Hitlerite grouping. The ANL was allowed to run down in the early 1980s.[citation needed]

The organisation was revived in 1992. In the 1990s its main efforts have been to oppose the British National Party, which denies that it is a Nazi Party (while retaining many of the policies and members from the fascist National Front plus newer far right ideologies such the "third position" adopted by many Italian fascists such as Roberto Fiore - with whom the BNP maintain regular contact).[1]

The organization was also critical of the government of Italian Prime Minister Silvio Berlusconi, which was an alliance of centre-right and far right political parties. It was merged into Unite Against Fascism in 2004.



1. Love music, hate racism

2. Unite against fascism

3. Build the resistance</description>
  <mission>To Unite against fascism</mission>
  <name>The new Anti Nazi League</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8917</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">222</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/te/ED/CL/27/8O/Lf/OM6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
