<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Ban Dihydrogen Monoxide!

Dihydrogen monoxide is colorless, odorless, tasteless, and kills uncounted thousands of people every year. Most of these deaths are caused by accidental inhalation of DHMO, but the dangers of dihydrogen monoxide do not end there. Prolonged exposure to its solid form causes severe tissue damage. Symptoms of DHMO ingestion can include excessive sweating and urination, and possibly a bloated feeling, nausea, vomiting and body electrolyte imbalance. For those who have become dependent, DHMO withdrawal means certain death. 

Despite the danger, dihydrogen monoxide is often used: 

as an industrial solvent and coolant. 
in nuclear power plants. 
in the production of styrofoam. 
as a fire retardant. 
in many forms of cruel animal research. 
in the distribution of pesticides. Even after washing, produce remains contaminated by this chemical. 
as an additive in certain "junk-foods" and other food products. 
Companies dump waste DHMO into rivers and the ocean, and nothing can be done to stop them because this practice is still legal. The impact on wildlife is extreme, and we cannot afford to ignore it any longer! 

The Horror Must Be Stopped!

The American government has refused to ban the production, distribution, or use of this damaging chemical due to its "importance to the economic health of this nation." In fact, the navy and other military organizations are conducting experiments with DHMO, and designing multi-billion dollar devices to control and utilize it during warfare situations. Hundreds of military research facilities receive tons of it through a highly sophisticated underground distribution network. Many store large quantities for later use. 



1. Dihydrogen Monoxide is potentially lethal.</description>
  <mission>Ban the use and proliferation of Dihydrogen Monoxide, a potentially fatal agent.</mission>
  <name>Ban Dihydrogen Monoxide</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8921</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">117</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vj/eE/jv/8v/8b/Mf/PHKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
