<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>(from http://www.soar-usa.org/published/about_us.html )

SOAR! was established as the direct result of an article that appeared in the Wall Street Journal and which brought to public awareness the disturbing fact that the retirement needs of women and men religious in the United States have reached critical proportions. This information proved a source of shock and concern to the public.

A 2004 survey prepared by the Religious Retirement Office (NRRO) indicates a $7.4 billion shortfall in funds needed for religious elderly. As a result, many religious institutions have limited resources to care for elderly and infirm members. This is an astounding and distressing reality. The average annual social security benefit for religious is $4,125 compared to $11,064 for lay recipients.


SOAR! was established in August, 1986. It was formed through the initiative of a concerned group of lay people as a vehicle for further raising national public awareness of the religious retirement crisis, for networking concerned laity, and for providing financial resources to religious communities to assist them in the care of their elderly members.


1. We are committed to to raising and providing funds for congregations to meet immediate needs of their retired members

2. We are committed to educating the public about the serious retirement needs confronting elderly religious

3. We are committed to developing a national network of concerned individuals who wish to respond to this need</description>
  <mission>Assuring financially stable and personally secure futures for elderly and frail members of Catholic religious congregations in the United States, augmenting the efforts of the institutional Church.</mission>
  <name>Support Our Aging Religious</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8928</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">50</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">80.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xX/k1/iF/Hy/zF/TG/EgCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
