<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Born in Ponce, PR, possessed of a continual smile and an attitude of &#8220;this has a solution!&#8221; Manuel Rafael &#8220;Felo&#8221; Candamo was an excellent student, and for a time was the fastest reader in Puerto Rico. Unable to afford to finish college after the death of his father and mother, he joined the US Air Force and served with distinction in the intelligence field, earning numerous medals and traveling the Mediterranean and Eastern Europe. Upon leaving the service, he became an entrepreneur whose broad ranging curiosity led him to work on projects ranging from robotics to fusion to nanotechnology and tele-medicine, primarily to benefit his beloved Puerto Rico and other Caribbean countries. Through it all, he was the ultimate &#8220;connector&#8221;, maintaining touch with childhood friends, making new friends in every place he visited and linking everyone for their mutual benefit. He always believed in the strength of an individual, and their ability to join him in his quest to assist a community or a country face new challenges, through his innovative approach to problem-solving. His most important mission was helping to raise his daughter, Gloria Mercedes, with his wife Janet. The Manuel &#8220;Felo&#8221; Candamo Memorial Fund has been established at the Community Foundation of the National Capital Region to support causes that were of great importance in Manuel&#8217;s life.


1. To provide scholarships to Puerto Rican students motivated to contribute to their communities

2. To support non-profit organizations that foster community development and entrepreneurship

3. To support cancer research, as cancer claimed the lives of his mother, his older sister, and finally of Manuel himself.</description>
  <mission>To provide financial support to Puerto Rican college and college-bound students.</mission>
  <name>Manuel Candamo Scholarship Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8931</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">106</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">225.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/AL/1e/Nu/Y3/uJ/Dn/picS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
