<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>(information supplied by Brent Able, thank you)

We received an email from Childrens Hospital today (see below). In the three years that I have been on their blood donor mailing list, I have never received such a plea so it probably is a serious situation. They are specifically seeking donors of type "O pos" and "O neg" blood.  Would you mind passing this on to any Kiwanians who happen to donate blood or who might be interested in donating?  I clipped the following info from a Children's' Hospital blood donor letter which indicates why donated blood is critical for them:

As Children's continues to grow, so does the demand for blood. Every month more than 860 units of blood and blood products are transfused into sick and injured infants, children, and teens. Currently we collect only 30 to 40 percent of the blood that we need for our patients. Having enough blood available is critical, as kids may require fresh blood 5 days old or less. Blood donated to Children&#8217;s goes directly to our patients &#8211; so miracles happen sooner, rather than later. Babies undergoing heart surgery require blood that is less than five days old. There are countless numbers of children involved in accidents who need blood transfusions almost immediately. Your blood donation will help children with various medical conditions; such as sickle cell anemia, which requires 1 to 10 units of blood per month.

Personally, my son Anthony was the recipient of at least three-four blood transfusions while hospitalized there. I know it is difficult to get downtown for many people but if anyone is able and willing to help, they can call to schedule an appointment @ 202-884-5437 (also see the contact info below). Check out the following webpage for more info on donating blood at Children's':  http://www.dcchildrens.com/dcchildrens/ProgramDisplay.aspx?ProgramId=309

Thanks,

1. Blood donatio saves lives</description>
  <mission>supply vital blood to children</mission>
  <name>Give Children Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8933</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">20</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/aY/8Q/RH/3o/3a/4M/ti1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
