<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Infection with cytomegalovirus (CMV), a member of the herpes virus family, is very common. Between 50% and 85% of people in the United States have had a CMV infection by the time they are 40 years old, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).

Children typically become infected with the virus in early childhood, especially those in child-care and preschool settings. When symptoms do appear, they are similar to those seen in mononucleosis ("mono") and last about 2-3 weeks

CMV is mainly a problem for certain high-risk groups, including:

*Unborn babies whose mothers become infected with CMV during the pregnancy 
*Children or adults whose immune systems have been weakened by disease or drug treatment, such as organ transplant recipients or people infected with HIV 
 **Once a person has had a CMV infection, the virus usually lies dormant (or inactive) in the body, but it can be reactivated. The virus is more likely to be reactivated &#8211; and cause serious illness &#8211; in people who have weakened immune systems due to illness.

My mom was infected with this virus when she was pregnant with my sister, Calli. My brother, Chad, was attending a day care at the time in which is sought to be the beginning. My sister was born, January 26th, 1986. She was 2 weeks premature and she had an enlarged heart. She recieved severe brain damage from the birth. Her heart kept stopping everytime my mom push. Today, my sister is 21 years old and is a wonderful human being. She was diagnosed with Cerebral Palsy and she is 3/4s deaf. But she is absolutely amazing! 

My objective is to create awareness for this virus and help those that have been affected by it. I'm also here for support. I know my sister would answer any questions. :)


1. Help people notice it and treat it!

2. I believe we can create awareness.</description>
  <mission>To create awareness of CMV.
To support those that have been affected by it.</mission>
  <name>Cytomegalovirus (CMV)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8939</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1209</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.44</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/TJ/fx/cH/00/iP/3p/jbIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
