<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Hazon means &#8220;vision.&#8221; Hazon works to create a healthier and more sustainable Jewish community &#8211; as a step towards a healthier and more sustainable world for all.

Hazon is best known for a series of Jewish Environmental Bike Rides, in New York, Washington DC, and Israel which have raised over $2.4 million and given grants of over $1 million to Jewish environmental projects over the past five years. They bring together a remarkably diverse group of Jewish people, foster people&#8217;s Jewish journeys, and inspire participants.  

These health-promoting and Jewishly-inclusive bike rides compliment Hazon&#8217;s food work: Hazon is at the forefront of an emerging national movement at the intersection of food and Jewish life. Hazon&#8217;s food work programs include Tuv Ha&#8217;Aretz, the first Jewish Community-Supported Agriculture (CSA) project in North America; a Food Conference which expects to bring together 200 Jewish chefs, farmers, educators, and food enthusiasts in December; Min Ha&#8217;Aretz, Hazon&#8217;s Family Education Initiative for day school children and their parents on issues of food, health, and Jewish life;  &#8220;Food for Jewish Thought,&#8221; an adult curriculum on the same topic; and &#8220;The Jew &amp; The Carrot&#8221; an award-winning blog at www.JCarrot.org.


1. Since 2000 we have created innovative and powerful programs built around outdoor physical challenge, especially bike rides.  

2. Since 2004, we have developed a second program area, focused on the relationship between Jews, food and contemporary life.

3. Our programs foster community that is passionate, joyful, spiritual and socially progressive; that emphasizes tolerance, respect, dignity and diversity; and that engages people where they are, not where we might like them to be.</description>
  <mission>work towards a healthier and more sustainable Jewish community -- as a step towards a healthier and more sustainable world for all.</mission>
  <name>Hazon</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8941</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">218</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">579.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yu/bD/VO/0p/qP/gH/zLSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
