<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>    " The more you begin to investigate what we think we understand, where we came from, what we think we're doing, the more you begin to see we've been lied to. We've been lied to by every institution what makes you think for one minute that the religious institution is the only one that's never been touched.
     The religious institutions of this world are at the bottom of the dirt. The religious institutions in this world are put there by the same people who gave you your government, your corrupt education system, who set up your international banking cartels. Because our masters don't give a damn about you or your family. All they care about is what they have always cared about which is controlling the whole damn world.
     We have been misled away from the true and divine presence in the universe that men have called God.
     I don't know what God is but I know what he isn't. And unless and until you are prepared to look at the whole truth, wherever it may go, whoever it may lead to. If you want to look the other way, or if you wanna play favorites, then somewhere along the line your gonna find out your messing with divine justice.
     The more you educate yourself the more you understand where things come from, and the more obvious things become, and you begin to see lies everywhere. You have to know the truth and seek the truth and the truth will set you free."

     There is not a single piece of non-biblical historical document from around the time of Christ that states his existence. You'd think someone who walked on water, turned water to wine, and ascended to heaven for all to see would have something written about him somewhere.


1. "It must be difficult... Those who have taken authority as the truth. Rather than truth as the authority." G. Massey

2. The bible is merely an astro-theological hybrid.</description>
  <mission>Take the power away from the few who know the Truth, by sharing that Truth with the world.</mission>
  <name>Outlaw Religion</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8944</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">286</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1j/xj/LZ/OE/d4/Qv/GAlS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
