<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Confederate States of America cause has been created to preserve the southern heritage. Southerners are proud and respectable people, they will inform you that The Civil War was fought over States Rights, and not Slavery. The Confederate Flag is a symbol of Honor, Pride,and heritage. It's not a symbol of hate as many people believe. Our Southern Heritage is important and we will discuss it with you as long as the Truth is being told and we will steer you away from the "facts" that the schools are trying to teach our children on how the Confederate States of America was formed and the reason why secession was our only choice. Southerners believe in God, Family and Friends, being polite to others, whether you know them or not, working hard to get the things you need, and praying hard that your decisions are the right ones to help your kids grow up and live as they should. As General Robert E. Lee said, "There are few, I believe, in this enlightened era who would not agree with me that slavery as an institution is a moral and political evil." Confederate heritage is one part of America's diversity which must be preserved. 

The flags of the Confederate States of America were very important and a matter of great pride to those citizens living in the Confederacy. They are also a matter of great pride for their descendants as part of their heritage and history. -- Winston Churchill




I give credit to  http://www.rebelwithaclue.com/ for most of my information

1. We must preserve our southern heritage

2. We can't forget our past </description>
  <mission>Preserve our southern heritage</mission>
  <name>Confederate States of America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8947</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2109</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Cr/FQ/II/vZ/p0/Jz/Wq7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
