<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is just a classic example of corporations seeking insignificant reductions in operating costs through tax relief, by transferring the burden to private citizens.  The truth is, general aviation cannot shoulder the financial burden of the aerospace industry, nor should it.  

So why should you care about General Aviation?  Because here in the United States, you can expect quick medical evacuation by air.  Your communities can expect aerial firefighting efforts if needed.  Our highways and communities can be protected by law enforcement aviation assets.  You can book a charter flight into areas that are otherwise inaccessible.  These are a few reasons why GA shouldn't be squeezed out of the skies by the airlines, but the biggest reason is freedom.  In the US, any private citizen, with the desire, may enjoy flight over our country, without a cost that keeps them from doing so.  In the US, poor citizens enjoy the freedom of flight in small planes right along with air carriers.  This is not the case in other countries, where only big companies and privileged individuals can experience aviation.

"The FAA's funding will run out on September 30, 2007, forcing Congress to act to keep the agency operating, either by reauthorizing the existing tax-based funding system, accepting the Bush administration's proposed FAA funding scheme of increased taxes and user fees, or by writing Congress' own new funding legislation. "

-AOPA Online http://www.aopa.org/faafundingdebate/

Here's what needs to happen.  Call your congressman.  Ask to speak with them, or atleast someone that handles transportation issues in their office.  Tell them that you and your community support H.R. 2881, the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2007.   That's it.  Some of you merit a reminder that THEY WORK FOR YOU!  Our representatives need to hear from their constituents, not just lobbyists.

1. The US has the safest, most efficient aviation system in the world.

2. GA is nearly extinct in other countries who have tried to impose a system of user fees.

3. We should not fix what is not broken, and break it in doing so.

4. Congressional oversight of the FAA should continue.

5. We should help encourage the growth of our airports and GA, not destroy it.

6. Through these efforts, secure the blessing of flight for our future generations.</description>
  <mission>To ensure that the US Airspace system remains the very best in the world.  To protect the priveleges of the private citizen and small organizations in using our national airspace system. </mission>
  <name>Support FAA Reauthorization Act of 2007: H.R. 2881</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8948</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/AO/hU/ax/bo/nx/xI/wx1S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
