<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our evolution has stalled. The governments of the world purposely keep everyone unaware and afraid. Television has stuck a stick in the spokes of our road to perfection. God is not in a book that somehow forgot to mention dinosaurs, it is inside everyone and everything. Peace is not a prerogative right now - with world peace, when we know that we are all one, there can no longer be arms trade. That is not in the plan.



"Fundamentalist Christianity - fascinating. These people actually believe that the the world is 12,000 years old. Swear to God. Based on what? I asked them.

"Well we looked at all the people in the Bible and we added 'em up all the way back to Adam and Eve, their ages: 12,000 years."

Well how fucking scientific, okay. I didn't know that you'd gone to so much trouble. That's good. You believe the world's 12,000 years old?

"That's right."

Okay, I got one word to ask you, a one word question, ready?

"Uh-huh."

Dinosaurs.

You know the world is 12,000 years old and dinosaurs existed, they existed in that time, you'd think it would have been mentioned in the fucking Bible at some point.

"And lo Jesus and the disciples walked to Nazareth. But the trail was blocked by a giant brontosaurus... with a splinter in his paw. And O the disciples did run a shriekin': 'What a big fucking lizard, Lord!' But Jesus was unafraid and he took the splinter from the brontosaurus's paw and the big lizard became his friend."





"Christianity has a built-in defense system: anything that questions a belief, no matter how logical the argument is, is the work of Satan by the very fact that it makes you question a belief. It's a very interesting defense mechanism and the only way to get by it -- and believe me, I was raised Southern Baptist -- is to take massive amounts of mushrooms, sit in a field, and just go, "Show me."" - Bill Hicks

1. Support the beliefs of Bill Hicks

2. Everyone in the world must think for themselves</description>
  <mission>Have everyone in the world listen to Bill Hicks and realize the disgusting state of the world. </mission>
  <name>Creative Evolution - Bill Hicks</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8953</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">118</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/me/nA/oN/Gk/jq/Gw/TOCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
