<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Most people in this country have difficulty finding a health care plan that fits into their monthly budget and provides them with comprehensive coverage. For transgender and gender non-conforming people, transphobia and other forms of discrimination sometimes make getting basic health care difficult or impossible. Therefore, HCAP works throughout California to increase full access to health care for transgender people and their families. HCAP receives specific support from individual donors, the California Endowment, California Wellness, and the Liberty Hill Foundation.

Through HCAP, TLC produces "Know Your Rights" pamphlets in English and Spanish to help people better understand the barriers that can prevent them from receiving full access to health care. We also present Transgender Health Law 101 workshop that familiarizes people with laws and regulations that they may use to better access care or seek remedies in case of discrimination. Participants are also provided with patient advocacy skills-building exercises to increase their ability to prevent discrimination in the first place. Finally, we work directly with health service providers who want to insure that they are providing accessible and non-discriminatory services.

In 2006, TLC, in cooperation with local partners, launched innovative, community-based organizing campaigns to secure transgender specific care in Alameda, Los Angeles, and Santa Clara Counties. For instance, along with FTM Alliance of Los Angeles, we helped to create C3 (the Community Clinic Campaign) and have produced several informational videos explaining the campaign (you can view them at: www.youtube.com/profile?user=FTMAofLA).

1. Health care is a universal right

2. Transgender and intersex people deserve to have their medical needs met

3. The trans community in Alameda County is not being sufficiently served</description>
  <mission>Start Low-Cost Transgender Clinics in Alameda County</mission>
  <name>Health Care Access Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8958</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">118</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/jw/qu/lZ/yX/oN/X5/pLuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
