<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It happens everyday and everywhere. A predator goes on the computer pretending to be some kid's friend. At first, they seem like every other kid your age until the questions gets more intense and the pictures get very explict. Suddenly, you hear the door bell ring and there standing in front of you is the man or woman you know as AngelWatching123 or BaseballMan88. They haven't come to be your friend. They have come to hurt you or even worse kill you. The internet has become so unsafe and so intense. Children give out so much information online and they don't even know it! It could happen to you or it could happen to someone you know and love. Do something.

RULES TO SAFETY
1. Do not give personal information such as your address, telephone number, parents' work address/telephone number,   or the name and location of your school.

2. Talk to your parents.

3. Don't EVER agree to meet someone online unless you have to bring a parent along.

4. Do not put a picture of yourself online.

5. Do not respond to rude messages. Tell your parents to that they can do something about it. For example, report the message.

6. Do not give your password to anyone except your parents. Not to best friends, girl friends, boy friends...NO ONE.  Make up one only you would know that you have never shared with anyone except your parents. 

7. Check with parents before downloading or installing software or doing anything that could hurt the computer or jeopardize your family's privacy.

8. Don't do anything that will hurt someone online or do anything that is against the law.

9. Try to have Firewall protection, Spyware, and any other virus protection.

10. Do not visit unknown chat rooms or meet online friends in a private online setting.


11. You shouldn't use your real last name online. ALWAYS make it fake expecially if it is very unusual.


12. DO NOT TALK TO STRANGERS!!!!!!!!! 


HELP OUR INTERNET BECOME A SAFER PLACE! 

1. The internet used to be safe. We have a right to be able to go on myspace or facebook and not have to worry!

2. No one deserves to raped and/or murdered because they met someone online and wanted to be friends with them.</description>
  <mission>stop all predators and make the internet safer.</mission>
  <name>Internet Safety</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8960</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">30</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sy/6m/bs/kN/Ea/2y/GhSS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
