<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> When diagnosed with breast cancer there are many agonizing and exhausting procedures that one must endure. I believe that the most demoralizing step these courageous women would have to take would be undergoing a mastectomy. A mastectomy is when a woman's breast is removed in order to take out cancerous breast cells/tissue.  These women are left with pain not only from the surgery but also from their loss of womanhood. As if this frightening experience was not enough, insurance companies are trying to make mastectomies an outpatient procedure. These &#8220;drive-through&#8221; mastectomies in which women are forced to leave the hospital after only a few hours of recovery, comes no where close to giving them time to heal from their surgery much less heal emotionally. 

There's a bill called the Breast Cancer Patient Protection Act that will require insurance companies to cover a minimum 48-hour hospital stay for patients undergoing a mastectomy.  Although women who undergo this procedure will need more than 48-hours to make it through this devastating time, the Breast Cancer Patient Protection Act can give these women a start in the right direction.  Lifetime Television has put this bill on their web page with a petition in which we can show Congress that we want the Breast Cancer Patient Protection Act passed. The Breast Cancer Hospitalization Bill is an important legislation for all women (and men that care about women). So lets show Congress what kind of impact our generation can have. Now is the time for our voices to be heard.   
 
PLEASE!!  Sign the petition by clicking on the web site below.  

http://www.lifetimetv.com/breastcancer/petition/signpetition.php

Petition: The Facts 

http://www.lifetimetv.com/breastcancer/petition/protectionact_2005.php



1. Get Informed

2. Spread the Word

3. Make a Difference

4. Stop Breast Cancer for Life</description>
  <mission>Give women who are struggling to survive Breast Cancer a fighting chance!</mission>
  <name>Stop "drive-through" Mastectomies</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8961</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">16</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ir/KM/Hu/Rm/dv/pp/ECdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
