<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>By providing very poor families with small loans to invest in their microenterprises, Village Banking empowers them to create their own jobs, raise their incomes, build assets, and increase their families&#8217; well-being. Here's how it works. Neighbors come together in financial support groups called &#8220;Village Banks.&#8221; Individuals borrow working capital for their microenterprises, and because they have little to offer for collateral, the group guarantees those loans. As businesses grow, families earn more, purchase more nutritious foods, and parents are better able to send their children to school. After a year or more, many Village Bankers make significant improvements to their businesses, their homes, and their lives. Because neighbors support each other while growing their businesses, Village Banking helps invigorate entire communities.

Village Banking is designed to reach the poorest of the working poor. FINCA clients&#8212;70 percent of whom are women&#8212;have no other sources of working capital. FINCA works closely with its clients to help them build their businesses so they can earn more, become part of the larger marketplace, and enter the global economy. In addition to working capital, we provide them with insurance, savings plans, and other services to help them weather crises such as illness or death in the family, or natural disasters.

1. Eradicate extreme poverty and hunger

2. Combat HIV/AIDS, malaria and other diseases.

3. Improve maternal health.

4. Reduce child mortality.

5. Promote gender equality and empower women

6. Achieve universal primary education</description>
  <mission>To Provide financial services to the world's lowest-income entrepreneurs so they can create jobs, build assets and improve their standard of living.</mission>
  <name>FINCA - Village Banking</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/897</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">97</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">32.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/C4D/3jAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
