<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The No Child Left Behind Act has a purpose we can probably all agree upon: improve education for every person in this country, regardless of their living situations.

However, those who support this cause find NCLB far too punitive. Instead of rewarding good performance, the law only punishes bad performance by taking away funding from the poorly functioning school districts, who probably need the money the most. While it is true that some corruption could be draining money, and that perhaps that money is not being put to good use, the government must be more careful about choosing to fund the schools who really need it.

We can hire people to help school districts decide what they should do next. This would create jobs. Also, people already in the education workforce should be ready to carefully examine each school district. Every school is like a child in a classroom, and to do its best it needs a lot of individualized attention. We need to work as hard to educate our youth as we expect them to work in school.

More will be added to this description over time, but for now, here is a URL for the United States government's education department.

http://www.ed.gov/nclb/landing.jhtml

No one is against what NCLB stands for, only the methods it uses.

1. No Child Left Behind has an honorable purpose, as stated by its title.

2. There are some key problems with the act, however, as listed above. It is too punitive and takes funding from the schools which need it the most.

3. We have to plan on giving far more individualized attention to districts and helping those which need help.

4. If everyone, including Congress, were to carefully think about this issue, we could amend NCLB to function much better.</description>
  <mission>uphold the concept that every child should attain a high skill level in academics while altering a law we believe to be flawed yet salvageable.</mission>
  <name>Make Education Go Farther: Amend NCLB</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8977</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">26</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gU/uA/Io/3t/QT/DM/1w5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
