<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Most of the nearly two&#8211;billion children in the developing world are inadequately educated, or receive no education at all. One in three does not complete the fifth grade.

Given the resources that poor countries can reasonably allocate to education&#8212;sometimes less than $20 per year per pupil, even a doubled or redoubled national commitment to traditional education, augmented by external and private funding, would not get the job done. Moreover, experience strongly suggests that an incremental increase of &#8220;more of the same&#8221;&#8212;building schools, hiring teachers, buying books and equipment&#8212;is a laudable but insufficient response to the problem of bringing true learning possibilities to the vast numbers of children in the developing world.

Any nation's most precious natural resource is its children. We believe the emerging world must leverage this resource by tapping into the children's innate capacities to learn, share, and create on their own. Our answer to that challenge is the XO laptop, a children's machine designed for &#8220;learning learning.&#8221;

OLPC is not, at heart, a technology program, nor is the XO a product in any conventional sense of the word. OLPC is a non-profit organization providing a means to an end&#8212;an end that sees children in even the most remote regions of the globe being given the opportunity to tap into their own potential, to be exposed to a whole world of ideas, and to contribute to a more productive and saner world community.

Until then, stay tuned.
www.laptop.org

1. Each child should own their own learning tool.

2. The OLPC commitment is with elementary education in the developing countries.

3. All children should have access to the internet and to local networks to share experiences and learning.</description>
  <mission>To provide children around the world with new opportunities to explore, experiment and express themselves.
www.laptop.org</mission>
  <name>One Laptop Per Child</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/8992</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">110</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/JY/7P/av/Nb/aT/40/wfIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
