<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>WATER IS ESSENTIAL FOR LIFE. Water is crucial for sustainable development, including the preservation of our natural environment and the alleviation of poverty and hunger. Water is indispensable for human health and well-being.
Yet many millions of people around the world face water shortages. Many millions of children die every year from water-borne diseases. And drought regularly afflicts some of the world&#8217;s poorest countries. The world needs to respond much better. We need to increase water efficiency, especially in agriculture. We need to free women and girls from the daily chore of hauling water, often over great distances. We must involve them in decision-making on water management. We need to make sanitation a priority. This is where progress is lagging most. That is why this year marks the beginning of the &#8220;Water for Life&#8221; Decade. Our goal is to meet the internationally agreed targets for water and sanitation by 2015, and to build the foundation for further progress in the years beyond
At the World Summit in Johannesburg in 2002, two other goals were adopted: to aim to develop integrated water resource management and water efficiency plans by 2005 and to halve, by 2015, the proportion of people who do not have access to basic sanitation.=
Among the themes that are central for the 'Water for Life' Decade are: scarcity, access to sanitation and health, water and gender, capacity-building, financing, valuation, Integrated Water Resources Management, trans-boundary water issues, environment and biodiversity, disaster prevention, food and agriculture, pollution and energy. 

This is an urgent matter of human development, and human dignity. Together, we can provide safe, clean water to all the world&#8217;s people. The world&#8217;s water resources are our lifeline for survival. we must manage them better.



1. everyone deserves fresh water</description>
  <mission>promote efforts to fulfill international commitments made on water and water-related issues by 2015</mission>
  <name>Water for life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9005</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ay/g4/vH/ew/OG/C5/AloS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
