<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>PROJECT SYNOPSIS:
TAPESTRIES OF HOPE exposes an issue that continues to be ignored: the rape and sexual abuse of young girls of Zimbabwe. In 2002, a 9-month old girl was raped. In 2003, a two-week old girl was raped and died from the trauma.

The cause of these rapes is shocking: men with HIV/AIDS believe that they will be cured if they have sex with a virgin; the younger and more &#8220;pure&#8221; the girl, the better their chances of ridding themselves of their disease.

A vital source of support for the girls has been the Girl Child Network (GCN), founded by Betty Makoni. With over 350 chapters and membership of over 25,000 girls, ages 0-18, this non-profit supports girls who are victims of abuse by offering career resources, mentorship programs, and classes that build self-esteem. GCN has also built two villages entirely devoted to creating a safe haven for girls to realize their full potential.
***

EXCLUSIVE!!
Read this personal recounting of film director's arrest, interrogation and incarceration in Zimbabwe carried by the Huffington Post (#1 news blog in the world):
http://www.huffingtonpost.com/michealene-cristini-risley/gratitude-musings-after-_b_62791.html
***

PARTICIPATE:
- Read the TAPESTRIES OF HOPE Blogs at:
http://savehope.blogspot.com

- Donate or invite friends to get involved in the project (right here on Facebook): http://apps.facebook.com/causes/view_cause/9008

- Purchase the TAPESTRIES OF HOPE FUTURE jewelry including the FUTURE Sterling Silver Pendant and FUTURE Earrings.  These are available at http://savehope.blogspot.com
***

Support the cause.

1. Provide a voice to the Girl Child Network (GCN) and its activities

2. Bring hope to the girls of GCN in Zimbabwe</description>
  <mission>Give a voice to abused girls in Zimbabwe</mission>
  <name>Tapestries of Hope</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9008</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1448</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">6563.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ja/7a/ZU/KM/HB/qW/o1/XlS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
