<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>GiveWell started with a simple question: &lt;b&gt;where should I donate?&lt;/b&gt;

As a group of eight friends, employed in the finance industry and researching these questions in our spare time, we discovered that it isn't a part-time job.  The issues charities address - from fighting disease in Africa to improving education in the U.S. - are extremely complex, yet useful information about what different charities do and whether it works isn't publicly available anywhere.  When we asked private foundations to share what they'd found and help us with our decisions, they refused.  &lt;strong&gt;We believe that information about how to help people should never be secret.&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;img src="/files/images/piechartnew.PNG" align=right hspace=10&gt;We also believe that small donors matter.  Big foundations make the headlines, but &lt;b&gt;individual donors give over 100 times as much as the Gates Foundation and over 6 times as much as all foundations combined.&lt;/b&gt;  If we can help even a small portion of them, we can have more impact than any mega-donor. If we can create dialogue and openness about what charities do, we can get the world's best minds working on its biggest problems. And ultimately, we can change the rules of the game: we picture a market that rewards charities for their ability to help people, not just for their marketing.

Holden Karnofsky and Elie Hassenfeld (&lt;a href="/people"&gt;bios&lt;/a&gt;) left their jobs, raised $300,000 in startup funds from former coworkers who believe in us and our mission, and invited charities to apply for $25,000 grants in five broad humanitarian causes (see top of page).  Through the application process, we collected detailed information about these charities' activities and published our &lt;a href="/research-summary"&gt;year 1 research reports&lt;/a&gt;.

We are &lt;a href="/plan"&gt;now focused&lt;/a&gt; on more deeply researching developing-world aid, as well as finding more donors who are interested in using our reports for their giving decisions.

1. In charity, as in everything else, generosity and good intentions aren't enough.

2. Donating without good information is just throwing money at our problems.

3. You should put as much care into your choice of charity as into your choice of restaurant.

4. Information about how to help those in need should never be secret.</description>
  <mission>Get real change for your dollar.</mission>
  <name>GiveWell (www.givewell.net)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9013</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">151</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1521.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/QU/zu/mB/hK/5Y/C6/CQ/dvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
