<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There needs to be an awakening. A point of realization where people sitting in church pews balancing their checkbooks and writing grocery lists finally see that something is wrong.

When Christians are warring amongst each other and the other people of the world, billions of newbors are destined to inherit poverty, and wealthy, worldly people, claiming to be Christians don't seem to care...

Something is desperately wrong.

The very world we live in is dying, both physically and figuratively. What happens when our faith dies along with it? There is nothing left.

Faith in our salvation in Jesus Christ. Faith in His plan for us and our lives. Faith in the never-ceasing love and guidance of God. 

When that faith is gone, the world is successful in dragging us along in its demise. But we must fight back! We must see that something is wrong, desperately wrong, and fix it!


1. Christendom should not be ruled over by any worldly authority, only by God.

2. People seeking to follow Christ must give up their lives and worldly ambitions and live day to day for Him.

3. The teachings of Christ advocate an end to violence in all forms.

4. In following the teachings of Christ, all people must unite to end poverty and social injustice.

5. The hypocrasy that exists in Christendom in the form of judgement and hatred of people like homosexuals, criminals, immigrants, people of other cultures, and people of differing political views must end.</description>
  <mission>Break down the barriers created by a dogmatic, faithless Christianity, and to replace them with the message of the open arms of Christ and the open hearts of His followers.</mission>
  <name>Revolution of Christ Followers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9014</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">67</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0k/uq/KF/YO/pt/Te/npyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
