<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Doctors Without Borders/M&#233;decins sans Fronti&#232;res (MSF) is a private international association. The association is made up mainly of doctors and health sector workers and is also open to all other professions which might help in achieving its aims. All of its members agree to honor the following principles: 

M&#233;decins Sans Fronti&#232;res provides assistance to populations in distress, to victims of natural or man-made disasters and to victims of armed conflict. They do so irrespective of race, religion, creed or political convictions. 

M&#233;decins Sans Fronti&#232;res observes neutrality and impartiality in the name of universal medical ethics and the right to humanitarian assistance and claims full and unhindered freedom in the exercise of its functions. 

Members undertake to respect their professional code of ethics and to maintain complete independence from all political, economic, or religious powers. 

As volunteers, members understand the risks and dangers of the missions they carry out and make no claim for themselves or their assigns for any form of compensation other than that which the association might be able to afford them. 

Upon starting a project, the following actions are taken as necessary:

Massive vaccination campaigns:

Training and supervision of medical personnel
 
Water and sanitation improvement

Data collection

Feeding

Patient care

Maternal and pediatric care
 
Distribution of drugs and medical supplies
 
Mental health care

Rehabilitation of hospitals and clinics

AIDS care and prevention

 



1. The only responsible ethical position is to take action.

2. Intervention is necessary, however is not based on any political, social, or religious interests.

3. Speak out against humanitarian injustices.</description>
  <mission>Make a difference in the lives of others around the globe. </mission>
  <name>Doctors Without Borders</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9026</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">719</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/LD/kK/FL/Ip/cD/g1/SZAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
