<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Despite cultural differences, we must think of dogs as any other creature in this world: deserving of compassion and a life without torment.

But dogs are violently slaughtered for food, mistreated, abused, starved, injured, deprived of attention, and the ability to move and play.

A few of their horrors:  
1. A collar put on as a puppy digs into their neck and cuts to the throat. 
2. No medical help for old or babies.  
3. Kept on short leashes that don't allow them to walk around; living in their own filth.
4. Kept in cages where they can&#8217;t even move.  
5. Deprived of food and water.  
6. Left in bad weather without shelter.  
7. Crammed in with other starving dogs living in feces.  
8. Maggots will eat their flesh as they literally rot alive.
9. 52 dogs to be sold as meat were buried alive.  3 survived.

Dog traders justify it by saying that they will be 
slaughtered.  The buyer picks his meat: sitting in a small cage starving and watching other dogs being slaughtered every day..waiting.

People with their own dogs imagine that these dogs are not like theirs.They are.  

The most demanded is a "yellow dog".  Yellow dogs are Labrador retrievers, Golden retrievers, and other yellow mixes.  Others include the Husky, Great Pyrenees, Saint Bernard, Australian shepherd, German shepherd, Terrier, Chow, muts, and more.

To end this, dog traders could be educated about other profitable jobs.  Buyers could be educated about the health risks involved.  The government could ban the slaughter of dogs.  Instead, they rationalize that there is a distinction between dogs for pets and dogs for food; justifying the legalization of dog consumption without facing the facts.

I urge you to visit the IDA website, read about the laws in Korea, and write to the South Korean Government and ask that they amend the animal protection law.

Writing to the government voicing our outrage may change at least one influential mind, and save one life.  We must start somewhere, no matter how insignificant that start may seem.

For more information, please visit: http://www.idausa.org/campaigns/korea/alert_060510.html

1. The dog above spent his entire life tied up in this shack, never let free, never loved. His collar even became embedded in his neck.

2. Loving animals Loving lives Loving ourselves

3. The greatness of a nation can be judged by the way its animals are treated- Mohandas Gandhi</description>
  <mission>Urge Korean Prime Minister to Strengthen Animal Protection Law by visiting http://www.idausa.org/campaigns/korea/alert_060510.html</mission>
  <name>Movement Against The Slaughter And Consumption Of Dogs In Korea</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9039</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">14916</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">356.9</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Po/ff/74/hQ/VY/rf/jioS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
