<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A fledgling charity in South Wales, not yet registered with the Charities Commission as funds have to be raised to a certain level before registration can be officially made.

I aim to:-
 
1.Raise enough funds initially to rent a shop in the Tonypandy/Porth area to allow donated items to be sold, thereby raising greater funds.

2.Use the shop income funds to buy food, equipment and shelter buildings in which to rehabilitate the cats which are rescued by this new charity. 

3.Long term plan is to buy land and build/open a rehabilitation and rehoming centre where members of the public can visit and see cats requiring new homes. Donations wil be requested from visitors, enabling the running of the centre to be further supported. All cats will be rehomed on a permanent loan contract, allowing cats to be returned if the new home is found to be not suitable at any time, legal ownership of cat remains with the charity at all times, thereby ensuring long term security for each cat.

4.Work with South Wales veterinary practices to create a specialist feline veterinary centre at the rehoming centre, some funds raised from this to be used in daily running of the centre.

5. Run a schools liaison/information project with local Junior Schools to inform children at a young age of the responsibilties that pet ownership and cats in particular may bring. Inform young people about feline welfare. 

All this needs a lot of work, dedication and PRIMARILY money. ALL funds will be most gratefully received. I am starting now 26th July 2007 with NOTHING, so please dig deep and donate, as there is a real need for felines in the South wales Valleys to be supported in this way. 

1. CEO</description>
  <mission>Rescue neglected and unloved cats, rehabilitate, and rehome with loving new owners.</mission>
  <name>Furmummy's Feline Rescue, Rehab and Rehoming</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9048</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">17</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/NH/Is/az/YA/kr/he/5tbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
