<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Sudanese refugees in Egypt:
There are tens of thousands of Sudanese refugees in Egypt, most of them seeking refuge from ongoing military conflicts in their home country of Sudan. They live among a much larger population of Sudanese migrants in Egypt, more than two million people of Sudanese nationality (by most estimates; a full range is 750,000 to 4 million who live in Egypt. 

Demographics:
From 1994 to 2005, 58,535 Sudanese nationals seeking asylum registered with the (UNHCR) in Egypt.
By December 2005, 31,990 of these asylum seekers had been accorded refugee legal status and 16,675 had been resettled in third countries. An additional 15,000 of the recognized refugees did not meet the resettlement countries&#8217; criteria and most, if not all, remained in Egypt under &#8220;local integration&#8221; status. This leaves just over 315 individuals who, according to UNHCR, were referred for resettlement but whose procedures for travel have not yet been completed. Of those who sought refugee status with UNHCR, 16,000 were rejected and eventually became &#8220;closed files,&#8221; and another 10,200 were given temporary asylum seeker protection. As of the end of 2005, 13,327 recognized refugees remained in Egypt.

Legal Status:
The January 2004 &#8220;Four Freedoms Agreement,&#8221; grants both Sudanese and Egyptians the freedom of movement, residence, ownership and work in either country.
Egypt, while a party to international refugee conventions, lacks a domestic asylum law and has deferred to the United Nations in determinations of refugee status. (UNHCR) office in Cairo is located in the suburb of Mohandessin, Giza. As the UNHCR is responsible for assessing applications for asylum, and providing refugee documentation, it has been the site of protests. Two documents are provided: so- called yellow cards that indicate the bearer is an asylum-seeker, and blue cards indicating that the bearer is a UNHCR-acknowledged refugee. In June 2004, UNHCR suspended the issuing of blue cards.


1. sudani refugees suffering from the civil war in their country we must help them 

2. they need education.

3. they need healthcare 

4. they need to be home again  but if a minimum degree of security found.</description>
  <mission>Discuss,Talk, &amp; find a peaceful,civilized way to help sudanese refugees in Egypt</mission>
  <name>Help Sudanese Refugees in Egypt</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9049</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">41</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">80.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/vw/zl/uJ/OH/5M/cu/VWbS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
