<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Gospel for Asia is a mission organization dedicated to sharing the Good News of Jesus Christ with the unreached millions of Assia through indigenous evangelists and church planters. Today more than 16,000 GFA native missionaries are sering God full-time, and several thousand young men and women are preparing for a lifetime of ministry in 54 GFA Bible colleges. 
&lt;br&gt;
The children in the Bridge of Hope fundation grow up in the following types of situations:
     1)They are among the most poor and need children, where they, if not their entire family, has to labor just to provide the barest of essentials;
     2)They roam the cities streets, being the recipients of cruel abuse and angry beatings. 
     3)They labor in factories, plantations, and pastures, compromising their health and crippling their bodies, either because they are bonded laborers, or they are enslaved by family poverty. 
&lt;p&gt;
By joining, you are given the oppurtunity to sponsor a child. For only $28 a month, you can provide a child in India with the message of Jesus' love, a quality education, school uniforms, medical care, and daily meals. You can also sponsor a missionary for only $30. 
&lt;p&gt;
I learned about Bridge of Hope during a recent concert for Five Talents More. Tell your friends about it. You don't have to sponsor a child all by yourself either. Myself and a friend are sponsoring a child and splitting the payment. Get a group of friends together and sponsor a child. I wanted to sponsor because so many adults think that as teens we are unable to be commit to a cause like this, but we can show the world that we can take care of those children.  
&lt;p&gt;
To find out how to sponsor a child, you can go to 
              
               www.gfa.org/sponsorachild



1. For the children, it is far more important to have a political commitment to primary education</description>
  <mission>be devout followers of Christ and to fulfill the Great Comission among the unreached in Asia through training, sending out and assisting qualified labors in partnership with the Body of Christ. </mission>
  <name>Gospel for Asia's Bridge of Hope</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9050</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">253</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">105.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/m4/4I/aK/DA/1k/HM/BxAS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
