<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>History of the Council for America&#8217;s First Freedom
The Council for America&#8217;s First Freedom was founded in 1984 to celebrate the bicentennial of the Virginia Statute for Religious Freedom, adopted in 1786 by the Virginia General Assembly. The Virginia General Assembly was then working from temporary quarters in a warehouse near the corner of 14th and Cary Streets in an area of downtown Richmond, Virginia, known as Shockoe Slip. This document served as the template for the first clause of the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States. Through this legislation, religious freedom moved from being an abstract philosophical ideal to being a legally protected human right. Although we continue to enjoy religious freedom, the &#8220;warehouse&#8221; at 14th and Cary Streets where this landmark event occurred no longer exists and now serves as a parking lot.

The mission of the Council evolved from commemoration to education &#8211; to educate the public about the history and importance of the Statute&#8217;s guiding principle &#8211; that all persons are entitled to freedom of conscience unfettered by the State. The Council was appropriately founded in and continues to be based in Richmond.

In 2002, the Council further defined its mission and goals when its board of trustees began to focus its efforts on an educational center, the First Freedom Center. Such a facility will be dedicated to promoting understanding and respect for religious freedom. The Council&#8217;s board secured professional expertise in planning, educational program development, and capital project management. In anticipation of the Center, it completed acquisition of the historic site and surrounding properties. 



1. A non-profit 501(c)(3) educational organization based in Richmond, Virginia.

2. Non-political; does not advocate a particular political viewpoint.

3. Non-denominational; does not ally with any particular faith, but rather, holds as one of its tenets that all persons are entitled to freedom of religion.</description>
  <mission>increase understanding and respect for religious freedom in diverse communities worldwide, through education about this core human value: the freedom of thought, conscience and belief. </mission>
  <name>Council For America's First Freedom</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9051</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">15</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Q4/Fp/mN/73/pa/PS/cLQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
