<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Opportunity International Australia exists to help poor people make their way out of poverty permanently. 

Our strategy is to provide people living in poverty with a small loan to start their own business. Whether it&#8217;s a farm, variety store or restaurant, this business provides them with a regular income and allows them to provide for the needs of their families. Previously, they struggled to afford basic items such as food or clothing. 

To complement microfinance, Opportunity International Australia offers enterprise development services. These include non-financial services, such as business training and product development, which help ensure each business reaches its full potential. 

As each business grows, it feeds a family, employs more people, stimulates a local economy and eventually helps to empower a whole community. 

And, because the money Opportunity loans out is repaid and then lent out again, each donation we receive is eternally at work. In fact, one donation to Opportunity International Australia can transform the lives of hundreds of people.

Opportunity International Australia believes a world without extreme poverty is possible. To help us make this happen, visit http://www.opportunity.org.au to learn more or donate.

Part of the global Opportunity International Network, we provide microfinance and enterprise development services to more than a million poor people in 27 developing countries.


1. Commitment &#8211; we strive to have an impact that is lasting and is inclusive of the very poor and marginalised in the developing world.

2. Respect &#8211; we believe that all people have the potential to live lives of safety, happiness and freedom. Poverty denies people the opportunity to live 

3. Integrity &#8211; we honour the trust placed in us by our supporters, ensuring that we manage all our resources in a manner that reflects our motivation. We

4. Stewardship &#8211; we promote excellence, professionalism and best practice in every aspect of our work both in Australia and overseas. 

5. Visit www.opportunity.org.au for more information.</description>
  <mission>Giving people living in poverty the opportunity to start a small business and transform their lives. Visit www.opportunity.org.au for more information.</mission>
  <name>Opportunity International Australia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9064</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">490</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tw/ii/gk/iK/yg/ol/xV/OtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
