<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Heart Disease is the #1 killer of men &amp; women in the USA. Strokes are #3. Lets raise awareness of why it's so important to eat healthy and have a healthy heart.

Go Red For Women is a campaign to not only raise awareness of these problems but a chance for companies to raise money to donate to the American Heart Association.

Cutco (Kitchen Cutlery) is selling Red Handled Table knives in a Black tray. They're limited edition table knives that come in a set of 4 with a tray. It's a $127 for this set and we're donating $12 of each set to the American Heart Association.

Our goal is to donate $500,000 to this cause by Sept 1st which is when these knives will be taken off the market. 

Cutco knives are not cheap knives in anyway. They're an affordable luxury, and are the best set of cutlery money can afford. There are many things that set Cutco apart from other leading brands. Things like the handle, DD Edge, and our Forever Guarantee. 

If you want to help with this cause but want to more about Cutco feel free to send me a message or visit the website at http://www.Cutco.com and see why we're different then the rest. 

If you know you want to help this cause then send me a message and we can talk about it.

You can help today, let everyone you know about the dangers of eating unhealthy and that they can contribute to this cause. If you don't cook, being able to help will change everything. I personally will be buying a set of these knives only because I want to contribute. 

1. Heart disease is the #1 killer of men &amp; women in the US 

2. Help show people what healthy eating can do for you

3. Support a healthy heart</description>
  <mission>Donate $500,000 before Sept 1st</mission>
  <name>Cutco Helping Heart Disease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9070</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oa/Y0/1e/KA/OQ/FJ/OkPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
