<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This Cause is on behalf of Final Frontiers Foundation, Inc. (a 501(C3) organization), whose purpose is to effectively take the Gospel to the more than 3 billion souls who have never before heard.  Currently we are ministering in more than seventy three countries on five continents. These are countries and peoples primarily closed to traditional missionary outreach, but open to us because of our unique method of missions. 

We believe that the training and subsidizing of national preachers is the most efficient and effective method of global evangelism.  Thus we seek to raise prayer and financial support from believers in America, for God's servants abroad, who are actively involved in church planning and discipleship.  Selection of those we sponsor is dependent upon their doctrinal beliefs, need and reputation.  We support only those who are serving by faith, never those who are waiting for a salary in order to serve. 

All those subsidized thru this foundation are involved in church planting.  Their various outreach ministries include: Bible translation, radio broadcasting, camps, Bible schools, outdoor and film evangelism, educational and health programs, blind and leper ministries, orphan centers and refugee ministries. 

97% of what you give goes directly to Final Frontiers. The other 3% is the credit card transaction costs. If you want to give directly to Final Frontiers, go to finalfrontiers.org.


1. We have been commanded to share our excess with the less fortunate. This is one opportunity.</description>
  <mission>Support international Christian pastors</mission>
  <name>Final Frontiers - KC will give $1 for every 10 people who join</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9079</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">59</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Wv/TJ/TG/Gk/Zd/gh/U7vS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
