<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Year after year, The Hobart Shakespeareans excel. They read passionately, far above their grade level; tackle algebra, and stage Shakespeare so professionally that they often wow the great Shakespearean actor himself, Sir Ian McKellen.

Yet this takes place in Room 56, at a large urban public elementary school. All of the children at Hobart Elementary School qualify for free breakfast and lunch, and few speak English as a first language. Many are from poor or troubled families.

What's the winning recipe? A diet of intensive learning mixed with a lot of kindness and fun. These children come to school at 6:30 a.m. and often stay until it is dark. They come during vacation. They take field trips all over the world. They play rock and roll music. Mediocrity has no place in their classroom. And the results follow them for life, as they go on to outstanding colleges.

It is not easy, but these children dare to defy society's expectations. These kids are hungry, and they want out. They work their way out. After all, there are no shortcuts.

Working together with staff, parents, and our community, we are determined to establish a level playing field to give each child the equal opportunity promised in the Constitution.   

Through disciplined study and high expectations, the children acquire the knowledge, skills, and grace necessary to earn their share of the American Dream.

(www.hobartshakespeareans.org)

1. Each child should be given the equal opportunity promised in the Constitution</description>
  <mission>The Hobart Shakespeareans is a public school classroom designed to improve the quality of life for economically disadvantaged children.</mission>
  <name>The Hobart Shakespeareans</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9104</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">50</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ou/fJ/pp/dN/oi/Ee/JewS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
