<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It is not what we do.It's what we have.
This is an illness...
I have been fighting an Eating Disorder for years now. I have spent the most of the last five years in different hospitals for treatment. Now I am fighting to stay alive again.. and I need to try to do something about this illness. If I die  I want to know that I did everything I could to stop ED's.Together we can do this. We can stop eating disorders before they're big, bad problems. We have the power to alter what we see in media and in our every day lives. Support kicking ED's to the curb.. if not for me.. for people you will know, a parent, sibling, friend... or yourself. Eating Disorders do not discriminate. You can't always tell when someone has an eating disorder by just looking at them. People of every age and shape are effected by this.  If you want to get out alive run for your life, help others run for theirs also.Being sick with an ED is not something to be ashamed of. I know that it takes strength to come forward with the truth, and up and out of denial, but if I can do it so can you. Don't hide any longer. Please take care of yourself and the people in your life. Be intuitive and watchful. As soon as you see the faintest problem get help! Don't let this illness continue to kill. 
I collapsed the other day but I'm still here. I have taken this as further reason for me to stop this from happening to other people. Please help me! Help save this mad world!! 

*And know that whoever wants to have support through this cause, I encourage that. If you wish to reach me just leave me a note. No pro-ana's please.
Love you all,
Carmen Dempsey

1. Raising Awareness On Eating Disorders

2. Recovery Support</description>
  <mission>Raising awareness on eating disorders</mission>
  <name>Raising Awareness On Eating Disorders</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9105</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">718</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bc/KR/T8/WI/kX/aG/FA/sRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
