<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There is nothing wrong with helping our fellow man, regardless of which country he is in; Yet, America needs to focus more on the poverty that our OWN people are struggling with today. Now don't get me wrong, I am COMPLETELY supportive of the foundations for helping those in Africa, etc. This organization is just kind of a reminder that we can help out right here at home too(I know, I know, you've heard that so many times.) But really, just because we are one of the richest countries in the world does not mean that every American citizen has the necessities they need to survive such as food, clothes, education, liveable shelter, safe environment, and even family/role models. We all know those in our own communities who struggle with not having the things listed above..so let's try and help!

Links of interest: http://www.abcnews.go.com/2020/story?id=2819991&amp;page=1

http://www.youthnoise.com/page.php?page_id=2242&amp;gclid=CMeg5cKAyY0CFQZTHgodGBs16A

This organization is also not attacking America, because there ARE organizations out there trying to change some things. But they could definitely use some more help. Helping is just as simple as donating food, clothes, or your spare time.

http://www.secondharvest.org/zip_code.jsp

http://locator.goodwill.org/

http://www.americasoupkitchen.com/

http://www.colorado.edu/cspv/blueprints/model/programs/BBBS.html

http://www.bbbsa.org/

1. There are children &amp; adults in America who need things from food to companionship, and we can help.

2. Other countries need our help, and we should continue to support these causes without forgetting about our own.</description>
  <mission>help those living in our OWN neighborhoods &amp; towns with their struggle with poverty.</mission>
  <name>Fight against poverty in America</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9106</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">398</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/FN/MI/Ob/aU/Ci/OA/scgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
