<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Children's National Network Society, Inc is a multi-dimensional organization which focuses on raising awareness of childhood diseases and teaching adolescents about the importance of giving back to society.  CNNS also works with other non-profit children's organizations to ensure that every child, no matter their location or condition, benefits from the funds raised in our communities. Whether it is by having local elementary school kids make cards for those sick and in the hospital or contributing to a cancer research fund, our mission will be carried out with love, integrity, honesty, and the utmost respect possible.

THE STORY BEHIND C.N.N.S.
Once a girl was born and it was a miracle. Many complications occurred during the pregnancy, which lead the doctors to believe she would be born with Spina Bifida (an open spine) and a cleft lip.  After many prayers she was born on her Father&#8217;s birthday as normal as any child could be. 
Throughout her life she volunteered avidly. In 3rd grade she was a peer facilitator, at 10 she helped as a traffic cop, and before graduating high school she had volunteered for organizations such as Annabelle&#8217;s Wish, Ronald McDonald House, St. Jude Children&#8217;s Research Hospital, Joe DiMaggio Children&#8217;s Hospital, Operation Christmas Child, and many more. 

A wise woman once said, &#8220;An idol mind is the Devil&#8217;s workshop.&#8221;  So with this in mind and after many years of experience in the non-profit world, she started an organization to benefit children all over the world and those right here in your hometown.

1. If you can see it and belive it, you can achieve it!

2. The children of today are the leaders of tomorrow.

3. The future lies in the hands of our children.

4. "An idle mind is the Devil's workshop."</description>
  <mission> To teach adolescents about the importance of giving back to society and the fulfillment they can receive by helping a needy child in the world today. </mission>
  <name>The Children's National Network Society, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9114</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">257</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/P8/PH/5w/In/q8/CJ/KBPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
