<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>On the 60th anniversary of Gandhi&#8217;s death, in his and Dr. King's memory, using their example of peaceful non-cooperation, let's take one day and show our leaders we will no longer cooperate with the direction this nation has been going. For just one day, let&#8217;s replace our national habit of mindless consumption with a day of conscientious non-participation. Let&#8217;s take one day and quietly celebrate those millions among us who are making a difference already. 

The goal of Unplug for Peace is to shut the system down for just one day to get our leader&#8217;s attention in a way that nothing else ever has. The vision is simple, a hundred million Americans refusing to go about business as usual. We will empty the skies, the schools, the malls, the offices, the roads and we'll do it by staying home and giving our infrastructure a day of rest. No lights, no radio, no TV, no phones. We'll take one day and consciously not consume to the best of our ability. We&#8217;ll give the planet a day to catch its breath, while we catch ours. 

UNPLUG FOR PEACE ultimately is about recreating the feeling of connection we shared in the wake of 9/11, but doing it voluntarily and pro-actively as a means of averting disaster rather than responding to one. 

1. To see America at peace, making our nation secure by partnership and understanding rather than by arrogant bullying;

2. To live in a nation where everyone, rich and poor alike, receives high quality healthcare dispensed with only one concern, the wellbeing of the patient;

3. To have our politicians strive to make sure government works for all the people and not just the donor class.  This means junking the current political system of institutionalized bribery and corruption; 

4. To foster genuine global prosperity, which is absolutely required to achieve world peace.  This means reasserting the legitimate role of government to end multinational corporate colonialism and piracy, which exploit nations and peoples in the name of Fre

5. To reassert accountability and checks and balances in our government by restoring the primacy of the Constitution as the law of the land; 

6. To make government once again an instrument of positive change environmentally, by ending the political dithering and fear of big business that prevents effective environmental action across the board; 

7. To re-ignite the engine known as the middle class, and not just in America but around the world.  This means taking measures to reverse the widening gap between the &#8220;haves&#8221; and the &#8220;have nots&#8221; in America and around the world. 

8. To have lending institutions function as responsible partners for growth rather than the profit-driven predators they have, in the main, become as we've legitimized lending practices that would make organized crime blush.  

9. To solve our immigration problem by assuring that citizens of other nations live in dignity and prosperity on their own soil, so we can be their partner and friend, but no longer need to be their refuge.  </description>
  <mission>re-ignite the spirit of citizenship </mission>
  <name>Unplug For Peace</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9121</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">14</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/al/qw/Yw/pD/0K/5f/kxsS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
