<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In 1984, HELPS International was founded as a 501(c) (3) by people within the tradition of Christian service. This sense of Christian service is seen in HELPS programs that extend a hand and give real hope for the future.

HELPS programs are implemented by volunteers from around the world and are offered regardless of ethnicity, social standing, political involvement, or religious belief.

HELPS believes in a world of freedom, stability, and personal opportunity.  In order to achieve these goals, HELPS programs are integrated in the areas of healthcare, education, economic development, and other special projects. HELPS works together with other non-governmental organizations, private enterprise, and local and national governments.

HELPS strives for permanent change through various programs, all of which involve mutual respect, responsibility, and partnership with local infrastructure and communities. This integrated approach ensures cohesion on a cultural, medical, spiritual and economic basis.

www.helpsintl.org


1. HELPS believes in the integrity of the indigenous communities.

2. HELPS believes special programs are necessary to break the cycle of poverty.

3. HELPS believes the situation in the developing world is critical and the window of opportunity is now.

4. HELPS is committed to assisting the people of the developing world through programs in education and literacy, medicine, and projects of practical and social concern and spiritual value.</description>
  <mission>To break the cycle of poverty by providing enduring programs of practical, social and spiritual value to the people in the developing world through a system of partnership and mutual responsibility.</mission>
  <name>HELPS International</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9122</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">405</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/q5/Zy/gn/nI/qq/lS/qJGS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
