<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Chechens [Vainakh] have struggled against successive Russian regimes in a bloody cycle of invasion, resistance, bloodshed and deportation.

The Chechen struggle represents more than political survival; it is also about the preservation of cultural identity and heritage. &#8220;The Chechens never reconciled themselves to Russian hegemony and had always been on the lookout for a chance to rid themselves of the bloody occupiers.&#8221; 

On November 2nd 1991, Chechnya unsuccessfully declared itself an independent state. 
&#8220;There is a blind spot in the Russian ethos concerning the North Caucasus that renders Russians unable to understand the peoples of the area &#8211; to the detriment of the cultures of all concerned parties.&#8221; 
&#8220;One of the most surprising consequences [of the Chechen conflict] was the fairly ambivalent attitude of key Western countries&#8230;to massive violations of the human rights of Russian and foreign citizens during the military phase of the conflict&#8230;Western ambivalence helped the Yeltsin regime considerably in pursuing the Military option in Chechnya for such a long time.&#8221;

The Chechen republic has been devastated by multiple wars and its people demoralized; thousands of ethnic Chechens and Russians residing in the republic have fled, lost their homes, become displaced, and many are living in refugee camps in neighboring regions under deplorable conditions. Rough estimates of total deaths up to 1999 report 35,000 people killed, the majority civilians.

 Given that Putin&#8217;s government is tight-lipped about the veritable state of affairs, imposing great restrictions on the media attempting to access the area, foreign aid and intervention have little chance of providing assistance to the troubled region. However, one can only hope for a positive turn of events and, once again, the return of the Chechen peoples and their unique cultures to the homeland which they have fought so strongly to protect, uphold, save and, most recently, liberate.

1. International intervention is necessary; end Western ambivalence

2. Monitoring by INGO's of human rights violations

3. Return of Chechen territory to the [Chechen] people</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness for the gross human rights violations and terror imposed on Chechnya</mission>
  <name>Independent Chechnya; End Russian Imperial Overstretch</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9134</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">512</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/lT/x4/JK/jJ/pk/LR/m3nS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
