<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The principle of self-determination,as enshrined in the 1945 UN charter, is that every nation is entitled to a sovereign territorial state, and that every specifically identifiable population should choose which state it belongs to, often by plebiscite. It is commonly used to justify the aspirations of an ethnic group that self-identifies as a nation toward forming an independent sovereign state, but it equally grants the right to reject sovereignty and join a larger multi-ethnic state.

We the people of the North are a nation unto ourselves. We have our own language and our own culture and what is more we have our own issues and needs which are consistently overlooked by the so called 'central government'. History is full of examples of the North being trodden on for the interests of the South. The closure of the mines in the 80s, the decline of the ship building industry are just two examples of how the North has been exploited in this manner. You only have to travel to Barrow in Furness to see this for yourself. This once proud ship building centre is now a virtual ghost town - all for the benefits of lining the pockets of London based share holders.

We the proud people of the North say enough is enough! 

We propose that every county North of and including Lincolnshire, Rutland, Leicestershire, Warwickshire, Worcestershire, Herefordshire shall hold a referendum to decide whether to join our new Northern nation.


Sign up now and show your support

1. freedom for the north</description>
  <mission>liberate the North of England from their Southern oppressors and form our own independent state</mission>
  <name>Northern Independence</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9137</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">50</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qu/jK/2w/ZC/nY/AR/SAtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
