<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>     
Adam Gould founder of the Kenya Children Project-  
        "After that was over we were able to see the children receive their morning porridge.  Slightly after that was lunchtime&#8230;Let me say that again LUNCHTIME!!!   What an incredible blessing it was to be there to serve the children their lunch for the day.  Two mothers have been hired to do all of the cooking with small jikos (little charcoal stoves).   We now have a small tin kitchen where all of the food is cooked.  We served large plates of rice, lentil beans, and sukuma wiki (kale).   We did so in each of the 3 classrooms we purchased next door to the church.  The kids received those meals in the new classrooms on new tables and benches made by one of the fathers.  It was just an awesome thing to sit there and watch these kids get a full meal.   They even got &#188; of an orange for dessert (which they receive twice a week). To this point God has blessed us with $52,000 for the project, which is awesome.   We still have a long way to go though, as our goal for the 3 year period is $782,000.  Just to give you an idea though of where some of the money goes, and the incredible job people do on the ground of being good stewards &#8211; to feed each child per month (porridge, rice, beans and greens 5 days a week and fruit 2 days a week) it costs $7 - $84 each year.   To feed every child in our school for the year it costs $4,704.  To pay each teacher per month is $200 &#8211; for the year $2,400.   To pay our 3 teachers for the year it costs $7,200.Thank you for your continued prayers and support.  I feel so incredibly blessed to be a part of this project.   Although sometimes I stumble over not making money (which really is Satan throwing stumbling blocks in the way), I realize what a privilege it is that God gave me this opportunity to raise the funds for and be involved with this project."

1. Education to break the chain of poverty

2. Boost Economy of the slum

3. Food for the children</description>
  <mission>In the slums of Nairobi, Kenya, Mathare Slum populated by over 600,000 people, children are not given a proper education. This project supplies funds in order to make a self-sustaining school/church</mission>
  <name>Kenya Children Project</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9144</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1243</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">614.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5U/rY/07/tr/TR/Ge/DlRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
