<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Some guys just don't get it. I never used to get it. And now I do. You want to know what a Beavers really want? Well it's a paradox. You see giving them what they want is really just giving back to yourself. Read on, you'll understand what I mean. 
Parents (our social upbringing), our schools, and especially the media- through movies, music videos (e.g. crappy songs like Christina Aguilera's "what a Beaver wants"), commercials, soap operas and sitcoms- have all told us how to treat a Beaver and "what a Beaver wants". But has it ever occurred to you that Beavers never fall for "nice guys" who try to give them what they want? Furthermore, has it ever dawned on you that Beavers DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY WANT anyway? Do you get the irony in all this? I hope so. However, *getting it* just doesn't cut it, in order to give a Beaver what she wants and needs, you need to understand it, and you need to live it. 
So how do you understand and live it? You care, by not caring at all. The best way to understand what a Beaver wants is to not ask that question at all. Just don't care. WHO CARES WHAT SHE WANTS? Why should you anyway? By not caring you allow them to be free, to do whatever so they please, thus giving them their own God given freewill. Since Beavers change what they want as often as a baby's diapers are changed, you can't really care about what they want, you will simply go crazy trying to give a Beaver what she wants. The feeble male mind is not equipped to handle such drastic fluctuations in desires. You'll need to give her not what she wants but what she needs, and that is a steadfast rock. 
Beaver are like a massive ocean of emotion. They flow and change like the waves and tides. They really have no direction. Whilst they can give to you the calmest and most peaceful experience, they can also brew the fiercest of storms sinking every man's ship that crosses their path. So if a Beaver is an ocean, what can a man be to give her what she wants? 


1. Beavers Need Love

2. Men Love Beavers</description>
  <mission>Help All Canadian Beavers</mission>
  <name>Support Canadian Beavers</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9157</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">13</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gO/rF/AY/GS/ki/Kl/pI3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
