<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What you will be reading are facts and information about the unfairness in the ratio of females to males in China, and how it is effecting their population.
Chinese researchers say, there are 41 million more males than females among China's 1.2 billion people, up 10 percent from the previous estimate in 1997.
China's family planning policy also complicates efforts to determine the extent of the problem. Strict limits on births have forced millions of parents to hide unapproved children, resulting in what Chinese call a "black population" of as many as 6 million unregistered children. Many of these children are believed to be girls.
The last major article about the problem in China's mainstream press appeared in 1997. Since then, despite government efforts, including a nationwide ban on sex-selective abortions, the situation has still not improved!
More broadly, Western and Chinese researchers are concerned that the trend, and the unintended consequences of family planning policies, will reinforce a sense that the lives of little girls -- and the women they grow up to be -- are less valuable than those of boys and men. Meaning, the Chinese Government is sexist.
When the one-child policy came into effect we began to see in the wealthy areas of China, what had never been done before in history &#8212; the killing of little girls.
Over the past decade, Americans have adopted more than 30,000 Chinese babies; almost all of them have been girls.
Raising awareness is important, the effort to emphasize equality of the sexes and the value of women in society will help reduce the problem in the long run.
Please join my cause to help save baby girls in China and to create a balance of equality in the ratio of females to males in China.

1. Women are just as important as men.

2. Baby girls should not be killed because they were born female.

3. More awareness on this situation should be acknowledged.</description>
  <mission>Emphasizing equality of the sexes and the value of women in China.</mission>
  <name>Stop Sex-Selective Abortions in China</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9166</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">266</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ix/VK/84/6W/MZ/nM/Dv5S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
