<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In authoritarian-controlled North Korea (Democratic People's Republic of Korea), human rights abuses ranging from mass malnutrition and hunger to torture of innocent political prisoners and their families to even state experimentation of chemical weapons on innocent civilians have left the people of North Korea in a situation of disparity. Due to the secretive nature of the North Korean government, information is hard to come by, but what little information there points to terrible human rights violations throughout the nation. It has been confirmed that several international laws regarding human rights have been violated by North Korea, and many believe this is just the tip of the ice berg. However, due to many political agendas and intense fear of North Korea, most governments tend to overlook or ignore the human aspect of the crisis in North Korea. We are a group of people dedicated to raising awareness of this terrible situation in the hope that eventually, the leaders of the international community decide to act to restore human rights in North Korea.


What you can do:

1. Donote to this cause, or other causes that have similar aims and goals. The foundation we support is the U.S. Committee for Human Rights in North Korea. There are many others to choose from, and we would suggest looking for one that suits you best.

2. Write a letter to your local, state, or national government represenatives asking them to take action on this issue.

3. Write your nation's offical represenative to North Korea or the United Nations asking them to work on solving this issue. You should also write to the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights, asking for the same thing.


Here are some links to more info:

1. http://www.hrnk.org/

2. http://www.amnestyusa.org/By_Country/North_Korea/page.do?id=1011213&amp;n1=3&amp;n2=30&amp;n3=963

3. http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_rights_in_North_Korea

4. http://hrw.org/doc/?t=asia&amp;c=nkorea

1. All people are entitled to basic human rights of freedom, equality, and a suitable standard of living.

2. No political agenda should come between what is the right thing to do.

3. Knowledge is power, and knowledge will save the people of North Korea.</description>
  <mission>Gain awareness for the abuse of human rights in the DPRK (North Korea)</mission>
  <name>End Human Rights Violations in North Korea</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9174</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1291</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">105.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ko/bV/bj/f7/Jo/bc/WrvS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
