<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Citizens Commission on Human Rights (http://www.cchrint.org)  is a non political, non-religious, mental health watchdog and non-profit organization. It has been responsible for more than 150 laws protecting individuals from abusive or coercive practices committed under the guise of mental health. CCHR works shoulder-to-shoulder with like-minded groups and individuals who share a common purpose to restore basic inalienable human rights to the field of mental health. These rights would include, but not be limited to, full informed consent regarding risks of treatments and all available medical alternatives, and the right to refuse any treatment considered harmful. CCHR's Board of Advisors, called Commissioners, include doctors, scientists, psychologists, lawyers, legislators, educators, business professionals, artists and civil and human rights representatives.


1. CCHRs mission includes requiring full informed consent to be enacted in the field of mental health

2. Informed consent would include disclosure of psychiatric drug risks including suicide, homicide, mania, psychois, heart attack, sudden death

3. Patients have the right to know that there are no medical tests in existence that can prove psychiatric disorders are medical conditions.

4. Patients have a right to know that there are non-drug, non-harmful medical treatments for addressing problems of mood, behavior and learning</description>
  <mission>To ensure basic human and civil rights are restored to the field of mental health, including but not limitied to full informed consent and the right to refuse harmful treatments</mission>
  <name>Citizens Commission on Human Rights (CCHR)  www.cchrint.org</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9178</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11204</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1871.85</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Bt/U0/mh/SZ/yl/5E/0t/i3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
