<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What are human rights?

Let's start with some basic definitions:

Human: noun
A member of the Homo sapiens species; a man, woman or child; a person.

Rights: noun
Things to which you are entitled or allowed; freedoms that are guaranteed.

Human Rights: noun
The rights you have simply because you are human.

United for Human Rights (UHR) assists and unites individuals, educators, organizations and governmental bodies to implement the Universal Declaration of Human Rights at local, regional, national and international levels. It was founded on the Declaration's 60th Anniversary in the face of continued worldwide abuses that violate the spirit and text of that charter. The Declaration, conceived by the United Nations, contains the 30 fundamental rights that together form the basis for a civilization where people can enjoy all freedoms to which they are entitled and nations can live in peace.

http://www.humanrights.com/

As one of UHR's primary functions is educative. The organization distributes informative and educational materials to increase public knowledge and bring about a full understanding of human rights. Further, UHR supports governmental and legislative measures that advance the full implementation of the Declaration.

&#160;UHR's sister organization, Youth for Human Rights International (YHRI), is a non-profit, tax-exempt organization headquartered in Los Angeles in the United States, with chapters around the world. Its purpose is to educate youth about human rights so they become valuable advocates of tolerance and peace. YHRI not only works hands-on with youth, but also with parents, teachers and mentors.

Youth for Human Rights International has expanded rapidly since its founding in 2001. Its first chapters outside the United States were established through a 4,500-mile educational human rights tour. Visiting fourteen countries, YHRI representatives delivered presentations to government officials, youth leaders and schools. Throughout the tour, they distributed copies of youth-oriented materials on human rights among teachers and pupils. The children responded with enthusiasm--writing stories, drawing pictures and composing songs to demonstrate what they had learned about human rights.

 As YHRI grew, it developed several additional human rights teaching tools. These include a fully illustrated child's version of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, an award-winning human rights music video, and probably the first ever series of audiovisual public service announcements covering each of the 30 rights in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. These YHRI materials, produced in 18 languages, are currently in use in more than 50 countries.

The widespread and sustained character of these educational actions has won the acclaim of prominent human rights organizations, earning Youth for Human Rights International numerous awards from such bodies as the United Nations Development Program and UNICEF.

http://www.humanrights.com/#/home


1. WHAT ARE HUMAN RIGHTS?

2. YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO KNOW</description>
  <mission>Our Mission is to educate people in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights so they become valuable advocates for tolerance and peace.</mission>
  <name>United for Human Rights</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9179</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10944</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">533.12</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Dk/UU/Fx/Mj/JG/lR/xd/CcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
