<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> Follow This Link to visit my personal web page and help me in my efforts to support RFL - Knox County North TN.

Please copy this url and past in your browser.
http://www.acsevents.org/relay/tn/fountaincity/kccline


Relay For Life is an overnight event that brings our community together to help support the American Cancer Society and its lifesaving mission to eliminate cancer as a major health problem. The Society works hard every day to prevent cancer and save lives by supporting groundbreaking research, affecting public policies that protect us from cancer, and educating people on how to prevent or detect cancer early. The Society helps people with cancer right here in our own community. And our efforts at Relay For Life can help the American Cancer Society to keep working toward a cancer-free future.

I want to invite you to show your support in the ongoing fight against cancer by joining us for this year&#8217;s event. Please click on the link below for more information, including details on the inspirational Survivors&#8217; Lap and the moving Luminaries Ceremony. We hope to see you there! If you can&#8217;t join us, will you please visit the site and make a donation to support our efforts? Either way, you will make a real difference in the lives of people facing cancer &#8211; and in the lives of the people who love them. Thank you!

1. Unfortunately, cancer is disease that effects all of our lives at some point.  Join in the fight against this life harming disease. </description>
  <mission>Aide in Cancer Research

Instead of using the Donation link; Please use this URL for donations to assist my team's Relay for Life efforts.  
http://www.acsevents.org/relay/tn/fountaincity/kccline
</mission>
  <name>American Cancer Society Relay for Life</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9189</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10469</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2543.15</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qw/QH/5m/ZH/vy/K5/DcxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
