<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>&lt;b&gt;DO NOT DONATE TO THIS CAUSE!&lt;/b&gt; The rules of the "causes" challenge included having to start a new cuase from scratch to make it fair to all causes. &lt;b&gt;Please donate to the cause "Leukemia and Lymphoma Society" by folloqing the link below, so your donation will count towards the challenge.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
http://apps.facebook.com/causes/view_cause/47255
&lt;p&gt;
 Please join this cause if you care about finding a cure for blood cancers! You don't have to join our team, donate, or anything like that, just as long as you join and get the word out there!

IMPORTANT: Please do not donate here, go to out website where the donations will show up as coming from FSU. Our link is below

The Light The Night Walk is The Leukemia &amp; Lymphoma Society's nationwide evening walk. Walkers carry illuminated balloons to celebrate and commemorate the lives touched by cancer during an emotional evening full of fun, food, music, games, and advocacy. Funds raised will support our mission to cure blood cancers.

Your participation will help save lives. Please join us in our fight against blood cancers, as we Light The Night with hope and raise funds to find a cure. Teams and individuals with the most donations will receive recognition and awards at the walk. We want FSU to show the rest of Tallahassee how it's done, and that young people really DO care!

This event takes place Thursday, October 11th at the Downtown Chain of Parks. 

HERE'S HOW TO JOIN TEAM FSU:
o Go to our Team Page at http://teams.lightthenight.org/TeamFSU
o Click on the yellow JOIN button
o Fill out the form, and you're all set! Thank you!
o Your walker welcome packet will soon arrive in the mail to the address you provided

To Register your own team: Join Team FSU first, then send an email to jbayo@fsu.edu

We're participating in the walk in honor of all individuals who are battling blood cancer. These people are the real heroes, and we need your support to help accelerate cures and give hope to patients and their families. Although research is responsible for increasing survival rates for these diseases, the battle is far from over.

We are planning meetings, group fundraisers, and other fun events that will help raise funds and awareness for Light the Night and bring us all together as a group; we are so excited to have your support of our team!

TO VIEW THE OFFICIAL LIGHT THE NIGHT VIDEO, CLICK BELOW:
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uMg7xK2gDxs


1. Every five minutes, someone in this country is diagnosed with blood cancer: Every ten minutes, someone loses the fight. 

2. Leukemia causes more deaths than any other cancer among children under the age of 20. This most likely includes you. 

3. Lymphomas are the most common blood cancers. 

4. The myeloma survival rate is only 32 percent</description>
  <mission>Our goal is to cure leukemia, lymphoma, Hodgkin's disease and myeloma - and to improve the quality of life of patients and their families.</mission>
  <name>Light the Night: FSU Chapter</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/920</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">113</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">48.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/DbO/6IPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
