<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The USO recognizes the sacrifices that service members and their families make for this country, and it is now more important than ever that they are remembered and supported. The USO offers a variety of programs and services that support the morale, welfare, social and entertainment needs of American service men and women and their families. With the help of its supporters, the USO continues to provide a "home away from home" to service men and women around the world. 

In times of peace and war, the USO has consistently delivered its special brand of comfort, morale and recreational services to the military. The USO, a congressionally chartered, private, nonprofit organization, relies on the generosity of individuals and corporations to support USO activities. 

Today, the USO delivers its programs and services at more than 130 locations around the world. In recent years, the USO opened centers in Kuwait, Qatar and Afghanistan to support service members participating in Operations Enduring and Iraqi Freedom.

The USO reaches out through:
Airport centers, welcoming weary military travelers with a place to rest and the ability to familiarize themselves with their new surroundings 
Family and community centers, promoting intercultural understanding and orientation to unfamiliar locations 
Mobile USOs, reaching out to troops in remote and sometimes unstable locations 
 
USO celebrity entertainment tours bring volunteer celebrities to entertain, lift morale, and express the gratitude and support of the American people. 

For 66 years, the USO's mission has remained the same. The USO will support U.S. troops and their families wherever they serve. Across the United States and around the world, the American military knows that the USO is there for them. By supporting the USO, Americans show their appreciation and express their gratitude to the men and women who defend us. 

Source: www.USO.com


1. Support the troops! </description>
  <mission>Raise money for the troops who serve overseas and stateside!</mission>
  <name>Support our Troops! Donate to the USO</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9220</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">725</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">285.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Lv/l5/4U/hd/0H/47/8fxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
