<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>** Please check out and join our new Cause page that benefits the Village called Race4Rwanda at http://apps.facebook.com/causes/race4rwanda ** 

Nearly one million people were murdered in 100 days in 1994. Hundreds of thousands of survivors became traumatized and the country was left in ruins. As a direct aftermath of the genocide, over 1.2 million children remain orphaned today &#8212; forever robbed of their parents, communities, homes, and any hope for a viable future.

Life disrupted&#8230;Life restored
The Agahozo-Shalom Youth Village (ASYV) aims to create a safe and structured community for orphaned children in Rwanda. A place where these traumatized youth can &#8220;dry their tears&#8221; (Agahozo) and &#8220;live in peace&#8221; (Shalom).

Within this environment, the &#8220;rhythm of life&#8221; will be restored: a child rises from his/her bed in the morning, eats breakfast with siblings and &#8220;parents,&#8221; walks to school and back home in the afternoon.

The result is healthy adults who are not only able to care for themselves and their families, but who are committed to making their community and the world a better place.


If you want to make a donation directly to the cause, go to
https://www.jdc.org/donation/personal.asp 

1. 1.2 million orphans (15% of Rwanda's population) are in need of housing, education, and medical help

2. The village will teach leadership skills to Rwandan orphans of genocide

3. ASYV will supply Rwandan orphans with community life to give them as close to a normal adolecence as possible</description>
  <mission>help the orphans of Rwanda</mission>
  <name>Agahozo Shalom Youth Village</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9221</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">206</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">290.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fl/Rd/Qb/b1/77/Qh/Mi0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
