<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>I am all about animal rights. I think people like Micheal Vick should pay for their crimes of animal cruelty. I used to believe like everyone else that Peta were the good guys. They wanted to help animals and that was good. That was before I found out their stances on many things. 

-Peta is against having animals as pets/companions. 

-They pay hundreds of thousands of dollars to arsonists to burn down businesses. 

-They KILLED 90% of the pets that they collected from members of the public.

- They have a $26 million budget and yet instead of opening no-kill shelters, they euthenize the animals they pick up.

- They threw the corpses of their animal victims in GARBAGE DUMPSTERS!

-PETA keeps records of how much sodium pentobarbital it takes to kill a puppy, but the group can't keep track of how many dead animals made it back into the company freezer.

-PETA vegetarian campaign coordinator Bruce Friedrich said that &#8220;blowing stuff up and smashing windows&#8221; is &#8220;a great way to bring about animal liberation.&#8221; 

-One entire PETA website is devoted to the claim-despite ample evidence to the contrary-that Jesus Christ was a vegetarian. PETA protests at houses of worship, even suing a church that tried to protect its members from Sunday-morning harassment. Its billboards taunt Christians with the message that hogs &#8220;died for their sins.&#8221; PETA insists, contrary to centuries of rabbinical teaching, that the Jewish ritual of kosher slaughter shouldn't be allowed. And its infamous &#8220;Holocaust on Your Plate&#8221; campaign compares the Jewish victims of Nazi genocide with farm animals. 

-PETA has attacked research foundations like the March of Dimes, the Pediatric AIDS Foundation, and the American Cancer Society, because they support animal-based research that might uncover cures for birth defects and life-threatening diseases. PETA president Ingrid Newkirk said that &#8220;even if animal research resulted in a cure for AIDS, we would be against it.&#8221; 



1. Animal rights are extremely important.

2. PETA are murderous hypocrites that kill the animals they are supposedly trying to protect.

3. I want to enlighten others to the truth.</description>
  <mission>Show people the truth about Peta and their hypocrisy. 
Also visit www.petakillsanimals.com. They are the ones who enlightened me.</mission>
  <name>People Against Peta</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9228</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">134</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yu/2o/W0/nb/yS/8x/HGHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
