<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The US government wastes billions of dollars a year on crop subsidies and import tariffs. The money goes to people who dont needs it, the money hurts foreign policy by creating dependancy in poor countries, it encourages bad health, and drains the US Treasury. We must stop this travesty!

The money often goes to people who dont need it. 

Large landowners can get hundreds of thousands of dollars a year even though their farms are self suffcient. Currently because of high demand from china and new uses like ethanol we are in an agricultural commodity boom period. This ensures high prices for farmers without subsides. These farmers dont need extra money.  

The subsidies hurt developing countries who can do nothing but farm. 

Some countries have only one thing they can do, farm. US subsidies coupled with food grants destroy economies in Africa and Latin America making them dependant on foreign aid and charity just to eat. If these countries cant be self sufficient they will always require charity from abroad. These countries then make it harder to pass free trade agreements such as the DOHA agreement.

Some subsidies are detrimental to our health.

The US has heavy corn subsidies coupled with tariffs on imported sugar. As a result companies use high fructose corn syrup instead of sugar because it is cheaper. Unfortunately our livers handle sucrose and fructose differently. It is harder for our livers to handle the sugar from corn, which is encouraged by subsides subsidies. 

Lastly we have a huge budget deficit.

There are plenty ways to use billions of dollars besides subsidies. Poverty, military, retirement, health care all come to mind. We can find a better use for this money.

We must unite to end US Farm subsidies now. 

1. Farm subsidies are awarded to those who dont need them

2. Farm subsidies cause poor countries to become dependant on rich ones

3. Farm subsidies encourage us to choose food which is bad for us 

4. Farm subsidy money can be used for many other things</description>
  <mission>End US Crop Subsidies</mission>
  <name>End US Crop Subsidies</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9230</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">54</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Co/3m/8D/Bw/mm/Es/Go7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
