<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In 1997, a tobacco CEO said that if it was proven to his satisfaction that cigarettes cause cancer, he'd shut down immediately to get a better old on things. Their website now admits that cigarettes cause cancer, but they're still open for buisness.

Smoking is an addiction. Over 4,000 chemicals are found in cigarette smoke, many of which are known carcinogens to both humans and other animals. Nicotine, a drug found naturally in tobacco, is highly addictive and makes it very hard for a person to quit smoking once they have begun the habit.

The Center for Disease Control and Prevention has reported that tobacco use remains the leading preventable cause of death in the United States, causing more than 440,000 deaths each year and resulting in an annual cost of more than $75 billion in direct medical costs. Nationally, smoking results in more than 5.6 million years of potential life lost each year. Approximately 80% of adult smokers started smoking before the age of 18. Every day, nearly 4,000 young people under the age of 18 try their first cigarette.

More than 6.4 million children living today will die prematurely because of a decision they will make as adolescents - the decision to smoke cigarettes.

Cigarettes contain tar, carbon monoxide, chemicals like DDT, arsenic and formaldehyde (a gas used to preserve dead animals). There is also rat posion in cigarettes. Would you ever put that in your body?

1. Smoking is stupid. It's the leading preventable cause of death in the United States.

2. Yellow teeth, horrible smelling clothing and yellow fingernails aren't hot; they will never be.</description>
  <mission>Prevent people from starting to smoke</mission>
  <name>Whudafxup With Smoking?</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9231</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">221</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GQ/Xa/H5/2T/0M/28/PqNS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
