<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>UNICEF is the driving force that helps build a world where the rights of every child are realized. We have the global authority to influence decision-makers, and the variety of partners at grassroots level to turn the most innovative ideas into reality.  That makes us unique among world organizations, and unique among those working with the young. 

We believe that nurturing and caring for children are the cornerstones of human progress.  UNICEF was created with this purpose in mind &#8211; to work with others to overcome the obstacles that poverty, violence, disease and discrimination place in a child&#8217;s path.  We believe that we can, together, advance the cause of humanity. We advocate for measures to give children the best start in life, because proper care at the youngest age forms the strongest foundation for a person&#8217;s future.  We act so that all children are immunized against common childhood diseases, and are well nourished, because it is wrong for a child to suffer or die from a preventable illness. We work to prevent the spread of HIV/AIDS among young people because it is right to keep them from harm and enable them to protect others. We help children and families affected by HIV/AIDS to live their lives with dignity. We involve everyone in creating protective environments for children. We are present to relieve suffering during emergencies, and wherever children are threatened, because no child should be exposed to violence, abuse or exploitation. We work in 191 countries through country programmes and National Committees. We are UNICEF, the United Nations Children&#8217;s Fund.

Source: UNICEF.com

UNICEF Positions Courtesy of Maura McGrath.

1. Provide equal education for all, regardless of gender.

2. Provide nourishment and vaccinations against common childhood diseases.

3. Work towards preventing the spreading of HIV/AIDS among young children.

4. Protect children from violence, rape, abuse, and exploitation.

5. Create a safe environment for children across the globe.</description>
  <mission>Help and protect children throughout the globe.</mission>
  <name>UNICEF: United Nations Children&#8217;s Fund</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/924</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">21079</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2049.48</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Pnv/M4hS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
