<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Multiple sclerosis (abbreviated to MS) is a chronic, inflammatory, demyelinating disease that affects the central nervous system, and the end effects are devastating for the victims overtaken by this disease, and their loved ones.

Multiple sclerosis affects neurons, the cells of the brain and spinal cord that carry information, create thought and perception, and allow the brain to control the body. Surrounding and protecting some of these neurons is a fatty layer known as the myelin sheath, which helps neurons carry electrical signals. MS causes gradual destruction of myelin (demyelination) and transection of neuron axons in patches throughout the brain and spinal cord.

The predominant theory today is that MS results from attacks by an individual's immune system on the nervous system and it is therefore usually categorized as an autoimmune disease. MS primarily affects adults, with an age of onset typically between 20 and 40 years, and is more common in women than in men.

Though there are several temporary treatments that can slow and aleviate symptoms and often times, patients can go into "remission" for a period of time, there is no known cure for multiple sclerosis. 

Because it affects the immune system and the nerves which lead to the brain, there is no way to recover from the disease after it has escalated too far. MS will cause impaired mobility and disability in severe cases.

More and more people are being diagnosed with MS every year, and without a cure, it is completely unpreventable. Nobody deserves to live with the devastation that this disease leaves. A cure must be found.

1. The devastation left behind by multiple sclerosis must be prevented.

2. Everyone has a part to play in the research of this disease; it can affect anyone.</description>
  <mission>Support the research that goes towards finding a cure for MS</mission>
  <name>Support Multiple Sclerosis Research</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9240</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10528</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">2552.73</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/3m/Sp/Wv/ya/2j/s4/xyQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
