<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>According to Anti-Slavery International, "A person enters debt bondage when their labor is demanded as a means of repayment of a loan, or of money given in advance. Usually, people are tricked or trapped into working for no pay or very little pay (in return for such a loan), in conditions which violate their human rights. Invariably, the value of the work done by a bonded laborer is greater that the original sum of money borrowed or advanced."
At international law

Debt bondage has been defined by the United Nations as a form of "modern day slavery" [1] and is prohibited by international law. It persists nonetheless especially in developing nations, which have few mechanisms for credit security or bankruptcy, and where fewer people hold formal title to land or possessions. According to some economists, for example Hernando de Soto, this is a major barrier to development in those countries - entrepreneurs do not dare take risks and cannot get credit because they hold no collateral and may burden families for generations to come.

Despite the UN prohibition, Anti-Slavery International estimates that "between 10 and 20 million people are being subjected to debt bondage today."
Modern example: prostitution

News media in western Europe regularly carry reports about one particular kind of debt bondage: women from Eastern Europe who are forced to work in prostitution as a way to pay off the "debt" they acquired when they were illegally brought over the border.

Debt bondage is a form of disguised slavery in which the subject is not legally owned, but is instead bound by a contract to perform labor to work off a debt, under terms that make it impossible to completely retire the debt and thereby escape from the contract. 


1. Initiate prosecutions of all documented cases of bonded labor

2. Provide protection to all witnesses who testify to the existence of bonded labor

3. Provide financial and administrative resources for the effective release and rehabilitation of all bonded laborers.

4. Initiate a thorough review and reform of Vigilance Committees</description>
  <mission>End Debt-Bondage</mission>
  <name>End Debt-Bondage/ Modern Slavery</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9250</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">28</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ic/m5/Sx/me/l3/U6/nkrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
