<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Mothers Against Drunk Driving (MADD Canada) is a non-profit, grassroots organization that is committed to stopping impaired driving and supporting the victims of this violent crime. At the heart of MADD Canada is our volunteers who include not only mothers, but fathers, friends, business professionals, experts in the anti-impaired driving field and concerned citizens who want to make a difference in the fight against impaired driving. 


1. That our primary reason for existence is to eliminate the killing and maiming caused by impaired driving.

2. Equally vital to MADD Canada's existence is supporting victims of this violent crime.

3. That MADD Canada is a grassroots organization that draws its strength, energy, and leadership from its volunteers.

4. That active participation in MADD Canada chapter activities is productive for the community and encourages healing for many victims of impaired driving.

5. An aggressive legislative and public policy advocacy program is a must to achieve MADD Canada's mission

6. That a National Victims' Bill of Rights must be created in order to ensure fair and respectful treatment of all victims of crime

7. That a balanced program of public awareness, education, legislation, and aggressive enforcement by police, crown attorneys, and the courts is essential to eliminating impaired driving.

8. That while an individual's decision to consume alcohol is a private matter, driving after consuming alcohol is a public matter.

9. That impaired drivers and others who directly contribute to the crime of impaired driving must be held accountable for their behaviour.

10. That proactive rehabilitation of impaired drivers is essential

11. That driving is a privilege, not a right

12. That impaired driving crashes are not accidents. </description>
  <mission>offer support services to victims, heighten awareness about the dangers of drinking and driving, and to save lives and prevent injuries on our roads.</mission>
  <name>MADD Canada</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9267</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5703</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">125.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sU/FK/Lh/rS/gX/WH/gqFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
