<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>San Francisco has become the first city in North America to ban the usage of traditional plastic bags in grocery and drugstores. Traditional plastic bags require 594 BTUs of energy to produce and are made from petroleum and other natural gasses, both of which are non-renewable resources. Not only does this increase our dependency on foreign suppliers but is also leads to the devastation and expungement of ecosystems and habitats worldwide. Each year the US consumes more then 380 billion plastic bags, sacks, and wraps, making up more than 3/4th's of the 500 billion to 1 trillion plastic bags consumed worldwide every year. However, the devastation does not end at the factories; it continues on its way to the stores, into the consumer's trash bins and finally either swept away by the wind or comes to rest in a landfill for up to 500 to 1000 years until they finally decompose. After fulfilling their duties, these seemingly innocuous bags make their way to kill hundreds of thousands of sea turtles and other marine animals who have mistaken them for food. But, it doesn't end there either. Bags do not just harmlessly biodegrade and disappear, instead they photodegrade, meaning that the sun eventually brakes them down into tiny toxic particles which contaminate the soil and waterways, ultimately getting into our food and drinking water. Plastic bags create toxins and global warming emissions throughout their entire life cycle - - from production to consumption and beyond. With New York being one of the most famous and influential cities in the world, it is our responsibility to help lead the way in the fight against global warming and pave the way to a cleaner and safer planet.

SIGN PETITION: 
http://www.thepetitionsite.com/1/plastic-bag-ban

Links &gt;&gt;
http://www.reusablebags.com/facts.php?id=2

1. Plastic NEVER Biodegrades and is extremely TOXIC

2. Use reusable bags!</description>
  <mission>This group is meant to get people informed on the hazards of Plastic and to encourage the usage of reusable products.
</mission>
  <name>Ban Plastic Bags In NY!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9271</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">67</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/0V/dI/bQ/aQ/KE/12/QJuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
