<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>PLEASE DO NOT CLICK THE "DONATE" BUTTON ON HERE. See details below:

That's right- I'm going to run a marathon! 
So how am I doing? Well I've built up to more than 1/2 the distance of a marathon (26.3 miles) and raised almost $3000 (my goal is $4500).

Believe it or not waking up at 6 am on sat. and lugging it out under the oh so hot LA sun seems much less painful to me than asking for financial support. 

But then I remind myself: I'm really asking on behalf of the thousands that are infected by HIV daily. I'm asking for that man and woman who needs healthy food, but is living on $800/month; who needs dental care, but is a risk at any dentist office; who needs encouragement, but is carrying an isolating disease.

I also remember that you all care for me, and many will give if you are able and if you are asked.

So that's what I'm up to: filling you in &amp; asking if you would support me and ultimately those who need care as they struggle with this epidemic.

The fundraising deadline is August 15th but there is a grace period afterwards (phew!).

THANK YOU fo your support and encouragement. If you're inspired and willing- please pass on the cause!

PLEASE DO NOT CLICK THE "DONATE" BUTTON ON HERE. INSTEAD PLEASE GO TO: 

http://www.aidsmarathon.com/participant.asp?
runner=LA-5047&amp;EventCode=FL07

OR

You may make a check payable to: 
AIDS Marathon-LA (include LA-5047 in the memo field)

Donations may be mailed to:
National AIDS Marathon Training Program
c/o AIDS Project LA
2550 9th Street #103
Berkeley, CA 94710-2551 

PLEASE DO NOT CLICK ON THE "DONATE" BUTTON TO DONATE. THE DONATION THERE DOES NOT GO TOWARDS MY PERSONAL GOAL OF $4500.

ALL Donations are Tax Deductible. 
Tax ID#: 52-1122-122 (National AIDS Marathon)

Please feel free to get in touch with me should you have any questions or concerns at: (415)702-5561 or stineybean@gmail.com

1. improving the lives of people affected by HIV disease

2. reducing the incidence of HIV infection

3. advocating for fair and effective HIV-related public policy.</description>
  <mission>Provide education, food banks, transporation, home health care and other vital services - to help keep people alive until there is a cure 
</mission>
  <name>the AIDS Marathon</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9272</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">37</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/xJ/l4/ma/Xy/Ac/lI/rZQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
