<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>At the beginning of 2007 in Australia, 1394 people were waiting for kidney organ transplants.  Six months later, only 107 people in the country had donated organs (of all types).  In 2009, the figure is increasing slightly, but not enough to save those who are victims of our own system.

Australia has a system where people must deliberately register on the national organ registry, also called the opt-in system.  Only one quarter of our population has registered to become an organ donor, where in more than 50% of cases, if someone dies, the their family steps in to overrule the donor's dying wish.  

Some European countries (like Spain) don't have an opt-in system, they have an opt-out system which works in the opposite way to ours.  The opt-out system sees all healthy organs being taken from those who die UNLESS they have registered on the opt-out organ donor registry. This is not an immoral or unethical practice as you ALWAYS have the choice to opt-out if you wish.  Countries that have an opt-out system in place have an incredibly high (and successful) rate of organ transplants.  Therefore, the thousands of young and old people awaiting a second chance at life through organ donation usually get a transplant quite quickly, unlike Australia where you can be waiting years and years and then it's too late.

If Australia claims to be amongst those countries at the forefront of medical developments in the world, why do we allow ourselves to have one of the lowest organ donor and transplant rates in the whole world? Unethical to take peoples' organs, you think? Why don't we take them unless people have opted out? 
Hopefully Australia will in the near future propel to the forefront by implementing an opt-out system (like the Austria and Spain). However, as we currently stand, this is not a brilliant (nor forward thinking) place to be, and it's only getting worse.  Someone pull a finger out and make the right decision for our nation and humanity, will you?

My aim is to increase peoples' awareness of the significant need for more organs donors (living or deceased) in this country, and am hoping you will tell your friends about it too.  Most people won't think about being an organ donor until it hits close to home.  It only takes a moment to get on the national organ donor registry, and make sure you tell your family about your absolute wishes to donate as they can overule your wish after you've gone.  Copy and paste this link into your web browser to register now: http://www.medicareaustralia.gov.au/yourhealth/our_services/aaodr.htm 

Thank you,

Michelle

(I am working on having my cause linked to an Australian kidney organisation, however, Facebook currently only caters for US causes where monetary donations are made.)

1. Australia should implement the opt-out system

2. Anonymous donors should be allowed to donate in Australia if that's their wish

3. A healthy donor's wishes cannot be overturned by ANYONE, AT ANY TIME</description>
  <mission>To raise peoples&#8217; awareness of the significant need for more kidney organs transplants in Australia.</mission>
  <name>Kidney Transplants Australia</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9276</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1580</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">225.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Fg/vr/Qx/c3/mN/wy/pYlS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
