<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Bible verses, the confirmation passages, and Sunday school songs we memorize as children often come rushing back in times of stress.
We take comfort in the child-like faith of our baptism that still exists within us and we reach for it in times of weakness.
Armed Forces Ministry chaplains know all about these kinds of needs. Warriors are supposed to be strong in body,mind, and spirit. Military training can makr the body and mind strong, but it takes the ministry of the chaplain to maintain the spirit.
There are specially trained clergy who have been called upon and deployed globally. Some are active parish pastors who have left their flock to serve others, usually far from home.
Army units continue to rotate to Iraq and Afghanistan in a relentless cycle. Troops deploy to volatile regions as the U.S. maintains its presence in allied countries. All the While, chaplains offer faithful pastoral care, worship opportunities, Bible studies, baptism and confirmation instruction, moral guidence, and hospital visitation to thousands of military personnel.Chaplains bring gods strength to men and women of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine, Reserve, and National Guard who are lonely and separated from spouses and loved ones.


As chaplains provide the spiritual support for our troops, they rely on your prayers and gifts to sustain them in their service. 

And please do NOT donate any money yet...I am still trying to find the correct beneficiaries

1. Maintain a corps of active duty chaplains who serve with military men and women all over the world.</description>
  <mission>Serve Those who Serve</mission>
  <name>Ministry To The Armed Forces</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9280</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eY/zS/hN/Jq/Jg/4A/selS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
