<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>From Greek atheos; godless


What is Atheism exactly? Most people either don't know, or have misconceptions of what it is to be atheist. One thing it is not is anti-religion. In fact, several organized religions fall under the definition of what atheism is, such as Buddhism, Taoism, etc. It is not anti-God, God hating, or theist hating, because true Atheism is about peace and the growth of knowledge. It is not an immoral group with ethical behavior. Many critics claim that it is not possible to live a moral life without "God," but atheists abide by the same social and government laws as those who believe in God. And lastly it is not "Darwinism" or solely believing in evolution. Many atheists believe in the theory of evolution, but it is not what it is based on. 

Atheism is the lack of belief in a deity or "God." It is purely disbelief in an omnipotent being who rules with supreme power. Simple as that. 

Why? Why do atheists choose not to believe in an all omnipotent Lord? there are many reasons, varying from each person, but the most common is that most religion is so unbelievable. With common sense and a good soul-search, many of us realize that what we have been told about God and religion just doesn't add up with modern science and historical evidence. 

A popular questions towards atheists is where they get their morals from, since they don't have a holy book to guide them. This is a simple question, we use our common sense. Common sense tells us that certain things are right, and some wrong, it's not complicated. Plus, rules should change as a society progresses. The social structures in the early days of Islam and Christianity are radically different from modern society, so codes that may have worked then, will not work now. As a functioning person in the world, I am able to realize what is morally and ethically correct with a little knowledge and a little common sense. 

Now, the charity group that donations for this group goes to is an American based Atheism headquarters. This is because in America, atheists are faced with discrimination, mainly from lack of knowledge. This group tries to change that by educating people, which is what people need most. Education can change everything, and when we can create a world where the largest power houses are atheist, we can start a generation of peace and science. 

1. Atheism is the lack of belief in a deity or "God."

2. We are pushing the world of science and technology to create a brighter future

3. We use education as a weapon against ignorance, and common sense as a moral compass</description>
  <mission>To unite existing Atheists and to clear up misconceptions about Atheism. </mission>
  <name>Atheists United </name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9308</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">198</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/nA/vR/8A/R2/0V/D4/YEgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
