<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>1. Stopping the BUM-HUMPING without lubrication
 of OUR Mother Earth!!!
 
2. Help the  Re-Generation of the Ozone layer!!! 

3. IF only industrial and commercial methods of garbage dispersal changed renewal of our Ozone would give mother earth that helping hand to start the reversed effect of Global Warming caused by NOT Recycling, NOT Reusing and by NOT Reducing materials such as (1).Woods(pallets/crates/demolition),  (2). Papers(used/unused/office papers/WAX) ,(3).Plastics(all),  (4).Cardboard's(all/every),     (5.)Styrofoams(every type),  (6).Metals(ferrous or non-ferrous),  (7).Glass and pop &amp; alcohol containers.  

4. All recyclable materials are worth money. 

5. Needless to sAy aLL products take energy to make so why use up resources on making new when there already here TO BE USED and REUSED!

6.did you know 70-80 percent of the worlds wood goes to making pallets and crates!!                


WASTE NOT WANT NOT

HOW LONG WILL A ENGINE RUN WITH NO OILS AND FLUIDS? NOT LONG RIGHT
 EVERYTHING WILL SEIZE UP 

NOW IF EARTH WAS SUCKED DRY OF ITS NATURAL MINERALS AND OILS WONDER WHAT WOULD HAPPEN????/
THE EARTHS SHIFTING 
NOT SO SMOOTHLY
 I BE-LIVE ITS CALLED EARTHQUAKE!
(do you notice them every year more and more stronger an stronger uplifting upon the earths great lands and even greater oceans.)

knowledge is power
power in numbers 

numbers is whats needed in the fight for the greater good 

generations to come is my worry, how bout you?

DOES ANYONE REALLY CARE?????????????????????

ALSO,.............................. HAVE YOU THOUGHT ABOUT THE AUTOMOBILE INDUSTRIES AND THERE BIG ASS TESTICLES , so WHY's THEY FIGURE THAT THEY CAN CHARGE US ALL SHIT LOAD OF $m$o$n$e$y$ FOR AN ITEM THAT THEY KNOW WILL EVENTUALLY COME BACK AT THE INDUSTRIES...............................

explanation:  A car, truck , van, motor bike any vehicle is WORTH MONEY and when we are done with that particular AUTO we would most likely get rid of, give away or just discard in one way or another not thinking of the actuality of it all,...that old truck or car of yours is worth cash money almost (92-96%) of any given every single part that's made of metal down to the nuts and bolts is worth $$$-rite-down-to-the-pound ! 
so basically it will come back to auto industries; in turn re-cycled and perhaps some metals are again used to build a:  50,000 BMW or a 35,000 CHEVY truck, It may-be used for a more Mother Earth friendly vehicle but as it may be that and those cars are very expensive which therefore becomes so far out of reach, with only a small fraction of the Earths population being able to afford one.    IF everyone owned one would it help the quote"GLOBAL WARMING" un-quote ? ? ///??////????/////?///?//????/?////?//////???/

1. doug d. Aka.RECYCLING VIGALANTE(R.V.) is at work!!!!

2. (R.V.)quote: "only DEATH WILL STOP me from helping the Healing of OUR MOTHER!!!"  and "still then my energy will be positivly past onward; infinite"

3. Mother Earth NEEDS YOU! (every single-one of-us)

4. JIMMY, Butter</description>
  <mission>Re-Generation of OUR Mother Earth!!! IF not us then who?</mission>
  <name>SAVE OUR MOTHER(earth)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9311</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3488</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/HY/dr/ww/WI/Rn/2x/cIkS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
