<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>In times of national conflicts, children suffer the most. Children's Voices recognises that while it is necessary to bring the current conflicts to an end, it is also important to try and ensure that such conflict does not happen again. To do so, we need to help children to heal, forgive or at least understand those that caused them harm. Those children that lost parents, family and support structures because of poverty, abuse and war, need our urgent support. Orphanages around the world house thousands of children who do not have parents to guide them and who do not have proper access to education and opportunities of betterment. While some of the orphanages are adequately provisioned, others are sadly lacking in basic necessities. Before a child can learn, a child has to be fed and clothed. Children's Voices' and Peace Appeal South Asia recognizes this basic need of children in south Asia. Through our 'Appeal of the Child' program we support needy and unsupported children's homes with monthly, clothing, toys, books and basic amenities. The Children's Voices program supports homes that shelter children who: lost their parents in war; are victims of human trafficking; been abused by family members; been forced in child labor; have no family to take care of them; or are from families that cannot take care of them. This program is not only about providing material assistance. Children's Voices provides a personal support. The staff visits the homes to spend time with the children, sharing a meal with them, or simply talking, spending time and playing with them. Children's Voices hopes to foster attitudes of understanding, care, empathy and love with the children we work ...which would benefit the war-torn societies we work in.

1. The child shall have the right to freedom of expression; this right shall include freedom to seek, receive and impart information and ideas of all kinds, regardless of frontiers, either orally, in writing or in print, in the form of art, or through any ot

2. Teaching children understanding and tolerance of other cultures and religions.

3. Every child should have opportunities and room to grow.</description>
  <mission>Reduce the suffering of children by working and advocating against neglect, abuse, exploitation, child labour and military recruitment</mission>
  <name>Children's Voices</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9315</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">241</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gk/es/md/Qf/Po/JS/KwxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
