<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>For over 100 years, The Canadian Lung Association has been dedicated to its mission of promoting and improving lung health for all Canadians. A non-profit and volunteer-based health charity, The Lung Association depends on donations from the public to support lung health research, education, prevention and advocacy.

The Lung Association works at the national, provincial and community levels to improve and promote lung health. We focus on chronic lung disease like asthma and COPD, infectious diseases like TB, flu, and pneumonia, and breathing disorders like sleep apnea. We provide reliable and trusted information to both citizens and governments, and we advocate for improvements when lung disease patients are getting inadequate care.

We fund world-class medical research in Canada to find treatments- and ultimately a cure- for lung diseases. Through the Canadian Thoracic Society and Canadian Respiratory Health Professionals, we help doctors and allied health professionals set the highest standards in patient care, and continue to expand their knowledge about lung diseases and treatments.



1. Many lung diseases can be prevented.

2. Doctors and allied health professionals must set the highest standards in patient care, and continue to expand their knowledge about lung diseases and treatments.

3. People must be properly informed regaurding the health effects of air pollution, indoors and out.

4.  We need support for smokers who are trying to quit, and educational material and programs must be provided to make sure fewer people take up smoking. 

5. Governments must be encouraged at every level to create laws and policies that promote clean air and protect our lungs.

6. Continued research is needed into the cause and cure of both cronic and atmospheric lung diseases.

7. BUT MOST OF ALL "Every Person Deserves To Breath Easily"</description>
  <mission>lead nationwide and international lung health initiatives, prevent lung disease, help people manage lung disease by promoting lung health. </mission>
  <name>Canadian Lung association</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9323</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">270</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cG/xC/ci/0L/Pu/lz/TdBS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
