<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>PROJECT DESCRIPTION
The Muslim American Society Service Corps&#8217; (MSC) &#8220;Build a Backpack&#8221; Campaign will supply underprivileged children from all backgrounds with the school supplies they need to be ready to learn for the new school year. MAS Boston is helping to give every child an equal opportunity to achieve their dreams. Together we can help families in the Greater Boston Area benefit from this campaign, regardless of faith or ethnicity.

STATEMENT OF PROBLEM
Imagine arriving at school on your first day. All of your fellow classmates are sporting brand new clothing, carrying a fashionable new lunchbox, and have a brand new backpack slung over their shoulder. Imagine that you try to hide your disappointment and embarrassment as you file into your classroom, and silently sit at your desk hoping that nobody will notice that when the teacher says &#8220;pull out your pencil and begin writing&#8221;, you do not even have a pencil!
This heart-breaking scenario is not restricted to third world countries. Every year, it is played out in schools across this nation, affecting needy children from north to south and east to west. Without even addressing the issue of new clothing, the cost of pens, pencils, markers, erasers, paper, binders, crayons, etc., can really add up. According to a 2006 National Retail Federation survey, the average family spent about $527 for back-to-school supplies. For low-income families, this can be prohibitive. This problem is compounded for low-income families in the Greater Boston Area who must sometimes make a decision to buy school supplies or put food on the table!

The 2007 "Build a Backpack" Campaign will end on August 15th.

You can support one child by donating $15

1. Every child deserves an equal chance

2. We've been blessed with an education, let's bring this blessing to others</description>
  <mission>Provide 500 children with backpacks and school supplies</mission>
  <name>Build a Backpack Campaign</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9329</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">72</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">122.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/a6/qi/3C/XK/r0/ZL/nQeS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
