<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>My friends.  We are living in a very complicated and confusing world.  There are rising powers looking to the downfall of our way of life and our ideals, there are extremist groups that hate us simply for who we are, we are faced with important questions about our environment, our policies, and our future.  We are at a time in history that will decide much of what our future will be; and it is in this time that we turn our attention to the selection of a new leader.  

Many of you I'm sure have been awaken to the hypocrisy, greed, and incompetancy that often pervades our national governmental scene no matter which side of the aisle you support.  I'm sure you are troubled by the lack of honest, strong, leadership vying for the White House in the current election.  But we turn our attention to former Senator Fred Thompson.  

Born and raised in the state of Tennessee, Mr. Thompson has been a key advocate for morality, ethical conduct, integrity, and strength that the people of the United States deserve in their government.  He has stood for the conservative ideals of Ronald Reagan, and has the commanding ability that is necessary for this role.  

He is also well known for his acting career, starring in several movies and the NBC show, Law and Order and this career in combination with his strong ideals, has earned him the label of the next Ronald Reagan.  

Senator Thompson is the strong, honest, and hardworking leader we need to solve issues such as our border crisis, a government subject to out of control spending, international challenges, global terrorism, and many other issues that we face or may face in the future. 

That is why we support Fred Thompson for President of the United States in 2008


(These statements are not endorsed by any political candidate)

1. Fred Thompson emulates the values cherished by the majority of Americans 

2. Fred Thompson is honest, hard working, and strong.

3. Fred Thompson is the right man for the job.   </description>
  <mission>Support the candidacy of Fred Thompson for President of the United States</mission>
  <name>Fred Thompson for President</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/933</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">753</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">75.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/FFi/5kZS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
