<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>When mentors and their matches meet on their own, at workplaces, in schools, or at different locations throughout the boroughs, the goal is to match every youth in need with a long-term, caring role model. This special relationship can positively contribute to both of their lives. No matter what the program, the impact of one adult on the life of one youth in need is truly amazing.

BBBS offers three types of mentoring programs: 
Community-Based, Site-Based, and Special Populations. 

I. COMMUNITY &amp; SPECIAL PRIORITY PROGRAMS Youth &amp; volunteers meet anywhere, anytime (it's up to the adult mentor, the little brother or sister, and the parent/guardian). "Bigs" and "Littles" meet at least twice a month (usually on weekends) and spend time together one-to-one on their own, planning and participating in activities of their choice. The time commitment is eight hours per month, for one year. 

Traditional Mentoring Program: Our largest program, serving the general population ages 7-17, in need of an adult mentor.

II. SITE-BASED programs meet regularly at a designated time at a specific location. They generally meet only during the school year and are supervised by an on-site social worker. Matches are one-to-one, with occasional group activities.

III. SPECIAL POPULATIONS include youngsters who may have specific problems. However, they and their volunteers have the same requirements as Community-based programs.

1. "Big Brothers Big Sisters of NYC...the most established of mentoring organizations." - The New York Times</description>
  <mission>Our mission has been to provide adult mentors to children who need caring role models in their lives.</mission>
  <name>Big Brothers Big Sisters of New York City</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9336</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">45</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yv/Za/aW/Lb/4A/qQ/AKUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
