<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>As an American, every single person is hit over the head daily with four main messages:

1. Our world sucks - its falling apart in front of our eyes

2.  It's your fault

3.  You must sacrifice to fix the problem

4.  Everyone agrees.  Debate is over



This group is intended to give hope to those who don't know any better.  Our world does not suck, we are doing just fine.  Our world has natural heating and cooling cycles, of which we know very little.  And honestly, who's to say that we are at the perfect temperature right now?  Therefore, it is not your fault.   Your 'carbon footprint' is so miniscule compared to the scale of the earth If humans were not here, earth would experience the same changes.  But those in congress who view this as a national crisis, bigger than fundamental islam or illegal immigration, say that you must pay in the form of taxes and regulations.  Al Gore's ideas would cost literally dozens of trillions of dollars over his 30-40 year projections.  And even by his unfounded estimates it would affect the environment only .01% of a degree.  Americans would be paying 2-3 trillion dollars per thousanth of a degree in the best case scenario.  Live green if you want; that's totally great.  Just don't force me to.  Lastly, not everyone agrees on the issue.  Saying debate is over doesn't make it over.  The UN group concensus is not really a consensus at all, the scientists who participated never saw the whole report, only sectionalized parts that they had to either disagree or agree with.   Any many thousands more beleive this is total baloney.

1. Global warming is not a crisis, nor created by man.

2. Defend your rights over anyone who wishes to control you

3. Stand and speak the truth when confronted with a lie</description>
  <mission>dispel the governmental propoganda and control regarding global warming</mission>
  <name>Stop the myth of Global Warming</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9338</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/EC/UL/Qq/PM/Ia/l6/iLwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
