<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>International China Concern is a Christian development organisation bringing love, hope and opportunity to China&#8217;s abandoned and disabled. Founded in 1993 by David Gotts, International China Concern exists to help the disadvantaged live life to the full and to their God-given potential.

We believe every child is precious and has the right to be loved, to have hope for the future and the opportunity to realise their dreams.

The Need
Although China is experiencing rapid economic growth there remains a deficit in social welfare for the disadvantaged, especially the disabled. Hundreds of thousands of babies and children continue to be abandoned each year. Training for Chinese nationals working in social welfare is limited and many have little or no understanding of how to care for those with special needs. Support services for families with special needs children are limited and in most areas, do not exist. Many families simply cannot afford to pay for surgery and hospital care upfront forcing them to make heartbreaking choices.

Our Response
For more than thirteen years International China Concern has partnered with the Chinese government to develop social welfare for the abandoned and disabled. Our reputation and relationships in China place us in an excellent position to not only provide services and homes for life but also empower and train Chinese nationals to see lives saved, families supported, communities transformed and attitudes changed.

Our China projects are predominantly managed by Chinese nationals and supported by dedicated international volunteers both in China and abroad. World wide offices in seven countries raise finance and awareness, provide resources, and recruit prayer partners, sponsors and volunteers with a heart to serve in China.


1. Love, hope and opportunity for every disabled child

2. International China Concern is a Christian development organisation bringing love, hope and opportunity to China&#8217;s abandoned and disabled</description>
  <mission>http://www.chinaconcern.org
International China Concern is a Christian development organisation bringing love, hope and opportunity to China&#8217;s abandoned and disabled children

</mission>
  <name>International China Concern</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9339</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Nh/4r/dd/Ra/KX/IU/pXCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
