<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>When we the people join together, we are the law. Together we can replace our war mongering leaders with those who can begin the long process of repair. If it can't be done then we must sieze our own country in order to not be guilty by association. We must prove to the world that we the people do not agree with the actions taken by our government. We have the technology and man power to not need a war caused by our own thirst for oil. The fact that our world leaders are aware of this fact means that all the other peoples of the world see us as no better then any other empire that has risen and fallen. As our leaders atempt to repair the foundations of our economy they all fail to realize that we are only delaying the inevitable. That we are in fact sealing our fate, when our resources have been exausted, and we no longer have the luxury of oil, we will be cast into a depression of the likes the world has never known. It is a sad day to be a North American, as the morals and beliefs that carried us through the first world wars have been wiped away by the blood of the middle eastern people, as well as our own. Everything we stand for is now nothing more then a joke to the rest of the world. When we are saposed to be the ones who set the bar for so many other countries, you can't help but ask yourself "How much longer do we get to enjoy peace? Before the rest of the world comes knocking on our door for the wrongs we have committed?" . We have all done wrong, as we simply idly sat back and watched. They say it was for freedom, and that it's to protect our freedom. We have however given up our freedom, and that fact will be realized very soon. As our actions have given reason to many people to in fact wish terror apon us.

We will pay for gerations for what the greatest criminals of our time have done.

1. We must create a new goverment.

2. We must create new economic foundations.

3. We must create an army to protect ourselves.

4. Our army must be under the direct control of our the people.

5. We must never forget.</description>
  <mission>Prevent our names from being further soiled by those currently in power.</mission>
  <name>FUCK BUSH</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9349</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">469</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/FF/3h/uk/fl/6H/ns/eMTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
