<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Meningitis is the infection of the membranes that surround and protect the brain and spinal cord.  The most serious form, bacterial meningitis, is caused by a bacterial infection known as meningococcal disease. The disease is a rare but potentially fatal illness that can strike at any time. It is the most common cause of bacterial meningitis in the United States among toddlers, adolescents, and young adults. Each year, about 3,000 Americans become infected with the bacteria, and, tragically, as many as 1 in 10 of those people die from it.

As deadly as meningococcal disease can be, most cases in the United States could potentially be prevented by a single vaccination.

It is essential that we be aware of this illness and spread our knowledge on to others. We can help put an end to the tragic, unexpected occurrences caused by meningococcal meningitis.

For information on symptoms, treatment, prevention, and specific behaviors that can put people at a greater risk for developing meningitis, please visit http://www.fightmeningitis.com.

Additional Resources:

http://www.nmaus.org/
http://www.meningitisfoundationofamerica.org/templates/
http://www.meningitis.org/
http://www.voicesofmeningitis.org/
http://www.nfid.org/meningitis/


**This cause was created in memory of Sara Michelle Khirkhah, whose life was taken by meningococcal meningitis on March 21st, 2007. She was the most energetic person one could ever imagine--always healthy and full of life. Please join in honor of her and others whose lives have been lost to this disease.**

1. Meningococcal meningitis can be prevented and treated--nobody should die from this disease.

2. The key to eliminating death and disabilities caused by meningococcal meningitis is by spreading awareness.</description>
  <mission>To educate others on the severity of this disease and the vital importance of preventing it.</mission>
  <name>Meningococcal Meningitis Awareness and Prevention</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9366</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">41551</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">861.19</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/QE/zc/ov/M0/yj/DW/rd/mUS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
