<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Whether it is global warming, rainforest annihilation, the spilling of hundreds of thousands of gallons of oil into the ocean, or the handful of other man-made catastrophes, the earth seriously needs our help! It is extremely saddening to know that an estimated 17,000 species become EXTINCT every year due to humans&#8217; impact on the environment... If you have ever relaxed at your cabin while watching the sun set over the lake, gone hiking in the forests to breathe in the fresh air and get away from the hassles of everyday life, or maybe even remember fondly the times when you were little and chased bugs and other creatures around the yard, then you also realize how critical it is that something be done to ensure future generations have the privilege of creating the same memories.

If you have thought about doing something to help but didn&#8217;t, or couldn&#8217;t, donate the $50 that some organizations require you to, &#8220;Save The Earth One Dollar At A Time" is your answer. This cause offers you the chance to make a difference in the world with almost no effort whatsoever. Whatever the amount you decide to give to donate will be sent to The World Wildlife Fund where each dollar will have a huge impact. It really takes all of five minutes to make a priceless donation! 

Do it for Steve Irwin who passed away doing what he loved more than anything, your dad who loves to go fishing on his days off, or even the kid down the street who constantly brings in snakes to show his mom. Spread the word and ask your friends and family to match your gifts. Each dollar given makes a direct impact on the world YOU live in...


1. Did you know?... DISPOSABLE CHOPSTICKS are the #1 destroyer of rainforests!</description>
  <mission>improve the earth we ALL live on</mission>
  <name>Save The Earth One Dollar At A Time!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9367</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qG/5f/uN/2m/HP/or/toRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
