<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Today's left leaning world has conservatism on the ropes. Articles in national publications are proudly announcing the death of American conservatism. Conservatives have been silent for far too long. He are in hiding, not dead. "Conserving Conservatism" is a cause that seeks to unite the loose pockets of conservatism across the states, and to present this united front to the liberals seeking the White House in 2008. We can be a powerful force in the upcoming elections if we simply abide by the courage of our convictions, and speak out against the rising tide of liberalism. 

Our aims are to promote American conservatism, and to seek the advancement of that ideology in the upcoming 2008 congressional and presidential elections. Our ideology is simple: it includes slowing things down just a bit. Contrary to faulty public opinion, we are not devoted to stunting the growth of progress or "afraid" of change; we are, however, dedicated to preserving the time honored and valued institutions of our past, while cautiously correcting those that may require it. In sum we feel that radical change in our institutions uproots our foundation ad fosters political and social instability, causes upheavals in the traditional family structure, and corrupts society in general. 

These are our beliefs, and we stand at a great crossroads. In 2008 the fate of the nation depends on our willingness to fight here and now. This is the crisis that we face. And in the words of the ever quotable Ronald Reagan, "The crisis we are facing today [requires us to make] our best effort, and our willingness to believe in ourselves and to believe in our capacity to perform great deeds; to believe that together, with God's help, we can and will resolve the problems which now confront us. And, after all, why shouldn't we believe that? We are Americans. God bless you, and thank you."

Join our general Command Center Group, Conserving Conservatism:
http://txstate.facebook.com/group.php?gid=4117476817

1. Supporting candidates to promote conservative causes

2. Promoting small government

3. Promoting states' rights

4. Promoting social conservatism

5. Promoting religous conservatism

6. Promoting bioconservatism

7. Promoting a free market economy

8. Building a strong military

9. Resorting back to fiscal conservatism</description>
  <mission>To promote the basic ideology of American conservatism. </mission>
  <name>Conserving Conservatism</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9393</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">4294</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.75</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/5Z/iz/SY/24/Dx/XE/U0US.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
