<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is CP?

Cerebral palsy--also known as CP--is a condition caused by injury to the parts of the brain that control our ability to use our muscles and bodies. Cerebral means having to do with the brain. Palsy means weakness or problems with using the muscles. Often the injury happens before birth, sometimes during delivery, or, like Joe, soon after being born. CP can be mild, moderate, or severe. Mild CP may mean a child is clumsy. Moderate CP may mean the child walks with a limp. He or she may need a special leg brace or a cane. More severe CP can affect all parts of a child's physical abilities. A child with moderate or severe CP may have to use a wheelchair, as did Joe, and other special equipment. Sometimes children with CP can also have learning problems, problems with hearing or seeing (called sensory problems), or mental retardation. Usually, the greater the injury to the brain, the more severe the CP. However, CP doesn't get worse over time, and most children with CP have a normal life span.
One of the Canadian Associations I recommend donating funds to, is:

The Canadian Electric Wheelchair Hockey Association
Ontario Southwest Division,
P.O Box 9047
1795 Ernest Ave
London, Ontario
N6E 2V5
Also Great Beneficiaries for donations:

Easter Seals Society
London Office
974 Dearness Drive
London, ON 
N6E 2R8

Participation House Support Services
586 Creston Avenue, 
London, ON 
N6C 3A6, (who do placements for adults with CP, with full medical staff at hand).

Joe was a part of the wheelchair hockey association as a member / player, and greatly enjoyed it!  They created "The Joe Franze Award", that is awarded each year, following his death!

The Easter Seal Society was great with helping fund things, or helped fund for things Joe needed.  You could also donate to your local Easter Seal Office.

For all in this cause,, I will donate $2.00 for each member who joins!!  These Donations will be applied once a month!!~~~Liz Franze.

1. Making sure there is enough support for families who have a member with CP

2. Enough support, gov't or otherwise, for children or ADULTS, with CP

3. Resourses for frustrated, Family members or Friends who think they're not doing enough!</description>
  <mission>Raise Awareness, Support, and donations, (to the Canadian Beneficiaries listed as well),  in any way!</mission>
  <name>Cerebral Palsy Awareness - In Memory Of My Brother Joseph Franze</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9395</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">432</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4P/VC/Ct/fQ/Qz/hw/ZL/jyS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
