<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Dear Family and Friends&#1513;&#1500;&#1493;&#1501;!  
I will be traveling to Israel in October to participate in &#8220;The Wheels of Love&#8221;, a 150 mile bike ride from Tiberius to Jerusalem. Alyn Hospital is Israel&#8217;s only comprehensive pediatric and adolescent rehabilitation centre and one of the world&#8217;s leading specialists in active and intensive rehabilitation for children.  Children with congenital and/or acquired conditions, victims of car, domestic accidents and terror attacks, head trauma, elective surgery and cancer, are treated at the hospital.
   As you probably know, the Israeli economy and the Israeli health care system in particular, are in crisis.  This is a result of the government&#8217;s preoccupation with the security situation and need to shift funding away from other areas.  Every year Alyn needs to raise millions of dollars just to close the gap between the actual cost of care and the amount reimbursed by referring sources.
   What can one person do to help Israel?  I am going to ride for those that cannot.  I will cover the costs of flying and cycling in Israel myself and am very gladly volunteering my time, money and body for this cause.  My personal goal is to raise $5000.  All you have to do is make a contribution.  You can make a donation directly to Alyn Hospital and help Israel in a meaningful and very personal way, by sponsoring me.
   All donations are tax-deductible and can be made over the Internet via http://www.alynride.org/alyn/onlineDonations.php. I will be notified of all on-line donations. 
  I would like to thank you in advance for your participation in this worthy cause.  Feel free to pass this letter on to anyone who might share your enthusiasm.
   Love,
Dina Lustiger, Rachael Shulman, and Emma Rand


1. The children of Alyn deserve to have the best medical care possible.</description>
  <mission>help the children of ALYN hospital by participating in a bike tour for their benefit.</mission>
  <name>ALYN- Wheels of Love</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9398</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">53</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Wj/1r/er/i1/gm/ct/dh8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
