<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Garbage Patch is a BIG waste land of plastic.  The problem is that the garbage patch is in the Pacific Ocean and it is the size of North America.  This garbage patch consisting mostly of plastic is killing Marine Life and heating up the oceans.  Since some of the plastic is microscopic, it is difficult to clean up.  One if the biggest problems is that since it is in no man's land neither the US or Asia is willing to clean this big wasteland because it would be some multi-billion dollars they would not have to spend.
Joining this cause and raising awareness is the first step to clean up this mess.  Also next time you are on the beach make sure you don't litter because it most likely will end up harming sea life and end up in the Pacific Gyre Garbage Patch.


One thing that is being studied now is the effect that the microscopic pieces of plastic have on humans.  These plastics act like magnets in the ocean collecting toxins including PBCs, pesticides, and other harmful chemicals.  These then get bio-accumulated (accumulates in the animal) in the fats of the animals that eat them.  These chemicals then get bio magnified (increased in toxicity) when the fish or plankton that are eating the plankton get eaten.  This is cause for concern because we are the top of the food chain and if we are eating fish who have fed on plankton, then how toxic is the food you're eating.  This raises the question; What's in your seafood? 

1. The Pacific Ocean must be rid of this garbage patch to help marine life. 

2. Refuse (the use of plastic bags), Reuse, and Recycle.

3. We should not only Stop the Garbage Patch, we should get rid of it.</description>
  <mission>Prevent the Pacific Gyre to get any worse</mission>
  <name>Stop the Pacific Gyre Garbage Patch</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9420</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1021</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">166.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tm/Nz/6l/ZO/pO/Wb/hf/XKS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
