<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>KFC suppliers cram birds into huge waste-filled factories, breed and drug them to grow so large that they can&#8217;t even walk, and often break their wings and legs. At slaughter, the birds&#8217; throats are slit and they are dropped into tanks of scalding-hot water&#8212;often while they are still conscious. It would be illegal for KFC to abuse dogs, cats, pigs, or cows in these ways.

KFC&#8217;s own animal welfare advisors have asked the company to take steps to eliminate these abuses, but KFC refuses to do so. Many advisors have now resigned in frustration.

Please join Pamela Anderson, Sir Paul McCartney, His Holiness the Dalai Lama, The Rev. Al Sharpton, and countless other kind people worldwide by not eating at KFC.

Sign the Petition to Stop Kentucky Fried Cruelty:
http://kentuckyfriedcruelty.com/g-pinkpetition.asp

Kentucky Fried Cruelty
http://kentuckyfriedcruelty.com/

PETA
http://www.peta.org/

Go VEG
http://www.goveg.com/

Caring Consumer
http://www.caringconsumer.com/


1. Adopt the &#8220;Animal Care Standards&#8221; program. This would lower the amount of ammonia in the air in factory farms, improve the living spaces and lighting in chicken sheds, prohibit the intentional starving of breeding birds...

2. Breed for health rather than rapid growth, and stop feeding drugs to chickens. This would reduce the rate at which birds suffer painful, crippling diseases and injuries, such as broken legs, heart attacks, and lung failures.

3. Make all welfare standards transparent and verifiable. This would simply ensure that the animal welfare program is being adhered to through announced and unannounced independent audits.

4. Boycott KFC.</description>
  <mission>Reduce the suffering and abuse of animals on factory farms and keep up the pressure against KFC.</mission>
  <name>Kentucky Fried Cruelty</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9434</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">37</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/h2/Es/ix/of/fi/yF/02iS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
