<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This is a very sensitive cause in which I was highly
inspired by almost 25 years ago. There were three best-friends by the names of Debra, Brenda and Linda that sat at a kitchen table one night and decided to make the dream of getting Africville back, if even for a few days, come true! These special ladies then took over from where there families had first laid the grounds of the first Africville Genealogy Society.They planned how and where everything was going to take place.

They carried on what we now know to be the Africville picnics and reunions.

 It was a pleasure for me to be given the chance to know the History of my ancestors, to know exactly what their struggles were and the racial way that the City dealt with them. Well they may have stole, moved and relocated the people away from their homes but they still couldn't take the spirit out of Africville.

These three ladies inspired me and hopefully we will be able to do the same with our generation, to live on the Africville spirit, to do what we can to make this evolve to the next level, all in LOVE for the people of AFRICVILLE. 

Africville will always remain a scar on the city!!

This site is dedicated the three founders: the late Debra Dixon-Jones and the two remaining founders Brenda Steed-Ross and Linda Mantley. May GOD BLESS them. PEACE.
                   


1. The city has to stop stealing away innocent peoples lands 

2. Give back the land that the City slyly moved people out of to make a Doghouse

3. Stop the hidden racial way that the City has about it's dealings when it comes to our PEOPLE!!

4. Staying strong as a community!! </description>
  <mission>Gain the rights back to OUR property that has been stolen away from the People of  Africville</mission>
  <name>Give Africville back</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9448</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">913</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7F/W3/nr/zZ/zZ/0E/6A/h2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
