<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>        Revamping EDucate Pakistan

What was the aim of EDucate Pakistan (EDP)?

What has EDP achieved since it came into being?

What liaisons has EDP achieved till now?

Where is EDP going?

These were a few questions that I asked myself and I came to conclusion that the only way for moving forward was to address them one by one:

What was the aim of EDucate Pakistan (EDP)?
EDucate Pakistan, aimed to focus on the educational policies being implemented by the government. To set up a watchdog that would closely monitor them and come up with the plausible solutions that would make education affordable and accessible for every Pakistani. 

What has EDP achieved since it came into being?
EDP came into being as a Cause on Facebook (an online networking website) in July 2007. Since then it has over 1700 (and rising) supporters. While many would argue that, many on the Cause are just what they are, supporters of the cause, it is indeed true that EDP became stagnant over the next two years. What has been the downfall was that I wasn&#8217;t able to induct more people in the EDP team and it was too big a task to achieve alone. 
What liaisons has EDP achieved till now?
EDP made its first contact with an international NGO, Marshall Direct Fund (MDF) via Facebook, when Mr. Nick Kelly posted the MDF fan page on the Cause page. It was then that correct note was hit and EDP got to interact with MDF and its team. Ever since then, EDP is trying to promote MDF&#8217;s operation in Pakistan.

Where is EDP going?
EDP is still a youth-run organization. It still aspires to construct a watchdog for implementing proper educational policies in Pakistan. It still believes that contrary to the dual standards of education prevailing, it requires a proper system of education that caters for all education. EDP believes that the current Pakistani youth will pave the way for FREE Education in Pakistan. InshAllah. Become a part of EDP and its efforts.


1. Education improves national economy</description>
  <mission>Free and unbiased education for all Pakistanis</mission>
  <name>Support for revamping the Education System in Pakistan (an EDucate Pakistan effort)</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9454</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2023</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/IC/Wr/dx/ls/LD/aw/KM/zjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
