<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Foundation For Tomorrow (TFFT) uses education as a tool to fight poverty in developing nations throughout Sub-Saharan Africa. We strive to make the largest impact through educational scholarships, teachers training, library and computer center constructions. TFFT supports orphans who would not be able to receive a primary, secondary or tertiary education. TFFT seeks to create environments in which peace, health and human welfare prosper as a result of a well educated population.

There are 800 million people in the developing world who can&#8217;t read. We need to think of these children as our children. They are the world's responsibility. As Bill Gates said at the World Health Assembly in 2005, "In our world today, some lives are seen as worth saving and some aren&#8217;t." We can&#8217;t allow this. He went on to say he looks forward to when, "people will finally accept that the death of a child in a developing world is as tragic as the death of a child in the developed world." This belief in the equal value of human life is at the core of why TFFT committed to shining a light on the situation in Africa.

According to UNICEF, 10 million children each year; 30,000 each day, die from avoidable, poverty related causes. Through education, we can mitigate this tragedy. Education isn&#8217;t a hand out, it&#8217;s a hand up. For the cost of a new pair of shoes we can contribute to an education program in the developing world that can save/improve the life of a child. 

The Foundation For Tomorrow, more than just a project, it is a movement to empower Africa's children through education. Won&#8217;t you help?


www.thefoundationfortomorrow.org

Check out our blog:
www.thefoundationfortomorrow.blogspot.com

1. Universal Primary Education

2. Orphan's Rights

3. Fighting Poverty through Education</description>
  <mission>Empowering the future of developing nations</mission>
  <name>The Foundation For Tomorrow</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9463</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">899</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">435.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rp/AH/7q/xw/1o/Br/vROS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
