<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Criminal Code provisions on animal cruelty have changed little since 1892 and are serously inadequate.  Parliament has been debating reforms to the laws since 1999.  Currently, Senate Bill S-213 has been introduced raising penalties for animal cruelty but in all other respects, fails to modernize the laws.  

You can help!  

Write to your MP and tell them that you fervently oppose S-213 and you support legislation like C-373 

Find out who your MP is by using your postal code at: 
http://www.elections.ca/home.asp?textonly=false 

For a quick overview on why Bill S-213 is inadequate: &lt;a href="http://cfhs.ca/files/amendments_at_a_glance_corrected.pdf"&gt;amendments at a glance&lt;/a&gt; 

The differences are explained here: &lt;a href="http://cfhs.ca/law/differences_between_current_law_bill_s_213_and_effective_legislation"&gt;differences&lt;/a&gt;

We need more Parliamentarians to know that this IS an issue that Canadians care about and will factor into their vote! 

Should you like to help us to push this issue in Parliament, write to your MP and to the Justice Minister, the Hon. Rob Nicholson, and voice your opposition to S-213

Cut and paste this sample letter:
&lt;a href ="http://cfhs.ca/law/what_can_you_do"&gt;what you can do&lt;/a&gt;
Mail it to:
The Honourable Rob Nicholson
Minister of Justice
House of Commons
Ottawa, ON K1A 0A6

Download the petition http://cfhs.ca/files/petition_ottawa.pdf  and return signed petition forms to:

Mark Holland
Member of Parliament, Ajax-Pickering
House of Commons
Ottawa, ON K1A 0A6

**this address does not need a stamp**
Also, any mail addressed to a legislative address in Ottawa - such as the House of Commons -- does not require postage. Free!  It makes it that much easier to help :-)

*****NOTE:  DO NOT DONATE TO THIS CAUSE. IN ORDER TO CREATE IT, I HAD TO PUT A BENEFICIARY. NO CANADIAN HUMANE SOCIETIES EXIST ON FACEBOOK.   THIS IS ALL THAT NEEDS TO BE DONE. NO MONEY IS TO BE DONATED AT ALL!!!  ******

1. The animal cruelty laws are seriously outdated and must be changed immediately to include unowned animals and strays and impose harsher penalties

2. FOLLOW THE LINK TO DOWNLOAD THE PETITION AND HAVE IT SIGNED. Return signed petitions to Mark Holland. His address is listed above. It's free--no postage required.

3. DO NOT DONATE MONEY TO THIS CAUSE. WRITE YOUR LOCAL MP AND TELL HIM/HER THAT THE ANIMAL CRUELTY LAWS MUST BE UPDATED. Use the cut-and-paste letter or create your own!!

4. DO NOT SUPPORT BILL S-213. WRITE TO YOUR MP AND THE JUSTICE MINISTER AND LET THEM KNOW HOW YOU FEEL!! IT IS INADEQUATE IN COVERAGE AND PROTECTION FOR ALL ANIMALS</description>
  <mission>Have Bill S-213 defeated in parliament so that appropriate legislation can be enacted to properly protect animals.</mission>
  <name>HELP CHANGE THE ANIMAL CRUELTY LAW: Support Bill C-373 and help stop Bill S-213</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9466</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">98</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Cg/Jw/dh/RU/y8/wp/2kRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
