<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>JCADA provides a safety net for Washington area-Jewish women and men caught in an abusive or violent relationship.  Founded in 1999 in response to a pressing need in the Jewish community, JCADA is a non-profit group allied with a host of organizations whose shared mission is to assist victims of domestic abuse to become empowered and obtain safe environments as well as to educate the Jewish community about domestic abuse and appropriate responses to it.  

JCADA is fighting this problem with a three-pronged program of prevention, education and support, 

Prevention:
&#8226;	Teach teens to recognize signs of abuse and to avoid dating violence/sexual assault
&#8226;	Help students understand bullying and harassing behavior and develop appropriate 
responses 
&#8226;	Train parents to recognize signs of unhealthy relationships and how to intervene
&#8226;	Sponsor domestic abuse training programs for rabbis, educators and clinicians
&#8226;	Advocate for the rights of abuse victims in the political arena  

Education:
&#8226;	Sponsor a speaker&#8217;s bureau to increase awareness of domestic abuse 
&#8226;	Disseminated educational information to organizations in our community
&#8226;	Provide outreach programming focusing on education and involvement
    
Support:
&#8226;	Maintain a hotline staffed by Jewish women who understand the needs of
Jewish women
&#8226;	Link referrals to community services throughout the area
&#8226;	Provide assistance with planning for personal safety
&#8226;	Offer financial support for counseling in cooperation with the Jewish Social Services Agency (based on need)
&#8226;	Offer limited financial assistance to victims and families (based on need)
&#8226;	Sponsor a community support group for women to help them become empowered

   HOTLINE &#8211; 1-800-883-2323

  			        Local number 301-230-7284					

1. Many people do not realize how serious domestic abuse is in the Jewish community and it needs to be addressed</description>
  <mission>provide a safety net for Washington area-Jewish women and men caught in an abusive or violent relationship.</mission>
  <name>Jewish Coalition Against Domestic Abuse</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9472</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Jr/0M/Zf/fJ/M0/E8/xRcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
