<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Calling for help should never be a crime.  However, in most places, people are subject to arrest and punishment if they call for medical assistance during an emergency involving illegal drugs or underage drinking.

One state and more than 60 colleges have taken a stand by enacting life-saving Good Samaritan Policies (GSP), which shield people from punishment during an emergency and thus remove any hesitation to call for help.  While campus policies only shield students from punishment within the school system, the state of New Mexico passed a law in 2006 shielding citizens from arrest if they do the right thing by calling for help.

The mission of this cause is to save lives by enacting as many Good Samaritan Policies as possible, both at the campus and state level.  Please help the cause indirectly by inviting your friends, or help directly by donating (below) or contacting SSDP's field director, Micah Daigle (micah@ssdp.org), to find out how to start a Good Samaritan campaign.

More info about the campaign can be found at http://www.ssdp.org/campaigns/ccc/goodsamaritan/

A newsletter article about Students for Sensible Drug Policy's efforts to enact GSPs can be found at http://www.ssdp.org/newsletter/200707/article4.shtml

1. Calling for help should never be a crime.

2. Good Samaritan Policies (GSP) save lives. In fact, a study of the GSP at Cornell University showed that calls for medical assistance increased dramatically after the policy was enacted.

3. Helping people with drug abuse problems is more important than punishing them.</description>
  <mission>To prevent overdose deaths (from alcohol &amp; other drugs) by removing punishment/arrest when friends call for help.</mission>
  <name>Good Samaritan Policies - Save a Life!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9473</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1085</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">268.68</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/n6/2y/vK/hi/Ni/U4/UGuS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
