<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Millions of trees are cut down every minute just to make paper for all reasons. Most of these papers are used to make assignments and examination scripts. If they were only used for books i would say that it's fine, but using extra paper to make examinations is just harsh. Students and others can get every knowledge they need from the internet, and also some of them can be found in books, but having exams means that people have to go through a tough time learning everything from the books and then writing them again on paper. Exams can sometimes lead to the death of some people. This is because the failing of examinations can cause students to suffer severe depression and breakdowns, which often lead to suicide. So I say this to all my fellow students, join me in my cause to STOP EXAMS and SAVE TREES, as this can also be beneficial to nature and provide assistance to prevent global warming.


~~~

After much thinking i've decided, why not every member donate at least one dollar to this cause? Ask your parents too, i mean, by the way the member count has been progressing, i'm sure we can have a whole lot of money that way. We can also start our own thing, go global, and maybe, just maybe, actually save a few rainforests! :)

~~~

Thank you all for joining! :]

1. Trees are vital for the survival of life.

2. This is not a true cause.

3. This cause is just a thought that i made up because i don't like exams.

4. After much thinking, i've decided that we can all make this cause truly beneficial by donating at least one dollar each.

5. If you don't have that kinda money, you could also ask your parents too, after all i'm a kid too. I'll ask mine.</description>
  <mission>Save the trees and ease the lives of our fellow students.</mission>
  <name>Stop Exams, Save Trees!!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9499</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">38272</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/f0/36/pw/1r/GG/3Z/Bx/e8S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
