<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Each year, an estimated 2.1 million older Americans are victims of elder abuse and neglect by someone they depend on for care or protection.
Only 1 in 14 cases of elder mistreatment are unreported.

Currently, 75% of the net assets in this country are owned by people 50 years and older. As a result, the potential for elder financial abuse is extremely high.

[Main Types of Abuse]
Neglect (55%)
Physical (14.6%)
Financial/Material Exploitation (12.3%)
Emotional or Psychological (7.7%)
Sexual Abuse (0.3%)
and Self-Neglect, Abandonment...
(Sources: National Center on Elder Abuse. 1996)

Again, only 1 in 14 cases are reported...and sadly, the most elder abuse and neglect takes place at home. Family members, other household members or paid caregivers tend to be the most frequent abusers.

[What can you do!?]
# Visit your grandparents (parents) and talk to them often!!
- Elder who are most at risk of abuse are isolated and frail

# Educate yourself for community resources!
- Neighbor Senior Groups/Centers, APS (Adult Protective Services), local Ombudsman Program, etc...

# Join Neighbor-watch program!

# Learn about signs/potential indicators of Elder Abuse!

# Donate!

WISE Elder Abuse Prevention Program provides educational programs for seniors to learn how to prevent from being abuse victims. 
For details, visit www.wiseseniors.org.

WISE Senior Services established the Financial Abuse Specialist Team (FAST) in 1993 to combat the rising tide of elder financial abuse. FAST Consultants share their expertise and advice "Fiduciary Abuse Specialists" who are employees from Adult Protective Services, the Long-Term Care Ombudsman program, Office of the Public Guardian and care managers from local social service agencies.

"Worry about the stories your grandparents don't tell you!"



1. Vulnerable seniors should be protected. Providing seniors with the knowledge and skills they can use to protect themselves from becoming a victim of these crimes and to maintain their quality of life is essential.

2. Physical abuse, sexual abuse, emotional or psychological abuse, neglect, abandonment, financial or material exploitation or/and self-neglect should be prevented.</description>
  <mission>To prevent the victimization of older adults and to protect vulnerable seniors from becoming victims of financial, physical or emotional abuse.</mission>
  <name>Stop Elder Abuse!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9501</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">682</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/aM/Oe/fJ/GC/0w/wz/OgqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
