<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Pedophilia is running rampant all over the world. Children are being sexually exploited by a pedophile at the rate of 1 out of 6 boys before the age of 16 and 1 out of 3 girls before the age of 18 (1 out of 4 before the age of 14). These statistics are based on reported cases of sexual abuse (UN Report).
We, as citizens concerned for the safety of children everywhere, must do something to stop this horrific crime NOW! Don't allow another innocent child to become the victim of these predators. They are stalking, seducing and convincing our children that what they do is right. They say they do it in the name of "Love". (These law breakers claim to be sexually stimulated by children ranging in ages from birth to 18 years.) 

A pedophile doesn't have a certain "look" that distinguishes them as such. They could be married with children of their own. They could be the next door neighbor, the baby-sitter or a relative. Pedophiles tend to choose occupations that put them in close contact with children such as teaching, counseling, daycare, scouting, coaching, etc. (I'm certainly not saying that all people in these professions are pedophiles because the overwhelming majority are not.) What I am saying is be aware of whom your children are spending their time with. Don't be afraid to ask questions. Trust your instincts. Listen to your child and really hear what he/she is saying. Be concerned if your child shows fear or mistrust of an adult. Children are basically honest and open about their feelings so trust their instincts, too. 
Wouldn't you rather be safe than sorry? 



1. Educate and raise awareness concerning this alarming subject

2. Don't live in denial...this is happening everywhere

3. The Middle east has a booming rate of pedophiles because they have the liberty to act out their "desires" unpunished</description>
  <mission>Break the Taboo and teach on how to stop such dispicable acts of sodomy towards our innocent children</mission>
  <name>HELP STOP PEDOPHILIA IN THE MIDDLE EAST</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9504</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">160</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Us/xc/lB/0e/tx/hk/vUES.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
