<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Foundation for a Smokefree America was founded in 1989 by Patrick Reynolds, a grandson of the founder of the R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company. A former pack-a-day smoker, Patrick saw his father, oldest brother and other relatives die from cigarette-induced emphysema, heart disease and cancer.

Concerned about the widespread death, disease, and emotional and economic hardship caused by tobacco, Patrick Reynolds divested his RJR stock, quit smoking and became, in the words of former Surgeon General C. Everett Koop, "one of the nation's most influential advocates of a smokefree America."

Since first speaking out publicly in 1986, Mr. Reynolds has testified before Congress, as well as State and municipal legislatures, on a wide range of tobacco issues. His actions have earned him the praise and admiration of his colleagues, including the World Health Organization, which honored him in 1988, and the Mount Sinai Hospital Group of Chicago, which named him "Humanitarian of the Year" in 1989.

In April, 2009, Mr. Reynolds was invited by the Health Ministry of Greece to help build public awareness about the dangers of second hand smoke, and to rally public support for Greece's new smoking ban, to take effect July 1, 2009. Alexis Zorbas of the Miinistry of Health in Athens commented, 

"At our conference launching the national campaign for our law prohibiting smoking in public places, Mr. Reynolds gave a well-informed, polished and persuasive speech, and assisted us in promoting the Greek State&#8217;s agenda on tobacco, through strong and very positive national media coverage of his visit. Moreover, his talk to youth at one of our local schools was a tremendous success. 

"Mr. Reynolds has been a most valuable addition towards our public health efforts in Greece, and has made a noticeable difference to our national efforts against smoking." 

The Foundation is now seeking sponsors for more international speaking tours for our founder, Patrick Reynolds, in nations where smoking rates are high, such as Asia, Europe and the Middle East. 

Patrick Reynolds' name, his story and his dedication to improving the health of present and future generations make him a unique and powerful spokesman against smoking, and an effective ambassador for the international smokefree cause. 


Video of recent TV news appearances: www.Anti-smoking.org/tv/


Links to recent print news coverage: 

www.Anti-smoking.org/news/ 


Video clips from the educational video of Patrick Reynolds' live talk to youth: 

www.tobaccofree.org/clips/truth.htm 


Keywords: 
anti-smoking, anti-tobacco, anti smoking, anti tobacco, antismoking, anti-cancer, anti cancer, anticancer, antitobacco, smoking, tobacco, second hand smoke, no smoking, teen smoking, anti smoking charity, org, group, campaign, anti tobacco charity, dip tobacco, chewing tobacco, chew, dip, addiction, drug, prevention, drug prevention, tobacco prevention, youth smoking, youth, teen, teen smoking 



1. To prevent teen smoking through our websites and educatioal videos

2. To help empower smokers to quit successfully, through our website's referrals to the best available resources

3. To find sponsors for press tours for our founder, Patrick Reynolds in poor nations where smoking rates are high, in Asia, Europe and the Middle East

4. To empower youth to defend themselves against the onslaught of tobacco advertising and peer pressure

5. To establish in-house anti-smoking anti-tobacco programs to fight tobacco use at the local, regional and national levels</description>
  <mission>Our websites motivate youth to stay tobaccofree, empowers smokers to quit successfully, and educate globally about the problem of tobacco use</mission>
  <name>Foundation for a Smokefree America - Anti-tobacco, anti-smoking, anti-drug &amp; quit smoking info</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/952</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1526</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1224.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4I/d2/e1/dE/iP/4j/k2/TgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
