<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>... Imagine getting a lot more from a multi-million dollar, international company with a long track record of success&#8230;and growing!

Welcome to ACN &#8211; the worlds largest direct seller of telecommunications services!

ACN is your opportunity to change the future for you, your family and everyone important to you; to create a new and dynamic life&#8230;and a life without boundaries.   In fact, the ACN Opportunity has helped  hundreds of thousands of people just like you control their destiny and build successful ACN businesses. 

               THERE'S MORE....

Enroll today or view our business presentation to learn more.

Success as an ACN Representative is not guaranteed, but rather influenced by an individual's specific efforts. Not all ACN Independent Representatives make a profit and no one can be guaranteed success as an ACN Independent Representative. 

This is not a "get rich quick" skeem that will make you wealthy overnight, even though we all wish that could happen ....unless you win the JACK POT.

LET'S GET BACK TO REALITY HERE!

The point is for Congolese  &amp; other ethnics to understand My Vision here. I'm not asking anyone to give money to the cause directly TO ME OR ANY THIRD PARTY FOUNDATION because I want everyone to understant &amp; feel the URGENCY of this matter. You have the power to do what you always wanted to do... Something right for yourself, family &amp; friends abroad.
Partake in This Movement &amp; YOU will feel that sense of GREATNESS in you on behalf of your fellow-Congolese back home. Make that difference you longued for so long.








1. Global Telecomunication is a Universal Right.</description>
  <mission>Embrace The Uprising Opportunity Of Digital Technology. ACN:   It&#8217;s Life&#8230;Without Boundaries . 
Visite ACN website at www.acncanada.ca</mission>
  <name>DR CONGO &amp; Global TELECOMUNICATIONS</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9525</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Kg/es/MW/TC/AQ/wG/ISVS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
