<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Ni&#241;os de la Luz, or Children of the Light, is located in a reserved section of La Ceiba, Honduras. It was founded by Bill Kwiatkowski in 1994 and currently houses 22 boys who would be otherwise homeless. There are aggressive plans to build a new residence hall to house an additional 40 boys.

Children of the Light (COTL) will provide the Honduran children with an alternative to life off the streets, showing by way of words and deeds the love, mercy and compassion of God. The many boys have all be rescued from various forms of abuse and homelessness. The COTL see drug addiction as a significant problem in Honduras and one of it's goals is to help the children of Honduras resist the temptation of drugs and care for the already addicted. One method COTL will use to reach this goal is to provide a clean and safe haven for the children to go as an alternative to living on the streets. By providing shelter, food and spiritual guidance , we hope to provide a family atmosphere where children can live and receive an education through the attention and love of caring workers. Our goal is to help the needy children become productive citizens. COTL's goal is to work with the whole person, body, mind and soul.

You can help by just adding this Cause and inviting your friends. You can also use the link below to donate via Credit Card or you can call 011-504-3304-1414. You can also visit the website below and view photos of the Children and the Project directly. Thank you!

1. Just one homeless child is too many.</description>
  <mission>To provide love and hope to the homeless street children of Honduras.</mission>
  <name>Children of the Light</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9532</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1503</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1494.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Qf/Cd/rT/1e/zv/Sy/Mf/J4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
