<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>WHAT IS PARKINSONS DISEASE?

Parkinson's disease (PD) belongs to a group of conditions called motor system disorders. The four primary symptoms of PD are trembling in hands, arms, legs, jaw, and face; rigidity, or stiffness of the limbs and trunk; slowness of movement; and postural instability, or impaired balance and coordination. As these symptoms become more pronounced, patients may have difficulty walking, talking, or completing other simple tasks. The symptoms of PD are subtle and occur gradually.  As the disease progresses, the shaking, or tremor, which affects the majority of PD patients may begin to interfere with daily activities.  Other symptoms may include depression and other emotional changes; difficulty in swallowing, chewing, and speaking; urinary problems or constipation; skin problems; and sleep disruptions.  

Highly debated, stem cell research, will bring about the cure for not only Parkinsons but many other illnesses such as Diabetes, Alzheimers and other chronic conditions.
Every day thousands of un-used stem cells are being discarded which could be used for research to bring about the cure for debilitating diseases.
While stem cell research on healthy cells is wrong, but what about the ones that are 'just being thrown away'.
Without a cure Michael J Fox and Muhammed Ali will face a limited life, imprionsed by a body they can't control.
And so will millions of other nameless, faceless people around the world.
It's symptoms grow worse over time and sufferers become severley disabled.  Currently the only research being done are on animal models to develop new drug therapy for Parkinsons.
Only time and proper research will cure this awful disease and it's time people be made aware of Parkinsons, the sufferers thereof and the search for a cure - stem cell research.

It's time to take action!

1. The United States Government must take a stand and allow research to be done on unusable stem cells!

2. Parkinsons must be recognised as a disease that is totally debilitating and ruins lives!

3. People must realise Parkinsons Disease leaves the sufferer in hell, on medication that will eventually stop working after a period of time. All we ask for is research...</description>
  <mission>Find a Cure for Parkinsons Disease

HOW CAN YOU HELP THE CAUSE:

JOIN the cause
INVITE all of your friends (repeat daily)
DONATE if you are able to
DISPLAY the cause in your profile
</mission>
  <name>Help Cure Parkinsons Disease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9558</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">21535</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">11403.83</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Db/OR/BR/QP/BG/ya/rd6S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
