<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>It is not often that I ask for assistance, but this is a life threatening situation.
Ruan van der Walt is a young man of 24 who is a personal friend of my cousin Donovan. He is suffering from kidney failure. Due to his illness he has not been able to keep on working and therefore has no income. Below is his story and the details of why he is unable to obtain the necessary care from the state hospital. In the light of this situation it is imperative that he maintain his medical aid so that he may have funds for the transplant that is required. A fund through a NPO has been set up to assist him in this regard.
Could you please pray for the following:
-          That the necessary finances will be made   
           available through the donations into the   
           NPO bank account.
-          That God will touch this young mans body   
           and life!
Should you require any more information please contact me or if you are interested in assisting financially the bank details are on the attached document. Some friend have offered to do art work which can be sold, whilst others have sold old books. Others have baked and sold cookies, as well as hosted pamper days to raise money.

If you would like to make a donation, here are the details:

Vukutentele Project Support Initiative (Pty) Ltd
Standard Bank
Nelspruit 052852
Account 030282470

Please provide us with the following deposit reference: RUAN


Thank you all. 


1. Everyone deserves a chance!

2. How would you feel if this were you?

3. How would you feel if this were your brother boyfriend or husband?</description>
  <mission>Raise enough moola to keep this man alive...........</mission>
  <name>RUAN VAN DER WALT FUND RAISING</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9560</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/bS/lM/fO/lQ/jx/nD/8SgS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
