<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Guardian Angel home provides many services in Will County, Illinois.&lt;p&gt;

Some of their services include:&lt;P&gt;

The Sexual Assault Service Center is available to help survivors of sexual violence and their significant others in Will and Grundy Counties.  Their sexual assault service has a 24/7 hotline, and they provide numerous services from counseling to legal advocates to help victims of sexual assault.  24/7 hotline 815.730.8984&lt;P&gt;

Groundwork provides a safe temporary residence for abused women and their children, 24 hour accessibility.  They also offer group and individual counseling.&lt;P&gt;

B.A.S.E. is a before and after school enrichment program. We emphasize a wide variety of exciting and fun activities to assist children in school preparation and peer relationships. Our goal is to motivate a child&#8217;s desire to learn, grow and interact and assist the child in his/her academic success&lt;P&gt;

Alternative school for BD children.&lt;P&gt;

The Parent Aide program offers support and assistance to parents who are experiencing challenges as a parent. Parent Aides are trained, professionally supervised individuals, who assist parents under stress and those whose children may be at risk of abuse or neglect.. The parent aide provides this assistance in the home by developing a trusting relationship with the parent and by being a positive role model. They provide assistance with daily tasks such as finding transportation, budget planning, exploring child care options, household management, dealing with professionals and emergency needs.&lt;P&gt;



1. Up to one-half of all husbands physically abuse their wives at least once

2. One out of three girls and one out of four boys will be sexually abused before the age of eighteen

3. Domestic violence is the single major cause of injury to women

4.  Approximately 90% of sexual assaults are committed by someone the victim knows

5. Domestic violence and sexual assault/abuse occurs in all racial, economic, age, gender, and educational groups

6. Forty percent of the women murdered in this country are killed by their husbands or partners

7. Over half of all sexual assaults occur on a date

8. Violence in the home usually becomes more frequent and more severe over time

9. Offenders of childhood sexual abuse often have families and children of their own

10. In 2003, 50% of adolescent boys and 39% of adolescent girls identify at least one common situation in which they believe it is acceptable for a male to physically force sexual activity upon a female</description>
  <mission>To improve the quality of people's lives-especially those who suffer from - abuse, neglect, or emotional trauma</mission>
  <name>Guardian Angel Community Services</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9562</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">34</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yG/jS/cD/PA/A7/OB/1tIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
