<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is child sexual abuse - and what can I do about it?

If you are not exactly sure what sexual abuse is - or what you can do - you&#8217;re not alone. 

All sexual touching between an adult and a child is sexual abuse. Sexual touching between children can also be sexual abuse when there is a significant age difference (often defined as 3 or more years) between the children or if the children are very different developmentally or size-wise. Sexual abuse does not have to involve penetration, force, pain, or even touching. 

If an adult engages in any sexual behavior (looking, showing, or touching) with a child to meet the adult&#8217;s sexual needs or interest, it is sexual abuse. Most often child sexual abuse is a gradual process and not a single event. 

By learning the early warning signs and how to effectively step in and speak up, sexual abuse can be stopped before a child is harmed. 

Adults must take the primary responsibility for preventing child sexual abuse by addressing any concerning or questionable behavior which may pose a risk to a child&#8217;s safety.

Visit www.StopItNow.org for lists of Warning Sign Behaviors to Watch For, more FAQs - and FREE Resources and Prevention Tools.

1. Child sexual abuse is preventable; it's not inevitable.

2. Adults are in the best position to keep children safe from sexual abuse, especially before they are ever harmed.

3. Anyone directly impacted by child sexual abuse should know that they are not alone - and that help, hope &amp; healing are available.

4. Children have a right to grow-up with stable, nurturing relationships and a life free from trauma from any form of violence, including sexual abuse.

5. Make people aware that StopItNow.org has balanced info, practical resources &amp; confidential help for dealing with child sexual abuse.</description>
  <mission>To mobilize adults, families &amp; communities to take actions that protect children from sexual abuse.</mission>
  <name>We Can Prevent Child Sexual Abuse - Let's Stop It Now!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9564</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">44891</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">371.96</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kX/Zd/QG/vY/VX/rl/5T/pPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
