<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>As you all well know, the situation in Sri Lanka is tenuous at best, and the recent political and humanitarian upheaval lends very little hope for such a dire situation. According to the United Nations, the closure of the A-9 highway leading to the Jaffna peninsula-a vital transport route, has hampered aid deliveries and food assistance.  Approximately 165,000 internally displaced people (IDPs) that are heavily reliant on this assistance are especially suffering the brunt of this action, lending to increased levels of malnutrition.  Living costs have increased ten-fold on the peninsula, exacerbating the crisis and poverty of an already war-fatigued population.

We are kindly asking for your assistance in providing financial assistance to these future doctors to subsidize their living costs so that they can complete their medical education.  The annual subsidy is $600 per student.  Alternatively, you can provide assistance through recommended $50 monthly installments. 

All contributions are greatly appreciated and can be directed to &#8216;IMHO,&#8217; earmarked for &#8216;Jaffna University&#8217; and mailed to:

	InternationalMedical Health Association
	P.O. Box 61265 
                Staten Island, NY 10306, USA.

Alternatively, please visit http://imhousa.org/donate.html to make a one-time or monthly donation using your credit card via PayPal or direct debit.  Please be sure to include your email or mailing address in order to receive a receipt for your donation.  

Thank you for your time and consideration to save and brighten the futures of those in need.



1. Alleviate Malnutrition

2. Support Education</description>
  <mission>alleviate the humanitarian suffering in Sri Lanka</mission>
  <name>Help subsidize rising living costs of the war-afflicted people of Sri Lanka!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9572</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">151</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">78.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Im/yB/OQ/Xe/Fl/PZ/DSrS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
