<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Worldwide, 46 MILLION women decide to end their unborn child's life every year. Every day, that number is at a staggering 126,000. 126,000 human beings that would have otherwise been able to LIVE.
(The Alan Guttmacher Institute and Planned Parenthood's Family Planning Perspectives. www.abortionno.org)&lt;br&gt;

According to the previous source:
-1% of all abortions occur because of rape or incest; 
-6% of abortions occur because of potential health problems regarding either the mother or child,
-and 93% of all abortions occur for social reasons (i.e. the child is unwanted or inconvenient).&lt;br&gt;

Between 1967 and 1990, only 151 abortions have been carried out to save the mother's life, a figure amounting to 0.004% of all abortions.
(http://www.spuc.org.uk, Dr Michael Jarmulowicz, cited in The Physical and Psycho-Social effects of Abortion on Women: A Report by the Commission of Inquiry into the Operation and Consequences of The Abortion Act, June 1994 p. 5)&lt;br&gt;

With most health problems out of the way, the vast majority of abortions are carried out because the child is INCONVENIENT or simply just unwanted. &lt;br&gt;

Put these facts in with the millions of years of genocide--6 million+ Jewish people murdered in the holocaust, the thousands of African Americans murdered in racist lynchings... Abortion seems very closely related.&lt;br&gt;

The only thing left to do is to get in the face of abortion. Spread the word, spread the facts. It's not going to go away, it's not going to get better. Abortion is genocide and should never be a constituational right anywhere or for anyone.&lt;br&gt;

Join, Recruit, Donate. Do anything you can.

www.abortionno.org
www.abortionno.org
www.abortionno.org isn't something for the weak of heart or stomach. The things you'll see on this website aren't G-rated. GAP is an amazingly successful organization, and their strategy is the only thing left to do.&lt;br&gt;

http://abortioninstruments.com/
same as above.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;



1. Human life begins at the moment of conception.

2. Abortion is the murder of a human being.

3. No woman should ever have the choice to end the life of her child. Abortion should never be a constitutional right.</description>
  <mission>To put an end to the mass murder of millions of unborn children every year.</mission>
  <name>Abortion is Genocide</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9602</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1163</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pg/qN/8q/0e/Fe/V7/gXfS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
