<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Lurie Family Autism Center LADDERS, located in Lexington, MA, is a multi-disciplinary clinic dedicated to helping those with autism and autism-related disorders.   The director of Dr. Margaret Bauman, M.D.

Friends of LADDERS, Inc. is an organization of parents, civic leaders, businesspersons, professionals, and other volunteers committed to providing support to the LADDERS program and to raise funds to underwrite expansion projects. Aware of the reality that children with developmental disorders including PDD/Autism cannot always be adequately serviced through healthcare or education dollars alone, Friends of LADDERS hopes to bridge the gap by raising private funds.

Founded in 1981, Lurie Family Autism Center LADDERS is an interdisciplinary program designed to provide services in the evaluation and treatment of children and adults with autism, pervasive developmental disorder and related disorders. 

We strongly believe that each child merits the opportunity to be carefully evaluated and to receive the quantity and quality of services necessary to allow that individual to reach his or her maximum potential for independence and personal growth, regardless of economic, social and ethnic background. 

For more information, visit www.ladders.org.  Sign up for the FOL e-newsletter at http://www.ladders.org/mailing.php

1. Support Lurie Family Autism Center LADDERS, a multi-disciplinary clinic located in Lexington, MA </description>
  <mission>LADDERS is interdisciplinary program designed to provide services in the evaluation and treatment of children and adults with autism, pervasive developmental disorder and related disorde</mission>
  <name>Friends of LADDERS, Inc.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9606</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">179</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/aZ/AP/jO/Lz/gc/6u/hrdS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
