<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community Council (CDGLCC) is an organization devoted to serving the Capital District's lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgendered (LGBT) community. Located in Albany, NY, the Council has been serving the Capital District for over thirty years. We provide numerous programs and activities including youth and peer support groups, cultural events, commUNITY (our publication), Capital Pride, The Rainbow Caf&#233;, as well as workshops and seminars on issues of concern to the community such as health, personal finance and family/legal matters. We are also home to a number of recovery groups that serve the LGBT community.

The Council's mission is simple &#8211; to promote the well being of all gay, lesbian, bisexual, transgender and queer identified people and those affected by discrimination based on gender identity and expression. The Council provides services to over 5,000 people annually.

The Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community Council operates a Community Center located at 332 Hudson Avenue in Albany, New York. The Center is the oldest continually operated Gay and Lesbian Community Center in the United States. The Community Center serves as a focal point of the LGBT community.

The Council is administered by an all volunteer Board of Directors, and a paid staff consisting of an Executive Director, a Program Director and an Administrative Coordinator. The majority of programs and services are carried out by the organization's committees and a strong network of dedicated volunteers.

1. Promoting the well being of all gay, lesbian, bisexual, transgender and queer identified people and those affected by discrimination based on gender identity and expression</description>
  <mission>To promote the well being of all gay, lesbian, bisexual, transgender and queer identified people and those affected by discrimination based on gender identity and expression.</mission>
  <name>Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community Council</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9608</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">52</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/w3/6K/rS/3A/zp/hA/xuCS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
