<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our mission is to bring this crisis to an end. 

The first step is awareness. Many people still turn a blind eye to the murder rates, turning off the news and skipping those sections of the newspaper that are daily reminders. If we want to stop the violence, we must get everyone to take a good, hard look at the crimes.

The second step is support. Families all over are suffering the loss of a loved one. Now more than ever, children under the age of 18 have the highest mortality rate in the city. Why must parents lose their children to these senseless acts? We must rally around them, support them, and help them to get through their time of crisis.

The third step is action. Few people will come forward with the names of these murderers, even if they witnessed the crime. Why? They are terrified. Too many people have been injured or killed for trying to take these criminals off the streets and it is  not right. They live in fear for their lives and their loved ones. The police must step up their efforts to provide security and protection for those who come forward and they must start bringing in the murderers. 

We must petition, protest, and tell the Philadelphia Police, the Commissioner and the Mayor that enough is enough.

We must stand up to these criminals and tell them no more blood will be shed.

We must take back the streets. Because everyone deserves the right to live without fear.

1. Philadelphia Police and Authorities must make a better effort to protect individuals who come forward with information.

2. Laws regarding individuals involved with these murders must be better enforced and more effort should be made to find them.

3. The people of Philadelphia are tired of the funerals and bodies. ENOUGH IS ENOUGH!</description>
  <mission>raise awareness of the ever growing murder rate in Philadelphia and surrounding areas.</mission>
  <name>Project: Paint It Black</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9625</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SC/DV/ic/p2/7L/dJ/4c0S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
