<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Project Linus's twofold mission: 

- First, it is our mission to provide love, a sense of security, warmth and comfort to children who are seriously ill, traumatized, or otherwise in need through the gifts of new, handmade blankets and afghans, lovingly created by volunteer &#8220;blanketeers&#8221;.  

- Second, it is our mission to provide a rewarding and fun service opportunity for interested individuals and groups in local communities, for the benefit of children.  

Project Linus National Headquarters is located in Bloomington, Illinois. National President Carol Babbitt, and Vice President Mary Balagna, both full time volunteers, direct and orchestrate the activities of Project Linus chapters located across the United States. Both have been involved with the organization since late 1998, as chapter coordinators and now as directors and officers. They also maintain a very busy Central Illinois chapter, donating an average of 350 blankets every month to local children. With chapters in all 50 states, Project Linus continues to grow. Blankets are collected locally and distributed to children in hospitals, shelters, social service agencies, or anywhere that a child might be in need of a big hug.

"I am extremely pleased by the outpouring of support Project Linus has enjoyed." states Babbitt. "The comfort brought to a child by a Project Linus security blanket should not be underestimated. Thanks to our many blanketeers and our chapter coordinators, millions of children and their families have been given comfort and security at a time when they need it most. In addition, blanketeers are given an opportunity to use their talents and abilities in most rewarding way."

Statistics as of June 30, 2007:
- Blankets Donated: 2,210,100
- Chapters: 406
 


1. No child should go through such an ordeal without the love, security, warmth, and comfort handmade blankets can provide</description>
  <mission>to provide love, a sense of security, warmth and comfort to children who are seriously ill, traumatized, or otherwise in need through the gifts of new, handmade blankets and afghans</mission>
  <name>Project Linus</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9630</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1082</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">138.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Lx/rt/vH/xH/t3/cY/hqiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
