<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>     Septic shock is a serious condition that occurs when an overwelming infection leads to low blood presure and low blood flow. The Brain, heart, kidneys, and liver may not work properly or may fail.  
    Most victims of septic shock, have very little chance of servival, unless treated promptly and properly. It occurs mostly to children and the elderly. symptoms include;
*High or very low temperature, chills
*Lightheadedness
*Shortness of breath
*Palpitations
*Cool, pale extremities
*Restlessness, confusion
*Rapid heart rate
*Low Blood Pressure

Risk Factors include;
*Diabetes
*Recent infection
*Long-term use of antibiotics
*Recent surgery or medical proceedure.
*Lymphoma

     Septic Shock attacks though flu like symptoms, therefore making it difficult for people to know they are suffering from it. Every hour septic shock is not treated, your mortality rate drops by 7%. With the demand today of family doctors, and how they take on such heavy work loads, they are not treating or testing their patients properly leading to more complications, especially to the elderly. 

     My Grandfather recently passed away of septic shock. His symptoms were as stated, making it very difficult to recognize. He was fine working in his garden early in the morning, came inside with a chill, and by 12:00am he was intubated on life support, and passed away only a few days later. I believe that if he had been given proper care before this occurance he may still be alive today.

1. Always demand proper care from your family physician

2. Know the symptoms of septic shock, especially if you are already at risk</description>
  <mission>To help people be aware of the symptoms of septic shock before it is too late.</mission>
  <name>Septic Shock Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9631</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">155</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.25</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SC/2C/Jj/Tt/wQ/Sx/Q2kS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
