<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The term &#8220;child abuse&#8221; refers to the violence, mistreatment or neglect that a child or adolescent may experience while in the care of someone they either trust or depend on, such as a parent, sibling, other relative, caregiver or guardian. Abuse may take place anywhere and may occur, for example, within the child's home or that of someone known to the child. 

There are many different forms of abuse and a child may be subjected to more than one form:  

Physical abuse may consist of just one incident or it may happen repeatedly. It involves deliberately using force against a child in such a way that the child is either injured or is at risk of being injured.  Physical abuse includes beating, hitting, shaking, pushing, choking, biting, burning, kicking or assaulting a child with a weapon.1 It also includes holding a child under water, or any other dangerous or harmful use of force or restraint.  Female genital mutilation is another form of physical abuse. 

Sexual abuse and exploitation involves using a child for sexual purposes. Examples of child sexual abuse include fondling, inviting a child to touch or be touched sexually, intercourse, rape, incest, sodomy, exhibitionism, or involving a child in prostitution or pornography.2

Neglect is often chronic, and it usually involves repeated incidents. It involves failing to provide what a child needs for his or her physical, psychological or emotional development and well being.  For example, neglect includes failing to provide a child with food, clothing, shelter, cleanliness, medical care or protection from harm.3 Emotional neglect includes failing to provide a child with love, safety, and a sense of worth.



1. Child abuse must stop !!!

2. Its wrong it needs to stop !!!

3. Its not right to hit anyone !!!</description>
  <mission>Bring a stop to child abuse.</mission>
  <name>Stop child abuse</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9634</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">253</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/ZY/6G/fK/vL/zy/UV/gh/1OS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
