<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Multiple Myeloma is an incurable, however treatable, form of cancer commonly found in the age of 60's. 

It is a cancer of the plasma cell. 

Only less than 1% of the people diagnosed with this cancer are under the age of 40 hence this rare form of cancer.  

The average age for the person with this form of cancer is approximately sixty-eight (68).  

Symptoms of this particular cancer form can be found at http://www.multiplemyeloma.org/about_myeloma/2.04.php in detailed tables.
 
Current types of treatments (note some are still being investigated in clinical trials, some are pending patents/FDA approval in different countries, etc) are as following:

- Dexamethasone;
- Thalidomide;
- Velcade;
- Chemotherapy;
- Doxorubicin;
- Stem cell transplantation;
- Radiation therapy;
- Lenalidomide (Revlimid);
- Aredia;
- Zometa;
- Aresenic trioxide;
- Bisphosphonates;
- Colony-stimulating Factors;
- Erythropoietic Agents;
- IMiDs;
- Pamidronate;
- Trisenox; and
- Zoledronic acid.

More information can be found on the site of http://www.multiplemyeloma.org/, as well the international website: http://myeloma.org/.  It is quite informative and easily understood.  



1. To bring knowledge to those lost in the tumbles of confusion.

2. To develop a secure system where people can get together to ask questions and voice their concerns, as well to find answers.

3. To help lessen the burdens on people involved and enable them to have a better understanding of this rare cancer.</description>
  <mission>To have information available for people, and people involved, with Multiple Myeloma and to allow them have confidence, support and tools to face this as easy as possible.</mission>
  <name>Multiple Myeloma</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9640</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1790</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/yK/Zx/Nd/WV/4P/6c/HqQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
