<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The American Red Cross needs you! 

Various Opportunies to Help &#8212; Red Cross volunteers provide relief to victims of disasters and help people prevent, prepare for, and respond to emergencies.

No Special Skills Required &#8212; The Red Cross needs people with all kinds of different backgrounds, talents and skill levels. And, if you need training, we'll provide it. 

Volunteers constitute 96 percent of our total work force to carry on our humanitarian work:

Every year the Red Cross responds to more than 70,000 disasters&#8212;including approximately 150 home fires every day. 
About 11 million Americans turn to us to learn first aid, CPR, swimming, and other health and safety skills. Last year, more than 158,000 people volunteered to teach those courses. 
Half the nation's blood supply&#8212; six million pints annually&#8212;is collected by more than 155,000 Red Cross volunteers . 
Among our emergency services for the men and women of the armed forces is the delivery of urgent family messages&#8212;around the clock and around the globe. 

Twin Cities Red Cross Responding to Hwy. 35W Bridge Collapse. Our hearts go out to everyone affected by the 35W bridge collapse tragedy. The Twin Cities Red Cross is responding to this disaster by providing mass care, mental health counseling and more to those affected. 

To register yourself as SAFE and WELL or to search for information on a loved one - please visit www.safeandwell.org. Concerned family and friends can search the list of those who have registered. You can also call (612) 871-7676. 

Family Assistance Center
A family assistance center is located at:
Holiday-Inn Metrodome
1500 Washington Ave. 
Minneapolis, MN 55454

For further information please visit &lt;a href="http://www.redcrosstc.org/index.cfm"
target="_blank"&gt;American Red Cross Twin Cities Area Chapter&lt;/a&gt;.

1. Disaster Services

2. Blood Services

3. Health and Safety Services

4. International Services

5. Volunteer Services

6. Youth Services</description>
  <mission>The American Red Cross helps people in emergencies every day. Whether its half a million disaster victims or one sick child who needs blood, Our vital work is made possible by people like you. </mission>
  <name>American Red Cross Twin Cities Area Chapter</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9642</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">142</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">40.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Gr/t2/nP/PL/SA/vH/xZtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
