<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Global warming is THE issue of our time.

Youth have always been at the forefront of great social change.

Campus Climate Neutral is a nationwide, non-partisan campaign to mobilize law students in support of campus greenhouse gas emission reductions and global climate change solutions.

Working with CCN, students take on projects that range from studying their schools emissions to writing and advocating for city and state legislation.  The project works with partners that range from faith groups to justice groups to the Department of Defense.  

To start your own project or for more info, search for our co-chair Jay Heeter on Facebook, and send him a message. 

Check out our new blog at http://naelsblog.blogspot.com.

Donations to CCN will help develop this project to train future leaders while building solid climate change laws and policies today.

CCN is a project of the National Association of Environmental Law Societies (NAELS), a coalition of over 50 law student groups that aims to connect, educate, and inspire the next generation of environmental leaders. 

1. Global climate change is the most important environmental threat facing the world today.

2. Students can build and drive practical solutions to climate change on their campuses and in their communities.  

3. Campus Climate Neutral trains and inspires future leaders to build their skills to face the environmental issues of tomorrow by making a difference on critical issues today. </description>
  <mission>STOP GLOBAL WARMING by connecting, educating and inspiring the next generation of environmental leaders through ACTION to build successful laws and policies today.</mission>
  <name>Campus Climate Neutral</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/965</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">280</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/a6s/EjLS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
