<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The National Jewish Democratic Council is committed to those values shared by the Democratic Party and the vast majority of American Jews - including the separation of church and state, a strong US-Israel relationship, and reproductive freedom. 

NJDC's singular set of priorities includes:

Educating Jewish voters about the very real differences between their Democratic and Republican candidates for elected office through special reports and voter guides. NJDC has distributed more than 250,000 informational guides to Jewish households in recent election cycles. 
Informing candidates for public office about the need to address and support issues of concern to the Jewish community. 

Advocating on behalf of Jewish and Democratic ideals on Capitol Hill and in Jewish and national media. 

Fighting the radical right agenda at every turn through research and reports, grassroots advocacy, working directly with lawmakers in Washington, and educating journalists. 

Engaging and cultivating a new generation of young Jewish Democratic leaders by replicating our highly successful Washington-based Young Leadership program in other major cities, including New York, Boston, Los Angeles, Cleveland and South Florida. 

Expanding Jewish awareness of critical legislative activity through quarterly and biweekly publications, as well as Breakfast Roundtables and Domestic Issues Forums featuring congressional and executive branch leaders.


1. A strong US-Israel Relationship

2. The Separation of Church and State

3. Reproductive Freedom</description>
  <mission>be the national voice of Jewish Democrats</mission>
  <name>National Jewish Democratic Council</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9672</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/65/j6/x2/87/o7/Ht/kbmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
