<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>First off, for all you people that do like KFC (which is a lot of people) we are not asking to get rid of KFC! All we are asking is that KFC not abuse their chickens. 
KFC does all the cruel things to their chicken right before they serve them to us. Here are some things they do...

1. Cram many chickens in excrement-filled sheds that stink of ammonia fumes.
2. Break the legs and wings of the birds by haveing them bred to be too top-heavy and also because workers carelessly shove them into transport crates and shackles. 
3. They slit their throats and drop them into tanks of scalding-hot water to remove their feathers. They are usually still conscious and able to feel pain.
4. KFC also lets tired, frustrated factory-farm and slaughterhouse workers handle live birds, so many of the animals end up being sadistically abused. They have been documented tearing the heads off live chickens, spitting tobacco into their eyes, spray-painting their faces, and violently stomping on them. This was discovered more than two years after KFC promised PETA that it was taking animal welfare seriously.
And they do a lot more!

All we want them to do is things like adopt the &#8220;Animal Care Standards&#8221; program, Switch to controlled-atmosphere killing (CAK), Switch to mechanized chicken gathering, Breed for health rather than rapid growth and stop feeding drugs to them.
All we want is a happier life for these chickens!

Visit www.kentuckyfriedcruelty.com and www.peta2.com for more information

If everyone just donates about $10, that will help a lot.
Thank you for reading all of this and hopefully you will join, invite others and donate
&lt;3

1. KFC is cruel to their chickens.

2. Chickens and all animals have rights.

3. Every animal deserves a happy life.</description>
  <mission>Is to make KFC more humane place for animals.</mission>
  <name>KFC Cruelty</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9678</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">857</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qY/2b/KS/Zc/ju/6y/M8NS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
