<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>ProyectArte is a New York- and Buenos Aires-based oganization that creates, develops and supports innovative arts projects in the Americas.

ProyectArte's principal program is the free ProyectArte School in Buenos Aires, Argentina, whose mission is to discover, educate, and develop promising young artists in that country. At the school, modelled after the Renaissance-era Master-Apprentice model, a socioeconomically diverse group of talented youth ages 15 to 18 study fine arts with some of Argentina's most distinguished artists. These aspiring artists study intensively for 10 hours a week, using a special curriculum developed by some of Argentina's leading artists and educators.

In just four years, ProyectArte has become Argentina's premier institution for youth arts education. ProyectArte's students and graduates have exhibited their work at the Centro Cultural Recoleta, Argentina's most visited public exhibition space, as well as the Chelsea Art Museum in New York and the Johnson &amp; Johnson Arts Center in New Jersey. In spite of their young ages, ProyectArte graduates have participated in numerous group and solo exhibitions, and many have sold works to collectors in Buenos Aires and New York.

To expand ProyectArte's impact, the Proyectar ("to project" in Spanish) program brings our scholarship recipients to poor public schools throughout Buenos Aires to conduct art workshops for younger schoolchildren. Since its inception, the Proyectar program has reached more than 3000 schoolchildren in 20 public schools.

1. Quality arts education should be available to all talented students, regardless of their capacity to pay.

2. Uniting talented students from diverse socioeconomic backgrounds affords a valuable opportunity for dialogue and friendship across Argentina's rigid social boundaries.

3. Helping underprivileged students to succeed, both artistically and economically, creates a virtuous cycle that will pay dividends for generations to come.</description>
  <mission>To draw attention to and garner support for ProyectArte, Argentina's premier institution for youth arts education.</mission>
  <name>Support Arts Education Across the Americas</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9689</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">351</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">275.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/kS/gP/uS/tI/cj/Np/y0NS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
