<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>"Asbestos is the general term for a number of naturally occurring fibrous forms of mineral silicates. These grow in chainlike crystal structures of billions of microscopic fibers that are so light they can float in the air for hours or even days. The fibers are so pliable they can be woven into cloth.
Because it is literally a rock, asbestos is waterproof, fireproof and corrosion-proof. Manufacturers quickly found that this "magic material" had hundreds of applications in building, homes, appliances, automobiles, and in a variety of common products from ironing board pads and cigarette filters to hair dryers and children's clothing.
The problem with asbestos is the fibers. They break off at the slightest provocation. Needle-sharp and shaped like spears, they can be inhaled by the thousands with each breath. Some physicians believe even one of the fibers, lodged in the wrong place, can eventually kill a person.While many of the fibers find their way safely out of the body, others inevitably embed themselves in soft tissue and cannot be removed. They most often lodge in the lungs and lining of the abdomen but have been found in nearly every major organ of the human body, including the brain and heart.
Asbestos exposure is related to increased levels of several types of cancer, especially of the lungs and stomach. Asbestos is the sole cause of mesothelioma (mees-o-thee-lee-oma), a virulent and fatal cancer that doctors say is more physically painful and psychologically devastating than AIDS. It also causes asbestosis, a serious, progressive, and potentially fatal disease that eventually kills its victims by cutting off their oxygen supply. Asbestosis can lie dormant and then suddenly "flower," causing death in a relatively short time; its victims are said to have ticking bombs inside their chests."
-Excerpt from "Fatal Deception, The Untold Story of Asbestos." by Micheal Bowker

1. People around the world must become aware of the hundreds of thousands that have died due to asbestos-related diseases.</description>
  <mission>Raise awareness about asbestos fibers and asbestos-related diseases.</mission>
  <name>Asbestos Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9692</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">57</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/qK/V6/gl/Ah/t7/Rr/KEkS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
