<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>With American consumers clamoring for the rich hues of mahogany and cedar furniture, tropical timber prices have skyrocketed, driving hundreds of illegal loggers into the Peruvian Amazon in search of these majestic trees.  Demand for hardwood flooring has set off a similar race to cut down trees in the rainforests throughout Asia and Africa.  The effects of this illegal activity are disastrous for the species, the forest, and the local indigenous communities that rely on this ecosystem for their survival. In addition, illegal logging severely undermines legitimate forest trade.  

In Peru, most remaining mahogany is located in protected areas and territorial reserves set aside for indigenous peoples who have had little or no contact with the outside world.  When illegal loggers invade these areas, they kill wildlife and engage in violent conflict with the indigenous groups.  They often spread deadly diseases that the isolated peoples have no way to combat, and build roads in protected areas, badly damaging the ecosystem.  If the illegal logging of mahogany does not stop, the tree could become commercially extinct in the next 5 to 10 years.  Without proper controls in place to address illegal logging, other species will soon follow in a destructive pattern of overexploitation and depletion.

Eliminating the market for illegally imported tropical timber means that the illegal loggers will not be able to sell the timber they cut, and as their operations will no longer be profitable, they will stop destroying the forests and livelihoods of the people living near these forests.

But fear not!  By clicking on the link below and SIGNING THE PLEDGE, ENCOURAGING YOUR FRIENDS AND FAMILY TO SIGN IT, and INVITING PEOPLE TO JOIN THIS CAUSE, you can show your support for the Amazon's forests and native peoples and start to make a difference.

http://www.peruforests.org/petition

1. Illegal logging devastates wildlife and local communities.

2. Some of the tree species being illegally logged (including bigleaf mahogany and Spanish cedar) are endangered or on their way towards becoming endangered.

3. Illegal logging contributes to climate change by releasing carbon into the air from carbon sinks.

4. You can help to stop illegal logging by helping to put downwards pressure on the market- ask your family, friends, and school to stop purchasing illegally logged tropical timber.

5. Tell your Representative and Senator to support the &#8220;Combat Illegal Logging Act of 2007.&#8221;  This bill would make it illegal to import illegally logged timber and forest products into the United States.</description>
  <mission>Stop the illegal, unsustainable logging of tropical timber.</mission>
  <name>Stop Illegal Logging</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9703</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">93</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/NG/eI/rf/Ud/Qf/YV/qNnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
