<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Origin of Kurds:
According to Vladimir Minorsky There is no doubt that the term Mar (Medians) refers to Kurds. Furthermore he writes that in the curious Armenian manuscript containing samples of alphabets and languages, written some time before A.D. 1446, a prayer in Kurdish figures as specimen of the language of the Medians''. 
The Kurds must certainly be connected with the Karduchi mentioned in Xenophon and the Gordyaei mentioned in other Greek and Latin authors, with the Kordukh or Kortschaikh of the Armenians and the land of Gardu of the Aramaic and Syriac writers. 
One of the earliest records of the name Kurd is to be found in a Pahlavi Sassanid text in which the battle between Sassanid King Ardashir I and Madig King of the Kurds in the early 3rd century CE is mentioned.
The name of the Kurds proper however can only be dated with certainty to the Kurdish tribes' conversion to Islam in the 7th century AD.
According to Encyclopedia Columbia, Kurds are commonly identified with the ancient Corduene which was inhabited by the Carduchi.
Gradual linguistic assimilation of the various indigenous peoples to this Median language in the course of the Iron Age marks the beginning of Kurdish ethnogenesis. 

History of the Kurds:
Ancient period
The present-day home of the Kurds, the high mountain region south and south-east of Lake Van between Persia and Mesopotamia, was in the possession of Kurds before the time of the ancient Greek historian Xenophon, and was known as the country of the Carduchi, Cardyene or Cordyene. Xenophon referred to the Kurds in the Anabasis as "Kardukhi...a fierce and protective mountain-dwelling people" who attacked Greek armies in 400 BCE. 
The kingdom of Cordyene or Corduene was a high mountain region south and south-east of Lake Van between Persia and Mesopotamia, and it was situated to the east of Tigranocerta[24] (east and south of present-day Diyarbak&#305;r). The word Corduene is no doubt the ancient representative of the modern Kurdistan, and means a country in which Kurds dwelt. Now Kurds seem to have been at one time the chief inhabitants of the Mons Masius, the modern Jebel Kara Dagh and Jebel Tur, which was thence called Gordyene, or the Gordisean mountain chain. The tract to this day known as Kurdistan, the high mountain region south and south-east of Lake Van between Persia and Mesopotamia, was in the possession of Kurds from before the time of Xenophon, and was known as the country of the Carduchi, as Cardyene, and as Cordyene.
Corduene became a province of the Roman Empire in 66 BCE and was under Roman control for four centuries until 384 CE. The Roman historian Pliny, has considered Cordueni (inhabitants of Corduene) as descendants of Carduchis. He has stated, Joining on to Adiabene are the people formerly called the Carduchi and now the Cordueni, past whom flows the river Tigris.... The people of Corduene were known to have worshipped the Hurrian sky God Teshub.
Medieval period
Kurdish Cavalry in the passes of the Caucasus mountains (The New York Times, January 24, 1915).
In the seventh century, the Arabs possessed the castles and fortifications of the Kurds. The conquest of the cities of Sharazor and Aradbaz took place in the year 643 AC.
In 846 AC, one of the leaders of the Kurds in Mosul city revolted against the Caliph Al Mo'tasam who sent the famous commander Aitakh to combat against him. In this war, Aitakh proved victorious and killed many of the Kurds. In 903 AC, during the period of Almoqtadar, the Kurds revolted again. Eventually Arabs conquered the Kurdish regions and converted the majority of Kurds to Islam.

1. Kurdish Issue</description>
  <mission>support the Kurdish Issue</mission>
  <name>Support the Kurdish Issue</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9708</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2911</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">35.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1L/hy/8P/v4/Yj/zz/fWhS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
