<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>With so much armed conflict happening and more conflict promised to appear, the world is at a real threat of experiencing a new World War.  Iran sending aid to Al-Qaeda in Iraq.  Russia testing new ballistic missiles in "response to American aggression."  North Korea testing new missiles.   Venezuela being taken over by an Anti-Western radical leader.  Iran refusing to put an end to its nuclear ambitions.  The Chinese sending spies to the US and spending a huge amount of money on military development.  All of these signs of aggression - and so many more - point to a decidedly grim future unless the United States and the other countries of the world agree to end this heightened state of aggression through diplomacy.   

1. The nations of the world - both leading and developing - must join hands and denounce the proliferation of nuclear weaponry.  All must hope for - and work for - a nuclear weapon free world.

2. Enemies must talk to enemies, and friends must help friends.  This world will get no where if nations in conflict refuse to communicate with eachother.  Conflict can only be avoided by the same thing that drives a developing friendship: communication.

3. Every government of the world must be held responsible for any reprehensible crime against humanity that it commits - or allows to befall upon - any citizen of its country.  Respect for human life is the cornerstone of any peaceful world.

4. A war of words is infinitely better than a World War.  Diplomacy must be used to face the coming conflicts that could easily force our world into outright conflict.

5. International bodies - like the African Union, United Nations, NATO, and the European Union - in addition to individual citizens - must take an active role in the deterrence of conflit and hate in the world.</description>
  <mission>Our mission is to show our support for the use of diplomacy whenever possible in order to avoid another armed conflict that will bring us into what would essentially qualify as the Third World War.</mission>
  <name>Support Diplomacy - Avoid WWIII</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/971</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">567</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/OOd/DuHS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
