<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This cause in dear to my heart and very close to me.  Unfortunately, this illness has such a negative stigma to it but in reality it is not that all uncommon.  I just want to get the word out and have a safe community where one can come and make friends that will support them whether they go through the same thing or not.

Signs of Borderline Personality Disorder

1. Shifts in mood lasting only a few hours.

2. Anger that is inappropriate, intense, or uncontrollable.

3. Self-destructive acts, such as self-mutilation or suicidal threats and gestures that happen more than once.

4. Two potentially self-damaging impulsive behaviors. These could include alcohol and other drug abuse, compulsive spending, gambling, eating disorders, shoplifting, reckless driving, compulsive sexual behavior.

5. Marked, persistent identity disturbance shown by uncertainty in at least two areas. These areas can include self-image, sexual orientation, career choice or other long-term goals, friendships, values.

6. Chronic feelings of emptiness or boredom.

7. Unstable, chaotic intense relationships characterized by splitting.

8. Frantic efforts to avoid real or imagined abandonment.
-Splitting: the self and others are viewed as "all good" or "all bad." -Alternating clinging and distancing behaviors (I Hate You, Don't Leave Me).
-Great difficulty trusting people and themselves. Early trust may have been shattered by people who were close to you.
-Sensitivity to criticism or rejection.
-Feeling of "needing" someone else to survive
-Heavy need for affection and reassurance
-Some people with BPD may have an unusually high degree of interpersonal sensitivity, insight and empathy.

9. Transient, stress-related paranoid ideation or severe dissociative symptoms.


1. Give a community to those who may need others to confide in.

2. Show people theres hope and love out there.

3. Raise money to spread the word and help facilites that treat BPD.</description>
  <mission>Bring awareness and support to those who need and to those who want to help.</mission>
  <name>I Hate You, Dont Leave Me: Borderline Personality Disorder Awareness</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9713</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1559</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.47</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/iL/J7/TF/we/AO/IR/GcPS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
