<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Multiple international human rights organizations, including Amnesty International and Human Rights Watch, accuse North Korea of having one of the worst human rights records of any nation. North Koreans have been referred to as "some of the world's most brutalized people", regarding their severe restrictions on political and economic freedoms. North Korean defectors have testified to the existence of prison and detention camps with an estimated 150,000 to 200,000 inmates, and have reported torture, starvation, rape, murder, medical experimentation, forced labor, and forced abortions.


RELIGION

The North Korean Constitution protects freedom of religion, however, according to Human Rights Watch, ever since the rise of communism, free religious activities no longer exist as the government sponsors religious groups only to create an illusion of religious freedom. In practical terms all religion in North Korea is superseded by a cult of personality devoted to the rulers Kim Il-Sung and Kim Jong-Il.

According to a ranking published by Open Doors, an organization that supports persecuted Christians, North Korea is currently the country with the most severe persecution of Christians in the world.


Weapons of mass destruction

On October 9, 2006, North Korea conducted its first nuclear test. The blast was smaller than expected and U.S. officials suggested that it may have been an unsuccessful test or a partially successful fizzle. North Korea has previously stated that it has produced nuclear weapons and according to U.S. intelligence and military officials it has produced, or has the capability to produce, up to six or seven such devices. As of October 2006, North Korea is not believed to have the capability to deliver a nuclear warhead by affixing to a missile or other nuclear weapons delivery system. The most likely means of transport would be aircraft, which could be monitored

1. North Korea should be liberated.

2. The UN should do something about human rights violations in North Korea.

3. The Korean people deserve something better than the current dictatorship under Kim Jong-il.</description>
  <mission>Bring awareness to the human rights violations in North Korea under Kim Jong-il</mission>
  <name>End Human Rights Violations in North Korea</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9717</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">68</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/aM/6L/pR/nW/Az/IP/XSqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
