<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Striplin Foundation, Inc. is a 501 (c) 3 organization based in New York City. TSF was created in honor and memory of Mary Agnes Rhodythe Striplin and her daughter Amanda Tia Michelle Striplin, who were both killed in a tragic car accident August 22, 1999, and James E. Peoples III, their beloved son and brother who survived the accident with critical and nearly fatal injuries.  The tragedy occurred as the family was driving Amanda to begin her freshman year at the University of New Orleans. 

To honor the memories of Amanda and Mary, and the hope of James, The Striplin Foundation, is an organization founded and operated by the family, with Mrs. Dorothy Striplin, mother and grandmother of the deceased, serving as President. Our goal is to disseminate information on mental health issues as it relates to de-stigmatization and support for families, consumers and the organizations that serve them.  We also give annual college scholarships to high school seniors.  

We hope that TSF will become a main source of mental health illness information and a prime outlet for advocates to help make a difference in communities of color. Our two programs:  THE AMJ SCHOLARSHIP AWARD and THE MAGGIE FUND  have been growing strong and with your support we hope to continue growing and expand our level of outreach.


1. Our goal is to provide financial support and information to these women, their families and the organizations that serve them by helping to de-stigmatize mental illness and by assisting those in need of appropriate medication, counseling and hospitalizati</description>
  <mission>Our goal is to disseminate information on mental health issues as it relates to de-stigmatization and support for families, consumers and the organizations that serve them.  </mission>
  <name>THE STRIPLIN FOUNDATION, INC</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9722</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">95</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">100.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/OS/LG/oX/lN/5K/nP/2NFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
