<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Our dream is that young people are empowered by what they learn from and contribute to the development work of communities around the world.&lt;br/&gt;
Young Australians can participate in grassroots community development projects with Australian Volunteers International. They not only make a contribution to others, but also become empowered as future decision makers on global issues. &lt;br/&gt;
AVI youth volunteers work on projects in India, Papua New Guinea and the Philippines, and can work with our partner organisations in Central Australia, Vanuatu, Costa Rica, Guatemala, Guyana, Nepal, South Africa, Tanzania, Uganda and Zambia.&lt;br/&gt;
Participants are encouraged to fundraise or seek sponsorship to meet project costs.&lt;br/&gt;
All projects are team-based (10-12 volunteers per team) and run for 10-12 weeks.&lt;br/&gt;
Age range 18-28; no qualifications or experience required.&lt;br/&gt;
Qualified and experienced Australian and local team leaders manage project activities and ensure the safety and well-being of volunteers.&lt;br/&gt;
Several departures per year (scheduled to suit university breaks).&lt;br/&gt;
Projects include remote living, village home-stays and group accommodation.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.australianvolunteers.com/youth"&gt;www.australianvolunteers.com/youth&lt;/a&gt; or 1800 331 292&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/aviyouth"&gt;www.myspace.com/aviyouth&lt;/a&gt;

1. All projects are determined by local communities and directly benefit the community

2. Giving young Australians in-depth experiences of life in developing countries and an understanding of development issues

3. The Youth Program supports initiatives that help to reduce poverty, promote gender equality, increase environmental awareness and address very urgent health issues</description>
  <mission>To enable young Australians to undertake short-term assignments in developing communities overseas </mission>
  <name>AVI Youth Program</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9730</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">222</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/TL/rs/Sp/i3/3D/Wc/VUwS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
