<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What I'm trying to do here is to make graffiti an art, and not a crime. I want to make it legal for people to walk around with a bag full of spray paint or paint markers and not get brought down to the police station.    


art1&#8194; /&#593;rt/ Pronunciation Key - Show Spelled Pronunciation[ahrt]
&#8211;noun
1. the quality, production, expression, or realm, according to aesthetic principles, of what is beautiful, appealing, or of more than ordinary significance.
2. the class of objects subject to aesthetic criteria; works of art collectively, as paintings, sculptures, or drawings: a museum of art; an art collection.
3. a field, genre, or category of art: Dance is an art.
4. the fine arts collectively, often excluding architecture: art and architecture.
5. any field using the skills or techniques of art: advertising art; industrial art.
6. (in printed matter) illustrative or decorative material: Is there any art with the copy for this story?
7. the principles or methods governing any craft or branch of learning: the art of baking; the art of selling.
8. the craft or trade using these principles or methods.
9. skill in conducting any human activity: a master at the art of conversation.
10. a branch of learning or university study, esp. one of the fine arts or the humanities, as music, philosophy, or literature.
11. arts,
a. (used with a singular verb) the humanities: a college of arts and sciences.
b. (used with a plural verb) liberal arts.
12. skilled workmanship, execution, or agency, as distinguished from nature.
13. trickery; cunning: glib and devious art.
14. studied action; artificiality in behavior.
15. an artifice or artful device: the innumerable arts and wiles of politics.
16. Archaic. science, learning, or scholarship.

art. (n.d.). Dictionary.com Unabridged (v 1.0.1). Retrieved September 24, 2006, from Dictionary.com website: http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/a
rt

Clearly, it is obvious that graffiti is in fact, art. Art is expression; an outcry from the human soul. Humans deserve to be heard; less we resort back into a society of animals.

Graffiti on residential homes and commercial businesses is wrong however; as these are not only private properties, but these are not places where graffiti is needed or wanted, or else they would already be there.

Graffiti of obscenities, vulgar, and such are not and should not be appreciated as they should not be seen by small children.

However, anyone who has been around a metropolis before has seen and recognized beautiful graffiti; free of obscenities, vulgar, and the like, and are truly endowed with talent and skill. This is the graffiti the people wish to see.

However, public property is and should be, public domain. People should be free to use public property, or at least the outside of public property, to place art and express themselves.

Also, putting graffiti in Industrial zones really isn't wrong either. Sure it's private property, but industrial structures are generally not colorful or "artsy," and industrial buildings are not meant to be flashy or beautiful in particular statements.

Residential zones and commercial zones are meant to look beautiful according to what the owner of the property sees in their opinion. They can let people graffiti if they wish, but random people placing graffiti on their buildings may add up into something the owner no-longer finds beautiful, and will have to remove at his or her expense, which is not right at all.

Industrial zones and most public buildings are not designed to look beautiful on the outside, but to be beautiful in what they do. The original buildings themselves are generally not very pretty to begin with, so they do need graffiti to make them look a little better.

1. Graffiti is an art.

2. Graffiti isn't just writing on the walls</description>
  <mission>Make graffiti an art.</mission>
  <name>Graffiti, Legalize it</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9736</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">209</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Kb/8R/3s/E8/0y/Wp/oE/X4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
