<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>This cause is to get people to show their support of helping the babies of Aotearoa. 
There has been too many cases of child abuse ocurring more and more in our country and it has to stop. These babies are supposed to be our future, instead, they are abused and dead before the even get to start school. 
This cannot go on any longer. Please add this cause to your profile to show your support.Leave your comments of support and give your thoughts.
 This is not a gesture of charity, It is an act of justice. It is the protection of a fundamental human right, the right to dignity and a decent life. 

The link below will direct you to a story on a 3year old boy who was killed by his brith parents after being taken from his foster parents home. It is a disturbing story and has graphic photos but its reality and it needs to be seen to understand the full extent of what these poor babies go through. 
http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/1/story.cfm?c_id=1&amp;objectid=10439204

Another story of a baby girl, Nia, who died today (3/08/07). Nia is a three year old girl from Rotorua who is in a coma in hospital because she was literally tourted for three months by some of her own family.
Being swung on the clothes line until she flung off, been put in the dryer and it turned on are only a couple of things this poor girl has gone through.
Today she was taken off life support. Another beautiful little baby, who will never get the chance to go through life.

Check out the link:  http://www.tv3.co.nz/News/NationalNews/Babyputinclothesdryerduring3weeksoftorture/tabid/423/articleID/31422/Default.aspx

PLEASE SHOW YOUR SUPPORT TO THE BABIES OF AOTEAROA!




1. Child abuse is wrong and is detrimental to the well being of any kid.

2. To help kids learn that they don't have to hide that they were abused, and that they do have someone to run to if they need to.

3. To slowly make the world a better place for children. No matter how small the contribution.</description>
  <mission>To help save the babies of Aotearoa from abuse.</mission>
  <name>Stop Child Abuse Aotearoa - Pacific Soul Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9740</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1765</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">160.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/RJ/MW/QZ/sC/7U/WP/iKQS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
