<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We will be fundraising in various ways to help unger and his parents through this terrible time.
Our dearest friend Robin Unger had a accident on Monday July 30th.  Him &amp; some friends were hanging out at a dock &amp; the water was very shallow. Unger, being the active person he is, decided to jump off the dock into the water, attempting a backflip &amp; a half &amp; smashed his head on the rocks below.  Lee Cobb, one of Ungers many friends, jumped in to save him when he realized he was not moving. Rick Driscoll, Shane Jackson, &amp; Lee Cobb all assisted Unger until the ambulance arrived.
Unger is an incredible person and even if you have not met him, you would most definetly like him.  He is the most caring, modest &amp; loving person I have ever met &amp; im sure all of his frineds would agree with me. He is now in Kelowna General Hospital in the Intensive Care Unit.  He dislocated &amp; fractured disc C5 &amp; C6 in his back.  He also has tremendous nerve damage throughout his body.  It is an absolute miracle that he is still able to move his arms, which is amazing because he'll still be able to spin records, one of his major passions.  
Unfortunatly at this time he isnt able to partake in Mauy Thai or Ju Jitsu, 2 activities he was training in. Robin was a very active person.  He worked as a roofer, loved to play soccer, kick ball, enjoy the lake, go camping.  Like any of us, Robin also loved to Party &amp; I feel that  the support and love from his friends will be most effective while helping him to possibly enjoy some of his normal daily activities when he recovers.  We will set up a drop box for anything you can spare for a relief fund to ungers parents &amp; obviously Unger.  We will also be very open to any ideas you may have for fundraisers, to help unger through this accident.  Thank You so much for your consideration &amp; support. Please pray for our friend, our love &amp; support will absolutly help him to get through this.

1. to help robin and his family in any way we can

2. to get robin back to his rightful self as soon as possible</description>
  <mission>raise money for our good friend Robin unger, whos life has recently changed dramatically</mission>
  <name>THE HUNGER FOR UNGER</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9741</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">2</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/G5/8t/qJ/T0/wJ/JM/P4zS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
