<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We are here to petition Safeway for fair treatment of its employees. Safeway has been cheating its employees and abusing their rights!

I personally have been fired from Safeway due to a minor discrepancy. One of the younger sales associates took 8 cents off of my purchase without my knowledge using a store coupon. I was suspended alongside with 21 other employees in 2 months' period. I later received a letter informing me of my termination. Having called the UFC Local 400 (Safeway's union) every day for 2 weeks, I&#8217;ve waited for a response for a month and a half and I haven&#8217;t heard back from them to this day.

When I was hired as a full time food clerk I was earning $6.15 an hour. Later I found out from my union representative that the minimum wage Safeway is allowed to pay deli food clerks is $7.10 an hour. I&#8217;ve now been trying to file a claim for retroactive reimbursement, but, as I stated earlier, it&#8217;s virtually impossible to get in touch with the union that took a decent chunk of my paycheck every week.

Unfortunately I'm not the only person who&#8217;s been cheated by this company. A partially disabled woman in her 30s with bills to pay got a job in the deli and was promised 30 - 40 working hours weekly.  That never happened. After working in the deli for a few months she was further demoted to a courtesy clerk position due to her disability and got a pay cut. She is now unable to pay her bills and meet many other expenses.

Safeway needs to know that its employees will not stand for this poor and demeaning treatment. Consequently, if Safeway continues such humiliating practices it will stand a major threat in having legal employee confrontation and boycott on the customers&#8217; side.

1. Unfair pay of Safeway's employees must stop.

2. Unfair treatment of disabled employees is wrong and must cease.

3. Unjust termination of employees is wrong.</description>
  <mission>Provide fair treatment for Safeway employees</mission>
  <name>Fair Treatment For Safeway Employees</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9748</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.02</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Uk/Gj/CM/CC/nc/Wu/QdOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
