<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What is diverticulitis? 

Diverticulitis is a condition in which diverticuli in the colon rupture. The rupture results in infection in the tissues that surround the colon. 

What is diverticulosis? 

The colon (large intestine) is a long tube-like structure that stores and then eliminates waste material. As a person ages, pressure within the colon causes bulging pockets of tissue (sacs) that push out from the colon walls. A small bulging sac pushing outward from the colon wall is called a diverticulum. More than one bulging sac is referred to as diverticula. Diverticula can occur throughout the colon but are most common near the end of the left colon called the sigmoid colon. The condition of having these diverticula in the colon is called diverticulosis. A patient with diverticulosis may have few or no symptoms. When a diverticulum becomes infected and ruptures, the condition is called diverticulitis. A patient suffering from diverticulitis will have abdominal pain and tenderness, and fever. When bleeding originates from a diverticulum, it is called diverticular bleeding. A patient who suffers the consequences of harboring diverticulosis in the colon is referred to as having diverticular disease. 

Diverticular disease is common in the Western world but is extremely rare in areas such as Asia and Africa. Diverticular disease increases with age. It is uncommon before the age of forty, and is seen in more than fifty percent of people over the age of sixty in the United States. Whereas most patients with diverticular disease have no or few symptoms, some patients will develop bleeding, infection (diverticulitis), constipation, abdominal cramps, and even colon obstruction.



1. We need to know that eating healthy will help eliminate diverticulitis which is a disease.</description>
  <mission>Inform people of this type of disease.</mission>
  <name>Diverticulitis</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9759</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">106</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/fx/xm/EM/iK/GH/kt/NrIS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
