<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The funds received from the Show Me Campaign will directly support the Millennium Village intervention work to eliminate hunger, improve health and fight disease in 5 villages in Tanzania. The Tanzania cluster has a total population of roughly 25,000 people, and include the villages: Ibiri, Ilonglangulu, Isenga, Mabama, Msimba.

Background: 
In 2007, inspired by reading "The End Of Poverty" by Columbia University Professor, Dr. Jeffrey Sachs, John Legend traveled to Ghana in West Africa where he recognized "the real, tangible impact of extreme poverty on millions of people around the world."  His response was to launch the Show Me Campaign (ShowMeCampaign.org), a grassroots movement whose mission is "to fight economic and spiritual poverty through fostering sustainable development (personal, social, educational, economic) at the individual, family, and small community levels."

&#8220;Show Me&#8221; is a song written and performed by John Legend on his sophomore album, Once Again.  &#8220;I originally wrote &#8216;Show Me&#8217; as a prayer to God asking simple honest questions about life and death and why there&#8217;s so much suffering in the world.  As I grew with the song, I realized I shouldn&#8217;t limit those questions solely to God; I should ask those questions of others and myself&#8221; says Legend.  &#8220;Show Me&#8221; has grown from a question into a call to action. The simple yet profound themes of the song form the founding principles for the Show Me Campaign.  




1. Our generation can end extreme poverty by 2025

2. Global Poverty is Over, if you want it.  </description>
  <mission>End Extreme Poverty by 2025. </mission>
  <name>Join John Legend in Ending Extreme Poverty by 2025 - Show Me Campaign</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9767</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1197</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">882.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Zf/Gl/bT/Dh/5f/LP/XA3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
