<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description> 
Scouting in Central and South Western Connecticut


The Connecticut Yankee Council, Boy Scouts of America serves over 25,000 youth members and over 5,600 volunteer leaders within five separate age-appropriate programs in the Fairfield, New Haven County area of Connecticut and the town of Southington in Hartford County.

The Scouting program here in the Connecticut Yankee Council provides 554 positive value-based; educational orientated programs for youth. These 544 different programs (called units) are split amongst five different age appropriate programs; Cub Scouting (boys in grades 1-5), Boy Scouting (boys age 11-18), Venturing (co-ed program for boys and girls 14-21 based on outdoor high adventure) Exploring (co-ed program for boys and girls 14-21 based on career development), and Learning for Life (in-school co-ed program for youth in grades K &#8211; 12).

In addition to the many services that Connecticut Yankee Council finances so that young men and women may experience an affordable Scouting program, the Council also provides over $20,000 in financial assistance to low income families who can not afford to send their child to an outdoor summer camp program.

Collectively, Scouts from Connecticut spent over 100,000 days camping at Sequassen Scout Reservation (Council owned Camp in Winstead), Deer Lake Scout Reservation (Council owned Camp in Killingworth), and John Sherman Hoyt Scout Reservation (Council owned camp in Redding).

1. Provide Scouting for all those who wish to join</description>
  <mission>To serve others by helping to instill values in young people and in other ways prepare them to make ethical choices over their lifetime in achieving their full potential.</mission>
  <name>Connecticut Yankee Council, BSA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9794</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">52</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/z6/4D/pZ/fc/Hp/6G/SZ2S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
