<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>P.O.P.T - Power of Positive Thinking

This cause was thought into existance by Pieter Kemp 28 July 2007.

The purpose of POPT is to tell as many people about the power of positive thinking, AKA Laws of Attraction.

Now you may of heard of the Genie and the Lamp, 3 wishes right? Wrong! You have endless wishes as long as you ask for it. eg. I'm sure my car is making a funny sound, something must be wrong...what happens, well something turned out to be wrong. What do you think about these words you are hearing? How is your current mood? Did you wake up on the wrong side of the bed this morning?
OR
Are you constantly fighting against the drama of the day by being positive and seeing the greater good in life. I must admit, this is extremely important to do, I too am guilty...more too often then needed.

P.O.P.T is a virtual name, no Copyright needed, nor is it a registered trademark. However when i did a Google search I found something quite interesting.

These are the results when searching for POPT&gt;&gt;&gt;Programs that use popt can easily allow users to add new command-line options, which are defined as combinations of already-existing options&lt;&lt;&lt;

I will now explain why this is quite odd.

Now think of your dreams, do you have dreams or are you a pilot who is busy flying without a mapbook, compass or communication? Write your dreams down, Read your dreams out a LOUD, believe in yourself that you are worthy more in life as these things which we think we are only capable of.

The already-existing options are our dreams, we must just create it in our minds eye.

This is my challenge to you...









1. Write down your dreams as if they already exist

2. Dont let the power of your dream be overshadowed by the drama of your day

3. Associate with people of the same POPT principles.

4. Ask and believe that you are worth more then what you might or might not believe about yourself

5. Read and listen to Audio books of people of a POPT nature

6. Tell as many people as possible about POPT

7. Be thankful for the things you have

8. Be greatful for other peoples success, as you want them to be greatful for your future/current success.

9. Love the person you are now</description>
  <mission>To Motivate people!</mission>
  <name>P.O.P.T</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9795</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">48</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/sV/sJ/Bm/Gz/41/LW/gQeS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
