<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Joining this cause means that you are making the Millennium Promise to help provide basic tools, knowledge and necessities to some of the poorest people in Africa which can put them on a path towards sustained growth.

The Situation:
Roughly 1 billion people continue to survive on less than $1 a day. That means they go hungry before they sleep most nights of the week. They walk miles to schools and clinics. They don't have clean water to drink. And they die needlessly from preventable diseases that could be cured or treated for a few dollars. 

But as large as these problems seem, they are not insurmountable. In fact we have the wealth, the knowledge and technologies to do so. These real problems have real solutions--like seeds and fertilizer, bed nets, school meals, wells, sanitation and connectivity. 

In the year 2000, all nations of the world agreed to reverse this by 2015. In 2007, progress has been made but most every country in sub -Saharan Africa is falling behind. It's up to this generation to do something about it and work with those people most in need to lift them out of poverty.

Millennium Villages are demonstrating that through small, affordable targeted investments that extreme poverty and the many causes that lead to it including, hunger, disease, lack of water, can be ended with an integrated approach to development.

Approximately 5,000 people live in each Millennium Village. The project currently works with nearly 400,000 villagers throughout rural Africa. There are currently 79 Millennium Villages located in10 countries in sub-Saharan Africa: Ethiopia, Ghana, Kenya, Malawi, Mali, Nigeria, Rwanda, Senegal, Tanzania, and Uganda. 



1. Eradicate Extreme Hunger and Poverty

2. Achieve Universal Primary Education

3. Promote Gender Equality and Empower Women

4. Reduce Child Mortality

5. Improve Maternal Health

6. Combat HIV/AIDS, Malaria and other diseases

7. Ensure Environmental Sustainability &amp; 8. Develop a Global Partnership for Development</description>
  <mission>Achieve the UN Millennium Development Goals</mission>
  <name>End Poverty by 2025</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9804</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1197</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">195.05</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/MZ/ED/AG/30/xq/KC/Vk/vtS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
