<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Polycythemia Vera is a clonal chronic progressive myeloproliferative disorder characterized by an absolute increase in the red cell mass and usually by an elevated leukocyte count, an elevated platelet count and an enlarged spleen. Polycythemia Vera differs from many other hematological malignancies in that prolonged survival is enjoyed by most patients if excessive production of red blood cells and platelets can be controlled. Clinical effects can be characterized by episodes of thromboses, bleeding and excessive itching after exposure to water. Prolonged survival can be interrupted by the development of other syndromes including myelofibrosis and acute leukemia. 
Our Family's Story:
Polycythemia vera is hereditary in our family.  My great-grandmother developed it late in life.
My grandmother developed the disease 12 years ago and at the time was only given 7 years to live.   Because of treatment and the loving care of her family she was able to survive as long as she did.  She passed away on July 27, 2007 after her Polycythemia converted to acute leukemia causing her to have a stroke.  She will be greatly missed.
I felt compelled to bring awareness to this disease after a discussion about whether or not there was a Polycythemia Foundation.  I did some research about possible foundations and there is none.  The only one out there is a blanket foundation for a collective of blood diseases/disorders.  
My hope is to help any foundations doing research for this disease.  There is no cure, but hopefully there will be better treatments and more they can do to make patients more comfortable. 
If you wish to donate please visit:  http://mpdfoundation.org/donations.htm
This is the foundation mentioned above.


1. Polycythemia vera is a disease that needs awareness and research.</description>
  <mission>Increase awareness of a little known disease, Polycythemia vera.</mission>
  <name>Polycythemia vera Foundation</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9813</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">301</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">148.4</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gR/V2/w5/ZZ/kK/Gp/28YS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
