<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Starfish Initiative began with the belief that there must be a more effective way to connect resilient, economically disadvantaged, talented and academically capable Scholars with the social and financial resources needed to ensure their success through college. 

**Our goal is to provide the very intense support required to protect and nurture our Scholars&#8217; dreams. We work to strengthen the Indianapolis community one Scholar, one opportunity, one dream at a time.**

What is Starfish Initiative?

Starfish Initiative is a not-for-profit organization that facilitates opportunities for economically disadvantaged high school students to achieve their dream of becoming powerful, successful models for future Hoosier generations.

What do we do?

We recruit eighth grade students by working with community centers, churches, private and public schools to identify students with potential to benefit from participation in the Starfish Initiative. We then  assist these students of exceptional promise to overcome the barriers of poverty and develop cultural capacity and leadership skills that prepare them to graduate from high school and college. Our goal is to "fill empty caps and gowns" by improving graduation rates in Indianapolis. 

For more information visit our website:
http://www.starfishinitiative.org/

OR call us at 317.955.7912


1. Provide intensive one-on-one mentoring and coaching

2. Offer leadership training

3. Motivate low-income youth and parents to understand that college is an option

4. Facilitate college-preparatory high school careers

5. Offer family-focused support services</description>
  <mission>To cultivate promising, at-risk youth into college-educated leaders, instilling in each student the desire to give back to the community.</mission>
  <name>Starfish Initiative</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9820</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">17</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/GA/6e/Eu/B8/7G/Nk/E1JS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
