<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>What affect does arts education have on a child?

Through the arts, a shy child blossoms, believing that he or she can truly accomplish the spectacular. Involvement in the arts lights up a child's face as the experience enlightens his or her soul.

Whether they are mastering the intricacies of Mozart or Chopin, or learning to pirouette en pointe, our students learn to express themselves in new creative ways as they discover and explore the arts at BMS.

Classes on-site at our facility in Brooklyn's historic Fort Greene neighborhood are offered after-school and on weekends and include lessons in all musical instruments and dance idioms. 

Over the years our students have progressed to perform at the professional level with such notable national companies as the Pittsburgh Ballet and the Miami Ballet. Current students have participated in the prestigious summer program offered by the Alvin Alley American Dance Theatre.

The next few years are critical to the future of BMS. In concert with the rejuvenation planned for our neighborhood, we intend to fully renovate our own landmark facility allowing us to expand our programming and in turn increase our service within the community.

At this time, we ask for your support. Our efforts are not possible without the generosity of our donors and benefactors.

The arts are an integral part in the building of a well-rounded person. 

Please consider making a gift to BMS. Your generosity will directly influence the creative development of Brooklyn's children.

1. Music is a fundamental part of every child's well-being.

2. If you don't act to revitalize this institution of music education, who will?</description>
  <mission>raise money to promote the Brooklyn Music School</mission>
  <name>Save the Music in Brooklyn</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9822</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">11</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">50.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/cr/Ir/ve/08/gD/rl/RFqS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
