<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The Northeast Family Center has established the Academy of Rock program to provide a powerful tool for engaging teens in a positive and creative atmosphere, empowering them to explore their musical interests, build self-esteem, and learn teamwork, regardless of their background, heritage, or income.

Whether it&#8217;s pop or punk, metal or blues, country or hip hop, the Academy of Rock provides the essential technical training and fundamental knowledge necessary to play in a band. Above all Academy of Rock is dedicated to the development of the whole person through mentorship with caring, supportive, and inspiring local professional musicians.

What started off as an after school club teaching simple cover songs at one Lincoln middle school has grown into its own program open to teenagers city wide. A great deal of this success is due to a strong community support system of local musicians who donate instruments and their time as volunteers to ensure that the program and each child experiences success. 

Because of this support, our students have enjoyed the experiences of playing multiple venues around Lincoln, spending time at local music studios, and meeting successful Nebraska artists.

These connections to the wider community have strengthened and enhanced the programs, but more importantly have demonstrated to our youth that they are valued and supported, and that they have skills and abilities that contribute to the community.

This success has been wonderful. Now youth more than ever are seeking out the Academy of Rock program and meeting that need has presented unique challenges to expand offerings and depth to our programs.

The Academy of Rock model has the potential to be implemented nationwide.

For more information visit http://www.Lincoln-NFC.org.

1. Youth have skills and abilities that contribute to the community.

2. Young musicians should have the opportunity to come together to play the music they love as a band.</description>
  <mission>Teach youth how to rock.</mission>
  <name>Academy of Rock</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9827</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">22</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/js/O0/In/RT/jS/jI/wusS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
