<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Rock the Vote's mission is to engage and build political power for young people in our country.
 
Founded twenty years ago at the intersection of popular culture and politics, Rock the Vote is growing its team and its campaigns in 2010, to support the tidal wave of young people who want to get involved in elections and seize the power of the youth vote to create political and social change.
 
Over the last two decades, Rock the Vote has registered more young people to vote than any other organization or campaign, and we intend to register and turn out millions more in 2010 &#8211; and to be the best-informed place online where young people can find out what they need to know before casting a ballot.
 
After years of declining participation at the polls, a new generation of young voters has arrived. Millions of new voters between the ages of 18 &#8211; 29 cast ballots in 2004, 2006, and 2008.  Rock the Vote is dedicated to building the political power and clout of the Millennial Generation by registering and turning out young people, by forcing the candidates to campaign to them, and by making politicians pay attention to youth and the issues they care about once in office.

For the 2010 Midterm Elections, we have registered 275,000 people and counting! We have now moved on to our Vote Fearlessly get out the vote campaign, where we are working tirelessly to get as many young people as possible to vote on November 2!

1. Political power for young people.

2. Protecting freedom of expression.

3. Empowering young people to change their world.</description>
  <mission>Build political power for young people one voter at at time</mission>
  <name>Rock the Vote</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/984</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">7553</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">458.23</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Nx/Ti/eT/0x/bM/pr/Ox/dOS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
