<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We at the Church of Google believe the search engine Google is the closest humankind has ever come to directly experiencing an actual God (as typically defined). We believe there is much more evidence in favour of Google's divinity than there is for the divinity of other more traditional gods.

We reject supernatural gods on the notion they are not scientifically provable. Thus, Googlists believe Google should rightfully be given the title of "God", as She exhibits a great many of the characteristics traditionally associated with such Deities in a scientifically provable manner.

We have compiled a list of nine proofs which we believe definitively prove Google's title as God.
&#187; PROOF #1
Google is the closest thing to an Omniscient (all-knowing) entity in existence, which can be scientifically verified. 
&#187; PROOF #2
Google is everywhere at once (Omnipresent). Google is virtually everywhere on earth at the same time. 
&#187; PROOF #3
Google answers prayers. One can pray to Google by doing a search for whatever question or problem is plaguing them. 
&#187; PROOF #4
Google is potentially immortal. 
&#187; PROOF #5
Google is infinite. The Internet can theoretically grow forever, and Google will forever index its infinite growth.
&#187; PROOF #6
Google remembers all. Google caches WebPages regularly and stores them on its massive servers. 
&#187; PROOF #7
Google can "do no evil" (Omnibenevolent). Part of Google's corporate philosophy is the belief that a company can make money without being evil.
&#187; PROOF #8
According to Google trends, the term "Google" is searched for more than the terms "God", "Jesus", "Allah", "Buddha", "Christianity", "Islam", "Buddhism" and "Judaism" combined. 
&#187; PROOF #9
Evidence of Google's existence is abundant. There is more evidence for the existence of Google than any other God worshiped today. 


1. The main purpose of Googlism is to promote the spread of knowledge through the use of Google.

2. There is nothing on Earth that connects people with the knowledge they desire as fast and effectively as Google. 

3. We believe in the clich&#233; "knowledge is power", and so should you.</description>
  <mission>Spreading the Word of the Church of Google</mission>
  <name>Googlism</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9840</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">179</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/gL/fN/wF/SJ/A8/So/5JRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
