<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://community.livejournal.com/sosrichmond/

http://www.greatamericanbakesale.org

http://myspace.com/greatamericanbakesale

http://eku.facebook.com/event.php?eid=4077793055

We are participating in Share Our Strength's Great American Bake Sale, an exciting and fun campaign to help fight childhood hunger in America. Today, there are more than 12 million children at risk of hunger in America. By participating in my Bake Sale, we can help end childhood hunger together. The proceeds we raise will directly benefit childhood hunger programs in our region.

Please contact us if you are interested in helping with an actual bake sale in Richmond. If we can get enough people to join me, we can help feed even more kids in need by having a physical bake sale and gain donations from Richmond and Lexington residents.

We're also holding a virtual Bake Sale. To help, simply:

1. Go to www.greatamericanbakesale.org
2. Click "Donate".
3. Search by the Bake Sale name, "S.O.S. Richmond."
4. Submit your online donation.
5. You will receive a letter of receipt in your inbox.

Together, we can help end childhood hunger in America!

For more information about the where the funds go or to host your own Share Our Strength's Great American Bake Sale visit www.greatamericanbakesale.org.

1. No child should ever have to go hungry.

2. Proper nutrition is key in helping today's children grow to become tomorrow's leaders.

3. Everyone can help somehow, whether it be through donation, volunteering or recruiting others.</description>
  <mission>raise money to provide food to needy children </mission>
  <name>Share Our Strength's Great American Bake Sale</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9844</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">105</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">150.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/4a/aJ/Uw/cH/oC/u5/P5KS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
