<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A 3 year old boy I met and lived with in Ecuador has recently become very ill.  Here is an update on his condition, which has unfortunately become much worse:

"Omar has a very rare congenital anomaly of the heart.  Essentially, his right ventricle does not have much if any muscle in it to pump the blood to his lungs and then subsequently to the rest of his body.  His right atrium has to do most of the work and therefore becomes enlarged.  This all can lead to collapse of the left lung as the heart impinges upon it as well as congestion of the liver as the heart cannot handle the blood that is trying to return to it to circulate.  The prognosis is very poor.  they are treating him with meds right now and he has an appointment again soon.  The doctor is talking to other doctors about possible surgery, but it is rarely done and apparently not with good results.  It is very expensive, possibly $20,000 for the surgery.  There are varying degrees of the anomaly with some people living well into adulthood.  However, there are many cases where the patients die as children.  It is just dependent on how much if any heart muscle Omar has.  The doc said we could speak again in a little while after he sees omar and talks to some more of his colleagues.  I think if it comes to surgery vs no surgery, we will have to seriously consider the possibility for recovery and weigh that against the exorbitant cost. 
     In the meantime, we can still be raising funds for his medicine as well as doctor's fees.  Apparently, the current doctor is not charging them much if anything.  However, I believe the timmy foundation has already incurred costs for omar."

A few other volunteers and myself have been trying to do some fundraising.  If anybody has any ideas, please let me know what you think.  

The Timmy Foundation is a non-profit organization aimed at helping children around the world with proper health care. They are also working on Omar's case - any money you donate here will help him and other children.

Thank you so so much for helping, if there's anything else you need to know or if you have ANY input, PLEASE do not hesitate to let me know.

1. Providing financial assistance for the unjust health care system in Ecuador</description>
  <mission>Provide financial aid to a boy in Ecuador who needs an operation.</mission>
  <name>OMAR</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9858</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">16</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">25.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/j1/ht/xM/o5/a1/2i/LkiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
