<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>According to Anti-Slavery International, over 20 MILLION people are in bondage. Unicef estimates that 200,000 children from jsut West and Central Africa are sold each YEAR.  

More than 43% of cocoa that comes west africa from  the Ivory coast, a poor naion where slavery is part of everyday life.  Children are often told they will live a better life there and will be able to support thier family with generous wages.  Families, however,never receive payment, and parents rarely see their children again.

These chilren suffer beatings and are starved.  They are kept locked up at night in small, filthy rooms, and they work more han 12 hours without breaks.  They are subject to dangerous working conditions, including using large machetes and pesticides without protection.  Although many children die or become to injured or sick to work, this does not stop people from using their labor.(teenink.com)

According to garstangefairtrade.org.uk there are an estimated 27 million slaves in Africa.  Thats TWICE the number of people taken from Africa during the 400 YEARS of the Atlantic slave strade.

An average slave in the American South in 1850 cost the equilvalent of $81,235.90 while today they cost only around $121.85 making them very accesable to anyone who watches them.

This is a huge problem.  But noone seems to know about it.  Slavery as been abolished in England for 200 years and for a long time in the U.S. as well.  Every country has it illegal.  I dont want your money, I just want to get the word out there that this is a huge problem and the world needs to know about this.

1. Slavery is a huge problem.

2. Slavery is worse than it was before.

3. People need to know about this problem.</description>
  <mission>Stop Slavery Worldround</mission>
  <name>Stop Slavery</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9866</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">57</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/SU/wH/CI/vM/sT/cw/nBRS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
