<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>A movement in Global Warming
Created By: Eric Worth





	My Project: Due to the many evidences that Global Warming has taken its effects on our beloved planet, we have to make our move to save it.  With glaciers and our two major ice caps melting three times faster than predicted, our future holds a place of despair and a place incapable of living.  Not only are there glaciers melting there is also; storms that are becoming deadlier as temperatures rise, increasing ocean temperatures causing the ocean to become more acidic and dense, more and more forest fires, rain storms that turned out to be extremely deadly, hurricanes hitting places never thought possible, less and less animal habitats, and many more planet threatening and life threatening issues.  If we don&#8217;t act soon, everyone&#8217;s life on this planet could be at risk.
	

     This is my plan of action: Educate people about the Climate Crisis with a video/documentary here in Vermont.  The video including scenes captured from around the Northeast kingdom.  Places rarely seen by... people who don&#8217;t live here, or for people who are just oblivious to what Vermont has.  For example, rivers and lakes secluded in the thick forests here in Vermont. Changes that Global warming has made to Vermont, i.e. how winter is becoming much, much shorter.  And rain is becoming much, much more popular.  

     When: When school has begun.  This will make it easier to distribute plans of action through out, making the word of Global Warming spread much faster.

      How Long: As long as it takes to get people to open their eyes.

1. Global Warming Is Happening.</description>
  <mission>Start A Movement About Global Warming and The Climate Crisis In Vermont.</mission>
  <name>OurOnlyHome&#8482;</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9871</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">39</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/aL/iT/Mi/NK/KS/Dz/MM7S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
