<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>The orphans of Kenya need our help.

Over 15 million homeless aids orphans live in Africa today.  1.5 Million of those live in Kenya with 100,000 in Nairobi alone.  Every student on this planet has a moral obligation to help these children lift their country out of poverty and famine through education. We all deserve to go to school and without our help these small children have no protection and face severe malnutrition, violence, sexual abuse, exploitation, abduction and even murder. 

Only one out of five girls enrolls in school, one out of ten completes primary school and one in a hundred completes secondary school.

I started The Nairobi Orphan Project because the problems these children face can easily be solved if each and everyone one of us makes a donation.  As a student myself who&#8217;s volunteering this summer to teach orphans in Nairobi I know first hand the enormous power we have to create a better future for our fellow students in Nairobi.  The Ivy League Challenge is a global fundraising effort to build boarding schools in Nairobi for 5-year-old AIDS orphans.  We have the privilege of a great education and here is our chance to pay it forward.  The challenge is to raise $100,000 next Year to build the first school and I know we can do it.  The challenge ends on 1st December 2008.

100% of the money raised goes to the &#8220;The Nairobi Orphan Project&#8221; Foundation who are building the school.  

THE WINNING UNIVERSITY WILL HAVE THE SCHOOL'S BUILDING NAMED IN THEIR HONOR  AND THE PERSON WHO RAISES THE MOST MONEY WILL WIN A FREE TRIP TO NAIROBI FOR THE OPENING OF THE SCHOOL!

We hope you and your friends will join us in showing the orphans of Nairobi that we care.

www.nairobiorphanproject.com

Dane Bailey
Harvard University

(The Nairobi Orphan Project's fiscal sponor is the International Humanities Center (IHC) who are responsible for processing all of our donations)

1. Education is a universal right.

2. Education is the key to ending poverty in Africa.

3. The responsibility of child poverty rests on the shoulders of every human being.</description>
  <mission>To build a school for 5 year old AIDS orphans.</mission>
  <name>Nairobi Orphan Project - The Ivy League Challenge/COLUMBIA</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9882</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">15.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/tX/Ho/fO/dm/Z3/wL/HP/L4S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
