<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>We're all supposed to get eight hours of sleep, right? Well, for many people &#8211; especially that raucous group known as college students &#8211; eight hours of sleep is a tale of mythology. Unfortunately, it is also a myth for the parents of children with cancer.

So in 1998, St. Jude Children's Research Hospital (founded by the one and only Danny Thomas) looked to harness the energy that seems to power college students and have them direct it toward supporting research against pediatric cancer.

Starting in St. Jude's own backyard at the University of Memphis, Up 'til Dawn continues to grow into a powerful fund-raising program that offers college students a chance to help raise funds and awareness for St. Jude.

The year-long fund-raising event program includes various fund-raising activities throughout the majority of the first semester into the beginning of the second semester and concludes with an all-night extravaganza which is usually held in February. And yes, these celebrations keep everyone up 'til dawn. Students stay awake in honor of the patients and families that endure so many sleepless nights at St. Jude. The students' motto is "cancer doesn't sleep, so neither should we."

Currently more than 200 colleges and universities nationwide participate in the program. Collectively, more than $15 million has been raised for St. Jude. This year, when the numbers flipped over to reveal the amount of money raised, everyone was excited to see that they went above and beyond their goal ending at an amazing $140,367!

Up 'til Dawn has proven to be an extremely effective philanthropy and not only does it benefit the children at St. Jude but all of the students involved in this great organization have been able to learn and grow from it as well. In the words of Travis Tritt, it's a great day to be alive!

1. A cure for childhood cancer must be found.</description>
  <mission>raise money for the children at St. Jude Children's Research Hospital while raising awareness</mission>
  <name>Up 'til Dawn @ University of Memphis</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/991</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1291</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">60.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/So/pl/4j/Sp/O7/7H/ds/6DS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
