<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Porphyria is a very rare metabolic /blood disorder. It affects very few people so not a lot of people have heard of the disease. Porphyria is a group of inherited disorders involving abnormalities in the production of heme pigments (the base material responsible for hemoglobin (red blood cell pigment), myoglobin (reddish muscle cell pigment), and another group of materials called cytochromes.
Porphyrias are characterized by 3 major findings: photodermatitis (light sensitivity causing rashes), neuropsychiatric complaints, and visceral complaints (such as abdominal pain or cramping). It can cause a lot of different problems in a person such as unexplained stomach pain, nausea, skin rashes, nerve problems, such as hysteria, hallucination, break downs, etc. It can even trigger other diseases or disorders. It was said that Charlemagne was said to have porphyria, he would go around his house naked screaming in sheer terror cause he was having hallucinations. There's not a lot that can be done about porphyria, research has come a long way since I was diagnosed with it, but it still not curable or prevented. There are medicines, injections, and certain things doctors can do now if it gets too bad or out of control. For women it can cause severe menstrual cramps, abnormal bleeding or period problems. It's as if your dying slowly when severe attacks comes on, and unless you have a miracle in your life I believe it can kill. But thankfully were in an age were there are medicines, and things that can be done to treat it if it gets out of hand. Porphyria is also known as the vampire disease. All I can say is it causes a major change in a persons mood swings, mind set, the pain grows intense and unbearable, and if I didn't pray and trust God to heal me when I did, I wouldn't be here today. But I'm hoping that in the future they will come up with a cure for this disease and people won't have to suffer like this anymore.


1. Research must go on, there must be a cure for this disorder.

2. More porphyria specialists are needed.

3. Porphyria is thought of too lightly, it is very serious and needs to be treated.</description>
  <mission>Inform, Support, and Cure.</mission>
  <name>Porphyria the hidden diease</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9945</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">246</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/24/1c/Xa/ok/up/44/XLnS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
