<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Polio is an infectious disease caused by the polio virus. The disease can strike at any age. The virus is passed through poor or careless hygiene, entering the body through the mouth, then multiplying inside the throat and the intestines. 

Once established, the polio virus can enter the bloodstream and invade the central nervous system, spreading along nerve fibers. As it multiplies, the virus destroys the motor neurons that activate muscles. The nerve cells cannot be regenerated and the affected muscles no longer function. Polio paralysis is almost always irreversible. 

In the most severe cases, polio virus attacks the motor neurons of the brain stem, resulting in difficulty breathing and can result in death. Most children and adults infected with the polio virus suffer only symptoms of a fever; only 1 percent of polio cases result in paralysis

A polio-free world is within our grasp. 

Join Rotary International in her efforts to end this crippling disease. Learn more about Rotary's ongoing effort to eradicate polio and how you can help through contributions to PolioPlus and PolioPlus Partners.

http://www.rotary.org/foundation/polioplus/

Despite tremendous progress in reducing the incidence of polio, it still exists. Polio will continue to threaten children everywhere as long as it exists somewhere. In this age of global travel, a new outbreak of polio might only be a plane ride away. 

Rotary International is the spearheading member of the Global Polio Eradication Initiative and is the largest private sector donor. It has contributed more than US$600 million to the polio eradication activities in 122 countries. In addition, tens of thousands of Rotarians have partnered with their national ministries of health, UNICEF, the World Health Organization, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and with health providers at the grassroots level in thousands of communities. 

1. Massive public education initiatives to promote immunization activities

2. Vaccine deployment strategies to reach children in remote or isolated regions

3. Using proper tools, such as vaccine carriers to protect vaccine in harsh temperatures and specimen containers to preserve the integrity of samples

4. Forming public-private partnerships that fortify national governments' health programs

5. A strengthened worldwide laboratory network will continue to support disease surveillance efforts long after polio has been eradicated

6. Most importantly, the global polio eradication program has paved the way for cease-fire truce agreements in a number of warring nations, negotiating major humanitarian assistance in fragile environments</description>
  <mission>To Achieve the Goal of a Polio Free World</mission>
  <name>PolioPlus</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9954</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">5061</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">934.1</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/45/vZ/3M/xI/D3/bg/AqxS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
