<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Grassroot Soccer uses the power of soccer to fight HIV and AIDS in Africa. An international 501c3 nonprofit organization, co-founded by Survivor Africa Champion Ethan Zohn, GRS trains professional soccer players, coaches, teachers, and other community role models to deliver game-based, interactive HIV prevention education with at-risk adolescents. GRS programs arm youth with the knowledge, lifeskills, and support they need to live HIV free and fight stigma in their communities.

To date, over 270,000 adolescents have graduated GRS programs in sub-Saharan Africa; we hope to reach over 1 million graduates by World Cup 2010 (which will be held in South Africa!).

Join the movement!

http://grassrootsoccer.org

A can't-miss 7 minute movie: http://lusakasunrise.com


"Grassroot Soccer's work is a refreshing and highly promising effort that can help turn the tide against HIV. Soccer is like a universal language...Grassroot Soccer reaches large numbers of young people with HIV education, and bases its programs on the best available evidence.&#8221;
- Helen Epstein, Author of The Invisible Cure: Africa, The West, and The Fight Against AIDS

"Football is a religion here...It's not easy to assemble 73 different tribes speaking literally 73 different languages, and football has been a catalyst. Football has played a very important role in bringing us together as a people, as a nation."
- Dennis Liwewe, Zambian Football Commentator

1. Young people (aged 15-24) make up 45% of all new HIV infections

2. 7400 new infections occur every day, though HIV is 100% preventable

3. Young people around the world have the power to turn the tide against the HIV pandemic

4. Role models (e.g. professional athletes) can set positive examples and inspire behavior change

5. Learning is NOT a spectator sport - interactive HIV prevention education is most effective</description>
  <mission>Using the power of soccer in the fight against HIV and AIDS</mission>
  <name>Grassroot Soccer United</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/996</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">3561</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">1130.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Ps/jc/SH/Yi/jb/x0/sS/EJS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
