<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>LifeNets.net is a non-profit association which is owned and operated by its members.  The self-proclaimed "Wikipedia of Activism"  we long to break down the traditional barriers between non-profit contributers and internal decision makers.  If you're tired of giving up your hard earned money to charitable organizations who only send you junk mail in return, this is the place for you.

Our Goal: Ending extreme poverty and genocide.
We are dedicated to the proposition that all human beings share an equal right to life.  Over half of the planet lives on less than 2 dollars a day and suffers from easily preventable diseases.  Despite the enormous amount of suffering created by extreme poverty, and the demonstrable success of economic interventions, less than a penny for every hundred dollars of wealth in the United States is spent on foreign aid.

Submit your thoughts and concerns to our government leaders/representatives via LifeNets.com at: 

http://www.lifenets.net/dev/?q=node/15&amp;refid=198

Don't delay what you can do today!




 



1. Communication &#8211; LifeNets is an organization dedicated to the art and science of effective communication. This is not a space for idealism or wishful thinking, but for pragmatism and scientifically rigorous study. Millions of lives hang in the balance. T

2. Competition &#8211; Those who perform the best are given more responsibility and influence within the community. The heart of the LifeNets meritocracy is action points which are awarded for various achievements such as inciting people to contact their represe

3. Cooperation  &#8211;  Cultures without competition become inefficient and dogmatic, unable to change or adopt new strategies.  Cultures without cooperation become inhumane. Our goal is to balance these two elements by fostering a competitive environment roote

4. Creativity &#8211; If ending genocide and extreme poverty were profitable, there would not be a need for this institution.  This means we will always have less money than business interests and other powerful political lobbies, and must out-think, not out-spe

5. Continouos Improvement  &#8211; What we do is too important to become complacent or allow ourselves to become satisfied with the way things were done before.  The true joy of work is in continually improving and making every day the start of something new.  I</description>
  <mission>TO END EXTREME POVERTY AND GENOCIDE</mission>
  <name>SAVE DARFUR - 400,000 KILLED AND COUNTING</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9964</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">10</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Z8/wG/a7/hD/N3/Vu/R2VS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
