<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>
Definitions pertaining to certain types of C.P. are written as follows.....  

Spastic Pelgia:  This type of Cerebral Palsy effects the legs and arms due to dammage in the brain that effects the motor skills of ones body, the lower extremides are more so effected then the arms, causing ones legs to turn in while walking, the arms are effeced in not fully opening the base of arms. The arms can only extend to a certain point before the muscles with the body tighten up and pull back , therefore, not allowing the full arm extention. With the legs, because the legs have a tendensy to curve in people with Spastic Cerebral Palsy gain a great deal of trouble with the allignment of ones hips its joints and sockets.  People with spastic C.P.  often encounter arthritus sooner then most abled - normal body people.  Spastic Cerebral Palsy is the worlds most C.P. disabillity

Atheiod Pelgia C.P. : Pertains not allowing stimulation to flow with the muscles , therefore a person with Atheiod Cerebral Palsy , has very little movement within their body. The only movement the can achieve is caused by artifical stimulation due to ones testing and treatments by ones medical doctors.  

Mixed Cerebral Palsy : is the the imformation as I illuted too earlier in the previous two definitions , but is a mixture , combonation which also may effect ones speech and sense of communication.  If you like a visual picture within your brain to allow to comprehend the difficullity of this disabillity allow yourself to picture a recent victim of a stroke, and then listen to speak, the brain does not proper commication as the linguists of the tongue.

Spastic Quadro Pelgia C.P. : The disabillity the effects the stimulation of arms and leg movement to be totally non functional. Most people with the type of Cerebral rely on wheelchairs from them to get from point A, to Point B in life. 




1. We need to raise much more awareness for the cause of Cerebral Palsy 

2. We need to have a voice and not to fear those people who are above us , like governments, 

3. There is much needed money in terms researching and finding cures for C.P. </description>
  <mission>Raise Awareness for the cause and disability of Cerebral Palsy</mission>
  <name>Driven for Victory</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9967</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">68</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/oU/kr/qi/0i/sS/U7/ZiiS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
