<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Alex Rodriguez. Commonly believed to be baseball's greatest player. Just signed a contract for $252 million over 10 years. Over $25 million a year. $45,000 per at bat. What did the average American make in a YEAR in 2005? $32,140.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Kimi R&#228;ikk&#246;nen. You may not have heard of him. He earns $51 million a year to drive a Formula 1 car.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Michael Jordan. In 1997, with endorsements from Nike (the horribly corrupt company that it is, but that's not what this is about), he made $78.3 million. That means that in 3.5 HOURS, he made what the average U.S. citizen made per year in 2005.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
What is the justification behind paying a person the same amount to swing a bat a few times as someone who works his ass off to better society? There is none. What is the justification behind paying someone $10,000 per minute of playing time to throw an orange ball? Can't think of any. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I don't care what you say about it "raising our hopes to achieve something in life" or "it gives us entertainment. "That's bull. You know what gives me hope in life and has since I was 3? Changing the world. Sure, it may give us entertainment, but is it worth it that one athlete is taking food from thousands around the world? I can entertain myself with a rubber band, thanks.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This must stop. Stop watching the games. Stop buying the tickets. Stop buying the shirts. Stop spending your hour's wage on a single hot dog. Go as far as never talking about it again. Please.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This is outrageous. And if you don't agree, then something is wrong with you. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
NOTE: All donations go to the Vh-1 Save the Music foundation, NOT anything anti-sports related. The reason for this is because I got the inspiration for this cause because of the "Save the Music!" cause. Our schools' music programs are dying because they are replaced by sports programs.

1. Professional sports salaries are outrageously high.

2. For the very minor contributions sports provide to society, it is not worth the cost.

3. By reducing athletes' salaries we can benefit the rest of society.</description>
  <mission>Drastically reduce the money dedicated to professional sports by not acknowledging its corrupt existence in order to fund endeavours that actually help the world.</mission>
  <name>Boycott Professional Sports</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9969</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Rm/dv/az/dE/Q2/DG/XQcS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
