<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>http://www.hisnets.org

:: The Problem ::

&#8226; Malaria claims twice the number of victims as AIDS each year. 
&#8226; Globally, 500 million people are infected with malaria every year. 
&#8226; Over 2.2 million people die from malaria annually. 
&#8226; 90% of all cases are found in Africa 
&#8226; Every 30 seconds a child dies of Malaria. 
&#8226; One case of malaria can cause up to 100 other infections. 
&#8226; Pregnant women and children under the age of 5 are most susceptible to malaria.

" The biggest problem is that westerners only think of HIV. HIV is a horrible disease of course. But, it is malaria that keeps Africa down. And the saddest part is that it is an entirely preventable disease." 
- Dr. Lamine Diawara (A Sengalese physician)


:: The Solution ::

HIS Nets is a non-profit organization which provides a Christian response to the global malaria epidemic in sub-Saharan Africa. While raising awareness of this on-going global crisis, HIS Nets is also mobilizing Christians and other caring groups to save lives and improve the quality of life of those in high malarial areas of sub-Saharan Africa.

HIS Nets purchases insecticide treated sleeping nets which are then given to African families. These special nets provide protection to an entire family at a modest cost. The nets are distributed by churches and other agencies free of charge as a tangible Christian witness.

&#8226; One net costs less than $6.00, so for less than the price of a dinner or movie, one life could be saved and an entire family can sleep in peace. 
&#8226; These special nets continue to protect families from mosquitoes, and thus malaria, for up to four years. 
&#8226; These nets have been proven to cut the incidents of malaria infection by half and child deaths from malaria by one-fifth.

info@HISnets.org

1. Most Americans and other westerners believe that AIDS is the biggest problem in Africa today.  Malaria, however claims twice the number of victims as AIDS each year.

2. The biggest problem is that westerners only think of HIV. HIV is a horrible disease of course. But, it is malaria that keeps Africa down. And the saddest part is that it is an entirely preventable disease.

3. Misquito nets, for less than $6, can save the lives of entire families.

4. These nets have been proven to cut the incidents of malaria infection by half and child deaths from malaria by one-fifth.

5. We provide a Christian response to the global malaria epidemic in sub-Saharan Africa. While raising awareness of this on-going global crisis, HIS Nets is also mobilizing Christians and other caring groups to save lives and improve the quality of life of t</description>
  <mission>To Stop The Malaria Epidemic In Sub-Saharan Africa With Misquito Nets</mission>
  <name>HisNets - Fighting Malaria: One Net At A Time</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9971</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">85</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">104.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eu/Mq/S6/4e/gT/4p/pIjS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
