<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Trailer Park Boys is a hilarious Canadian mockumentary television series focusing on the misadventures of a group of trailer park residents who live in Sunnyvale Trailer Park, located near Halifax, Nova Scotia. The show's creator and director is Mike Clattenburg. He is quoted describing it as "sorta like the show Cops, but from the criminal's perspective"

TPB has been a great success for the Canadian cable network Showcase, where regular programming includes several shows that also screen on major U.S. networks including Weeds, CSI, The L-Word, and Curb Your Enthusiasm. 

Despite the fact that Trailer Park Boys is Showcase's highest-rated Canadian series- their industry partners will not play the show uncensored to an American audience, and apparently are now starting to censor it more themselves.

It airs uncensored in the United Kingdom and Spain on Paramount Comedy, in the Republic of Ireland on Channel 6 , in Iceland on Skj&#225;reinn, in Australia on the Comedy Channel, in New Zealand on TV 2, in Israel on Xtra HOT, in the Netherlands on MTV Netherlands, in Denmark on DR2, in Portugal on SIC Radical, in Germany on Comedy Central Germany, and in Finland on Nelonen. 

In the united States, the network 'BBC America' formerly aired a stupidly (on their behalf) heavily-censored version of the show, and since everything was bleeped out and no-one could distinguish what in the flying fuck they were saying- it is no longer part of their lineup. Meanwhile- the show just launched to air in Poland on Comedy Central Polska!

Join this group to support the move to get this brilliant series finally fully aired on TV in America!

We love Trailer Park Boys, let's set it free!

1. Never trust a man with no shirt on!

2. Never Cry Shitwolf

3. If You Love Something, Set It Free</description>
  <mission>To bring this brilliant series back to American television!</mission>
  <name>Bring 'Trailer Park Boys' back to American TV Uncensored!</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9976</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">673</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/7v/j6/UF/AA/So/4b/QrTS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
