<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>If you would like to show your support add your name onto this letter to Peter Beattie. click on this link http://paradigmoz.wordpress.com/an-open-letter-to-the-queensland-government-in-support-of-palm-island-community-control-of-the-palm-island-community-store/#comment-524

To the Premier of Queensland, Mr. Peter Beattie and the Queensland Minister for Communities, Mr. Warren Pitt.


We the undersigned are writing to you regarding the privatisation of the Palm Island store and the decision the government has to make in awarding the tender for the store. 

You are faced with a choice between a body dominated by government representatives and people not from the Palm Island community or a corporation controlled by the people of Palm Island. We strongly urge you to support community self management as a key principle in making your decision.

We hope you will see the development of the Palm Island Community Store Aboriginal Corporation as a very significant and positive step in building a culture of economic enterprise, self responsibility and community pride amongst the people of Palm Island. We certainly do.

Please support this innovative development and award the Palm Island store tender to the Palm Island Community Store Aboriginal Corporation.

Yours sincerely,


1. The power of the opperating of the Palm island community store must stay with the Aboriginal community. 

2. Media is highlighting all the negative in the community so the government can control what happens on the island.  

3. Finally you have the power to stop the white man from invading Australia</description>
  <mission>To keep the Palm Island community store run by the Aboriginal community </mission>
  <name>Support Palm Island</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9978</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">1245</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.12</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/Yj/d5/KT/jV/yW/e3/8g3S.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
