<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Globalization has brought in its wake great tragedies of inequality: injustice in the distribution of resources, health, and human rights.  As the AIDS pandemic sweeps up millions in its deadly grip, heavy loads of debt drain resources of the countries that are most in peril. And as children die from diseases long eradicated in rich countries, their parents are further impoverished by trade agreements that undermine the economic stability of small farmers.

These are not separate problems, but interrelated pieces of a global crisis, one rooted in the continuing actions of the powerful.  Medicines exist to fight AIDS and other dread diseases, but most of those sick are denied access to them.  The wealth required to forgive poor countries their debts is insignificant, but rich countries continue to demand repayment.  The resources required to stem the spread of malaria are trivial, but simple bed nets are out of reach of the poorest and most at risk.  And inequitable trade deals continue to be penned by the powerful at the expense of the poor.  These are not intractable problems, they simply require different action, and soon.

Now a student movement is rising to challenge these injustices, to demand that all are served fairly by international systems of governance and economics. The Student Global AIDS Campaign, the Student Campaign for Child Survival, and the Student Trade Justice Campaign act on the premise that youth need not wait to make a difference; indeed, the only time to act is now.

1. Issues of global injustice are rooted in a common crisis, and cannot be fought separately.

2. Educating ourselves about the crises is an important fist step, but only advocacy and action will yield an end to this disaster.

3. Young people can make a positive difference now; if we wait to take action, it will be too late for far too many people.</description>
  <mission>demand an equitable future for all</mission>
  <name>Global Justice</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/998</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">252</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/eHP/2zXS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
