<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Journeys of the Heart is a non-profit, licensed and accredited agency based in Hillsboro, Oregon, that completes domestic and international adoptions. Journeys also has offices in Seattle, Washington, Honolulu, Hawaii, and just outside of Chicago in Glen Ellyn, Illinois. We are a mid-sized agency which places approximately 150 to 170 children per year. We have international programs in about a dozen countries, in addition to a very active domestic program, placing children born in Oregon, Washington and Illinois with families throughout the country. 

Journeys offers a personal and unique adoption experience. Here's why: Our commitment to adoption comes from our concern for all children, and a personal passion for adoption. We, Susan and David, started the agency in 1993 with a goal of getting as many of the world's children out of harm's way as possible, and into homes where they can grow and thrive in a safe, loving environment. 

We have been so profoundly touched by adoption, personally and professionally, that we only wish others to share in this joy. We can only describe it as life's greatest adventure - a journey of the heart. 

If adoption is in your heart and your future please contact us.  We will answer all of your questions.
info@journeysoftheheart.net


ZOO BALL LOVERS? High School and College Students alike can participate in the JOH annual fundraiser at the Brookfield Zoo! Contact me (KC) or any of the current WBHS NHS officers in the fall to learn how you can help (and have a good time!)!

Visit http://www.journeysoftheheart.net/bracelet/order.html to buy a purple adoption cause bracelet for $3.00!!! They're cute and the funds benefit JOH programs for children!

1. Every child deserves a safe, permanent, loving home.</description>
  <mission>Make Forever Families</mission>
  <name>Journeys of the Heart Adoption Services</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9983</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">24</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">10.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/1V/ty/b6/3Z/M4/hX/BzmS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
