<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Never has a man who retired from the game at the point that Art did been so summarily forgotten despite some of the lofty achievements that dotted his resume. Art Monk played in 3 Super Bowls (was injured for one) and won 3 rings for the Washington Redskins. 

He was the designated 3rd down receiver - someone the myriad of Redskin QBs that he played with knew would always get the first down. He was the consummate professional. He caught the ball as well a blocked well for his running backs and fellow receivers. And most importantly, he retired from the game as the most prolific receiver in the game. 

In an age where most receivers gain their notoriety by being vocal in the media, Art Monk exuded the kind of quiet confidence of a role model. A guy who went to work every day, did his job completely, and was satisfied that his teammates and coaches could count on him. And it's this that no doubt has hurt his chances of being enshrined in the Pro Football Hall of Fame.

The naysayers, like Sports Illustrated's Peter King and Dr. Z, have said that he wasn't feared by the opposition. That he wasn't the best receiver on his own team. That he doesn't have any highlight catches. All pithy explanations when compared with the value he had to his team, his career numbers, and his consistant play over the length of his career.

What a lot of people fail to realize when they compare Monk's numbers to the kind of numbers receivers put up nowadays is the proliferation of pass-happy offenses. Monk and his contemporaries (Mark Clayton, James Lofton, Henry Ellard, etc.) are the victims of this thinking. You have to compare his numbers with the players of his era. 

Spread the word and let local and national journalists and radio hosts everywhere that they need to investigate this story more. Talk to his coaches and teammates, like Joe Gibbs or Joe Thiesmann. Art Monk deserves to be in the Hall of Fame.

1. Art Monk deserves to be in the Pro Football Hall of Fame

2. Judging receivers by their highlight catches (Lynn Swann) or their self-promotion (Dallas Cowboy receivers) is not the way to identify the best of the best.

3. Anyone who retires as the best at his position numberswise deserves to be looked at as one of the best of his era.</description>
  <mission>Get Art Monk Enshrined in the Pro Football Hall Of Fame</mission>
  <name>Art Monk to Canton</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9992</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">6</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/pI/SO/uG/0E/0Q/GP/iniS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
