<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>There is No Global Warming
You can't find a real scientist anywhere in the world who can look you in the eye and, without hesitation say, "Yes, global warming is with us." There is no evidence whatsoever to support such claims. Scientific research shows that the temperature is actually cooling - very slightly - .037 degrees Celsius.  Because of modern science and improved equipment, this "cooling" trend has been most accurately documented over the past 18 years. Ironically, that's the same period of time the hysteria has grown over dire warnings of "warming." There is no proof that temperature is affected by anything that man has done. In fact, recent severe weather has been directly attributed to a natural phenomenon called El Nino. El Nino has been wreaking its havoc across the globe since long before man appeared. How about the reports that the polar ice cap is melting? Well, yes it is. In fact, it has been for about a million years or so. We are at the end of the ice age in which ice covered most of North American and Northern Europe. It is an outrage for Al Gore to tell you that most true scientists now agree that global warming is a fact. Almost 500 scientists from around the world signed the Heidleburg Appeal in 1992, expressing their doubts on global warming. Today that figure has grown to over 4000. Recently a Gallup Poll of eminent North American climatologists showed that 83 percent of them debunked the global warming theory. The United Nations released a report at the end of 1996 saying Global Warming was a fact, yet before releasing the report two key paragraphs were deleted from the final draft saying: 1. "none of the studies cited above has shown clear evidence that we can attribute the observed climate changes to increases in greenhouse gases."2. "no study to date has positively attributed all or part of the climate change to ...man-made causes." Entire article at: http://www.americanpolicy.org/un/thereisnoglobal.htm



1. Research more, before you jump to conclusions.

2. Don't believe everything anyone tells you,  just because they have a nice suit and a powerpoint presentation.

3. Have your own ideas about things.

4. Be individual, because that is the first step to freedom.</description>
  <mission>To learn the truth about things, and not fall under the over exaggerated statements the media and government has forced down our throats.</mission>
  <name>Global Warming Doesn't Exist.</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9996</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">95</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">0.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/LL/0a/FS/wf/7H/tB/BiFS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
