<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cause>
  <description>Founded in 1998, MENY is the oldest organization in the state of New York to advocate full and equal marriage for same-sex couples. A grassroots, not-for-profit organization, MENY and its dedicated volunteers are devoted to ending discrimination in civil marriage through education, awareness and media campaigns, political actions, and coalition building. Marriage Equality New York is also the founding chapter of Marriage Equality USA, the national organization with chapters in California, Ohio, and Pennsylvania.

Marriage Equality New York is a grass roots, all-volunteer organization with over 3,000 members and supporters and counting.

Without marriage, committed same-sex couples are denied over 1,138 federal rights and obligations including social security, hospital visitation, co-parenting rights, estate tax, and immigration, just to name a few.

1. Education. The key to winning our marriage rights is making sure our community, our allies and the rest of America learns how vital civil marriage is 

2. Media. Greater awareness lessens the fear many people have around same-sex marriage. MENY makes sure the media gets our side of the story, and the fac

3. Partnerships. MENY works building partnerships and alliances with LGBT and straight organizations, civil groups, churches and key individuals to get o

4. Political Advocacy. MENY carries the fight straight to Albany, lobbying our public servants to bring fairness to the law. We want equality and many of</description>
  <mission>An all-inclusive organization whose mission is to raising awareness of the important right of all persons to enter into legally recognized gender neutral civil marriage.</mission>
  <name>Marriage Equality New York</name>
  <canonical-url>http://www.causes.com/causes/9997</canonical-url>
  <member-count type="integer">8652</member-count>
  <total-raised type="decimal">3595.0</total-raised>
  <photo-url>https://causes-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/uv/br/sZ/wY/Z3/uq/EOpS.jpg</photo-url>
</cause>
